Chapter 6

There was something about the first of September that made anticipation crackle like lightning in her stomach. It wasn't just the Modified Polyjuice that she'd taken that morning, though the unpleasant sludge wasn't helping. It was the air itself, the barest chill in the morning that anticipated the turn of the season. She smoothed the school robes she'd already changed into and took a final glance in the mirror to make sure all was in order before she joined the others in their compartment.

Rigel's face hadn't changed at all from the beginning of the summer. Unfortunately, it had been impossible to update her Modified Polyjuice due to simple logistics. She had just been at Draco's house as Rigel, and didn't think she could pass off the dramatic shift in a space of a few weeks as unconscious metamorphing when 'Harry' hadn't undergone a sudden growth spurt in the same period. They would have to make do with waiting until next summer to update it properly; perhaps she and Archie would both have long absences abroad.

She'd still opted to take another dose of Modified Polyjuice, using the same hairs as the dose she'd taken at the beginning of the summer. She'd learned her lesson with the time-turner last year. Even though there was no reason to think she'd have to go longer than the end of term to take another dose, Rigel wasn't going to make such assumptions again.

Finding nothing amiss, Rigel left the bathroom and made her way down the train until she reached the compartment her friends favored. For once, she was the last to arrive. Pansy rose to greet her at once, the fierce smile on her face enough to warm Rigel's spirit even before the other girl wrapped Rigel in a firm embrace.

"Let me look at you," Pansy said, holding Rigel still with her hands while she examined her. "You've changed a lot, as usual." Rigel supposed from Pansy's perspective, she had. Pansy had last seen her at the end of term, before over a year and a half of compressed time had caught up to her. Luckily, she still looked a bit younger than she should, since she was older than her cousin now and the blending ritual averaged their ages to create the hair she used to assume her current face. Then again, her friends had all grown up a bit over the summer, too.

"You're one to talk," Rigel said, her eyes roaming over Pansy's features. The blonde girl's bone structure was more defined this year, as it looked like she'd lost most of the roundness in her face. As Pansy tilted her head and smiled, Rigel could see that her friend's poised expressions now had a face to match. Sometimes she forgot that Pansy was nearly a year older than her and Draco—or had been, in Rigel's case.

Pansy released her, but her eyes didn't leave Rigel's face as she asked, more seriously, "Are you doing all right, Rigel?"

She couldn't pretend not to know what Pansy meant, but she didn't really want to talk about that. Sirius had already made a minor fuss on the platform. He was deeply concerned with his son returning to Hogwarts after what had happened last year, though he tried not to show it. Rigel gave Pansy the same answer she'd given Sirius. "Never better." Honestly, she thought she'd be a lot better if people stopped bringing it up. Yes, she'd had a bad experience at Hogwarts last year, but the same could be said of every year so far. Despite that, there were far more good memories for her at Hogwarts than bad.

"How was everyone's summer?" she asked as she took the last remaining seat next to Millicent and across from Blaise.

"Wouldn't you like to know?" Theo's suggestive tone was accompanied by wagging eyebrows, which prompted Millicent to punch him in the arm and scowl.

"Not anymore we don't." The dark-haired girl was a couple inches taller and her voice had a lower, smoother quality to it than Rigel remembered. "I spent the summer abroad," Millicent added. "My father took me to Geneva with him to further my political education."

"Were you there after the World Cup?" Blaise asked, leaning forward with his elbows on his knees. As always, the intensity of his calculating, somewhat cat-like eyes distracted from any attempt to catalogue the rest of him, but Rigel still got the impression that he, too, was a bit taller.

Millicent nodded, grimacing. "What a fiasco. The British Ministry's reputation has never been worse. We insisted on controlling the event, and now it's come back to bite us."

"I hear Bulgaria has incinerated a number of our trade agreements," Theo said.

"They weren't the only ones." Blaise made a token attempt to sound concerned, but the primary expression on his face was fascination. "Several European nations have expressed reservations about doing business with Britain in the wake of an event many perceive to be destabilizing."

"Idiots," Draco said, shaking his head. "They'll regret that. My father says there's something big in the works that's going to make all this go away."

Millicent sat up straighter in her seat. "My father hinted along similar lines! Do you know what's going on? All I've gathered is that it involves Hogwarts in some way. It must be something monumental, if they want to sweep the World Cup disaster under the rug quickly."

"Father wouldn't give me specifics," Draco admitted. "He kept saying I'd find out soon enough. Then he started showing up to my dueling practice and giving me pointers. I can't fathom that he wants me involved in anything going on at that high a level, though."

"Very suspicious," Blaise agreed. "Mother hasn't said anything, but then, she rarely interests herself in politics beyond the social gatherings."

"Father told me to keep my head down this year," Pansy said, frowning slightly. "I did think it odd, but it makes sense if something big is happening at Hogwarts. Is the Party organizing it, then?"

Draco nodded. "Lord Riddle made it sound as though it was the Ministry's doing, but the way he and Father talked about it, I could tell it was meant to further our agenda somehow. Don't you think, Rigel?"

Rigel kept her face carefully neutral as she said, "Most likely. No doubt the Ministry is supporting it in order to recoup their losses from the World Cup." She was going to say something more, but a sharp pain in her head distracted her. She winced minutely and pushed her thoughts toward the likely perpetrator. Dom, not a good time to practice.

The jewel had been working on communicating with her sans meditation, as promised. So far, he didn't seem to have a good way to get her attention without pain, though the discomfort had been reduced with each successive time the construct attempted it. Dom's reply floated up in the back of her mind softly, like a bubble of air rising to the surface of a lake before popping. Not practicing.

Rigel fought not to frown. A real warning? She was on the middle of the Hogwarts Express, for Merlin's sake. None of her friends even had sustained eye contact—how could she be under mental attack? She caught Draco glancing at her furtively from across the isle and suspicion bloomed. Was Dom picking up on Draco's empathy? Had Draco scanned her emotions to try and get an idea of how she felt about Riddle's plans? Rigel summoned her Occlumency skills and smoothed her emotions into utter calmness. After a few moments, the slight headache receded and she assumed whatever it was Dom was reacting to had stopped.

She'd only been distracted for a minute, so the conversation was easy to rejoin. Millicent was saying that the Ministry was desperate to look as though it was in control, so the big event their parents had hinted at must be a way to save face.

"It's about money for the Ministry," Rigel said, remembering what she was going to say earlier. "The Department of Games and Sports is bankrupt. All that personal property loss at the Cup means lawsuits and thousands of demands for refunds. Whatever Riddle has planned, if it brings in revenue, the Ministry will support it completely. Harry says her dad has a hand in some of the preparations, too, so this thing is at least big enough to warrant professional security." Her father had intimated as much when she'd prodded Archie into asking James if he should expect to see him at Hogwarts that year. James had awkwardly said he wasn't at liberty to confirm anything, which essentially confirmed it. If the Auror Department was involved, the Ministry was giving Riddle their full cooperation.

Her friends all exchanged wary looks. "That makes it sound like it could be a spectator event of some kind," Theo said slowly. "Making money usually means asking for donations or charging for something."

"And either one requires the same thing: press," Millicent said.

Draco scowled. "How troublesome. We'll have no peace."

"We'll be expected to put a very good face on," Pansy added, nodding slowly. "It explains Father's advice, too. With the anti-pureblood backlash from the Cup, we can't afford to draw too much attention to ourselves in front of the media."

Theo huffed a sigh. "All plans for a quiet year foiled before it even begins. Face it; we're cursed."

"What do you mean 'we'?" Blaise sent Rigel a half-lidded look.

Draco and Pansy both bristled on her behalf.

"You can't blame Rigel for—"

"How dare you suggest such a—"

The compartment door slid open, cutting off the their outrage. A head of yellow pigtails poked in shyly and a pair of wide eyes swept the compartment slowly before resting on Blaise. "Um. Hi," she squeaked out, voice barely above a whisper.

"Hannah." Their dark friend stood gracefully and smiled. "Excellent timing. Shall we?"

He shot a small smirk over his shoulder as he exited the compartment with the Hufflepuff girl in tow. Pansy shot him a resigned glare and Draco looked positively murderous.

"He did that on purpose," Draco snarled.

"Enhanced shifter hearing," Theo said, nodding sagely. "Probably knew she was coming all the way down the train car."

"I thought her relatives didn't approve of Blaise," Millicent said, a contemplative frown on her face. "Last I heard their families haven't reconciled."

"He doesn't care," Theo said, shrugging. "Blaise chose her, and he'll keep at it until he gets his way."

Millicent quirked an eyebrow at Theo. "Perhaps Blaise is more like his mother than I realized. I've heard Lady Zabini always gets what she wants, too."

Pansy shook her head. "Careful what you suggest, Millie. Lady Zabini also has a tendency to outlast her critics."

As a group, they agreed it would be best to change the subject. The afternoon wore into early evening, and Rigel was just contemplating a nap when their compartment door opened again, this time for the Weasley twins. Rigel assumed they were there to see her, but to her chagrin both Fred and George zeroed in on Draco with Kneazle smiles.

Draco scowled at them, but rose unprompted and retrieved a substantial sack from his trunk. With the dignity only possessed by the truly annoyed, Draco handed it over to Fred's eager possession with barely a sniff.

"What a pleasure doing business with you, Draco," Fred said cheerfully, bouncing the sack to produce a clinking noise that made him grin even wider.

Rigel watched Draco's eyebrow twitch at being addressed so casually by the redhead, but to his credit he did not rise to the bait. "Try not to lose it on your way out," he said stiffly, reclaiming his seat in open dismissal of the twins.

"How's it been, Rigel?" George asked, quite obviously not in a hurry to leave.

"Just fine, you?"

"Oh, you know, a little experimentation here, a minor re-purposing of the kitchen there." George shrugged. "We're pretty sure Mum would have kicked us out of the house if we'd been of age."

"There's always next year," she said encouragingly.

Fred and George laughed. "Good to see you, Pup," Fred said, saluting her as he pocketed the sack of galleons at last.

"See you around," George added, waving facetiously to the rest of the compartment before he and Fred took their leave.

When the compartment door shut behind them, Theo could no longer contain himself. "What did you do to owe the Weasleys that many galleons?"

"Shut. Up." Draco turned his face to the window and would say no more.

Mischievously, Rigel leaned around Millicent to mouth tell you later. She was impressed with her friend for keeping his end of the wager, but that didn't meant she wasn't going to let him be teased mercilessly for falling for it in the first place.

Rigel kept an eye on Draco as they settled at the Slytherin table in the Great Hall and awaited the Sorting. He was much more put together than the previous year. He looked comfortable in his own skin, and she was pleased that he seemed fully capable of controlling the emotive input his gift provided even in the moderately rowdy crowd of excitable returning students.

She was a bit fatigued from her menstrual cycle once again making an appearance. It had taken a couple of months to re-regulate her body after stopping her time-turner use, but she was back to her usual schedule now. She just wished they'd hurry up with the Sorting and start the feast. Her cramps were always worse when she was hungry.

"Is anyone we know being Sorted this year?" Draco asked Pansy.

Pansy tucked a lock of hair behind her ear thoughtfully, and Rigel noticed it was now long enough to reach past her shoulders. "I think the Rowle Heiress is eleven this year. The Carrow Heir, too."

"Don't forget Billy Travers," Millicent put in.

"I thought he was slated for Durmstrang." Pansy's mouth was a thoughtful moue. "Isn't his father friends with the Headmaster there?"

Millicent shrugged. "I saw him on the platform. I guess Durmstrang wouldn't take him."

"Durmstrang's definition of pureblood is more strict than Hogwarts'. I'm fairly sure one of his great grandmothers was a Muggleborn," Draco said.

"Durmstrang requires four generations of magical blood on both sides?" Rigel hadn't known that. It seemed a very strict requirement, and she wondered how many people at Hogwarts met that standard.

"Preferably more, but if your surname is old, you can get away with four as a minimum," Millicent explained. "And they don't make exceptions for creature blood, the way schools like Beauxbatons do."

"Technically Beauxbatons accepts all students, regardless of blood," Rigel pointed out.

"Technically, that's a load of centaur dung," Theo said, snorting in amusement. "If you look at their actual acceptance statistics, Halfbloods make up a steady five percent; they keep that quota for publicity purposes, and I hear the Halfbloods pay twice the tuition anyway. As for Muggleborns, I think the last one on record was six years ago, and she didn't graduate."

Rigel held her tongue, but she couldn't help the disgust she felt at how readily those of lesser blood were dismissed and discarded without ever being given a proper chance. She felt a small mental spike and flicked her eyes to Draco. He was watching her intently, and Rigel narrowed her eyes before quelling her emotions firmly. The pain subsided and she sent a quick, thanks Dom, to her mindscape. As the Deputy Headmistress at last paraded the first years into the hall, Rigel was left wondering just how often her friend scanned her emotions. Was he just using it on everyone all the time or did he check up on her emotional state specifically? Either way, she may have to be more careful.

The hall quieted, and the Sorting Hat came alive once more to sing.

"There is a tale you may have heard;

The whole world knows it well

And every year inside this hall

That story I retell

There once were four inspired lords

And ladies who it seemed

Did take upon themselves a task

That no one else had dreamed

On this site they built a castle

Matched to their ambition

Its walls would house the children if

Their plans came to fruition

Its doors would open wide to all

Who sought to fill their minds

Yes, every child was welcome here

Regardless of their kind!

Sir Godric loved the daring ones

And Salazar, the sly

Rowena sought the ones with smarts

And Helga, those who try

And while each had their favorites

The truth was widely known

The founders cared for all their charges

—Not one group alone!

Although Godric designed me to

Decide where you will stay

What many now forget is that

Each student got a say

The truth is that your choices are

What make you so unique

A cursory inspection just

Can't find the things I seek

No one is born courageous, wise,

Ambitious, or hard working

It's folly to imagine I

Could find such traits just lurking

It's willpower alone that makes you

Something to behold

So disregard your prejudice!

Forget what you've been told!

Instead look to your heart to judge

Who you would like to be

And when you try me on I promise

—that is what I'll see!"

Perfunctory applause rang out, but, like last year, it was filled with murmuring and curious commentary.

"I swear it gets less specific every year," Theo said, laughing a bit. "I mean, if it keeps deteriorating the first-years will have to sort themselves."

"It is quite old," Blaise pointed out. "Perhaps its magic is finally fading."

Rigel thought it more likely that the hat had simply forgotten its audience. Still, the Sorting proceeded without incident. The Carrow boy was the first to join Slytherin, and Rigel couldn't help but wonder how an eleven-year-old could have such a haughty look about them. Rowanda Rowle was a timid little thing, with long brown hair hanging into her face, and Travers, who seemed much too big to be a first-year, had a sullen-faced look about him that Rigel hoped wasn't permanent.

"Not much hope for the new lot," Theo commented as the Sorting Hat was taken away.

"Too soon to tell," Pansy said kindly.

They quieted as Dumbledore stood to give his opening announcements. The anticipation on her classmates' faces told Rigel they expected the Headmaster to say something about the anticipated event their parents had hinted at. Dumbledore, however, gave the usual start of term reminders and warnings and sat back down, with absolutely no reference or allusion to any kind of unusual happenings at Hogwarts that year.

Her eyes slid along the Head Table, noting the new faces. There were only two. One was a dark-haired man with a solid build who she supposed was probably the new Care of Magical Creatures professor, because the other one was Auror Dawlish. She recognized his close-cropped hair and perpetually serious expression. He could only be their new Defense professor, but she wondered whether Dumbledore or the Ministry had arranged for him to take a leave of absence from work for so long.

When the food appeared, her year-mates seemed too distracted to even notice, but Rigel dug in with alacrity while they furiously discussed the conspicuous lack of information.

"Maybe he's not permitted to say anything," Millicent supposed.

"More like he doesn't approve of whatever is happening," Draco said. "If it's something that's going to make the S.O.W. Party look good, there's no reason for Dumbledore to support it."

"If none of our parents have revealed it yet, chances are we won't find out until an official announcement," Blaise reasoned.

"You'd think they'd want to at least warn the students that something was going on," Theo said, sounding a bit put out. "After all, we can't be the only ones who have heard something from our parents.

"Ask Snape," Rigel said. Her friends all turned to look at her. She took a swig from her water goblet and cleared her throat. "He usually knows what the Party is up to when it happens at Hogwarts." At least, she suspected he did.

"You say 'up to' like it's going to be a bad thing," Pansy said, frowning slightly.

"Isn't it always?" Rigel shrugged as her friend's troubled expression deepened. "Maybe this year is the exception," she allowed. "I mean, bringing politics into a school full of kids never ends badly, does it?"

Draco was looking increasingly alarmed and Theo straight out gaped at her. Blaise shot a look up and down the table around them before leaning forward and lowering his voice. "Be careful, Rigel. The Party has ears everywhere, and it can make life difficult for you."

Rigel leveled a look at Blaise and slowly slid it to encompass each of her friends in turn before saying, "I don't give a brass Knut if the Party hears my opinion. I'll say it to Riddle's face. Whatever is happening at Hogwarts this year is a bad idea."

Pansy's face paled two shades and she immediately changed the subject. "Will you be starting up the Dueling Club again, Draco? We all so enjoyed it last year."

Draco picked up the thread of conversation easily, but his eyes kept flicking worriedly toward Rigel. He was not the only one. She knew she had unnerved the others with her blunt speech. She didn't care, though. She was so sick and tired of tiptoeing around the Party's ill-conceived plots while they played havoc with her life. As she picked at her food, waiting for the feast to end, she began to feel a bit guilty at startling them, though. It wasn't their fault that their families were embedded in the Party. They didn't know where the Basilisk came from, nor anything about the Dominion Jewel and Riddle's hand in its presence at Hogwarts. It wasn't really fair to put them in the position of listening to her criticize it, when any perception of disloyalty on their part might spell trouble for their families.

She needed to pull herself together. She'd grown too bold in the last few months, forgotten how to keep her own council. She couldn't be herself here, and she couldn't afford to forget that while Pansy, Draco, Millicent, Blaise, and Theo were her friends, their ultimate loyalty was not to her and never would be.

Rigel kept to herself for the remainder of the meal, and when Slytherin House traipsed to the dungeons she hung back a little, letting the others pull ahead of her in the crowd. She had a moment of wistfulness as she thought of her time in the lower alleys that summer. That freedom was beyond her reach right now. It was time to focus on the task at hand.

When they'd assembled in the common room to await their Head of House, Rigel sidled back over to her friends and gave them an apologetic smile. Pansy sighed, but took Rigel's hand and pressed it briefly. "Do try not to give us all heart attacks at every meal this year, Rye."

She reached up with her free hand to ruffle her bangs sheepishly. "Sorry, Pan. I don't mean to burden you with my worldview. Sometimes my tongue runs away from me."

Pansy's gaze was both worried and a bit sad. "You can talk to us about stuff like that, you know. Just maybe," she dropped her voice, "not in the middle of the Great Hall."

"Right." Rigel grimaced. She had really lost her head there. She probably ought to start exercising her Occlumency all the time, if for no other reason than that Riddle's name was likely to come up an infuriating amount over the next few months. She could only hope that whatever he was scheming came to a swift conclusion and left them in peace.

Snape's appearance commanded instantaneous silence. He surveyed the room slowly, probably mentally accounting for all who ought to be present. His eyes met Rigel's briefly before moving on and finally resting on the new first-years.

"Welcome to Slytherin House," he said. Somehow Snape's voice could fill a room no matter how quietly he spoke. "I am your Head of House, Potions Master Severus Snape. No doubt you believe you understand what Slytherin House entails; forget the misconceptions you harbor. Slytherin House is a unit. We are the bulwark of tradition against a backdrop of indolence and idiocy. Here, you will find refuge for neither. Your triumphs will be your House's pride, your disgraces likewise. That said, Slytherin House will not itself make you into the witches and wizards you aim to be. Every individual in this room must work for their ambitions. It is for Slytherin House to support and safeguard those ambitions until they see achievement."

He paused for a moment to sweep the room with his gaze before continuing in a slightly different vein. "If you have not heard rumors already, know that this year there are certain anticipated events that will elevate this school to public scrutiny like nothing you have experienced thus far. With the eyes of the world upon us, you will make Slytherin proud. Each of you will do your part to present a dignified, unified, façade until this charade is over." He cut off a sixth year's question with a sharp cut of his hand. "You will know more when it is necessary. For now, simply be cognizant of your appearance and behavior. If any one of you brings shame to the house of snakes, it will not be only me that you must answer to." With that ominous declaration, Snape swept from the room, leaving the prefects to corral the firsties and the rest of them to exchange murmured conversation.

"Well, that answers that," Theo said, releasing a small laugh. "We've just become the Abraxans in the Party's dog and pony show."

"And me without my manicure done," Millicent said drolly.

Rigel laughed along with the others, but there was a burning sensation in her stomach that she doubted would go away until she knew exactly what the year was to entail. It was like being told you had a grave illness but the exact diagnosis was inconclusive. She just wanted to know what was going to happen so she could start dealing with it.

When Snape dropped Rigel's fourth year class schedule next to her plate at breakfast, Draco snatched it up so fast she was surprised he didn't pop a joint. He ignored her long-suffering sigh and perused it at his leisure.

"No potions," he said. "I suppose you're self-studying again this year." His eyes boggled. "Alchemy? Since when do you take Alchemy?"

"Ah, well, remember last year when I was taking more classes than you thought?" Rigel's smile wilted slightly under Draco's affronted glare. "Yes, I am taking Alchemy."

"Healing I guessed, but how did you even get into Alchemy? You need recommendations from about three different professors." Draco was a little more worked up than Rigel would have anticipated, if she had thought to realize that her friends would be very curious about her schedule this year.

Pansy gently plucked the schedule from Draco's hand and looked over it herself. "You've dropped Ancient Runes," she said, humming thoughtfully.

"I figured I could self-study that subject the easiest," Rigel explained. "Arithmancy pairs really well with Alchemy, anyway, and I knew I wanted to keep that one."

"What's it like, learning from Dumbledore himself?" Blaise asked from across the table, shameless in his eavesdropping.

"Very different from my other classes," Rigel admitted. "He literally wrote the textbook himself. His handwriting is a little hard to read sometimes, and there are no chapters or quizzes or tests. We just kind of meander from topic to topic as it comes up."

Blaise raised his eyebrows. "That sounds a bit lackadaisical. Isn't there an OWL curriculum you should be following?"

"Actually, no, there's no OWL for Alchemy," Rigel said. It had been one of her first questions, too.

Draco frowned. "What's the point of taking the class, then?"

"Some people learn things for their own sake," Rigel said, smiling.

"But you could be taking a class that did provide you an OWL," Theo put in. Rigel looked over to see him and Millicent both following the conversation with unabashed fascination.

"OWLs don't really matter for me," Rigel said honestly. "I only need a handful to keep my wand. The Potions Guild only requires the Potions and Herbology NEWTs anyway as a prerequisite to trying for the Mastery."

"You are such a Ravenclaw sometimes," Draco complained. He turned to his own schedule finally and scanned it quickly. His mouth dropped open in shock. "No Dueling? What are they playing at?" Draco stood at once, breakfast forgotten, and strode off in the direction of the professors' table.

"Perhaps the Defense professor isn't up to teaching two classes this year," Millicent said, chewing her bacon thoughtfully. "Shame. I liked your uncle okay, Rigel."

Rigel inclined her head in thanks. When Pansy finally returned her schedule she looked it over to make sure the things she'd discussed with Professor Snape were reflected accurately. Monday and Wednesday she had Charms, Transfiguration, and Herbology. Tuesday and Thursday were DADA, History, and Arithmancy. Friday she would have Healing in the morning and Alchemy in the afternoon. Astronomy was every Thursday evening after sundown. Potions wasn't listed anywhere, but she'd already agreed to have lessons Friday, Saturday, or Sunday with her Head of House, depending on his schedule each week.

"Rigel," Pansy said, causing her to look up at the blond girl curiously. "Is your schedule correct in putting you in the fifth year Healing class?"

Rigel nodded. "I'm the only student for fourth year, and the fifth year class fits better in my schedule anyway. Madam Pomfrey says it won't be any trouble to get me up to speed. It didn't sound like her fifth year student was much more advanced."

Pansy nodded thoughtfully. "Healing has an OWL, I believe. Will you take it at the end of the year?"

Rigel blinked. She had not thought of that. "I suppose I may as well," she said. "The NEWT isn't offered at Hogwarts unless you get special permission, so this will be my last year taking it officially regardless."

"Why is that?" Pansy asked.

"I think it's because an NEWT in the subject requires a wider range of experience than can be got from a classroom alone," Rigel said. "At AIM, Harry's program has her working at local hospitals in a supervised role, because for a lot of the practical aspects, you need an actual sick or injured person or animal to practice on. Madam Pomfrey can only provide so much in a few hours a week. I know she has had NEWT students in the past, but they end up dropping most of their other NEWT classes and focusing on that alone."

"I hadn't considered that," Pansy said, looking somewhat ill. "You practice on animals, Rigel?"

She winced. "I do. Sorry, Pan. Madam Pomfrey puts them unconscious and numbs them up, so they don't suffer if I make a mistake. Also, we only use animals that can be usefully harvested. It's not wanton, but I can't tell you an animal never gets hurt."

The girl shuddered slightly. "I'm glad I didn't apply to take that subject."

"What do you have this year?" Rigel asked, turning her attention delicately away from the gruesome realities of Healing class. "Did you stick with Arithmancy?"

"I did," Pansy said, pushing her schedule toward Rigel for a quick comparison. "I dropped Divination—it wasn't as rigorous a subject as I thought it would be. I'm sticking with Care of Magical Creatures, though. Did you know Rookwood's uncle is teaching it this year?"

Rigel shook her head. "That's bound to be a great class, then. He owns a creature reserve, right? I bet he's a lot more knowledgeable than last year's professor."

If Pansy noticed that Rigel chose not to say Pettigrew's name out loud, she let it go gracefully.

Breakfast was wrapping up and Draco had not returned. Rigel and Pansy decided it was better to meet him in class than to wait around and potentially lose points for all three of them being tardy, and began making their way toward the Great Hall doors.

A voice from the Ravenclaw table called out to Rigel as she passed. Rigel turned to see Cho Chang waving at her from the other side. She approached curiously, Pansy close behind her. "Good morning," she said, tilting her head as the Asian girl thrust a stack of parchment at her. "What's this?"

"Madam Pomfrey told me you were joining my Healing class," Chang said, smiling in a way that brought out the soft prettiness of her features. "Those are my notes from last year. It's just me taking it this year, so it'll be nice to have company and someone to study with."

Rigel took the notes with a returning smile. "This is very kind of you. I'll be sure to study hard so I don't hold you back too much."

Cho shook her head, and her long, black hair briefly obstructed her eyes before she pushed it back again. "Madam Pomfrey says you are already ahead of the fourth year curriculum. I'm sure we will learn a lot together."

"See you Friday, then," Rigel said, tucking the hefty stack of notes away in her bag neatly. It would be nice to have a classmate to bounce ideas off of, she thought. Archie was decidedly ahead of her now in every aspect of Healing, and his explanations were sometimes too advanced to follow easily.

As she walked toward the Charms classroom with Pansy, her friend looked sidelong at her and said, a playful tone to her voice, "That was interesting."

"Why's that?" Rigel asked, quirking an eyebrow at the mischievous expression on Pansy's face.

"The Changs are relatively new to English Wizarding society, but they have good connections all the same," Pansy said, choosing not to answer the question directly. "She walked about with Adrian for a few months last year, but they parted amiably."

"That is very interesting," Rigel said flatly, fighting an eye roll as she understood Pansy's pointed speculation. "If only I weren't already betrothed."

Pansy bumped her admonishingly. "You can't hide behind that contract forever, Rigel. It's perfectly obvious you have no intention of marrying your cousin."

"Only to someone as brilliant and socially accomplished as you, dear Pansy." At least, Rigel hoped it wasn't that obvious to anyone else.

Draco caught up to them as they reached the classroom, and one look at his face told them he had not been successful in correcting the perceived deficiency in his schedule.

"No Dueling, then?" Rigel guessed, frowning sympathetically. "Did Snape say why?"

"No," Draco said, scowling. "I know it has something to do with whatever the event is that's happening here, though. He said I can't start my Dueling Club again, either! How is that fair?"

"They cancelled the class and the club?" Pansy raised her eyebrows. "That's a rather obvious hint. Are they holding a dueling tournament?"

"I asked that, and Snape said that wasn't why. I couldn't tell whether he was lying—his Occlumency is too good for my Empathy to read," Draco complained. Rigel gathered he must be very annoyed if he went so far as to mention his gift aloud. He normally pretended he was merely clairvoyant rather than acknowledge it openly.

"It could also be because of the press," Rigel pointed out. "Maybe for some reason people don't want it known that Dueling is taught at Hogwarts."

"It's a magic school, it's supposed to teach us those things." Draco shook his head with disgust and flopped into his seat with all the grace of a narcoleptic troll falling unconscious.

"It's not exactly an uncommon subject," Pansy agreed. "I suppose we'll have to wait and see what the reasoning is. If there is a dueling competition to be held, then you can enter. If there isn't, we'll find another way to practice."

"Exactly," Rigel said encouragingly. "Who says we have to form a club to practice dueling?"

"I tried that," Draco said, sighing dejectedly. "Snape said if he got a single report of any Slytherins dueling on Hogwarts grounds he would hold me personally responsible and I'd be in detention for a month."

Rigel couldn't mask her surprise. Snape practically doted on his godson. For him to issue so severe a threat could only mean that the dueling ban was serious. Pansy made encouraging noises about finding somewhere Snape wouldn't be monitoring to keep up their practice, but all Rigel could think was that if there was some kind of dueling competition at Hogwarts, she would stay well out of it.

No one was sure what to expect from the new Defense professor. Whether at meals or in the corridors, Auror Dawlish always bore the same staid look of disinterested professionalism. By Tuesday, rumors already abounded that Professor Dawlish was strict and humorless, but they had also heard that he didn't assign essays. It was with cautious curiosity that the fourth year Slytherins and Gryffindors took their seats for the double lesson.

Dawlish read off the roll briskly, only pausing to mark down modifications to pronunciation before continuing without comment down the list. As he tucked the roll away in a pocket of the olive trench coat he seemed to favor, the Auror surveyed them with a blank expression. A couple of steps in his sturdy boots brought the tall man to the center of the room, where he paused and snapped, "Eyes on me."

Those students at the front of the room who hadn't turned their heads to follow the man whipped around in their seats, startled.

"The first thing you will learn in this class is to always keep your eyes on the biggest threat in the room. That would be me, in case it wasn't clear." His icy blue eyes narrowed as they swept the classroom once more. He walked to the back of the classroom and turned to face them. None of the students looked away.

Rigel felt her eyebrows rise of their own accord. Unexpectedly, Auror Dawlish could carry a room. She knew the man was one of her father's go-to Aurors for important assignments, but she'd never heard him speak more than a handful of words at a time. Then again, she supposed she'd always seen him on duty, most often guarding the Minister in Fudge's personal detail. She wondered again how he'd gotten the Defense Against the Dark Arts job this year. Was the Ministry looking to have a presence at the school? Or had the man simply fancied a chance to teach?

"I am John Dawlish, Auror, Halfblood, and for the remainder of this term—your worst nightmare." Dawlish began to walk back toward the front of the room and it was almost amusing to watch the class swivel to follow his progress like moon-blinked owls. "For the last two years I've served as the Deputy Head of Security for the Minister of Magic. Before that, I was head of Special Response Force Three. I've been fighting the Dark Arts longer than any of you have been alive, so you will respect me in this classroom, understood?"

There was silence, and more than a few confused looks were exchanged among the students. Rigel couldn't think of any other professor who had just flat out demanded respect from his students. It would be interesting to see how it worked out for him.

Dawlish resumed his slow pacing, this time to the right side of the classroom. Was he really going to be moving about the entire lesson? It was going to get tiresome to follow his every move for over an hour. "I have reviewed the syllabi for your previous three years. Near as I can tell from the notes they left behind, your previous professors were well-meaning at best and utterly incompetent at worst."

Rigel tamped down on the offense she felt on Remus' behalf. There was no sense being upset when Dawlish likely hadn't ever met Remus and didn't mean the criticism personally.

"You covered minor schoolyard jinxes and a lot of useless theory in your first year," Dawlish said, ticking off his fingers deliberately. "Your second year you seem to have wasted entirely. I thought the exams in Professor Lockhart's files were a joke at first, but it seems he was just a narcissistic loon." Muffled chortles swiftly turned into awkward coughs as Dawlish whipped his head around to search for the noisemakers. "Last year, Professor Lupin appears to have attempted to catch you up, but while he covered Dark Creatures comprehensively enough, spell-casting fell to the wayside."

"He taught Dueling, too," Ron said, frowning.

"An optional class only helps those who opt into it," Dawlish said. Leveling a menacing look at the redheaded boy, he added. "Don't speak out of turn again, Mr. Weasley."

Ron swallowed and nodded shortly. Rigel caught his eyes and smiled. It was nice of him to defend Remus. He smiled back, shrugging a bit.

"Eyes on me!"

Rigel grimaced, moving her gaze back to Auror apologetically. "Sorry, Professor."

Dawlish met her eyes for a stern moment. "I won't say it a third time." When she inclined her head deferentially, he continued. "Thus far you have not been exposed to anything truly dangerous. While I understand the logistical drawbacks to bringing a quintuple-X dark creature into the classroom, you can and will be familiar with the majority of dark curses by the end of this year."

Many of the students perked up in interest. It was true that while they'd studied the theory behind many practices of the Dark Arts, they'd yet to actually see most of it in action.

"Some people think it's irresponsible to teach dangerous spells to kids," Dawlish said, making his way slowly across the front of the classroom. "They're right, and I won't." She could almost feel the collective sigh of disappointment from the class. "What I will teach you is how to recognize them and how to counter them. I'm guessing you've never had a Bone Crushing Hex thrown at you, Mr. Malfoy."

Draco startled slightly at being singled out. "Can't say I have, Professor."

"Your name is on the roster for last year's Dueling class, is it not?" Dawlish asked.

Draco nodded slowly. "Yes, Professor. We typically didn't try to kill one another, however."

"Exactly," Dawlish said, stressing the word with a growl. "In a friendly duel no one is going to try to kill you, so how will you react when it happens? Many witches and wizards believe that to hunt Dark Arts users you need to know a lot of Dark Arts yourself. Fight fire with fire, as it were. Well you don't. If any of you are ever in a fight for your life, you only need to remember one principle: react appropriately."

Dawlish snapped his wrist out and had palmed his wand before Rigel had time to draw a surprised breath. His wand arm twisted unerringly toward Draco and a jet of light shot toward the blond without the murmur of a spell to foreshadow it. Rigel had pulled Draco sideways toward her the moment she saw the wand brandished his way. Her friend ended up half-collapsed in her lap, but the Stinging Hex missed his head.

Draco straightened with slow dignity, a slight flush riding high on his cheekbones. "Thanks," he murmured to Rigel under his breath.

"Anytime," she said, a bit breathless at the unexpected attack.

"Not bad, Mr. Black," Dawlish said, a slight smirk pulling on one side of his mouth. "Didn't spare a thought for anyone behind your friend, though. I only missed Miss Davis by an inch. Why didn't you shield, if your reflexes are so good?"

"I didn't have my wand out," she admitted.

"That sounds like a bad idea, doesn't it?" At his quiet words, there was a rippling shuffle as students produced their wands from pockets and sleeves. "In this class, you will not be assigned homework or quizzes. Your motivation to study will be the number of injuries you walk away with each day."

Rigel guessed she wasn't the only one who felt a fission of trepidation at that ominous pronouncement. It was going to be like a whole year of Remus' dodging exercise. Except there was nowhere to dodge while sitting behind a desk.

Dawlish didn't seem concerned with the fear of Mordred he'd just put into every student. "The key to staying alive when an evil wizard tries to kill you is in matching appropriate actions to particular threats. You might be tempted to dodge everything—that will get you killed. You might try shielding against everything instead—that will also get you killed. If you learn to react intelligently to each spell as it comes, you might still be killed, but there's a higher chance you'll live to at least run away. If you die, the Dark Arts win. This is Defense Against the Dart Arts, right?" Most of the class nodded uncertainly. "Then we don't want the Dark Arts to win!" he barked.

"Each lesson I will demonstrate a handful of dangerous spells and teach you how to recognize them on the fly. Next week, you will be tested on your reaction to these spells. I will be casting them on each of you without mercy. Only by properly distinguishing each spell will you be able to react appropriately to it. Some spells cannot be shielded against. Some spells cannot be dodged. If you don't know which is which, how can you survive?" Dawlish frowned around the room at them all as though they had personally offended him by being unable to adequately defend themselves from hypothetical evil witches or wizards. "Mr. Black, what spell did I send at Mr. Malfoy?"

"A Stinging Hex," she said.

"How do you know?" he pressed.

Rigel didn't think he would care that she'd seen about a thousand of them in her sessions with Remus, so she simply said, "The white light is distinctive in the way it flares slightly around the wand before being propelled forward. Also, the Stinging Hex moves slightly faster than the average speed of magic." That was one of the reasons Remus said it made for good dodging practice.

Dawlish grinned at her. "Well, well, there may be hope for your survival. Very good, Mr. Black. Five points to Slytherin."

The Auror spent the rest of the class demonstrating several advanced dueling spells that reacted badly when they came up against a shield. Rigel had no idea that there were Hexes that could explode if they encountered a shield; add to that the very small number of shields that were strong enough to protect from blast at point blank.

Dawlish promised them that next time they would go over spells that affected a wide area and so couldn't be dodged. She found herself looking forward to it. Even Draco seemed a bit mollified by the end of the class.

"At least we'll be learning something useful in Dueling," he said to Rigel and Pansy on their way out.

"Are you still going to try restarting the club?" Pansy asked.

"Of course," Draco said. There was no hesitation in his voice. "I worked all summer on the lesson plans. I just have to find a way to do it without Uncle Snape finding out."

Rigel silently wished him luck with that. There wasn't much that Snape didn't find out about, one way or another. Then again, perhaps she was giving him too much credit. He wasn't omniscient, after all. If he were, she would have been discovered and arrested by now. For a number of things.

Defense was not the only class that impressed her that week; Rigel found herself enjoying fourth year classes more than any other year thus far. She was finally catching up to the advanced theories and concepts that she'd started studying way back in first year, when completing Flint's assignments had meant hours of extra research in the Library each week. For the first time, she felt like she'd come full-circle. Her regular course work would now be bridging the last of the gaps in her knowledge, and she was somewhat surprised to realize how much of the fourth-year syllabus she already had a good understanding of, if only because of the background research she'd done is the core subjects just to keep up with Flint's increasingly challenging assignments.

Also for the first time, she could openly study anything she wanted to in front of her friends. Nothing she was interested in could be considered suspicious because everything was above board. If her friends were confused by the almost gleeful about of books Rigel brought into the common room each evening, they wisely chalked it up to 'things about Rigel that no one needs to try explaining' and let her have her fun.

When Friday dawned at last, Rigel was positively bouncing through her morning workout with Draco and Pansy.

"Will you stop grinning?" Draco stopped his squats to glare at her, and there was something so amusing about watching him try to glare and pant and the same time that her smile grew even wider. "Stop it!" Draco cried, a laugh escaping him accidentally. "Damn it, Rigel, your happiness is making me sick."

Rigel laughed. "Enjoy it, Dray. I know you rarely get to experience such pure, unadulterated academic joy."

"You're quite excited for your Alchemy class," Pansy said, continuing to lower and raise herself calmly as she spoke. "If it's really so interesting, you must explain how it relates to Arithmancy some time."

"Sure," Rigel said easily. "Though that's not what I'm excited about. I have my first Potions lesson tonight with Professor Snape."

"So what?" Draco was having trouble looking annoyed while stubbornly fighting a smile. "You've had Potions with him for three years already."

"I'm learning free brewing this year," Rigel said. She had to say it almost reverently. It was what she'd been looking forward to all summer.

"Isn't that dangerous?" Pansy asked. "I think I've heard that many potions-related injuries and even deaths occur because of free brewing."

Rigel nodded happily. "Nearly all fatalities among certified potioneers are in some way related to free brewing. It's very difficult to learn, partly because so few Masters adept in it live long enough to pass on their knowledge. Professor Snape is the best there is, though, so he probably won't let any harm come to me."

"What do you mean 'probably'?" Draco spluttered.

"No guarantees in free brewing," Rigel said. She felt like humming, but restrained herself when Pansy sent her a reproachful look. "I'm sure I'll be fine," she assured them. "Professor Snape wouldn't offer to teach me if he didn't know what he was doing."

Pansy and Draco dropped the subject, but she had a feeling they'd be counting her limbs before she went to bed that night.

With an effort, she managed to calm her good spirits to a level Draco found tolerable before they went in to shower and change. She did still have Healing and Alchemy to attend before she got to sink into the mental nirvana that was a proper Potions lesson after a long summer of independent experimentation.

Healing was a short lesson, with Madam Pomfrey merely going over the syllabus she and Cho were to follow, and reviewing major concepts that Cho had covered the previous years so that Rigel understood where to focus her studies to make sure she was caught up before the next week. Cho had been correct when she said Rigel had already been a bit ahead of the fourth year Hogwarts syllabus, so there wasn't anything that she'd never been exposed to through either Archie's curriculum or her own research. The major difference in the coursework for fifth year Healing was the inclusion of magical maladies instead of primarily dealing with physical injuries.

After lunch, armed with the password 'Cauldron Cakes,' Rigel made her way to the Headmaster's office for her Alchemy lesson. Dumbledore was waiting for her by the bookcases when she reached his office, and no matter how many lessons she had with the old wizard she couldn't quite reconcile his venerated person with the cheesiness of his secret passageway. She couldn't help but smile as he pulled the book and led them through to what served as his classroom. There was something about Albus Dumbledore that put her at ease.

It didn't make any sense, considering he was at least as dangerous as Riddle, in his own way, so the fact that she felt inclined to relax in the Headmaster's presence should itself have been a large red flag. It was hard to remember that, though, when he offered her a lemon drop and hummed cheerfully to himself as he laid out the supplies they would need for the lesson.

"This is your year two Alchemy text," he said, presenting her with another small journal that looked a lot like her 'first year Alchemy text.' Sure enough, as she flipped through it she was confronted with Dumbledore's familiar looping cursive.

Rigel pulled out the previous year's book from her bag and held it toward the Headmaster, saying, "I finished what we hadn't covered over the summer, Sir."

"You may keep it," Dumbledore said, smiling genially. "One never knows when a good reference may come in handy." Rigel smiled back in thanks and stowed both books before taking the sole seat at the table and pulling out her note-taking materials. The Headmaster began to slowly pace the length of the small room on the other side of the work table, idling stroking his beard as he was wont. "Last year, Mr. Black, we started our arrays with a collection of components and, using precise transfiguration equations, built those elements into something whole. This year, we will begin the study of transforming one whole object into another whole object in a single, complete alchemic event. Unhappily, the arrays we study this term will not always be as perfectly balanced as those you have become accustomed to. In the course of alchemy, it is often the case that the individual portions that make up one object are not perfectly matched to the same portions in the object you would like it to become."

Rigel nodded her head slowly. "So we'll sometimes have leftover elements at the end of a transmutation," she surmised. It made sense, since the odds of having the exact same elements necessary to constitute two completely different objects were probably quite low.

"Just so," the venerable wizard confirmed. "The inverse is also true. At times the object that is broken down will not have all of the necessary elements to form the object defined by the array, and the Alchemist will need to include additional components in the first half of the equation in order to make up for that."

Dumbledore took out a piece of chalk and began drawing a simple array on the wooden table in front of Rigel. The runes defined a single-element transformation, and the Headmaster produced a small piece of wood for the input position. "This array you may not recognize, but it is a useful one to know if you ever need to write a letter while in the middle of a forest. It transmutes wood into paper."

Interesting. They'd only scratched the surface of transforming the nature of starter components the previous year. Mostly they'd been turning raw components into a complex form of themselves—a piece of metal into a metal box, for instance—or else a couple of elements into a compound.

"If I were to tell you that the amount of paper I've defined in the output equation is more than the amount of wood I've provided is capable of producing, what do you theorize will happen when I activate the array?" Dumbledore asked when he had finished the alchemic array.

Rigel frowned. "It either won't work, or the array will use all the wood it has available and only produce the corresponding amount of paper."

"What about the extra magic in the array that is not used by the time the wood is gone?"

Dumbledore always asked tricky questions, but Rigel couldn't think of any other answer than, "It will have to discharge into the air, since the array isn't designed to hold any excess magic once activated."

Her professor hummed thoughtfully to himself, but didn't tell her whether she was right or not. Instead, he briefly imbued the array with the requisite magic and activated it. The circle flared and the block of wood dissolved from the input side, while a pile of rough parchment materialized on the output side. Instead of stopping, however, the array seemed to grow, if anything, brighter before finally fading away. With the array used up, the only thing remaining on the table was the stack of parchment and a warped, twisting spiral that seemed to have been gouged out of the wood beneath it.

Rigel had never seen an array do damage to the surface it was drawn on before. "What happened?" she asked.

"What do you think?" Dumbledore prompted.

Rigel looked at the pile of paper, which she thought was a bit higher than it had been before the second, brighter flash, and said, "The array thought the table was part of the wood it was meant to transmute? But that's never happened before."

"When you put magic into an array," Dumbledore said, "it wants to be used. The magic pulled the cellulose from the wood of the table because it was the closest. If I had drawn that array on the back of your hand, the array would have attempted to transmute your fingers into parchment, too."

She paled a bit. "That's not good."

"Alchemy can be a very dangerous art," Dumbledore agreed gravely. "You must never forget that the array drives the magic you imbue toward completing the task outlined in the runic inscriptions. If your equations do not balance, special precaution must be taken to account for the leftovers, as you put it. Now let us try another example, but this time you will imbue the array, Mr. Black."

Rigel hesitated. She knew this was going to come up—there was no way to continue her Alchemy lessons without addressing it—but somehow she still felt nervous about what she was going to do. "Professor," she said tentatively. "Would it be all right if I… recalibrated my magical constant?" She was prepared to explain that her magic had gone through certain changes since the last time she'd used it for their classes, but without a word of question Dumbledore reached into his robes and pulled out the calibration device as though he'd merely been waiting for her to ask.

She gaped at him as he set it on the table. How did he guess? The Headmaster twinkled at her. Rigel had to smile as she took hold of the cold metal tube. "Thank you, Sir."

Rigel told herself not to be afraid. She had to have an accurate magical constant to progress in Alchemy, and she had already decided it was a subject she wanted to one day marry more closely with Potions. There was no reason why anyone besides Dumbledore should ever know what her magical constant was, and even if it got out, there was no reason for Archie's exact magical strength to ever be known once they'd both graduated and switched back. She closed her eyes and channeled her magic, trying not to worry about it. She just let go.

The magic poured out of her at a phenomenal pace. She opened her eyes on a gasp to see the crystal at the end of the calibrator tumbling through yellow and green without pause. It pushed through blue at a fair clip, then began to slow, bleeding lavender and brightening to a proper violet before darkening to an almost eggplant shade and finally holding steady. Rigel set the device down somewhat shakily. It hadn't been that dark when she'd measured it at Frein's for the suppressor. Had the year of living with the suppressor really made it noticeably stronger?

Dumbledore spread a color chart on the table beside the device, not seeming to notice her unease as he mused happily, "Marvelous, simply splendid. We can proceed to more complicated arrays much sooner that I had planned. What do you think? Does it look 'plum' to you?"

"Sure," she said, trying not to let the slightly hysterical laugh inside her chest bubble out. How could it have gotten worse?

"A 1.3 it is, then," Dumbledore said, smiling serenely at her. "How incredible."

"Is it?" Rigel shook her head on a sigh. "What's your magical constant, sir, if you don't mind my asking?"

The Headmaster affected a somewhat modest expression. "Mine happens to be .97," he said.

She blinked at him, then looked down at the color chart on the table. The very darkest value on the scale was pure black, and it held the base value 1.0 as the corresponding constant. Trust Dumbledore to be literally off the chart. She actually felt a bit better about hers, knowing that. "How did you ever calculate that?" she asked, now immensely curious. Being lower than the lowest standard meant that he would have been constantly overshooting the calculated input.

He twinkled at her again. "It took careful trial and error to reach the exact number. My first six months, all my arrays exploded. Nicolas was quite displeased with the destruction I wreaked on his workshop."

Rigel tried to imagine the venerated wizard before her blowing up someone's workshop, but she really couldn't picture it. Dumbledore put away the color chart once more and Rigel dutifully made note of the 1.3 value for future equations. She'd expended energy beyond the point of being able to imbue any arrays for a few hours, so Dumbledore wrapped up the lesson there. "If you have nothing else that piques your curiosity today, I will see you next week," he said. He folded his hands in front of his robes and waited patiently while she thought.

There was one other thing she could ask him about, but she wasn't sure it was a good idea. When she paused an awkward time in answering, Dumbledore said, seemingly to no one in particular, "On the rare occasion that a question utterly baffles me, I find I generally have a good idea where to look."

There was no harm in asking, she told herself, as long as she phrased it as an academic inquiry. "I was thinking about this the other day, sir, and it's not really related to Alchemy, but is there ever an instance in which a person's magical core might resonate with another's?"

Dumbledore gave her a long look and began slowly curling the end of his beard around his finger as he thought. "Rarely, a set of twins may have magic similar enough to cause a sort of recognition between the two. It is not a true resonance, however."

"What if the two people aren't related at all?" she asked, striving to sound neutral. "Does it mean those two people would be similar in some way?"

"Not necessarily," Dumbledore said. He lifted his eyes to the ceiling in a gesture she recognized as him trying to recall a distant memory. "I have never heard of two unrelated persons having resonant magic," he said after a lengthy silence. Rigel fought her disappointment until he added, "Except in one peculiar incident many years ago. This may take some explaining, I'm afraid. Do you have time for a story?"

Rigel nodded quickly.

"Wonderful. Well, I once knew a young woman who was researching the North American Hodag. Are you familiar with the Hodag, Mr. Black?"

Rigel tilted her head. "Just the horn—it's used in alertness potions, though it can be dangerously potent."

"Just so," the Headmaster said. He began pacing the room once more as he continued his story. "The Hodag is also endowed with impressive fangs that, when used on potential prey, inject a very interesting venom into the victim's system. Unlike most venoms, which tend to paralyze or slow prey into a docile state, the Hodag's venom contains a small piece of its own hyperactive magic, which rouses its prey into a state of over-alertness that can last for many days. Eventually, the sleep-deprivation and adrenaline overdose compromise the prey's defenses utterly, and that is when the Hodag make a meal of its victim."

Rigel thought that was a rather gruesome way to go, but animals had to eat as much as she did, she supposed.

"You may be wondering how the Hodag keeps track of its intended prey until the venom takes effect," Dumbledore said, smiling slightly at the look on her face that said she hadn't been wondering that, but probably should have. "This is where the Hodag's other unique ability comes into play. This creature is capable of tracking to its own magical signature. The venom it releases is quite literally a small piece of its own magic, and the Hodag can sense the location of the pieces of magic it gives away, provided it remains within a certain distance to its source. Isn't that remarkable?"

"Quite," she said faintly. Her mind was whirring with a dawning dread. Was such a thing really possible? Had she been… tagged, like some kind of animal? Dumbledore was continuing his anecdote, and she struggled to pay attention. She couldn't do anything now, she reminded herself; she needed to know the full extent of the situation first.

"My student of many years ago believed that any magical creature, including wizards, should be able to do the same as the Hodag, if only they had a way to share a piece of their own magic with another." Dumbledore's face grew somewhat somber as he said, "She devised a ritual to transfer a piece of her own magic to another wizard. Her fiancé at the time volunteered. You could say it worked—too well, alas. His core fully assimilated the magic she bestowed on him, and the resulting resonance between them became so unbearably uncomfortable that they could not stand the slightest contact from that day on. Even worse for my dear student, her theory was incorrect; while she experienced resonant feedback upon direct contact with her fiancé's skin, she could not, try as she might, sense or track him in any way."

"Did they figure out how to reverse it?" Rigel asked, only feeling slightly better that the resonance had not provided any concrete information to the woman about her fiancé.

"I'm afraid not," Dumbledore said, sighing. "The two separated and never came within a few feet of one another again. The experiment was deemed a failure, and I myself have not considered the story further until now."

"Is there a record of the experiment somewhere?" she asked. Despite Dumbledore's assurances that nothing had come of it, she couldn't help the slow panic developing in her brain. Riddle wouldn't do a thing like that for no reason—if, indeed, that was what he'd done with no ritual or even a spell that she'd noticed. What if he'd found a way to make it work? What if he could track her? Monitor her? What if her already knew she hadn't left the country over the summer? What else could he already know?

Dumbledore tugged his beard with a frown. "I don't believe our esteemed library possesses a copy of the complete report, but I will make inquiries if you are truly interested."

"Yes, please," she said, trying not to look too desperate. She wanted to run straight to the library and look up everything it had about resonance and cross-contamination of one's magic. She felt dirtied by the idea that she might have had a piece of Riddle floating somewhere in her core. There had to be a way to purify it. She just needed time to research.

She thanked Dumbledore for the lesson and tried to clear her mind of its agitation as she headed down from the tower. There was nothing she could do about it yet. She was in the same boat that she'd been in yesterday, and there was no reason to let Draco sense her upset when immediate alarm wouldn't do any actual good. She vowed to just focus on her upcoming Potions class instead. She was not going to let Riddle ruin it. Not this.

At dinner, Snape handed her a folded piece of parchment and said, "We will meet in lab three tonight, Mr. Black."

Rigel nodded and ignored her friends' amusement as she increased the speed at which she consumed her meal. She gathered her book bag and took her leave with a hurried, "See you guys," to the others.

She followed the instructions on the parchment to a part of the dungeons she hadn't traversed since first year when she'd made a point to explore every area of Hogwarts she could. She didn't even know Snape had a lab that was so out of the way, but when she knocked and entered it became clear why they were using it.

Lab three was utilitarian to an uncomfortable degree. There were no stools, and what counter space was available had been secured to the left side of the room while the right side held only a single brewing station, well away from anything else. Her first thought was that it would be awkward carrying ingredients back and forth so far. As Snape handed her a heavy-duty protective covering, she understood.

"Is this lab specifically for free brewing?" she asked, taking the covering and frowning as she noted it was as heavy as one of Remus' training belts.

As she tried the full-body apron on, Snape confirmed her guess. "This lab is for particularly volatile brewing. The walls and floor have been reinforced with containment spells, and a number of voice-activated wards are in place around the cauldron stand."

The protective garment, which covered her from chin to knees, seemed to fit well enough. Snape hung it on a sturdy nail by the door, next to another, larger version.

"We store nothing in this lab besides the basics," he told her, gesturing to the bare surfaces and scant tools. "Bring eye protection and gloves to every lesson. You will melt more cauldrons this year than all of your year mates in their seven years combined—no small feat, I assure you."

She smiled, but nodded in response to his expectant look. She could barely contain her excitement. She wondered if they would start with a known recipe and alter it, or just begin from scratch and choose ingredients according a schema to add to the cauldron.

"Before we begin free brewing, there is one other skill you must master," Snape said. As though he could feel the disappointment leaking out of her ears, he narrowed his eyes. "Potioneers who do not learn this before attempting to free brew die. Horribly."

"Yes, sir," she said, smoothing her face into something less kicked-puppy.

Snape reached into his pocket and pulled out a stack of playing cards. He held them out and she took them, noting the distinctive brand across the top.

"Exploding Snap?" What did a kid's game have to do with potions?

"A training tool," he said, face impassive.

"Like the medi-minis?" she asked, tilting her head curiously at the innocuous cards. She had a basic understanding of the game, though she'd never been a huge fan. It was essentially a matching game, except if you didn't match cards in a randomly allotted amount of time, they exploded.

"These are to hone your sensing ability and your reflexes," Snape explained. "The cards heat up slightly before exploding, which means you'll need to cast a numbing spell on your hands to get the full benefit of this training."

"I know a couple," she assured him. "So I'm to try and predict when cards are going to explode? Without feeling the heat first?"

"Indeed. Before you begin free brewing, you must be able to sense remotely when a potion is reacting violently. It is not enough to maintain a connection with the potion via conscious imbuing; you need to be able to sense the danger instinctively." Snape paused to ensure she was following, and with a nod from her, he continued. "Magic sensitivity is a relatively common skill. All it requires is the projection of your magic into the environment around you. You will recall in your first year when I tested your core. The simplest way to examine a magical thing is to flare your magic toward it briefly and read the return. Do you understand this concept?"

Rigel thought back to first year. When her core had been tethered to Snape's, she'd been able to send a bead of magic along the connection. The echo had automatically translated into rudimentary information about his magical core. She supposed if the theory held true in other cases, she should be able to gather such information about anything around her, depending on how far she was able to project her magical pulse.

"I think I understand," she said, "but would I have to constantly be sending out magic to monitor the potion, since it could change state at any moment?"

"That is the second stage of this ability," Snape said, apparently satisfied that she was following so far. "When you have mastered flaring your magic, you must learn to maintain it in a continuous magical field around you. That application of the skill is not common, but it will save your life if your potion erupts unexpectedly."

"Will it be difficult to maintain this sensitivity field while also trying to conscious imbue?" Rigel asked. Conscious imbuing already involved splitting one's attention between the magic going into the potion and the other aspects of brewing. No wonder free brewing was so rarely taught.

"Extremely," Snape confirmed. "I will not begin free brewing with you until you can do it without concentrating."

She nodded slowly. She could understand that, if it was as dangerous as he said. "What will we be doing until I have this mastered, then?"

To her surprise, Snape tilted his head considering and asked, voice neutral, "What would you like to do, Rigel?"

She blinked. "Anything?" Was he serious? Her brain flooded her with options and she just stood there, gaping like an idiot.

"Within reason," he confirmed. "Is there any sub-specialty of the field you would like to delve deeper into before we devote your lessons entirely to the art of free brewing?"

Her first thought was Battle Potions, but she squashed it quickly. Even though she'd been extremely curious about them since Master Thompson had let his specialty slip, she knew better than to ask. The subject was carefully controlled by the Guild for a reason.

Snape noticed her deliberation. "What are you thinking?" he prompted.

Grimacing, she admitted, "I was thinking of Battle Potions, but I know you aren't allowed to—"

"Do you?" Snape's black eyes searched hers with interest. "If you were familiar with the rules that govern a Guild-sanctioned Apprenticeship, you would know that there is very little a Master is not permitted to teach his student. The only things truly forbidden are the secrets of another Master's work."

She thought her jaw might have dropped, but she was too distracted to be sure. "They don't regulate it at all? How can that be?"

"It is an old agreement, predating modern government and going back to the very establishment of the first Guilds. An Apprenticeship was a sacred pact in those days. There were no schools, no opportunity for instruction outside of one wizard's willingness to teach another. A condition for the first Masters' agreeing to join such an organization was that the Guild would have no ability to dictate what was or was not passed from Master to student. Nor can any Master be made to take an Apprentice unwillingly. The most the Guild can do is restrict what its members are allowed to distribute to the public." Snape's voice betrayed no interest in the history, but Rigel was fascinated.

"The Guild also sets the standard for achieving a Mastery," she pointed out. "So they do have some input it what ought to be taught in a traditional Apprenticeship."

Snape inclined his head. "In an indirect way, they do. The limits of the instruction, however, are not theirs to dictate."

"So… can we study Battle Potions, then?" she asked, hardly daring to believe it.

"It is not one of my specialties," Snape admitted. "I will look into it. We can begin with area-effect Potions in general and work our way around the topic from there. Very well. That is all for this evening, Rigel. Practice with the cards until you don't burn your fingers."

She nodded, tucking them away in her pocket carefully so they didn't activate and set her robes on fire. That would be embarrassing.

"Be careful pulsing your magic out around other people," her Head of House added as she headed for the door. "It's the same method used to read other wizards' auras, and those with very sensitive auras will feel it as your magic pushes up against them."

"So I can read other auras with this technique as well?" That could be useful.

"It takes significant study to understand the complexities of an aura," Snape said. "It is not like a core; you will not comprehend intuitively what your magic is telling you at first. The only reason this will be useful for free brewing is because you have developed an unconscious understanding of potions via your prolonged exposure to them through conscious imbuing."

"I see. Thank you, Professor." Rigel left the lab deep in thought. Ideas spiraled to the surface and floated for a moment before sinking back down to stew in the dark a while longer.

Despite what Snape said, Rigel did have a rudimentary understanding of auras through her study of suppressing and projecting her own. She wondered if they would be as incomprehensible to her as he assumed.

Her second week back, the morning post brought with it a package for "Archie" that Rigel grinned to accept. It was very obviously book-shaped, so she tucked it into her bag to examine later, ignoring Draco's outraged curiosity and Pansy's more politely inquiring expression. If this was what she thought it was, she wasn't going to share it with her friends just yet.

Ever since Sirius and Remus had declined to give her and Archie instruction on becoming animagi, Archie had been wheedling away his father's defenses. Harry had conspicuously let the topic drop. Her help wasn't needed, after all; Sirius couldn't really deny Archie anything. Not if he kept at it, at least. Finally, the day before they were due back at school, Archie reported that Sirius had agreed to recommend a book to educate them on the fundamentals.

Rigel fought a triumphant smirk all through breakfast, and when she had a moment to herself to unwrap the package she had to smile full out. Self Transfiguration was an innocuous title and its cover was plain brown leather. Nevertheless, it felt like the Sorcerer's Stone in her hands. Sirius might think that he was only giving them a basic foundation with his recommendation, but Rigel knew better. Between her and Archie, a good book was all they really needed. They could figure almost anything out together.

She had to wait until later that night to contact Archie. He'd told her before they parted that his friend Hermione liked to study by herself for a couple of hours every evening after dinner. That meant that midnight was the best time for her to reach him. It wasn't difficult to loiter in the common room until most people had gone to bed. Draco gave her an odd look as he finally packed up his Charms essay and headed for the dorms. Rigel just smiled and said she'd be in shortly.

As she continued to wait out the last stragglers, Rigel went ahead and took out Self Transfiguration to peruse the introduction. There were a lot of warnings about the dangers of partial transfiguration to living things. It sounded like pretty obvious stuff to her—you didn't try to transfigure half an animal into something, after all, unless you wanted to kill it horribly. It was the same reason Polyjuice was designed to transfigure the whole body. It was also why Metamorphism was such an impressive ability. You just couldn't do live transfiguration in pieces on the fly like that. It took a Transfiguration Mastery level of ability to pull off.

Anyway, it wasn't really as issue, since they would be aiming to achieve a holistic transfiguration. She had heard stories of wizards who could partially transform into their animagus form, but she wasn't sure how true they were. That was likely a very advanced variation on the ability.

At the end of the introduction there was a table of contents. It covered a variety of subjects, including permanent beautification and other self-altering transfigurations. She skimmed past those to the last section, which took up easily half the book, and dove into the theory of animagi as the torches burned lower and the night drew in.

At around one in the morning, she was finally alone. She took out Archie's mirror from her bag and settled into her low backed chair. His mirror didn't have flowers on it and was instead inscribed with briars around the edge. She spoke into it softly. "Harry. It's Rigel, are you there?" They'd agreed to use their assumed names when using the mirrors at school since there was always the chance of someone overhearing.

After a long pause, her reflection blurred and Archie peered back at her. "Rigel? It's only been a week—miss me already?"

"Always," she said. The sarcasm in her voice didn't diminish her smile at seeing him. This really was so much better than writing letters. "I got a delivery today from Sirius. Do you have a minute?"

"I have a lifetime of minutes for you, dear," Archie said on a winning smile. No matter how she practiced, her flattery never sounded that effortless. "Hermione is in the library studying, which means I am amusing myself in my room until she returns."

"How's that going?" she asked, suddenly reminded of his declaration that summer. "Are you really going to start a relationship with the girl?"

"I'm going to try," Archie said seriously. "I know it might make things awkward for you, but you can't deny you've put me in awkward positions a time or two. I won't let it compromise our ruse, of course, but I have to do this, H-Rigel. If I don't, and she falls for someone else in the meantime, I'll spend my whole life regretting it."

Rigel nodded. She could see how much this meant to her cousin and she wasn't going to stand in his way. He had already given up much for their dreams. They both had. She would gladly field questions about her own sexuality and weather remarks to the effect that she was unfaithful to her engagement contract if it meant Archie's happiness. She would do anything for him, and he for her. It was that simple.

"Good luck," she said, smiling sincerely at him. He grinned back, eyes full of gratitude.

"So what did Sirius send you? What we expected?" Archie's face, an exact copy of her own, gained an anticipatory gleam she recognized.

She positioned the mirror so that the title of her new book could be seen. "Think you can get a copy?"

"Undoubtedly," he said when she'd moved the mirror back to her own face. "How is it?"

"I just got it this morning," she reminded him.

He raised an eyebrow. "Exactly. So how is it?"

She laughed softly. "Caught me. It's pretty good so far. It seems like there are a few methods people use to figure out their forms. One of them is learning the Patronus Charm."

"That's a tricky one, isn't it?" Archie frowned.

"It is, and it's not a guarantee anyway. The patronus form sometimes matches the animagus form, but not necessarily," she explained. "Sometimes a strong personal connection will be manifested in the patronus instead."

"Sounds iffy," Archie decided. "What else?"

"Well, there's a potion," she began.

"Yes!" Archie laughed somewhat maniacally through the mirror. "We cannot be stopped!"

"Okay, calm down," she said, laughing a bit at his exuberance. "I was thinking it sounded like the best option, though."

"How long will it take?" Archie asked excitedly. He didn't ask 'how hard is it?' or 'can you brew it?' which she admitted warmed her heart a bit. Archie had such keen faith in her.

"At least two months to brew, and that's if I can get all of the ingredients to start," she admitted. "I'm going to need a vial of your spit, by the way."

Archie's face twisted in disgust. "Ugh, why do I feel like you're always asking for my bodily fluids?"

She sympathized, but there was no way around it. The first chapter of Self Transfiguration had outlined the pros and cons of the various methods. Under a footnote titled "Myths Debunked" the author had noted some of the common misconceptions, one of which required the would-be animagus to hold a mandrake leaf in their mouth for an entire month.

"Not that I don't relish the opportunity, but I promise it's better than the alternative," she said. Much better to soak the leaf in a vial of saliva than to try to eat around it for a month and hope they didn't choke on it in their sleep. "Once the potion is complete, I'll send you your dose and you can take it somewhere you won't be interrupted."

"That sounds suspiciously simple," Archie said.

She rolled her eyes at him. "The potion doesn't make you an animagi. It just allows you to take on the form temporarily. That's how we find out what form we have. Once you know, then you have to actually learn how to do the transfiguration. That's the really hard part."

"Two months just to learn our forms." Archie sighed. "Well, we knew it wasn't going to be easy. I'll send you the…spit."

"Make it two vials," she said with an innocent smile. "Just in case."

"This is why everyone thinks potions brewers are weird," Archie told her.

"It's not for the faint of heart," she agreed easily. That a task was unpleasant didn't mean it wasn't worth doing, in her opinion.

"Won't Dad be surprised when we already know our forms come winter break?" Archie grinned at her mischievously.

She returned it full strength. "Surely he didn't give us a book and expect us not to read it?"

"One day they'll stop underestimating us," Archie said.

"Not anytime soon, though." She said goodbye to her cousin and packed away the mirror carefully in soft cloth. She would peruse the ingredient list for the animagus revealing potion more tomorrow, though she knew just from a quick glance that she'd be ordering at least a couple of things from the apothecary in Hogsmeade. She didn't keep morning dew in stock, and certainly not samples 'untouched by human feet' whatever difference that was supposed to make. It would probably be at least November before she finished the potion, considering how much research was going to go into the ingredient list alone. She ought to have the time, though. She hadn't appreciated just how much time Flint's assignments had taken up until she no longer had them to occupy her evenings.

The room was quiet when she crept in from the corridor and shut the door behind her. She didn't need light to navigate to her bed and slip off her shoes, but as she climbed onto her mattress, the hangings on the bed next to her slid open and Draco's face peered over at her by the light of his wand. He had a book propped open on his knees and she wondered if he'd stayed up to read because he wasn't tired or because he was waiting for her.

"Hey," Draco whispered, setting his book aside. "Is everything all right? You're out later than usual."

Rigel nodded, whispering back, "Had to practice something for Potions. Snape said it would bother other people, so I was waiting until everyone went to bed."

"Oh." Draco's expression relaxed. She felt a bit bad for worrying him. Whether she acknowledged it or not, the events of last year hadn't only affected her. Draco had been there when Snape found her. No doubt the memory colored his concern for the hours she kept. "Did it work?"

"I haven't got the hang of it yet," she said, shaking her head. "That's okay, though. I'll keep trying." And that would be a good excuse for staying up late in the common room the next time she needed to talk to Archie, too.

"Rigel?"

She paused in fluffing her pillow to look over at her friend. Draco's expression was still relaxed, but there was an underlying concern that shone even through the dim light. Rigel put down her pillow and slipped off her bed. She climbed onto his and pulled the curtains shut so they could converse more naturally without worrying about waking their roommates. "What is it, Dray?"

"You've changed," he said simply. "You have this anger in you—I've never felt anger from you like this before. I want to help," he added, gazing at her imploringly. "It feels like you're pulling further away from me, though. I don't know what to do."

"You do more than enough," she assured him. She couldn't help feeling touched at his genuine concern for her wellbeing.

"I feel like I don't know how to reach you, sometimes," he admitted. There was a small crease in his brow that made him look older.

She took his hands carefully. "I'm right here. Sometimes I do get angry, but my anger is not aimed at you, Dray."

"I know," he sighed, clenching his hands around hers a little anxiously.

"I'm very grateful for your understanding, and Pansy's, though I may not always show it," she said softly. "I have changed. I'm sorry if it's hard on you sometimes."

"I'm sorry that I couldn't prevent the things that changed you," Draco said fiercely.

"Sometimes I wish I hadn't experienced them." She took a deep breath and mustered a smile. "If it means no one else did, though, I find I can accept it."

"You shouldn't." Draco exclaimed. He dropped her hands and put his own on her shoulders to shake her a little. "You always put others before yourself. It's going to get you in trouble—more trouble, I mean—someday. What if…" he looked away embarrassedly, but steeled himself before pinning her with a distraught look. "What if next time you don't come back, Rye?"

She swallowed, but the emotion was still thick in her voice when she said, "I'll always try to come back, Dray." It was the most she could promise.

"All right," he said. A split second hesitation, then he wrapped her in a quick hug that was so light she barely felt it. She hugged him back just as gingerly, then drew back with a small smile. "Night, Rigel," Draco said, smiling back. He waited for her to clamber back over into her own bed before he doused his wand light.

"Night, Dray."

She lay awake a while longer, wondering what she had done to deserve such a good friend. Well, she thought after a silent moment, she didn't deserve him of course. She was just very lucky. That was okay. She would simply enjoy his friendship while she had it.

It was the third week in September before Rigel found an evening to steal down to the kitchens and visit her favorite Hogwarts House Elf. She'd waited until dinner was over, so the kitchens were mostly occupied with cleanup when she climbed through the still life painting and waited at one of the tables until Binny was free.

"Young sir!" Binny bounced up and down on her heels and because Rigel was sitting down, they were almost at eye-level. "How is your summer being?"

"Very well, and yours?" Rigel asked.

"Madam Touraine is promoting me to Head Stable Elf," Binny told her. The pride in her voice and carriage was unmistakable.

"Well done! She must really trust you to give you so much responsibility."

"I is being the most experienced," Binny confided. "Still, it is being a great honor. Is young sir practicing his French this summer?"

"Not that much," she confessed. "Can we practice a little?"

"Oui." Binny led her through a series of basic conversational topics, and while Rigel was certainly rusty, she got back into the swing of the language before long.

After almost an hour of somewhat mindless chatter, Rigel asked Binny for some mice, if the kitchens had any, and in no time she had a trio of fat snacks for Treeslider. She bade Binny good evening and made her way up out of the castle and into the growing twilight.

Rigel made it almost to the forest's edge before her feet stopped moving of their own accord and she looked into the trees with increasingly short breath. Backing up a few paces, she breathed deep through her nose and shook her head. What was the matter with her? It was only the forest. She'd been in and out of the outskirts dozens of times in the past three years. She couldn't deny the slight tremble in her legs as she sat on the grass and simply stared at the tree line, unseeing. She hadn't been back there since…

A shudder rippled through her, and she bit down on a slightly hysterical whimper. She could feel the anxiety in her like a physical thing, pulling her shoulders in toward her ribcage and squeezing her lungs into empty sacks. Rigel ruthlessly smoothed her emotional state into eerie, unnatural calm. She would not get worked up over this. It was in the past. Nothing that happened months ago had the power to touch her now. That man was dead. That place was gone.

Wrapped in her artificial serenity, Rigel slowly stood and took first one step, then another toward the looming trees and shadows. She only made it to the first trunk before she had to sit down again and catch her shallow breath. She clenched her fingers in the dirt, wondering how the hell she was supposed to work through this phantom panic when it didn't make any sense.

She heard Treeslider before she saw him. "Juicccy moussse, niccce and sssoft, tasssty sssnack, all for me!" She didn't think anyone would believe her if she told them that singing sounded entirely ridiculous in Parseltongue. Nor would they believe that a snake could come up with a surprisingly catchy rhyme scheme—at least, it was catchy in his tongue. She could barely hear the original beneath the translation her brain superimposed.

"Ssspeaker! You have been gone for lifetimesss," Treeslider complained as his slim, green form broke from the underbrush. She thought he looked a little bigger than the last time she'd seen the snake.

"Sssomehow I do not think you sssuffered much," she teased the boomslang snake.

"You wound me, Ssspeaker." Treeslider made a show of coiling and uncoiling in agitation. "Much hasss changed thisss ssseassson. The thessstralsss have ssstolen my nesssting grounds. The new nessst isss not ssso niccce. And the Runessspoorsss, Ssspeaker, they are everywhere."

"What isss wrong with Runessspoorsss?" she asked, amused. They were not a particularly aggressive species.

"They bicker like nessstlingsss," Treeslider bemoaned. "Jussst one isss bad enough, with thossse headssss sssniping at each other. But thisss ssseassson there are many new densss. I can ssscarecccely essscape them."

"I am sssorry to hear of your troublesss," Rigel said solemnly. She produced the generous parcel the elves had prepared and said, "Would it help if you had sssomething to eat?"

"Perhapsss," Treeslider hissed. His attempt at nonchalance was ruined by the way his big eyes followed the parcel eagerly as she set it on the ground. She unwrapped it to reveal three fat kitchen mice and the boomslang snake nearly chortled with glee. "Sssuch a kind ssspeaker. Ssso good to your ssservant."

"You aren't my ssservant," she said, frowning. Was that what the snake thought?

"I watch over the foressst for you, Ssspeaker." Treeslider tilted his head in an odd parody of confusion. "Are you dissspleasssed with my reportsss? Or perhapsss… I ssshould have attacked that man."

"Man?" she asked, her heart rate accelerating.

"The one who makesss you sssmell of fear," Treeslider said. He sounded as miserable as a snake could. "The lassst time you came to the foressst, you were not alone. I ssstayed away, but I sssee I ssshould have defended my ssspeaker."

"Not at all," she said, swallowing her memories and leaning forward from her seated position so the snake could look her in the eye. "I jussst want you to know that you do not have to ssserve me in thisss way. I would ssstill bring you sssnacksss."

The snake swayed slightly back and forth for a long moment as though thinking. "Asss your ssservant, I recccieve your favor, Ssspeaker. The Runessspoorsss dare not challenge the ssspeaker's chosssen. I will continue ssserving you and you will reward me with juicccy delightsss."

She laughed. "Very well, Treessslider." There was no point arguing with the snake. Clearly, he did not feel overly put upon. Rigel stretched her neck as the snake gloated over its prize and asked him, "Will you ssstay awhile?"

"It will take time to devour thessse offeringsss, Ssspeaker."

She took that for agreement. "Warn me if anything comesss," she said, closing her eyes. She wanted to try practicing her sensitivity field outside of the castle. She'd been working on pushing out her magic the way Snape described, but it was difficult when everything it came into contact with sent waves of incomprehensible information back at her. There was just too much magic in Hogwarts—it was distracting.

Not to mention the other students. She'd only tried it in the common room once, and it was enough to give her a massive migraine. She felt every person who walked through her shaky field, and each sent a shiver of discomfort down her spine. It felt like static electricity whenever her projected magic touched another person. She had to wonder if that was how Draco felt all the time, bombarded by information that was exhausting to try to sort through.

Rigel hadn't even started practicing with the Exploding Snap cards. She could not yet focus on other things while maintaining her magical field. She slowed her breathing and let the evening air wash over her as she reached for her core. The first step, she'd found, was to gather her magic and pool it within her skin. How much she could pool before releasing it determined how far the resulting magical field would reach. Only when the magic she wanted was pulled from her core could she push it out of her in all directions.

At first, she'd found herself pushing it out in a thin disk around her middle, meaning she only received feedback from things that were three and a half feet off the ground. It took several days of sweat-inducing mental effort to create a full sphere of magic and pulse it away from her like an invisible explosion. Just like explosive energy, she felt the magic fade faster the farther it got from her. Things at the edge of her sphere barely registered while things right next to her lit up like Christmas trees to her magical sense.

Rigel had found she could send a single pulse of her magic pretty far, perhaps as much as fifty feet before she stopped sensing anything from the returns. If she tried to maintain a field around herself, though, she could only hold five feet or so. The field tended to fluctuate erratically, contracting and expanding again as her concentration wavered. In the quiet outdoors, however, she had a much easier time pushing the magic out around her and holding it there. She could feel Treeslider as a little crackle of energy just in front of her. As she focused on him, the energy slowly condensed in her awareness until it represented vaguely his relative shape and size.

"That itchesss." She heard the words as though underwater. Slowly blinking her eyes open, she attempted to maintain the field while answering, but as soon as she spoke it dissipated.

"Sssorry," she said. The snake had swallowed one of the mice and was curled around the other two contentedly. Rigel arched her back in a stretch. She kept her eyes open and gathered her magic again, this time flinging it out around her as far as she could.

"Ssssss." Treeslider jerked in a wordless hiss of annoyance.

She smiled apologetically, but her attention was far away, focused on the echoes of information coming back to her on waves of magical return. Several things with magic showed up in her mind's eye as she sifted through the knowledge. "What isss over that way?" she asked the snake, pointing off to the right along the tree line. "Up in the treesss." There was a crackling feeling like a dozen tiny spots of energy.

Treeslider flicked his tongue out and said, "Bowtrucklesss."

Rigel grinned. "And there? Sssomething in the ground." She indicated a point behind Treeslider and to the left.

"It's only a nessst of Runessspoors," Treeslider said, coiling a bit tighter around his remaining mice. "You don't want to talk to them. Ssso annoying. I cccertainly don't have enough miccce to ssshare."

"I wouldn't dream of asssking you to ssshare," she assured the possessive snake. She practiced for another fifteen minutes or so before the feedback started giving her a headache. Upon standing, she said, "Want me to walk your miccce into the foressst a bit? It'sss not sssafe to be exposssed while you digessst."

"Very well," the snake decided, uncurling from the two remaining mice and allowing her to pick them up gingerly as he awkwardly slithered into the trees with his bulging middle.

Rigel took a deep breath and held it as she followed, focusing only on Treeslider's rustling, ungainly form. She blocked out everything but the serpent's trail and made good headway into the forest before her fear reached into her chest and wrung out her heart like a wet rag. She gasped in air and stopped, leaning on a thick trunk to stave off dizziness.

"Ssspeaker?" Treeslider came back and surveyed her with a crooked head. "You sssmell of fear again."

"I'm fine," she said firmly, not sure if she was trying to convince the snake or herself.

"Thisss isss far enough," Treeslider declared, settling down in the roots of the tree that was propping her up.

Rigel deposited the mice in the circle of his protective coil and said, "Sssee you later, then."

She turned back toward the castle, and was relieved to note that it was much easier going the other way. Each step felt a little lighter and by the time she broke the tree line once more her breathing was mostly regular. As she walked back up to the castle, Rigel resolved to visit Treeslider at least once a week from now on. She refused to be ruled by fear.

The morning of the last Sunday in September, Dumbledore interrupted breakfast with an unexpected proclamation. He stood before the hall until it quieted and said, without a trace of his usual humor, "Tonight there will be a special feast here in the Great Hall. A number of Ministry officials and guests will be present and an important announcement will be made. I know you will all represent our school with pride. Please be in your seats promptly at six o'clock."

The old wizard sat, and chatter broke out across the House tables like quail startled from the brush.

"Finally," Theo said, grinning across the table. "I've been dying of curiosity."

"Dumbledore doesn't sound too thrilled about it," Millicent noted. "Wonder how long this has been in the works."

"Since last spring," Rigel said, thinking back with a mental scowl to the day Riddle and Snape had ambushed her about her magical suppressor. "Riddle was here to meet with Dumbledore about it at least once last term."

"Lord Riddle was here at Hogwarts?" Pansy's expression was bewildered. "Why didn't you mention seeing him, Rigel?"

"I was a bit distracted at the time," she said, shrugging uncomfortably.

Looking back, she was almost certain that was the day he'd done… whatever he'd done to her magic. Rigel had read through the report Dumbledore procured for her several times, but she still wasn't entirely sure what effect Riddle had meant to have on her. The report made it clear that the magical contamination, as she'd come to think of it, hadn't allowed the witch to glean any information at all about her fiancé. The magic she'd transferred to him had simply become his, and once it was gone she wasn't able to sense that bit of magic or exert control over it anymore.

Still, she was not satisfied. He had some reason for it, she just didn't know what yet. She would keep researching.

The day passed slowly as everyone tried to distract one another until dinner. Rigel sat in the common room through the early afternoon, reading through Dumbledore's Alchemy textbook while Pansy and Draco discussed increasingly wild theories as to what was going to be announced that evening.

It was almost a relief when their conversation fell silent. Rigel looked up from the notebook to see Rosier and Rookwood approaching their couch. Rookwood held a stack of white cards in his hand, which he distributed to the three of them with a rare smile. "A more formal invitation will be sent to your families, of course, but I wanted to invite you three personally."

Rigel flipped open the card and read the elegant scroll. You are cordially invited to the joining of Edmund Rookwood and Alesana Selwyn in sacred matrimony. The time, date, location and so on were listed on the back. It was to be the following summer, just after Draco's birthday.

Pansy leapt up from the couch and embraced Rookwood with an excited squeal. "I am so happy for you, Edmund. An outdoor ceremony is inspired."

"Thank you," Rookwood said. His deep voice was laced with satisfaction. "It was Alice's idea to ask my uncle for use of the gardens at his reserve."

"Congratulations," Draco said, standing to shake Rookwood's hand once Pansy had stepped back. "Smart move, having the wedding as soon as you graduate. Yours will be a splendid match."

Rigel rose as well and took Rookwood's large hand when Draco was through. "I'm sure the ceremony will be stunning," she said, smiling up at the upperclassman. "I'll remind my father to check the mail so we can RSVP."

"We will be glad to have you," Rookwood said, inclining his head in thanks.

"Indeed," Rosier added, his patience apparently expired. "Having the silver trio will make it a guaranteed success."

"No one calls us that," Draco said firmly as he reclaimed his seat. Rigel and Pansy followed suit and the older boys chose chairs across the small coffee table for themselves.

"They really do, though," Rosier said sadly. "Alas, for your dignity."

"How was your summer?" Pansy asked, cutting off Draco's simmering retort. Rigel thought the girl probably knew exactly how his summer had been, but she gave Pansy points for attempting to keep Draco and Rosier civil. Somehow it was always like oil meeting water with those two.

"Dreadfully uneventful," Rosier said. "I almost wish I'd been at the World Cup, if only for a break from the monotony."

"Excitement isn't everything," Draco said sharply.

"So I've heard," Rosier said, waving a hand dismissively. "I want to hear about Rigel's summer. I hear you spent it abroad. You do seem unusually tan."

She was no such thing after spending a month mostly indoors, but she humored the seventh year. "I was visiting the Darian Gap community in the Americas."

"What were they like?" Rookwood leaned forward with his elbows on his knees and his hands loosely laced. "I've heard the wizards there are entirely closed off from the world."

"Nearly," Rigel agreed. "They are closer to our definition of druids than wizards, really. The villages are too small to support specialized craftsmen. Each wizard makes his own wand or talisman. A lot of their magic doesn't rely on that, though. It's mostly plant-based or ritualistic."

"And you went as part of a Healing outreach," Rosier said. It wasn't really a question, but Rigel nodded all the same. "How did that go?"

"There was an outbreak of tropic fever while I was there," she said.

"He was put under quarantine for ages," Draco added, sending her a look that said he thought it entirely her own fault.

"Goodness, that sounds trying," Rosier said, cocking his head at her.

"It was quite virulent," Rigel agreed. In fact, the fatality rate had been near fifty percent until someone figured out that it was being transmitted through mosquito bites. Once they figured out how to ward villages against the bloodsuckers, infection rates dropped off completely. Fairly sure that her friends did not want the unhappy details, she merely said. "We couldn't save everyone."

Rosier's face went blank with shock at her blunt words and even Rookwood looked taken aback. It was Pansy who broke the awkward silence that followed. "It was so good of you to try, Rigel. I really admire your selflessness. Not many would have left their home and traveled to a strange new place to help those in need, particularly with the risks involved in handling an epidemic."

"It wasn't entirely selfless," Rigel said, smiling softly at her. "I did learn a lot."

"Honestly Pans, Rigel doesn't need more encouragement to put others before himself," Draco said, scowling playfully at her. The others laughed, and conversation moved on to more pleasant topics.

"How is NEWT prep going?" Pansy asked them.

"Fine."

"Awful."

They spoke at the same time and shared a brief smile. "Aldon exaggerates," Rookwood told them.

"Edmund is trying not to scare you," Rosier said, shaking his head. "The coursework is beastly. McGonagall's got us calculating the rate of magical expenditure in time-delayed transfigurations."

"The rate of what?" Draco's brow furrowed. "That sounds more like Arithmancy."

"It is," Rookwood confirmed. "Advanced Transfigurations requires a basic understanding of Arithmancy, however."

"The rate of expenditure changes for every different material, so it's not like you can even memorize the equation once and be done," Rosier said on a sigh.

"That's because the magical coefficient of every material is unique," Rigel said. The four of them turned to stare at her. She blinked at them. "It's not so much that the equation changes as the variable does. Materials that have a higher coefficient don't last as long when Transfigured because the coefficient describes how resistant the material is to magical change."

"How do you know that?" Pansy asked, openly curious.

"It's a basic principle of Alchemy," she said. Rigel remembered having to explain the same thing to Percy and wondered why they didn't teach that to seventh years right off the bat.

"I have heard that Alchemy is Transfiguration by way of Arithmancy," Rookwood said. "Is that accurate?"

"Basically," Rigel said, nodding. "Alchemy uses Arithmetic equations to calculate exact proportions of material and magic while relying on runic arrays to actually enact the Transfiguration."

"Sounds unnecessarily complicated," Rosier commented.

"It is for anything that can be achieved with basic Transfiguration," Rigel agreed. "Supposedly once you get to the upper levels, Alchemy can achieve Transfigurations that no other branch can replicate, but of course you have to be someone like Dumbledore to really take advantage of that."

"It does seem to have interesting applications, though," Pansy said. "At least, you have a better understanding of Transfiguration than we do, and that's Draco's best class."

Draco snorted. "Rigel studies too much." The look he shot Rigel made her think he knew where she'd found the time to pursue such advanced topics and was probably still annoyed that she'd had a time-turner for the entirety of last year. She smiled sweetly at him, aware that he couldn't say anything about the time-turner without getting her interrogated by the Unspeakables for breaking contract. All he could do was glower back at her silently. She had to admit he was good at that.

Eventually, and almost inevitably, the conversation circled around to what everyone was trying to pretend they weren't waiting for. The announcement.

"My uncle knows something," Rookwood said. He sounded certain. "He came to Hogwarts this year for more than just teaching."

"You think there will be creatures involved?" Draco wrinkled his nose. "Like some sort of circus?"

"If there are creatures involved, they won't be the kind you find in your average menagerie," Rookwood reasoned. "Uncle Aurelius is renowned as an expert in dangerous and hard to handle beasts. The only one better in his field is Master Scamander himself."

"Oh good, more danger at Hogwarts," Rosier drawled.

"I'm sure the Ministry has everything under control," Pansy said. After a moment she cracked a reluctant smile. "I sound entirely foolish saying that."

"Utterly barmy," Draco agrees. "The Ministry? In control of something? Bite your tongue."

"The Party will have it in hand," Rookwood said, shrugging unconcernedly.

Because they've handled things so well in the past, Rigel thought. She didn't say it out loud but Draco's sharp glance and the spike in her head from Dom told her that her feelings on the subject did not go unnoticed.

Rookwood and Rosier left about an hour before dinner, and Pansy rose as well. "You boys ought to smarten yourselves up for dinner. If there's really going to be dignitaries or press, your families will want you to look sharp."

"Mine won't," Rigel said, smirking.

"I'm sure you'll make an effort for my sake then," Pansy said primly.

She would, and the other girl knew it. Sighing, Draco stretched and gestured for Rigel to come along. "Might as well get dressed. If we hurry, Pansy will have plenty of time to tell us what we've done wrong."

"Don't tempt me, boys." Pansy laughed as they scurried off to their room. "And don't forget to change your shoes, Rigel!"

She looked down at her very serviceable black boots. "No one else appreciates you," she told them mournfully. They didn't answer, but if they could she knew they would agree with her.

The Great Hall did not look as it normally did on an average Sunday in September. It had been decorated. The theme was unclear, but there did seem to be a lot of silver and black. Tapestries depicting witches and wizards of great renown had been hung to cover nearly every available space alone the walls. She recognized the four founders near the Hall entrance, dramatically portrayed in dynamic poses that suggested decisive and inspiring action. Then there was Nicholas Flamel, Adalbert Waffling, Mopsus, Artimisia Lufkin, Falco Parkinson, and even Merlin himself, among others.

The House tables had been largely stripped of their own colors, and shining silver dishes had replaced the plates they normally ate on. The Head table had been modified as well. Where usually Dumbledore sat in the center of the table, his chair only slightly more ornate than the other staff members', now the center of the table was physically elevated on a kind of dais, with three chairs that looked more like thrones to draw all eyes to those seated upon them.

Riddle sat in the center, the very picture of a lord reigning over his court. He glittered faintly in ebony robes stitched with luminescent silver thread. The Headmaster had been shunted to Riddle's left, with the Minister of Magic, by rights the one who should have had the highest consequence, seated at Riddle's right hand. Not subtle at all, she couldn't help but think critically.

Rigel took her seat between Pansy and Draco without commenting on the new décor or seating arrangements. She did watch the others exchange wary glances up and down the table, but most of the students in Slytherin House clung to dignity and refrained from gaping at the dais with open confusion. She saw a couple of Gryffindors actually point and wanted to smile, but when she remembered who they were pointed at, the amusement dried up like spilt coffee, leaving only a ring of crusty emotional residue in its wake.

At precisely six o'clock, the doors to the Great Hall swung closed of their own accord, barely missing the heels of a couple of young Hufflepuffs who'd cut it too close. Everyone looked expectantly at the Head table, where the teachers sat with inscrutable expressions. The moment stretched into awkwardness before Dumbledore began to rise. As soon as the older wizard made to take his feet, Riddle stood smoothly and spread his hands wide. The Headmaster sank into his seat again with a faintly amused expression, and Riddle began speaking as though he hadn't noticed Dumbledore moving at all.

"Good evening, students, staff, Minister. Thank you all for joining me on this special occasion." Riddle didn't exactly smile, but his features nevertheless gave the impression of pleasure. "Tonight we have a great announcement. Some of you are about to be faced with an opportunity that comes along but once in a generation. For a determined few, this opportunity may define the trajectory of your lives." The Hall was filled with rapt faces and students leaning forward in their seats to see and hear better. "Before we get to that, however—let us feast!"

Riddle clapped his hands and food materialized on the tables to the tune of hundreds of disappointed sighs. The man certainly was sadistic.

The clatter and chatter of silverware and students echoed up and down the tables. Rigel studiously ignored it, serving herself vegetables and potatoes with her head down and her eyes focused on the table in front of her. Once she'd filled her plate, however, she found she had no appetite. Her stomach was churning. She had a premonition of impending plots twisting itself through her guts and no amount of lovely House Elf cooking could break through the welling nausea.

"You're not eating," Pansy said from her left. Rigel glanced over at her through her fringe.

"Not hungry," she admitted.

"Don't work yourself up over this," Draco advised lowly from her other side. "It won't be as bad as you seem to think."

Rigel knew, somehow, that he was wrong. It was going to be exactly as bad as she thought. Something about Riddle's smugly confident expression had told her as much. Still, she smoothed her emotions under a blanket of Occlumency and smiled politely to her friends. "Sure." They both looked disappointed at her rather obvious dissembling, but at least they left her to pick at her meal in silence.

As dessert was at last cleared away, the doors opened once more to allow a swarm of people to filter in from the Entrance Hall. Witches and wizards with cameras and quills hurried to crowd the Head table with shouted questions and flashing bulbs. Riddle stood tall before them, his particular not-smile managing to convey pride and benevolence all at once. Minister Fudge got to his feet hastily to beam at the press like a trained monkey. Dumbledore was the last to rise, slow dignity and a vague sense of disapproval emanating from his wizened figure.

With a wave of his hands, Riddle quieted the ravenous reporters. The students fell silent as well and a fresh wave of anticipation thrummed through the room. "The time has come to reveal the purpose of tonight's gathering. This year, Hogwarts will be host to a grand event—the first and only competition of its kind. The True Triwizard Tournament!"

At his declaration, the candles in the room flared with light and everywhere in the audience gasps and sighs of amazement rippled.

"What does he mean?"

"There hasn't been a Triwizard Tournament in ages."

The whispered conjectures spread through the Hall like scuttling creatures in the shadows. At another pass of Riddle's hand, the murmuring settled into a hush. Rigel's stomach clenched against her bad feeling as the dark-haired politician explained.

"For many years in our society a great debate has dominated the collective sphere. What makes a great witch or wizard? Is it nature or nurture? Luck or destiny? Does power reside in the mind… or in the blood?" Riddle allowed the shock to permeate his audience before his face relaxed into a predatory smirk. "This year at Hogwarts, we shall answer that question once and for all. A call will be sent out this very night to all corners of the world. Let any witch or wizard who believes in his or her greatness come to Hogwarts—and prove it."

"Circe's tits, he can't be serious." Theo's face was an open study of incredulity, and he was not the only one. Rigel's eyes slid from one shocked expression to the next. There was the leader of the S.O.W. Party, famed wizard of power and blood purest extraordinaire, declaring the question of blood supremacy unresolved.

For a moment, she wondered if he'd gone mad. He wanted to put the question of blood prejudice to a public test on the international stage? Then she realized what the end game would inevitably be. A pureblood would win the tournament, and the so-called debate would be dealt a killing blow in front of all and sundry. Riddle was gambling the foundation of his party—to win eternal vindication for his cause.

The press clambered with questions, but Riddle wasn't through. "In one month's time, on Samhain's Eve, the preliminary participants will be announced. A total of nine young witches and wizards will be chosen to fight for the chance to represent their communities. While contestants will not be excluded by blood or background, there will be certain restrictions. In order to present a fair contest of each category, the tournament organizers have chosen an age group that, we believe, best represents the potential of young magic wielders without restricting the pool of talent unnecessarily. For that reason, this tournament will be open to all witches and wizards between the ages of fourteen and seventeen."

The uproar was instantaneous. Younger students took to their feet in outrage at being excluded, while those fourth-year and above students whooped with wild delight.

"Why have an age range at all?" Millicent did not look particularly pleased to be included; mostly she seemed puzzled by the criteria. "Wouldn't the older students automatically out-perform the younger ones?"

"Depends on the criteria they use to determine participants," Blaise said, pitching his voice lower to cut through the din rather than trying to talk over it. "Lord Riddle said only nine will get to compete. That's not very many, if every teenager in the whole world gets to apply."

Rigel tried to un-grit her teeth, but it wasn't easy. With the cut-off at fourteen, at least some of her friends were guaranteed to get caught up in this tournament nonsense.

A flash of light from Dumbledore's fingers surprised most of the students into silence, at least long enough for the Headmaster to say, with remarkable evenness, "Please allow Tom to finish his explanation, students. Once the announcement is over, you may all go to your dormitories to discuss the news at length."

Riddle shot Dumbledore a look that was hard to read. Rigel thought he might be annoyed at the Headmaster's use of his first name. The politician raised his hands once more and said, ever so benevolent, "I know that some of you are disappointed. Rest assured that this event will be equally as thrilling to watch as to directly compete. The tournament committee has gathered expert minds from every field to create for you all this spectacular trial of talent, versatility, and will. From Samhain Day until Yule, the first nine chosen will undergo fierce preliminary trials, until at last one wizard from each category will rise to the fore. After the New Year, the real competition begins: one pureblood, one halfblood, and one muggleborn will go head-to-head in an all-out contest to decide who will be the winner of the True Triwizard Tournament and claim the title of Blood Champion for once and for all!"

Applause broke out spontaneously, and Rigel couldn't help but flatten her lips in despair of her classmates. Was no one considering the consequences of the kind of competition Riddle was describing? Could they not see the way this tournament would rip at the deepest divides in their society, inflaming old prejudice and giving outlet to the worst kind of superiority in every way? Could they see nothing beyond imagined glory and the base desire for gratuitous entertainment?

"Lord Riddle! What will the prizes be?" One of the reporters made himself heard over the noise and everyone settled down to hear the answer.

"Is eternal glory not enough?" Riddle laughed lightly at the man's stammered retraction. "But of course, there will be incentives. How else are we to attract the best and brightest the Wizarding World has to offer? For the nine semi-finalists, a cash prize of 500 Galleons will be awarded." He paused to allow the applause at that to die out before continuing. "The three Blood Representatives who advance to the finals will each receive 1000 additional Galleons, as well as a full scholarship to the secondary institution or Guild program of their choice, upon the completion of their regular schooling. We have partnered with nations worldwide to ensure that any finalist from anywhere on earth will be afforded the very best in advanced educational opportunities."

There was a great deal more applause at this. Rigel supposed uncharitably that it was hard not to support educating promising young people. "As for the Blood Champion, whoever that may be, he or she will win an all-expense-paid world tour, where the Champion will meet influential and outstanding witches and wizards from participating nations in a wide variety of fields. The Champion will earn one other prize as well. Would you like to see it?" The encouraging cheers did not leave any doubt that everyone would, if Riddle didn't mind, very much like to see whatever it was.

Riddle clapped his hands twice and smoke briefly obscured him. When the black fog evaporated a moment later, Riddle was holding a shining staff of purest silver. He lifted it horizontally above his head and declared, "Behold, the Rod of Zuriel!" From where she sat, Rigel could see that the body of the rod was wound with ropey filigree, but what drew the eye was the massive red stone set into the nest-like cradle at its top. It looked like a ruby, but she'd never seen a ruby so large, nor so perfectly red. A blood gem. How unbearably on the nose. Riddle turned slowly left then right, allowing everyone who wanted a glimpse to bask in the shining beauty of the staff. "This glorious staff will amplify the magic of any who possess it. An unparalleled tool deserving of a matchless master. The Blood Champion will be awarded its allegiance!"

A shiver went down her spine at his phrasing. Not the staff but its allegiance. Was it sentient? Rigel hoped not. She'd had enough of sentient stones to last a lifetime.

"Sir, a question from the Daily Prophet!"

"Yes, Miss Skeeter," Riddle said, giving an indulgent nod to the witch in acid green as he lowered the staff and placed it before him on the Head table.

"How will the tournament committee ensure the contest is fair?" Skeeter's voice dripped with sweetness. "Will the judges be above reproach?"

It was a good question. There was simply no world in which Riddle would allow a halfblood or a muggleborn to win his tournament. But how would he maintain the appearance of impartiality?

"There will the three separate stages, all judged in different ways, to avoid any murmurings of partiality," Riddle said smoothly. "When the various magical institutes around the world nominate their candidates, two dozen randomly selected school board members and representatives of the educational departments of various governments will be invited to participate in narrowing the field down to just nine participants. In the preliminary stages, a panel of judges, equally balanced in terms of blood status of course, will preside over the tasks, scoring candidates on a variety of metrics, some of which are, due to the nature of these preliminary tasks, unavoidably subjective. When the final three are chosen, however, the scoring changes. The final events will be measured according to a transparent rubric that corresponds directly to how a representative performs in the challenge. The winner will be determined according to his or her score in each of the final challenges, and so no one can say that it was subjectivity that ultimately determined whether a pureblood, halfblood, or muggleborn would become tournament champion."

"You certainly seem to have thought of everything, Lord Riddle," Rita Skeeter simpered.

It was a rather convoluted plan, Rigel thought, but it did upon first recitation give off an illusion of fairness. That alone made her suspicious.

"Why not use the Triwizard Cup?" another reporter asked loudly.

"That artifact's properties do not lend itself to our needs," Riddle said, sounding only a little apologetic. "Its choices are mysterious, after all, and we want there to be no question of integrity in this tournament."

"For what criteria will the preliminary candidates be chosen?"

"Ah, that is an excellent question!" Minister Fudge spoke loudly, clearly unable to hold himself back from the press conference any longer. "You see, this tournament is not necessarily about intelligence or book smarts alone. The candidates that become our preliminary contestants will have to be well rounded. Strong ability across multiple subjects is preferred, and the candidates will additionally be screened for creative problem-solving ability, work ethic, good character, and, of course, magical strength. Anyone can self-nominate, but recommendations will carry weight."

"Minister, is the Department of Games and Sports going to finance the tournament?"

"Ah, not fully, and we are accepting donations at this time," Fudge said, clearing his throat before adding, more loudly, "Though the Ministry of Magic is proud to sponsor the True Triwizard Tournament, I would like to thank Lord Riddle and the S.O.W. Party for conceptualizing the event and spearheading the planning committee. I would also like to thank Headmaster Dumbledore for agreeing to the use of the school and grounds in this manner. The good headmaster's support for the tournament logistics has been invaluable."

There was polite applause, but it only lasted a few moments before the reporters flew into a litany of inquiries once more. Rigel started to tune them out when the question of security arose and the entire conference began to devolve into the Minister weakly assuring the press that another incident like that of the World Cup was well outside the realm of possibility.

She turned this new horror over in her mind slowly, almost numb to its enormity. She actually felt a bit better, knowing what all the fuss was about now. It could have been much worse, she reasoned. What if Riddle had wanted to implement some new curriculum at Hogwarts that didn't include Potions? She shuddered at the thought and wondered how her mind had even conceived such evil. A tournament wasn't the end of the world. She would resignedly witness her friends making fools of themselves trying to get nominated and otherwise ignore the whole proceeding. It had nothing to do with her, and she would not allow the spectacle to distract her from her studies.

After another ten minutes of questions, Riddle finally cut the session short. "The Department of Magical Games and Sports will release a statement in the morning detailing all that we have covered tonight and more. Thank you all for your time. I wish you a pleasant good evening."

The reporters left, reluctantly but inevitably. When the Hall had returned to relative quiet, Riddle addressed the seated students again.

"Hogwarts is one of the few all-pure institutions left in the world. You are the bastions of our tradition, our culture; the pride of this community rests in your hands this year, students." Riddle looked down over the House tables with indulgent admonishment, like a mother reminding her children to eat their vegetables. "I trust that each of you will uphold the dignity of your blood over the coming year. Prepare to show the world what Hogwarts has to offer. To those of you who would compete: good luck."

With that, Riddle reverently picked up the Stick of Zuriel or whatever he'd called the silver staff and left the Hall. Dumbledore dismissed them all soon after, and Rigel joined the flood of Slytherins flowing down into the dungeons like a very talkative river.

"Who do you think they'll pick?" Millicent asked. "There are a number of talented students who qualify, though I suppose there's no guarantee that someone we know will get chosen."

"There has to be at least one from Hogwarts, don't you think?" Theo raised his eyebrows meaningfully. "After all, it's being hosted here. How embarrassing would it be for the Ministry if none of us got to compete?"

"What a convoluted tournament." Blaise's voice was neither approving nor disapproving, merely factual. "No doubt the reports will be confused and sensational tomorrow morning."

"That's why the DMGS is releasing a statement," Pansy reminded him. "They aren't giving people much time to apply. I wonder if that was deliberate?"

"Probably to cut down on the number of applicants the committee has to sort through," Draco said.

"Will your father be on the committee?" Millicent asked.

"I'm going to write and ask him tonight," Draco said, scowling slightly. "I can't believe he didn't tell me about this."

"Probably knew you'd tell your friends," Theo guessed.

As they approached the corridor that branched off toward Snape's office, Rigel peeled away from the crowd.

"Rigel?" Draco frowned at her as the others slowed to see where she was going.

"I've got to talk to Snape about something," she said, waving them on. "I'll meet you back in the common room."

In truth, she didn't have any pressing matters for her Head of House. She just didn't want to listen to her friends over-discuss the tournament for the next hour. If she could stall long enough in Snape's office, they might be done talking about it by the time she got back.

"Are you going to ask for a nomination!?" Nott's voice was both incredulous and admiring. "Working fast, aren't you?"

Rigel did not disguise the look of distaste on her face. "Not on your life."

She took her time walking through the dungeon halls. What was she going to give Snape as the reason for her visit? There was one thing she had been meaning to ask him about, only there hadn't seemed a good time to bring it up. As she researched magical transference in her free time, she'd become more and more concerned about what Riddle had intended that day in the spare classroom. Rigel wanted to ask Snape if he'd noticed Riddle doing anything to her magic, but she was afraid to know the answer.

What if he had known what Riddle was doing and hadn't told her? She had to admit that would hurt. Rigel knew Snape didn't approve of the way she'd handled her magic last year, but she didn't like to imagine that the Potions Master would go so far as to allow her to be violated in that manner. She could feel resentment threatening to climb up the column of her throat so she swallowed it down forcefully. She didn't know anything for certain. Perhaps it was past time she asked.

She knocked on the familiar office door. There was a longer pause than normal before Snape's voice called for her to enter, and he sounded a bit off. Wondering if she'd come at a bad time, Rigel turned the silver knob and pushed. She'd only taken a couple of steps before she stopped, hand still on the door and took a steadying breath. Riddle was in Snape's office, sitting at his desk as though he had any right to the Potions Master's seat.

"Forgive me, Professor. I'll come back tomorrow." She made to back out of the office but Snape's hand on the door's edge stopped her. She narrowed her eyes slightly, briefly contemplating letting go of the handle and walking out anyway, but the look in Snape's eyes dissuade her. He was staring at her in resigned frustration, and a flick of his gaze had her coming back into the office completely so that he could shut the door behind her.

"Just the boy we were talking about, Severus." Riddle appeared quietly satisfied, and the pleased glint in his eye provoked her to an open frown.

"Indeed," Snape's inflection revealed nothing. He conjured two chairs and bade her to sit.

Rigel sank slowly into the chair, content to ignore Riddle for as long as possible. "Was there something you required of me, Professor?"

Her Head of House pressed his lips together and shifted his stare to the indolently lounging Riddle. "Perhaps you should explain, Lord Riddle."

"Of course, Severus. Mr. Black—may I call you Rigel?" His smile was as fake as a Diagon Alley love charm. She jerked her head in a sharp negation but he seemed not to notice. "Severus was just telling me of his plans to nominate you for the tournament."

There was a dull buzzing in her ears and she blinked rapidly. She could not have heard him correctly. Her brain replayed the words in her head, confirming the dark horror that was building in her chest. "I don't understand." The words were faint and scarcely intelligible, but it was the best she could do as a hole of raw panic opened up inside of her.

"The True Triwizard Tournament," Riddle said, still smiling. Except there was no humor in his eyes and the smile held the aggressive edge of barred teeth. "Severus was saying, and I quite agree, that you would be the perfect candidate for Hogwarts to put forth."

Rigel turned to stare at Snape. There was simply no way that he would ever do such a thing to her. Would he? She searched his blank expression and found no reassurance. After an awkwardly long silence in which she begged him with her eyes to refute the awful man sitting in his chair, Snape's eyes flickered, every so briefly, toward Riddle and back.

She nearly gasped with relief, but managed to school her expression before it betrayed her. Snape had not wanted this. It was all Riddle. Again. Summoning her very best apologetically regretful expression, Rigel widened her eyes and bit her lip before saying. "That's very kind of you, Professor. I'm afraid I don't have time for such an undertaking this year, however. As you know, I have a full schedule."

Snape let the tiniest of grimaces slip onto his face and said, "I'm afraid I must insist, Ri—Mr. Black. It is very important that Hogwarts make a good showing for this event."

"Then it might be best to ask an older student," Rigel said reasonably.

"We are not asking another student," Riddle told her, voice chiding. "We are nominating you."

The use of 'we' did not escape her. She didn't know what Riddle thought he would gain by forcing Snape to nominate her, but he was out of his mind if he thought she would be participating in his circus. "I am honored," she lied. "Still, I won't be accepting. I hope you find someone suitable."

She made to rise, but Riddle's face fell into a hard glare and she found she couldn't complete the gesture. Merlin, but he was scary when he stopped pretending to be a normal person.

"You will be Hogwarts' representative for the tournament, Rigel." Even her name on his lips made her want to snarl with aberrance.

Lifting her chin, she glared back with all her might. "You cannot force me to participate, Mr. Riddle."

"Control your temper, Mr. Black," Snape cut in sharply. When she looked at him, the worry for her that lined his face was the only thing that kept her from snapping back.

"With all due respect, Professor, I will not go along with this. Nominate me all you like. Even if they pick me, I will decline to compete. Please fine another candidate." Rigel thought she'd kept a civil tone, but there was still a silent warning in her Head of House's eyes. So be it, she thought. If I have to defy even Snape to avoid this tournament, I will.

To her surprise, Riddle merely smiled again. "You have thirty days to change your mind. If you remain uncooperative, I will devise a means to change it for you."

"What does that mean?" Rigel stiffened her spine against the thought that he would use nefarious means to control her somehow. Even Riddle could not get away with the Imperious Curse, but she did not put anything past the abhorrent politician.

"No one is un-persuadable," Riddle told her. The way he said it, emotionless as a remark on the color of the sky, was the most ominous thing about it.

"You have nothing I want," she asserted. She couldn't think of a bribe that would be worth the dreadfulness of getting wrapped up in his little opera. No amount of money or knowledge was worth that.

"We shall see."

She stared in incredulous fury at the wizard before her. He thought he could just make her do something she didn't want to do? Let him try. Rigel kept her glare up until she felt the familiar flash of pain that was Dom's warning behind her eyes. She broke his gaze at once and stood. "If that is all, I best get back to the common room. Good evening, Professor."

Without waiting for a reply, she fled the office. It was only halfway back to the common room that she realized her hands were shaking. Closing her eyes, she slumped against a cold stone wall and let the rage crash over her. How dare he? What the hell did he think he was playing at? And Snape just stood there and let him—

With a slightly shaky laugh, she realized that was what upset her the most. Was her professor really so spineless? What did Riddle have over him, that he bowed to the man's every whim? She grimaced against the bitterness and straightened slowly. What did it matter, really, why Snape capitulated to Riddle's insistence? All that mattered was what she would do next. Rigel was on her own, that much was clear. That was fine. She would be her own support, as always.

Dizzy with the swirling implications of the night, Rigel made her way back to the common room and pleaded a headache when her friends waved her toward their chairs. She retreated to her room and dug in her trunk for a certain mirror. Archie needed to know about the tournament. At the very least, it meant many more eyes on Hogwarts than they'd even anticipated. The ruse would be tested that year like never before.

"Must you aggravate the boy every time you encounter him?" Severus was hard-pressed not to let his expression betray his dismay as he locked and warded the door after Rigel Black's abrupt exit.

"He purposely provokes my displeasure," Lord Riddle said unconcernedly. "Eventually, he will learn respect. That, or he will suffer the consequences."

Severus suspected it would be the latter. Rigel had very little sense of self-preservation, apparently. "How will you convince him?" he asked. He very much doubted the average inducement would appeal to a boy like Rigel Black.

Riddle's expression turned sardonic. "How would you go about it?"

Severus gave it honest consideration. His lord would accept nothing less. "It won't be enough to offer something he wants. Black could easily agree to participate and then make a poor showing to spite you." Riddle let out a noise of agreement. "You will have to offer him something he cannot afford to refuse. What that may be…" Severus lifted a shoulder. "I've no idea what he might value so much."

"He's a fourteen-year-old boy. It will not be difficult to discover," Riddle said confidently. After a contemplative silence, the dark-haired man shook his head and refocused. "Regardless, I had another reason for seeking you out, Severus."

He had wondered when Riddle would get around to what he'd originally come down to the dungeons to speak about. Certainly neither had expected Rigel to walk into the office so blithely. Severus suspected that Riddle would have waited until the end of the month to inform Rigel of his nomination, had the opportunity not presented itself so invitingly.

"The Potter girl," Riddle said, and Severus' attention snapped back to him in surprise.

"What about her?" he drawled, conveying to the best of his vocal ability that the girl ought to be of no concern to Riddle. She was of concern to no one but him, for the moment.

"I need you to separate the boy from his attachment to her. Regulus intimates that the girl has undue influence over our would-be champion." Riddle fixed Severus with a stern look. "Black cannot afford the connection, nor the distraction."

Severus paused for as long as he dared before answering. He had to think of some way to divert the politician's intentions. How had the man even known that Severus was in any way connected with Potter? "That will be prohibitively difficult, my lord. The two are closer than most siblings. Black would no sooner relinquish Harriett Potter than he would give up studying Potions."

"You will persuade him otherwise." Riddle appeared determined to pursue this course, and Severus couldn't help but wonder who had suggested this ill-advised plan to the politician. "Rigel Black is to be the perfect poster-boy for Pureblood preeminence. He cannot be so closely connected to a Halfblood."

So Riddle did intend for Rigel to win his tournament. Snape had suspected as much, but to have it as much as confirmed still lodged a weight in his stomach. Was it fate, that his student sought neither attention nor hassle yet was unable to escape either? "It may not be possible," Severus cautioned his lord carefully. "Could you not leverage their relationship instead?"

Lord Riddle tilted his head, considering. "As long as they are so attached to on another, both are vulnerable," he mused.

That was not quite what he meant. Severus offered, "A symbol of Pureblood who has strong ties to Halfbloods and Muggleborns would be more sympathetic to the moderates. Rigel's affection for his cousin will appeal to those who otherwise wouldn't support him as champion."

He had the satisfaction of seeing Riddle's eyebrows rise. "Interesting assertion, Severus. Are you certain that isn't your own sympathies talking?"

"If it is, my point is sound," Severus said, raising a brow of his own. "In addition, consider the girl herself: a talented young inventor, heiress to the Potter line. Her attachment to Rigel may be the leverage we need to win her to our side."

"You praise her." Riddle looked fascinated now. Not the best of indications, but at least he had successfully diverted the man's attention.

"Her ability speaks for itself," Severus said flatly. "Add to that the fact that she has the favor of the Aldermaster already, and you see why she is not as dependent on my good will as it seems. Her ideas are too compelling for the field to ignore. Better to have her in our corner before she becomes an unstoppable force in the academic community."

Riddle sat up straighter, looking at Severus as though he'd never seen him before. "And if I were to insist, Severus? If I told you that you must alienate the girl from her cousin in the next six months?"

Severus's gaze was steady as he looked at the powerful man across from him and said, "I would tell you it cannot be done. Beyond all that I have already mentioned, I have a contractual apprenticeship with both Rigel Black and Miss Potter. I can neither dissolve nor undermine either agreement without losing my own standing in the Guild. Regretfully, my lord, I am not the man for this task. If there is a way to separate those two, it is beyond my sphere of influence."

Riddle's gaze glittered with captivated curiosity. "Do you truly believe she can be persuaded to our side?"

"She will go where her cousin goes," Severus said slowly. That much he was sure of. "The boy will have to be convinced first. He doesn't like you," he added, in case Riddle had any delusions on that front.

"I don't require him to like me," Riddle said, looking amused. "Whether he wants to or not, he will become a symbol of our Party. When he wins this tournament and proves decisively that pure blood wins out, he will be ours by default. The people will rally behind him."

"Can a schoolyard tournament really accomplish so much?" Severus wondered aloud.

"Everyone loves a good sporting match," Riddle said, smiling slowly. "This spectacle will be like nothing they've ever seen. People who never thought they had a stake in blood politics will be choosing sides. That is the power of entertainment."

He suppressed the urge to widen his eyes and instead allowed the ripples of thought disturbed by that pronouncement to propagate silently. Severus could not shake the sense that Riddle was entirely correct in his assessment of the masses.

After a final instruction to keep pressure on Rigel Black regarding acceptance of his place in the tournament, Lord Riddle took his leave. Severus stayed seated a while longer before retiring. He had much to reflect upon. It was fortuitous, perhaps, that Rigel had requested to learn Battle Potions this term. Almost as though he knew what was in store for him. All Severus could do was prepare his student as best he could for what awaited. There was nothing else for it.

Chapter 7

Archie loved his cousin Harry, but hearing the mirror ding twice in as many weeks sent an immediate shiver of disquiet down his spine. Harry was many things, but chatty was not one of them; she would not call just to say hi, and they had finalized their cross-syllabi studying schedule the week before. Plus, it was only mid-afternoon. That meant Harry couldn't even wait a few hours until their designated calling time to talk to him. He locked the door to his room and fished the mirror from his bedside table drawer.

"Yes Rigel?" As soon as he spoke, the mirror's surface cleared to reveal his cousin's care-worn visage. His heart dropped at the look in her eyes, but he knew she wouldn't appreciate his panic. "What's happened?" he asked. If someone had discovered her identity, they were prepared to run, but surely it had not come to that already.

"There was an announcement tonight at dinner," Harry said. Her voice sounded a bit more vague than normal, as though she were still working through a sudden shock. "There's to be a tournament here at Hogwarts. Riddle's pushing for me to compete."

"WHAT—" Archie clapped a hand to his mouth and took a deep breath before continuing, at a more manageable level, "What does that mean? How can they force you to compete?"

"I don't know," Harry said faintly. At the sight of moisture gathering in the corner of his cousin's eyes, Archie's sucked in a sharp breath and started murmuring rapidly into the mirror.

"Oh, it's okay, Harry. Whatever it is, it'll be okay. I promise we'll work through it. Just start at the beginning and explain everything. I'm here as long as you need me." Archie wasn't sure if it was the words themselves or the soothing tone of his voice that slowly coaxed her out of her daze.

She blinked hard several times and pulled a slow breath in through her nose before sighing. "Okay. Yes. It started with Riddle's announcement…"

Archie struggled to hold onto a semblance of equanimity as Harry recounted the evening she'd had. He didn't have the emotional control that Harry did, though, and his brain was giving birth to a litter of worries while her tale unfolded. A tournament built around blood prejudice sounded like the most gauche thing he'd ever heard of. Harry couldn't compete in such a tournament. Who knew what kind of things would be asked of her? What if the competitors had to take some kind of contractual oath? What if she had to go swimming?

"…and then Snape acted like he didn't have any choice which means it's up to me to find a way out of this madness." Harry broke off her increasingly distressed recitation to suck in a breath and Archie interrupted her.

"It's up to us, remember. You're not in this alone. We can handle anything together." Archie waited until her eyes refocused on his own and gave Harry a confident smile. "Really, it's not so bad. All we know so far is that Riddle is trying to come up with some way to convince you to participate. He hasn't succeeded yet so there's not reason to panic."

"I don't know what he could offer that would tempt me," Harry said, frowning slightly. "I'm worried he'll take matters into his own hands somehow if he thinks I can't be persuaded any other way. I just don't see why he's so set on me competing. There are plenty of others who would gladly take up the mantel for the Cow Party. Draco would in a heartbeat. Theo, too, and Rookwood wouldn't turn the opportunity down either. I'm probably the worst possible choice for this!"

Archie sighed. "Not from his perspective. He doesn't know most of the reasons you're unsuited to this. What he does know is that you're powerful, smart, and strong enough to survive several things that might have killed other wizards your age. He knows you're the Heir to an old, Dark family that has recently pulled away from his influence. If you win this tournament, what happens?"

"Everyone thinks pureblooded children are in general more talented than halfbloods or muggleborns," Harry said glumly. "And I become the face of bigotry."

"The Black Heir becomes a symbol of pureblood power," Archie corrected her. "Don't think I'm thrilled about that, either, but we have more important things to consider. If it looks like the Blacks are moving back toward Dark politics, how many of the neutral pureblooded families might also reconsider their stance? Especially if the tournament succeeds in Riddle's true aim."

"What's that?" Harry asked, puzzled. He preferred her confusion to the lost, frustrated expression she'd been wearing just a few minutes ago.

"Riddle doesn't just want an anecdotal example to use in arguments favoring pureblood privilege," Archie said evenly. "He's trying to swing public opinion in general in favor of purebloods. Do you know what happened after Ireland won the World Cup?"

Harry blinked at him. "No. What does that have to do with it?"

"Ireland got a brand new stadium with ten thousand more seats than their old one held," Archie told her. "Because they're winners. People love a winner. It's why we root for teams in the first place. Us verses them. That's Riddle's game. He's tired of pureblooded families supporting halfbloods and muggleborns. The Light families' support is the only thing keeping purebloods from having even more advantages than they have now. Do you see what this tournament is going to do?"

Harry nodded slowly. "I was thinking something similar myself, though I hadn't thought of it like Quidditch teams. The number of people who root for a champion who doesn't represent their specific blood community is going to be low. Halfbloods will root for the halfbloods. Muggleborns for the muggleborns. And a lot of purebloods might root for the pureblood candidates without even thinking of it as a social issue. It will seem natural. Easy to choose a side. And easy to disparage the other side because that's just how human nature works once people choose sides. People are going to lose their minds. Oh Merlin, how are we going to stop this?"

Archie raised his eyebrows at Harry's words. Where had his apathetic cousin gone? And when had altruism become her first impulse, rather than an instinct she attempted to suppress beneath caution and guilt? While he was proud of her, he didn't think she fully comprehended the situation at hand. "I don't think anyone can stop it except Riddle, at this point," Archie told her. "The most we can do is undermine the effects."

"I could agree to compete and then throw the competition," Harry suggested reluctantly.

Archie grimaced. "There's no way Riddle won't think of that. If he gets you to compete, it will be with the understanding that you do your best. That's why he wants you to compete, not any of your classmates. They would be more eager, but their best isn't like your best, Ha—Rigel. Your best is scary. Riddle wants that."

"It's still a gamble," she argued, looking uncomfortable at his determination. "With candidates from all over, there's bound to be others with as much skill, if not more."

"I think all those convoluted precautions Riddle has put it place for 'fairness' will actually give him more control of the proceedings than most will suspect," Archie said thoughtfully. Riddle was a politician. He simply would not implement measures that did not favor him in some way.

He could see Harry running her free hand agitatedly through her hair, ruffling the front into disarray. "How is this my life?" she muttered. "Well, our life. I'm so sorry about this, Archie. If I hadn't garnered Riddle's attention we wouldn't be in this mess. How are we going to make Sirius understand?"

Archie's stomach clenched. His father would absolutely be against him participating in the tournament. Quite aside from Sirius' aversion to pureblood supremacy and all its rhetoric, he also just wouldn't be okay with 'Archie' doing something so dangerous after all that the last three years had entailed.

Still, that was not Harry's fault, and Archie could see that his cousin had enough on her shoulders. "Let me worry about Sirius," he said gently. "I'll write a letter breaking the news gently, and explaining as best I can what's going on."

Harry looked alarmed. "If you tell him what Riddle is doing, Sirius won't let that go lightly. He'll make an enemy of the SOW Party, and he's only just now coming back out into society again."

"I have to tell him something." Archie blew out a breath. "I'll think on it. You start brainstorming ways around whatever Riddle comes up with to get you to compete."

"All right." Harry looked slightly relieved to have a straightforward task to tackle. "Can you ask around AIM and see if anyone knows anything more about this tournament?"

"Sure," Archie said. That would be easy enough. He doubted he'd learn much, though. If he were Riddle, he wouldn't put too much effort into advertising this supposedly open tournament. The fewer applicants, the better control he had over who the 'impartial committee' determined to be the best competitors. Checking his watch, he realized Hermione would be coming to collect him for Sunday afternoon test prep shortly. "Are you all right?" he asked Harry.

She nodded with a small smile. It might have been convincing if not for the lines creasing her forehead and the sheen of overwhelmed moisture that coated her usually flat grey eyes. "Yes, go about your day as normal. Thanks for answering, cuz. I feel a lot less like road kill, though I maintain that Fate keeps running over me on purpose."

Archie laughed, relieved that at least Harry maintained her morbid sense of humor. "Call me again if the stress gets to you. I'm always here."

Harry nodded bravely. "I know. I won't forget. Talk to you soon."

"I'll ask the professor here about this tournament," Archie added.

"Do not get yourself nominated." There was his domineering cousin.

He grinned innocently. "Who, me?"

"Harry!"

"Just kidding. I promise not to make your life any harder, cuz." He searched her eyes a final time before smiling sadly. "Take care of yourself. Screw Riddle and the tournament and what anyone else expects. Don't do anything you can't handle."

Harry nodded seriously. "I'll do my best."

That's what he was afraid of. Archie knew Harry would do as she pleased, in the end. She always did. He just hoped it worked out for them again. The connection was cut off, and Archie put the mirror away slowly, lost in thought.

He'd been sort of vaguely concerned with the suspicions Harry harbored about what Riddle was up to that year, but since coming back to AIM he hadn't given it much attention. After all, if whatever he was scheming was as out in the open as it seemed it would be, how bad could it really be? Apparently it could be very bad. So bad that he wasn't sure how Harry's sanity would survive the pressure. Not only was she being coerced into championing a cause she vehemently disagreed with, a cause that had incidentally prompted her to commit to a lifelong deception at the risk of her very soul at the tender age of eleven, but in becoming that champion she would inevitably put that deception into the realest peril it had ever faced. That sort of thing couldn't be good for the psyche.

And here he was in North America, completely unable to give her the hug she so obviously needed. On a dissatisfied sigh, Archie checked his reflection in the mirror and summoned a more cheerful expression. When he looked less like he'd just be told his favorite dog had died, Archie left his room to track down Hermione. If anything could cheer him up, it was seeing her lovely brown eyes darken in concentration as she tried to answer his practice test questions. If the gods were truly smiling on him, she might nibble a quill while she thought.

He hadn't quite worked up the courage to tell Hermione how he felt yet, but he didn't have any trouble admiring her from across a study table while he waited for the opportune moment.

Rigel woke the next morning with a blinding headache. It seemed that all of the stress she'd been trying to ignore had caught up with her sometime in the night. She slowly unclenched her jaw and suppressed a groan as she slid off her bed and blinked against the crust between her eyelids.

She retrieved a pain potion from her kit and gulped it down in a single go. By the time she had changed into her running clothes and exited the bathroom, her head felt almost normal. Draco mumbled a good morning as he swapped her places in the bathroom to brush his teeth and comb his hair. Why he bothered grooming himself before going out to exercise, Rigel didn't understand. She supposed it was part of his charm, though.

When they were both mostly awake and dressed, they crept out of the dorm room and into the common room where Pansy awaited them. Rigel was always amazed at how alert Pansy seemed so early in the morning. She wondered if their blonde friend simply woke up refreshed and cheerful or if Pansy set an alarm much earlier than they did and used the extra time to reach full operational capability.

Rigel was looking forward to a long run that morning; she had a lot to sort out in her head as far as Riddle's tournament was concerned. She didn't count on Draco and Pansy noticing her preoccupation, however.

"Are you ever going to tell us what's on your mind?" Pansy asked. Her voice was light and even despite the brisk pace the three of them kept around the lake.

"I thought you said not to pester him!" Draco said before Rigel could answer.

She couldn't stop the laugh that bubbled up from her chest. Her friends were really too much sometimes. "Am I so obvious?"

"The aura of darkness hanging around you when you got back to the common room last night was," Draco told her frankly.

Rigel shook her head ruefully. "That bad, huh? Well, I had a bit of a shock, that's all."

"What happened?" Pansy asked. "Did Snape do something disagreeable?"

"It wasn't Snape—not really," she amended, as she had not quite decided whether to confront him on his lack of defense of her yet. Rigel hesitated, but she'd already started to explain. If her friends knew what was happening, maybe they would excuse her foul moods. "Riddle was in Snape's office last night. He's asking Snape to nominate me for the tournament."

"Oh, congratulations!" Pansy's smile faltered when she turned to see the scowl on Rigel's face. "Ah. That is… how dare he? Without even consulting you first?"

Rigel felt a smile tug at her lips involuntarily. "I know, I sound churlish and ungrateful. I really don't want to be in the tournament, though. I don't agree with its premise. I don't want to be the face of blood supremacy. I just want a quiet year."

"So don't do it." Draco said it with an obvious expression on his face. "I mean, you were polite when you declined, right?"

"The first couple of times…" Rigel grimaced. "At the end I was pretty annoyed though. I don't think I left Riddle with any illusions as to my attitude."

"Well, that isn't ideal, but I'm sure the damage can be rectified," Pansy said uncertainly.

Rigel shook her head sharply. "You don't understand. He's still insisting. I told him flat out that I wouldn't do it, and Riddle just said he would find some way to convince me."

"He said what?" Pansy stopped running and stared at Rigel in shock. Draco and Rigel stopped as well and all three took a moment to catch their breath before Pansy pinned him with a fierce look. "Rigel, he's threatening you. What did he say exactly?"

Rigel recounted the conversation as best she could, grimacing when Draco and Pansy both winced at her phrasing.

"You told him he has nothing you want?" Draco whistled lowly. "That's not good."

"But it's true," Rigel said, frowning.

"If he thinks he can't tempt you, he's going to use another kind of pressure instead," Pansy said. Her soft features were tight with concern. "Rigel, this isn't good."

"I know that," she said, clenching and unclenching her fists helplessly. "But what can I do?"

Surprisingly, Pansy was quick with the answer that Rigel had been trying to conceive all night. "Warn your family," the girl said, eyes full of deadly earnest. "Family is always the first thing people will try to use against you. If they know ahead of time and are prepared to withstand pressure on your behalf, that's half the battle won."

"Should you be telling me this?" Rigel was moved by the unhesitating practicality with which Pansy had met her explanation of the situation. She knew that Pansy and Draco ought not to help her undermine anything Riddle was plotting, considering their families both supported the Party, and yet here they were listening and commiserating with her. Perhaps there was some room between loyalty to family and friendship, after all.

"It's nothing you shouldn't already know," Draco said, an odd expression on his face. "Rigel… why don't you tell him you're medically incapable?"

She blinked at him. "Medically incapa—oh. You mean my… condition?" She glanced at Pansy, but the pureblooded girl looked merely concerned. Her friends hadn't really brought up the story Snape had spun to protect her time-turner the previous year, and Pansy still didn't know she'd ever had a time-turner. If Draco suspected the story was false, he still thought she had some sort of embarrassing skin condition that made her avoid close contact with others.

"Of course," Draco said, frowning. "You can't be expected to compete, considering."

"No one else knows about that," she said quietly. She didn't have to fake the fear she felt at Riddle ever discovering that secret. "I won't tell Riddle about it. If it turns out I can't get out of this, I'll deal with that as it comes."

"You're smart, Rigel," Pansy said, smiling bracingly at her. "Just don't let them take you off guard. I know you'll come through this okay."

Rigel smiled back gratefully. She truly didn't deserve her amazing friends. "Thank you guys. It doesn't seem so hopeless, saying it all out loud."

"Oh, it's hopeless," Draco said, a smirk creeping onto his face. "With you as our champion, Hogwarts is doomed."

"What's that supposed to mean?" Rigel demanded, playing along if only to lift the heavy, despondent feeling from her shoulders.

"We'll be a laughing stock," Draco bemoaned. "Think of it—the only champion who solves every task with a potion."

"Is that a challenge?" Rigel laughed. It wasn't funny—the very idea of participating in the tournament was horrifying at best—but it was cathartic to let the hysteria leak out a little.

"Don't encourage him," Pansy said, starting to jog once more.

They hurried to catch up to her. After a few minutes' silence, Rigel asked, "Are you guys upset that Riddle wants me to compete? Were you thinking of entering yourselves?"

"I was," Draco said frankly. "I think my father would have asked Uncle Severus to nominate me, if things had gone differently. I'm glad you told me now, though, that the Party already has a plan in mind. Otherwise I might have let hubris get my hopes up."

"You would make a good champion," Rigel offered tentatively. "You should enter. If I can get out of this, maybe you—"

"Don't fool yourself, Rigel," Draco said sternly. "I know you don't want to do this, but you have to ask yourself what the cost of defying Lord Riddle will be. I'll survive not being the pureblood representative. But promise me something," he added suddenly. At Rigel's prompting look, he said, slowly, "Promise me that if you are picked—if you can't refuse—that you won't just throw it away. You have to at least try, Rigel. Otherwise it's an insult to everyone who would be in your shoes, if they could."

Rigel felt the blood drain from her face. Could she promise that to Draco? She didn't want to try. She thought back to what Archie had said. If Riddle somehow coerced her into competing, there was very little chance that he wouldn't also coerce her into taking it seriously. She nodded after a long moment's thought. "Okay. If I have to compete, I'll take it seriously—for you, Dray."

He made a face at her. "Don't make it weird, you prat."

"Will you carry Draco's favor in your pocket for good luck?" Pansy wondered.

"Pansy!" Draco shot her a betrayed expression. "I am not the girl in this relationship!"

"Excuse me?" Pansy's challenging glare had Draco visibly backpedaling just as fast.

"Not that there's anything wrong with that. It's just not how our particular dynamic functions. Right, Rigel? Rigel, tell her."

"I will certainly dedicate my victory to Draco's virtue and grace," Rigel allowed.

"You take that back!" Draco lunged at her but Rigel took off into a sprint before his hand could grasp her neck.

They sprinted the rest of the way back to the castle. The lighthearted feeling of wings that carried her well beyond the end of the workout might have been adrenaline, but it also might have been the glowing wonderment in her heart at the idea that her friends really cared for her. They were willing to walk a delicate line for her, even though it gained them nothing aside from her gratitude. Their support and advice gave her the determination she needed to seek out her Head of House that very day. She would confront him alone, without Riddle there to ooze threats with his very presence, and see what the Potions Master had to say. Draco and Pansy were willing to take a risk for her. Maybe, a small, naïve part of her whispered, Snape would too.

She had a potions lesson scheduled Sunday afternoon already, so Rigel collected her protective gear and headed toward lab three a little early. If she could get the difficult conversation out of the way first, it might not even cut very much into her lesson. Snape was within when she arrived, but she noticed he hadn't made any preparations for brewing yet. He was simply waiting, arms folded across his chest and head tucked slightly so that his gaze drilled into the ground. She had seen that posture many times; it meant the Potions Master had succumbed to his thoughts completely. He'd likely been that way for a while, as even her quiet entrance didn't startle him from his reverie at once.

He knew she was there, of course. Snape always knew when someone was near. He had some kind of near-constant passive Legilimency that allowed him to recognize the feel of the minds around him. She wondered if it was related to the projected magical field she was learning for free brewing. There was probably a deeper mental aspect to it, but she wouldn't be surprised if the basic theory was similar.

She set down her gear and waited a few minutes for Snape to refocus on the world around him. When his eyes rose to her face, Rigel met his look with calm serenity. "We need to talk, sir."

His eyebrow lifted so slowly it had to be unnatural. "I presume your desired topic of discussion is the events of yesterday evening."

"Quite."

"State your piece, then," her Head of House said flatly. His arms were still crossed and the way his eyes narrowed at her stubborn expression didn't bode well for open communication. Still, she had to try.

"I want to know why you didn't defend me last night, sir. You know I don't want to do the tournament, yet you are prepared to nominate me anyway because Riddle asked it." She searched his closed expression and for once allowed the hurt to show clearly in her eyes. "I need to know if you bow to Riddle because you agree with him or if there is some other reason you cannot stand against him."

Snape's black eyes glittered at her as he waited for her to finish. When he spoke, it was measured and slow. "I do defend you, Rigel, though you do not perceive it. I have limited maneuverability in what Lord Riddle requires, but what leeway I possess I have spent almost exclusively on you these past three years."

Rigel blinked. "What do you mean?" She had expected Snape to either refuse to engage her on the topic or else to tell her that Riddle was acting for the best somehow. She hadn't let herself imagine that Snape would openly admit to being on her side. Still, she didn't know in what instances he would have needed to maneuver on her behalf.

"Think, Rigel. You have foiled more than one of Lord Riddle's plans. Do you know what usually happens to people who stand in his way?" Snape's frown was tight. "He removes them from his path, one way or another."

She thought quickly. "Has he threatened me?" Was Archie going to be in danger in the future?

"I convinced him there was no need to," Snape said sharply. "You first year, I persuaded him that you meant no harm, that you didn't know what you were doing, and that saving Draco's life was a good thing. It would tie the Black Heir to the Malfoy family, after all."

Rigel drew in a sharp breath. Had Mr. Malfoy's offer of a life debt been at Riddle's behest? Is that why they allowed Draco to maintain his close friendship with her? Because Riddle wanted the Black family realigned with his Party? Snape had continued without pausing, so she left that line of thought for a moment to catch up to what he was saying.

"Second year I expected a greater reaction. Lord Riddle seems to have overlooked your part in the death of Slytherin's monster and the magical construct's madness—"

"He didn't overlook it," Rigel cut in. "I made a deal with him."

Snape stared at her. "What could you possibly have bargained?"

"The construct told me everything in the Chamber. More than I admitted to Dumbledore," she said softly. Her magic squeaked like a cat whose tail had been yanked and she winced. That would be the vow warning her not to reveal anything specific. "I can't talk about the exchange we made. Suffice to say that he did not take my knowing anything about the construct stoically."

The Potions Master began to pace the small room agitatedly. "You should not make such bargains lightly."

"I didn't," Rigel said, frowning. "I don't doubt that without an assurance of silence Riddle would have ensured it another way."

Snape did not contradict her, which in itself was a bit terrifying. It was one thing to suspect that Riddle would go so far as to Obliviate or otherwise prevent a person from revealing his secrets, but quite another to have it essentially confirmed by one of his Party members.

"He has put that business behind him, at least," Snape said, almost to himself. "Last year he will not forget as quickly. Lord Riddle was livid at your interference."

"I was kidnapped," Rigel snapped, outraged. Riddle had no right to be upset with her that his minion had turned coat and lost his humanity.

Snape's eyes flashed. "Do not take that tone with me, boy. Riddle does not believe you had no hand in the destruction of the stone. He doesn't even believe it truly destroyed. Before I persuaded him otherwise, he was prepared to question you himself over the matter."

"How did you change his mind?" Rigel asked, not sure if she wanted to know.

"I intimated that you were not in any state to be interrogated," Snape said, his lip curling slightly.

"You told him I was broken," Rigel said, voice sharp.

"I bought you time to regain equilibrium before facing him," he corrected her. "Do not think you would have been beyond his reach in the Darian Gap, had he pressed the matter."

She paled. The thought of Riddle confronting Archie over the Dominion Jewel… it was unthinkable. Their ruse would crumble instantly. "Thank you," she said hoarsely. "I…did need the time."

He inclined his head briefly. "Then of course there is your obstinacy regarding this tournament."

"I won't do it," she said firmly.

"You will," Snape said, just as firm. "He will not give you a choice. The only question is what he will do to ensure your cooperation."

"So he is going to threaten me," Rigel said, eyes widening slightly. Pansy was right.

"I cannot be certain," Snape said, shaking his head. "You must prepare yourself for anything. He will use your vulnerabilities against you. Already he has asked me to divest you of your attachment to your cousin. He wants you isolated. Unsure of yourself and others."

"Wait," Rigel said, her head spinning. "He asked you to separate me and Harry? Why?"

"Lord Riddle believes that attachments are a weakness, but more than that, he is hoping to turn your loyalties toward the S.O.W. Party this year." At her incredulous look, Snape's lips twisted. "It is not so unthinkable as you assume. If he succeeds in making you his pureblood champion, you will stand apart from your classmates. It is a lonely competition, and you will be competing for something your family is unlikely to support."

She nodded slowly. That was certainly true. If her family pulled back from her, if she didn't have her cousin to rely on so completely… it might be enough to put her off balance. Still, she just couldn't see herself ever turning to Riddle for anything. "What will you do to Harry?" she asked dully.

Snape hissed. "Haven't you been listening? I will do nothing. I am trying to help you. And Miss Potter. My protection only extends so far, however. I warn you so that you can make your own defenses."

Unwilling tears sprang to Rigel's eyes and she ducked her head to hide them as she blinked them away with fierce impatience. She'd been so mistaken. Snape was supporting her. He always had been, only she hadn't seen it because she'd been so arrogant as to believe Lord Riddle tolerated her for his own reasons. "Thank you, sir," she said again. Her voice sounded choked and she flushed slightly with embarrassment. She must look exceedingly foolish, blubbering like a child over his protection—protection that extended to Harry, apparently. That alone had her chest filling with warmth.

"You are more than welcome," her Potions Master said gruffly. She peeked up to see an expression almost like embarrassment on his face, too. "Regardless, you must not rely on me. Lord Riddle will not be waylaid indefinitely."

Annoyance beat back her embarrassment swiftly. "He's not a lord," she muttered. "He doesn't head any of the old families, and he hasn't been granted an Order of Merlin First Class."

"He is what he says he is." Snape's tone was absolute. "That is power. Gainsaying it will not change the reality that most consider the man to be equal and above the other Lords of society."

She shook her head in slow disbelief. "Why do you follow him?" The question slipped out without her conscious decision, but once it had she didn't take it back. She did want to know. "You're a halfblood," she added bluntly. At his dark look she qualified her words slightly. "I'm not saying everyone has to support political agendas that align with their inborn groups, but I know you aren't a bigot."

"Do you?" His voice had grown silky—always a bad sign. She didn't retreat, though. In that moment, she felt closer to Snape than she ever had, as a mentor, a role model, a professor, and as a person, too. She wanted to understand him better, even if it made him uncomfortable.

"I do. I'm pretty sure you don't like werewolves, but you put an entire year of your life into improving the potion that helps them through transformations. I know Dumbledore asked you to do that Remus could teach here," she went on before he could protest, "but you could have easily found a way out of it. There are other things, too. You don't treat Harry like she's an idiot or unworthy to study potions just because she's a halfblood girl. You aren't rude to Mr. Hagrid or Mr. Filch, even though both would be considered undesirables according to the S.O.W. Party. You—"

"That is sufficient," Snape growled. "What is your point?"

"That you don't let a person's blood status or even magical affliction affect your interactions with them. I don't see what about Riddle's party ever drew you to it." She shrugged. "I guess they support other things, like loosening the restrictions on Dark magic and promoting the old cultural traditions. Those platforms get so buried under the blood mania. Is it worth it?"

Her Head of House's face was utterly devoid of expression. "My personal choices are none of your concern."

"I don't think you really support his ideals," Rigel said bravely. "I think he has some hold over you, and that it's going to affect what you can and can't do to help me." She blinked up at him in earnest. "I understand if you can't always protect me. I'd just like to know, so I can make my own plans, like you said."

Snape took a step closer and the menacing intimidation he gave off as he leaned into Rigel's personal space made her catch her breath. "Do not ever question my loyalties to the Party again," he breathed. "I have my own arrangement with Lord Riddle, and its details are not yours to know. Understand that I am limited in what I may deny him and make your… plans accordingly."

She gulped silently. "Yes, sir."

"Good. If this matter is settled to your satisfaction, we must discuss your training." Snape stepped back and unrolled a bit of parchment he plucked from his pocket. "Your classes end two hours before dinner Monday through Thursday," he noted. She wondered if he'd brought a copy of her schedule tonight specifically or if he carried it around so he knew where she was at all times. Somehow, she wouldn't put it past him.

"That's right," she said, not sure where he was going with it.

"Very well. You will report to my office on those afternoons for the next month. We don't have long to prepare you—"

"I'm not participating in the tournament," Rigel interrupted, exasperated.

"Nevertheless, I will train you as though you are," Snape said, sneering. "Are you going to turn down extra lessons?

She opened her mouth and then his words caught up to her. Her teeth clicked together with a snap. "What kind of lessons?" she said after a moment of frustrated internal debate. Who was she kidding? Of course she wanted extra training. She just didn't want to look like she was giving into the idea of competing.

"Self defense, silent casting, dangerous creature familiarization… a number of things, really," Snape said smoothly. The amusement in his eyes told her he knew exactly how tempted she was by the idea of extracurricular instruction.

"It won't interfere with my potions time." It was not a question. At Snape's affirmative nod, she sighed. "I suppose extra training never hurts. As long as Riddle understands I'm only doing it for the knowledge. I haven't agreed to compete."

"I think we are clear on that point," the Potions Master drawled.

Rigel silently reflected that no one was going to be clear on that. If her friends found out she was going to Snape's office every afternoon for extra training they would never believe she wasn't trying to get nominated for the tournament. Where was Snape going to find the time for this, in any case? With her filling up his late afternoons and weekends, how was he going to get all his marking done? "Do you have a time-turner?" she asked abruptly.

Her question startled a snort of laughter out of him. "It's called time management."

She peered at him suspiciously. "You're going to make the prefects do your marking, aren't you?"

"There's an idea," Snape said idly. His blandly innocent expression was not convincing.

After a moment of silence in which they both looked at one another appraisingly, Rigel thought she was tentatively satisfied with the way their conversation had gone. Snape hadn't exactly spilled his guts for her, but she hadn't expected him to. She knew more about where Snape stood in relation to Riddle and herself, even if he didn't openly admit to being disloyal to the Party. In addition, she knew now that she had more reason to be grateful to her Head of House than she'd ever imagined.

She suspected he was as exhausted from their guarded heart-to-heart as she was, so she offered, "Are we brewing anything today?"

Snape inclined his head, lips twitching upward just slightly. "I have a recipe for an area effect potion purported to dissolve into a mist that slows the movement of anything inside it."

Intrigued, Rigel tilted her head. "How do we prevent that reaction while we brew it? What's to stop it dissolving before we get it into the bottle?"

"You will recall your lessons in Indirect Stirring. A barrier is necessary to contain the potion inside the cauldron until it is at a stage that it can be transferred. Don your protective gear and I will begin the necessary ingredient preparation."

Rigel grinned. Potions was a balm to the soul. She was convinced that almost anything could be cured with the simmering sound of a full cauldron, including any lingering awkwardness between her and Professor Snape.

It was only much later, as she tested her magical field against the Exploding Snap cards in the common room, that she realized she had forgotten to ask about the resonance again.

Archie tapped his feet restlessly under the table in class on Tuesday, impatient for Congenital Diseases to end so he could ask Professor Willoweed whether she'd heard anything about the tournament happening at Hogwarts. In addition to being a Healing professor, Willoweed was the also charged with mentoring and career counseling for AIM's upper levels, which meant if anyone might know about a foreign competition open to students between fourth and seventh year, it would be her.

The lesson didn't seem as though it would be ending any time soon, however, and the reason was not surprising. Hermione was arguing about the textbook explanation. Again.

His beautifully spirited friend had always been opinionated, but this year the fiery witch was nothing short of a crusader. Hermione had blossomed in the Lower Alley sunshine and Archie found her transformation utterly fascinating. No cause was too hopeless for the fifteen-year-old healer-in-training. As evidenced by the impassioned way she railed against the medical community's widely accepted practice in regards to the increasing instances of infant mortality.

"So we just let them die?" Hermione demanded, voice high in indignation.

To her credit, Professor Willoweed kept a faultless composure. "No one is celebrating this, Miss Granger. The fact is, there is currently no known cure for the phenomenon commonly called the Fade."

"The way you describe it makes it sound like there's not even a known explanation," Hermione said hotly. "Infants less than a year old are dying inexplicably, and somehow it's not the number one priority at every research hospital in the world. Does no one else see a problem with that?"

Archie thought he ought to give Willoweed a break. "Hermione, it's not a worldwide issue."

"What?" she said, turning to blink at him distractedly. "What did you say, Harry?"

"The Fade isn't prominent in every Wizarding community," he said gently. "There are recorded cases around the world, but in terms of the overall rate of occurrence, it's only affecting a few places as badly as Britain. So it's not a worldwide priority."

Professor Willoweed inclined her head, and her curls barely twitched in their tight coiffure. "Additionally, Miss Granger, there has been a good deal of research into potential catalysts over the last half century. Despite that, there is no consensus as to the Fade's medical origin, if indeed there is a medical issue underlying the condition at all."

Hermione's eyes widened. "What does that mean? How can there be no issue? The babies die of something."

Their professor took a slow breath. "Some… experts maintain that there is nothing physically wrong with the children who Fade. Their symptoms present and progress in spite of every attempted treatment. Healing doesn't work. Quarantine doesn't work. No herbs or potions are known to forestall Fate's hand once an infant is afflicted. In the face of all this, who can say whether the disease is not more akin to a curse?"

"We treat curses, too," Hermione insisted. "Healing doesn't end at illness or injury. If our oath gives us responsibility for spell damage, then we have a responsibility to these infants regardless of whether the cause is ultimately magical or medical."

"It is kinder and more merciful to send a Fade-touched child home with its family." Professor Willoweed grimaced. "I don't like it any more than you do, but without a viable treatment option, we can do little but observe each infant's slow passing."

"Nothing is incurable in itself," Hermione said. Her eyes were bright, and Archie felt a sympathetic sting in his own in response. Hermione was the only one he'd ever met who agreed with him on that simple truth. There were no lost causes. Only cures that hadn't been discovered yet. "How can we in good faith simply give up?"

"Our community hasn't given up," Willoweed said firmly. "There are a number of renowned specialists still working toward better understanding this condition. Until they offer a solution—or even a course of action for mitigating the illness—the prescribed response to this diagnosis is as I said: make the child comfortable, direct close kin to Mind Healers who specialize in grief, and document every detail of the case carefully so that the data may be passed to those searching for a cure. Now, class, we are out of time. Are there any more questions?"

Hermione was biting her tongue on a number of questions, if Archie didn't miss his guess. Willoweed gave her an apologetic look and dismissed the class to lunch. Archie blew out his breath and slowly began gathering his materials. Once most of his classmates had flocked into the corridor, Archie said, "Professor, could I ask you about something before you go?"

She raised her eyebrows. "Something that couldn't be brought up during the lesson?" she prodded.

Archie smiled with all the charm in his piggybank—which, he admitted, was somewhat limited while he wore the hybrid 'Rigel' face. Still, he would work with what he had. "It isn't about Healing, exactly. I heard something from my cousin, who attends Hogwarts, and wondered if it was true."

Hermione, who of course hadn't left the classroom without him, frowned curiously at him. "Rigel wrote to you?"

Archie smiled, neither answering nor denying her guess. "He said that Hogwarts is hosting an international tournament of some kind. It's supposedly open to all students fourteen to seventeen years of age. I hadn't heard anything about AIM nominating a candidate, though."

Professor Willoweed looked utterly nonplussed. "A tournament? For students? I haven't heard of any such thing, Mr. Potter."

That was interesting. It had been a day and a half since the announcement. If the Cow Party meant to raise awareness for its competition internationally, they were doing a poor job of it. Unless they weren't advertising to certain schools on purpose. AIM had a lot of muggleborns. Only Ilvermorny had more. Could it be that Riddle didn't want to give those students too much time to apply?

"It was announced just this weekend," Archie said, feigning innocence. "Perhaps the news is just slow to reach us. Or perhaps AIM isn't going to participate."

"We regularly nominate candidates for international programs," Willoweed said, talking more to herself than to him. "There's no reason our faculty shouldn't have been notified. Thank you for bringing this to my attention, Mr. Potter. I will look into it."

"Sure, Professor," Archie said, grinning. "Hermione? Lunch?"

His brown-eyed girl tilted her head in a way that he knew meant she wasn't impressed with his acting ability. Still, she nodded and waited for him to sling his book bag over his shoulder before following him out of the room.

"Why are you interested in this tournament, Harry?" Hermione asked slowly as they headed toward the cafeteria. "Are you trying to enter? Would you be gone all semester?"

Archie shook his head. "No way. I don't want any part of it. I just wanted to know if AIM had been contacted about it or not. The whole thing is a pageant, 'Mione, except instead of beauty they're celebrating blood."

Hermione gaped at him. "Harry, stop." She pulled on his arm until he paused and turned to look at her. "Will you explain what you mean by that? A tournament that celebrates blood?"

He grimaced. "It's being put on by the S.O.W. Party." Hermione's nose wrinkled, and he quite agreed. "They want to 'settle the question' of blood purity once and for all, so they're hosting a contest for students around the world. It's going to pit blood categories against one another, so in the final round one pureblood, one halfblood, and one muggleborn will compete for the championship."

"That's utterly barbaric," Hermione spluttered. "Not to mention nonsensical. They may as well put people with Type A blood against those with B and O for all the scientific rigor it demonstrates!"

Archie laughed. "But which category would Type AB get to compete in? No, I'm afraid your Triwizard Tournament won't work at all, 'Mione."

"This is serious, Harry. Who on earth would allow such blatant bigotry a stage to prance around on?"

"Our Ministry of Magic, who else?"

Hermione's eyes flashed. "And roping children into it! What imprudence. I suppose there's some kind of prize or enticement?"

"Sure is, luv. A pretty one, too. Not as pretty as you, of course—"

"Not now, Harry." Hermione's cheeks flushed, but she would not be distracted. "We have to do something about this—this outrage."

"There's nothing stopping it now," Archie reasoned. "Besides which, we're well out of it here."

Hermione was appalled. "We can't just do nothing. I'm going to find out what the prerequisites for applying are."

She started off down the corridor with a vengeance. Archie, stomach clenching a bit at the familiar tone of stubborn determination in her voice, hurried to catch up. "Hermione, you can't be thinking of applying."

She tossed her hair and pinned him with a challenging look. "Why? You don't think I could do it?"

He raised both hands instinctively. "I didn't say that. Why would you want to be wrapped up in that madness, though? It's going to be like some kind of coliseum match, only you'll be the lion they set against their chosen warrior. The S.O.W. Party doesn't want to see a muggleborn do well, don't you see?"

Hermione looked every inch the lioness as she leveled a fierce glare at him. "I do see. I see exactly what they're trying to do and I'm going to make them regret it. I'll show them—the whole world, even—that muggleborns are every inch as magical as purebloods. They want to put it to a test? I eat tests for breakfast."

Archie couldn't help the startled laugh that escaped him, though he shouldn't find any part of it funny. Harry was going to kill him if Hermione actually entered this thrice-damned tournament. Still. "You're amazing," he said, smiling in a way that probably made him look dopey. He didn't care. "That tournament doesn't deserve you."

She favored him with unimpressed amusement. "Stop flattering me and help me find out about the entry requirements, Harry."

"As my lady commands," Archie said easily. He bowed, sweeping an arm out toward the corridor. She slipped ahead of him, and he tried not to stare too obviously at the way her hair swayed when she stalked.

The morning after the tournament was announced, a sign up sheet had been posted on the Great Hall announcement board where hopeful students could indicate their willingness to be considered for nomination into the tournament. There was no indicated limit to the number of students a school could put forth to the deciding committee, so there were a great number of names on the parchment by Thursday morning when Rigel walked into breakfast with her friends.

The popularity of the tournament didn't really explain why there would be such a large crowd gawking at the announcement board four days after students had begun signing up, though. Rigel could not see anything unusual over the heads of the students crowded around, so she turned her attention to her porridge and ignored it until Draco's curiosity overcame his decorum and he stood with a huff to go investigate.

Rigel exchanged an amused look with Pansy. Their friend couldn't abide not knowing what was going on around him. She assumed he would come back to report his findings, but instead she heard her name called sharply from across the hall. Rigel set her spoon down and turned to see Draco standing with an agitated expression in front of the message board. She slowly rose and made her way over.

"What is it?"

"Someone's—look, Rigel." Draco waved students out of the way and Rigel's stomach rippled with unease at the way they stared at her as they moved back.

She turned her eyes to the announcement board where a long piece of parchment was tacked for prospective tournament nominees. The parchment was almost full of names now, except… every single name was hers. Rigel Black had been written over and over in dozens of different handwriting. She felt her mouth press into a mirthless line. "I'm going to kill the Weasley Twins," she said calmly.

"Every time someone writes their name it turns into yours."

She turned her head to find Cedric Diggory standing with a group of other Hufflepuffs next to the board. "I didn't do this," she told him.

"I didn't figure you did," Diggory said, shrugging one shoulder. His handsome face loosed a smile that was like an arrow. "Still, it's a bit inconvenient, Black."

She was briefly taken aback that he knew her name—she hadn't really met him as Rigel, she didn't think. Then again, she supposed everyone in the school knew her name and face after the Valentine's Day fiasco, and then that floating flower prank…come to think of it, her self-designated press secretaries had probably been more effective than she gave them credit for.

"I'll see what I can do," she said, smiling back ruefully. Her eyes cut to the Gryffindor table and she heard the Hufflepuff boy suck in a breath.

"I'm suddenly glad I'm not a Gryff," he murmured.

"Only two of them are in any real danger," Rigel said. She flicked her eyes over to Draco, softening her face enough to convey gratitude. "Thanks for the heads up, Dray. I'll take care of this."

He nodded and broke off for the Slytherin table as she crossed to where Fred and George were holding court among the Gryffindor sixth years. She placed a hand on each of their shoulders and squeezed harder than strictly necessary.

"Ah—ow, Pup," Fred said, leaning into Angela Johnson to escape her grip. "Good morning to you, too."

"And such a surprise," George added, wincing as he bore her hold. "What strong fingers you have."

"The better to coax explanations out of wily redheads," she told him. The bright smile on her face stretched wide, but it didn't reach her eyes.

Fred eyed it with unease. "Caught the notice board, did you?"

"It was hard to miss," she said. "More publicity work on my behalf? You really shouldn't have."

"Well, it's too good an opportunity to pass up," George said. His tried to smile, but when her hand closed harder over his shoulder it turned into a grimace. "Godric, Rigel, you've got a grip like a grindylow."

She released them both and folded her arms across her chest instead. "I appreciate the great lengths you've both gone to on my behalf, but I'm going to ask you to change it back, now."

"No can do," Fred protested. "The world must realize the inevitability of your ascendance."

Rigel felt a headache creeping up her neck and consciously relaxed those muscles with an impatient shake. "I want no part of this tournament. It's a funny prank, but the teachers might get the wrong idea. Besides, it's starting to annoy people who actually want to be considered."

George rolled the shoulder she'd grasped gingerly. "We were going to undo it next week, anyway," he admitted. "You must admit it's a good continuation of the flower prank, though."

She conceded that much. If it had been anyone else, or even anything other than Riddle's tournament, she would probably have thought it harmless. "Some other time, maybe. This tournament has people a little on edge, don't you think?"

The twins exchanged a look. "So far the only one on edge about it is you," Fred said. His freckled face scrunched up in thought. "It's bothering you, isn't it? Granted, it's a mad idea to begin with, but there's no need to take it personally. The Cow Party is just being the Cow Party."

"I think it's a terrible idea," she said, sighing. "I'd just… rather not be associated with it if I can help it."

George frowned up at her. "Is everything okay, Rigel?"

She summoned a smile again. "It will be if you fix that sign up sheet."

Both redheads shrugged, though George still looked concerned. "Consider it done, Rigel."

"Since you asked so nicely," Fred added, waggling his eyebrows.

Rigel bowed her thanks and headed back to her breakfast. A shadow passed through her mind as a thought struck her. Her porridge was probably cold.

Draco watched Rigel make his way back toward them and slid sideways toward Millie to make room on the bench again where Rigel had been sitting. His dark-haired friend picked up his spoon and eyed his bowl in resigned disappointment. A flicker of Empathy and Draco could feel Rigel's mournful regret. Resisting the urge to roll his eyes, he took out his wand and shot a warming charm at Rigel's porridge.

Rigel looked over in surprise and beamed at him. "You're the best, Dray."

He fought the ridiculous hum of pleasure that thrummed through his veins and affected a wry expression. "Note to self: Rigel is easily pleased."

Pansy laughed from across the table. "He didn't look pleased a second ago. What happened over there, Rye?"

"Just the Weasley twins causing trouble," Rigel said. A peeved flush was creeping up Rigel's neck and Draco nearly flushed too when he caught himself admiring it.

"They switched all the names on the tournament sign up sheet for Rigel's," Draco said, distracting himself before he could do something as idiotic as scrutinize his friend's blood flow again.

Pansy shot an uneasy look at Rigel, but Millicent sounded intrigued. "Are they trying to get you nominated, Rigel?" she asked.

"Not anymore," Rigel said firmly. "I set them straight."

"You really don't want to enter?" Theo asked from Rigel's other side. "A lot of professors like you, and you've proven yourself resourceful, if nothing else. It's not the worst idea."

Draco fought a scowl. Not a bad idea? It was a brilliant idea. Rigel was perfect for this kind of competition, and Draco was not surprised Lord Riddle agreed. He was smart, talented, powerful, and he thought well on his feet. Plus, he had grit, which Draco could not say about most of their classmates. It was odd, really. Fortitude wasn't a virtue Draco had ever considered before, but his friend was tenacious in a way that most young adults their age were not. In a way that, Draco admitted, he was probably not.

"Thanks, Theo, but I don't have time for such a big commitment right now," Rigel was saying. Draco wondered just who the boy thought he was fooling. Rigel had already made it perfectly clear that he despised the very idea of the tournament, not to mention his contempt for Lord Riddle himself. Draco appreciated Rigel not repeating such dangerous opinions over breakfast, but it was a bit late to pretend he held anything but aversion to whatever the S.O.W. Party touched.

Sometimes Draco wondered what had caused Rigel's thoughts to shift so radically against the Party and Lord Riddle. Was he like others who had soured against the pureblood elite in the wake of the World Cup disaster? Was it because of what had happened to him last year? Or, a more realistic voice prodded him, had Rigel always thought this way? Perhaps he'd held these opinions as long as Draco knew him, and was only just now saying them aloud. Draco wasn't sure whether it was a good or bad thing that Rigel trusted them enough to be openly hostile toward their parents' political and social affiliations now. It certainly didn't make friendship with him more comfortable.

Than again, Draco reflected as he eyed Rigel contentedly shoveling porridge into his mouth, friendship with Rigel had never really been about comfort, had it?

Draco was drawn from his musing when Pansy asked him how the work to reinstate the Dueling Club was coming along. "It might be a lost cause," he said, frowning. "I can't find anywhere in the castle that's secure enough from prying eyes. The dungeons, the towers—they're ultimately too exposed. If Snape has the prefects on the lookout for students dueling somewhere out of the way, there's no way he won't find out eventually."

"What if we held the meetings earlier than most prefects are awake?" Pansy suggested. "We never see anyone on our way out to morning workouts."

"That's true," Draco said slowly. "How many people do you think will want to come if the time is so inconvenient?"

"Probably the same number of people who'd still participate despite knowing Snape was against it," Pansy said, her eyebrow quirking in subtle sardonic humor.

Draco grimaced. They would definitely lose members if people knew the Head of Slytherin was staunchly against the club. "I just don't understand why he's banning it," Draco muttered. "I understand taking away the class if Dawlish doesn't want to teach it separately from general Defense, but why deny us the club?"

Millie snorted. "Maybe they don't want it to seem like Hogwarts has an advantage when contestants start showing up here for the tasks. There's got to be some sort of dueling involved, right?"

Draco shrugged. Explanations wouldn't really placate him anyway. He wanted to keep his skills sharp. And he had plans for the club, Mordred curse it.

"Draco," Rigel said tentatively. Draco raised an eyebrow at his hesitant expression. Rigel seemed to steel himself before saying, "It sounds like what Snape is worried about is visibility. If you had a place no one would ever see the club meeting, he might let it go."

Draco thought back to what his godfather had threatened. He said if he heard whisper of the club operating, Draco would be held accountable. "I suppose if he doesn't hear about it, he won't really go seeking it out. Still, we're back where we started with no place to practice out of public view."

"I might know a place," Rigel said quietly. Draco whipped his head around so fast he nearly cricked his neck.

"You know a place," he repeated, wondering if he was hearing things. "Where?"

"It'd be easier to show you later," Rigel said. He spoke at such a low volume, Pansy had to lean forward across her food to hear. Draco wasn't getting anything from his Empathy at the moment, but he suspected his friend was uneasy. "It's not a place people know about."

Draco smiled in disbelief. "Rigel, that's—" he faltered as a thought hit him. "It's not…the Chamber of Secrets, is it?" Fascination warred with fear at the thought of trespassing through that place.

Rigel snorted. "Of course not. It was sealed off by the Headmaster after second year."

"Oh. Then I can't wait to see this place," Draco said. He turned back to his breakfast after adding, "You can show us before lunch."

He assumed Rigel knew of some out of the way abandoned classroom. Merlin knew Rigel disappeared often enough without explanation. He couldn't always be in his lab. Well, Draco amended, if anyone could spend that amount of time in a lab it would be Rigel, but it also made sense that he had somewhere else to go.

When Rigel dragged them all the way up to the highest floors of the castle, Draco had to wonder if the reason his friend was so freakishly fit wasn't because he traversed all those stairs so often. When the boy stopped in front of a tapestry of Barnabas the Barmy, Draco just wondered if Rigel had finally cracked under all the academic pressure he put on himself.

"This corridor is out of the way," Pansy allowed, "but I don't think it's quite big enough, Rigel."

Their friend only smiled slightly. "I was confused at first, too. Binny showed me this place." Rigel walked along the wall facing the awful tapestry with an expression of pure concentration on his face. Just as Draco and Pansy made to follow him, Rigel turned around and paced back toward them, then paced away again without explanation.

Then a door appeared in the wall, and Draco had to focus on keeping his eyes inside of his skull. "Tell me you didn't just open a portal inside Hogwarts' wards," he said faintly. He honestly would put nothing past the young wizard in front of him.

Rigel let out a short laugh. "Course not. This is called the Come and Go room, Binny says. It appears when you think of something you need and pace by this wall three times. I think it's been here since the castle was built."

He opened the door and gestured for them to go ahead of him. Reminding himself that Rigel would not let Draco walk into an abyss, and feeling oddly like he had the first night he'd followed Rigel through a secret passageway to the Owlrey, he stepped through and into a room that was almost as large as the Great Hall. The walls and floors were bare, but a line of dummies like those that populated the Defense classroom waited along one side of the room.

"This is… perfect," Draco breathed.

Pansy came to stand beside him and looked equally impressed. "How long have you known about this, Rigel?" she asked.

"A while," Rigel said vaguely. "I used it last year, when I needed somewhere to study that was quiet."

Draco understood what Rigel couldn't say without breaching his contract with the Department of Mysteries. This was one of the places Rigel would come when he was folding time and multiple instances of him existed in other places.

"It's a bit bare to be comfortable," Draco commented.

Rigel closed his eyes for a moment, and not a breath later there were large cushions piled on the floor between them. Draco's breath caught. "It's a magic room?"

"This is Hogwarts," Rigel said, deliberately misunderstanding him.

"Can the room provide anything you ask for?" Pansy asked. Her face shone with undisguised excitement. "Can I try?"

"Go ahead," Rigel said, smiling widely. "You just have to think it three times, and as long as the one who created the room didn't require it to be unchangeable, it should work."

Pansy laughed in delight as a series of lifting weights materialized on the ground before her. "This is brilliant, Rigel. It's perfect for the club, don't you think, Drake?"

Draco had to nod. It was perfect. And Rigel had given it to them, even though he could have kept it to himself forever, and no one would ever have known. "Thank you, Rigel."

Rigel ducked his head embarrassedly. "I'm sorry I didn't show it to you sooner. I should have."

"This more than makes up for your suspiciously secretive nature," Draco said, grinning. He expected Rigel to laugh, or maybe to smile sheepishly again, but instead his friend's face blanked. Draco caught the tail end of an emotion before Rigel smoothed out his feelings with Occlumency, too. Rigel was ashamed, and underlying the shame, unmistakably afraid. Draco stared at him, and Rigel stared back, expressionless. "I mean it, Rigel. This is amazing," Draco said. He put all the earnestness he could summon into his face and voice. It barely made a dent in Rigel's impassive façade.

"That's good," Rigel said evenly. "In all the time I've made use of it, I've never seen anyone else here, so there should be little chance of anyone getting wind of your club meetings. Still, it might be a good idea to swear anyone who still wants to attend to secrecy, at least until the school recognizes the club as legitimate again."

"We'll do that," Draco agreed. He didn't know what was upsetting Rigel, since he'd already tried to make it clear he wasn't annoyed with Rigel for keeping the room to himself. "I'll spread the word quietly, among last year's members, that we have a plan to reinstate the Dueling Association unofficially. If they want to participate, they'll have to swear not to reveal the meeting location before we show them."

"And if that puts people off, so be it," Pansy added. "After all, we don't want members who aren't completely committed to learning Dueling."

That decided, they left the room and Draco watched with silent awe as the door was swallowed up into the wall once more. Hogwarts really was incredible sometimes.

On Friday morning, Madam Pomfrey was pulled away from their Healing lesson to the Quidditch pitch after two firsties apparently collided in mid-air and injured themselves too badly to be moved to the Hospital Wing. Rigel and Cho offered to help, but Madam Pomfrey waved them off as she bustled out the room. Apparently emergencies were not a controlled enough environment to supervise two students.

"How's the year so far?" Rigel asked Cho. The girl looked a little tired, but nowhere near as stressed as some of the other fifth years she'd seen haunting the Library.

"Just fine, thanks," Cho said, tucking a long strand of hair behind her ear and peering over at Rigel in a way that made her look like a nervous kitten. "I asked one of the older Ravens for his fifth year syllabus before term ended last year. I've been reading ahead all summer, so the coursework isn't as overwhelming for me."

"That's very sensible," Rigel said, impressed. Reading ahead was undervalued, she thought. Her classes were always easier when she'd self-studied the material first.

"It's bookish," Cho said, huffing under her breath. "My mother despairs of me, holed up in the house all summer. I don't like the outdoors, though."

"I spend a lot of time indoors, too, over breaks," Rigel told her. "Brewing, mostly, but I get a fair amount of reading done, too."

"You should have been a Ravenclaw," Cho suggested. As soon as the words were out of her mouth she dropped her gaze, seeming regretful. "I mean, not that Slytherin isn't…" She trailed off, apparently unable to think of an appropriate compliment.

"Maybe in another life," Rigel said gently, smiling to show she was not offended. "You must be top of your year, being so prepared, right?"

Cho looked uncomfortable. "No, actually. My practical grades in some subjects aren't as high as I'd like."

Rigel nodded in understanding. "I know what you mean. Defense this year is especially tricky, since almost all of the points are practical."

Cho nodded. "Yes, exactly. My Defense grade has never been so poor."

She had a thought and tilted her head at Cho, considering. "If I told you there was a… study group, of sorts, for Defense, would you be interested?"

"A fourth-year study group?" She looked a little skeptical.

"It's open to all years," Rigel said. "It was more like a club, last year, but this year it hasn't been officially recognized by the school."

Cho blinked at her, a sharp light coming into her eyes. No one looking at the girl now could imagine she wasn't fiercely intelligent. "You mean the Dueling Club your friend Malfoy started last year? Isn't it a bit violent? I've seen it on the lawn. You all just pair off and shoot spells at one another, right? No wonder the administration disbanded it."

Rigel shrugged. "We do duel, since that's sort of the point of the club, but Draco also goes over other aspects of Defense. Basic spell combinations, agility drills, that sort of thing. With Auror Dawlish teaching the way he does, reflexes definitely come in handy. I don't mean to pressure you, or anything. If you're interested though, it might be helpful for your Defense grade."

The older girl looked torn. "You said… it's not an official club this year, right? Will we get into trouble for continuing it?"

"Not if nobody finds out," Rigel said, smiling innocently.

Cho's eyes narrowed. "This is why you are in Slytherin." At Rigel's unrepentant look, Cho sighed. "I do need to do something to improve," she said quietly. "Is it really okay for you to invite me?"

Rigel nodded. "Why not? It'd be good to have another Healer there, in any case. I can't always make every meeting with my potions schedule, and having someone to patch up minor injuries would go a long way to keep the club unnoticed. So what do you say? You want to give it a go?"

Cho smiled tentatively. "Okay. Where do I sign up?"

"Draco will handle that. You'll have to sign an agreement not to disclose the location of the club meetings before you're allowed to participate, but that's the only formality." Rigel noticed Cho didn't seem thrilled at the idea of signing such a thing, but clearly her grades meant more to her than the risk.

"All right," Cho said, sighing. "I can hear my mother now. 'Xiao Zhou! You dare to defy school regulations?' We'd better not get caught."

"She-ow Jo?" Rigel fumbled over the foreign words. "Is that what she calls you?"

Cho let out another small giggle-huff. "Yes. Cho isn't really my name, you know. It's Zhou. Cho is just easier for people here to say. Xiao Zhou means something like 'little Zhou.' It's a pet name, of sorts."

"Jou? Xou? Am I saying it right?" Rigel was trying to mimic what Cho—Zhou did with the 'Zh' sound, but she had a feeling it was very wrong.

"Pretty close," the girl said, looking pleased. "You don't have to call me that, though. It will only confuse people."

"I'll just use it in our lessons," Rigel said, shrugging. "No sense using 'Cho' now that I know that isn't you name."

"I'm used to it," Zhou said politely.

"Still, it's not the same, is it?" Rigel knew it wasn't. No matter how long she went by Rigel, it still wasn't really her.

Zhou smiled. "I suppose… it's not. Thank you, Rigel."

"Sure." They talked of other things, and before long Madam Pomfrey had returned. Rigel thought about the girl on her way to her lesson with Dumbledore, though, and considered that even the most obvious things about a person could be misleading. She ought to appreciate this fact about others, since she spent so long exploiting it in herself.

When another lesson with Snape passed without Rigel getting up the courage to ask whether he knew about the resonance she shared with Riddle, Rigel knew she needed to do something else about it. She'd combed through the Library for any information about magic transference and resulting connections. In addition to the anecdote Dumbledore had shared with her, there were a number of processes and rituals that purported to transfer a piece or all of one's magic to another being or object.

Most of them were Dark or at least censored, but Rigel's invisibility cloak meant that she didn't need to explain to a teacher why she wanted to research such topics. There were rituals to transfer family magic to adopted children, rituals to take a wizard's magic away forever, and even rituals to strengthen the magic of one wizard by siphoning it from another. The last were especially gruesome, and Rigel thought the reported results seemed unpredictable at best. It could not possibly be worth doubling raw magical power if the ritual also caused the two bodies of magic to clash violently, and sometimes fatally, within a wizard's core.

It did give her an idea for how to address the resonance, though. If absorbing new magic at sufficient quantities could cause a kind of civil war inside a wizard, then even a tiny amount should have noticeable effects. She just hadn't been paying close enough attention.

She asked her friends not to disturb her for the afternoon and sunk into meditation while comfortably nestled into her four-poster bed. The icy wind that met her at the edge of the mists momentarily disoriented her, but she remembered the sandstorm Dom had unleashed in the other layer of her mind and supposed he'd probably done something similar now that the mountainscape was the primary layer again.

She willed herself into the center of her mind and the world folded around her until she stood in the space room. A hundred shadows danced as the globes of light spun cheerfully around the large sun in the middle. She closed her mind for only a moment to savor the warmth, then turned and left the secure space, calling, "Dom?"

The construct materialized beside her in the underground corridor with a welcoming smile. "You're here," he said happily. "I wondered when you would visit again."

With a snap of his fingers they were transported to the cozy lab where she stored her decoy memories and aspects. The fire crackled merrily in the heath, but that was about all that Dom had left untouched. Where there had been bare rock exposed at the edge of the mountain cave there were walls, now, and a lovely oak beam ceiling. The furniture looked more like something carved by a master carpenter than the simple chairs she'd conjured originally. The rug that hid the trapdoor was gone. In its place, seamless wood flooring gleamed in the firelight. She couldn't tell where the trapdoor was at all, if it even still existed. Dom didn't move through the mental sphere the same way she intuitively tried to do. Perhaps he found a physical portal to be insecure. Probably he just thought it tawdry.

The carving of Sekhmet adorned the mantle in a place of honor. She had to smile at it. It seemed Dom had elected not to leave everything behind when he changed the layers of her mind.

"Tea, Harriet?"

She flinched involuntarily. "Rigel, in this layer," she told him. "Please."

Dom frowned at her, his even features perturbed. "What layer you project doesn't change who you are, you know."

"I know that," she said, a bit defensive. "If someone comes to this layer, though, you have to refer to me at Rigel, because that it what they will be expecting."

"You want me to have civil conversations with intruders?" Dom was openly amused. "You are a strange human."

"You knew that already," she said, sighing. She sat in the ornately carved chair he indicated and let him pour her a cup of tea. She had no idea you could create food in a mindscape. When she sipped at the delicate china cup she frowned. There was a certain emptiness to the beverage. It was like inhaling a very strong scent of tea. She had the vague impression that she was drinking it, but it didn't feel entirely real. Still, the taste was good.

"Where did you learn to make tea?" she asked.

"Peter," he said simply. He politely ignored the shudder that rippled through her at the unexpected sound of his name. "I learned much while we were bonded. What brings you here today, Rigel?"

Grateful for the change of topic, she leaned forward and set her teacup aside. "I have a problem."

"You have many problems."

"I have a new problem," she clarified, narrowing her eyes at his cheek. "I think someone has corrupted my magic."

"Impossible," Dom said fiercely. "I would have noticed."

"I think it happened before you… bonded with me," she said. "You wouldn't have known any different."

"Why did you not say something before?" Dom asked, tilting his head curiously. "Such a thing is certainly cause for concern, if it is true."

"I didn't know until recently," she admitted. "I touched a wizard's hand and my magic resonated; it was exactly the feeling that I had when you—when I—"

"Yes, last Spring," Dom said, waving his hand. "Are you referring to an incident about a month ago or so? I did feel that. The entire mindscape shook like an earth tremor. It stopped quickly, though, so I assumed you had foolishly put yourself in danger again and gotten your fool head knocked into something unforgiving."

She scowled. "I didn't do anything. I just shook his hand and there was resonance. There's no explanation for that except my magic having some part of his mixed up in it somehow."

Dom's face closed as he thought. "I do not think it is possible for one to transfer magic through a handshake alone. Magical transfer usually requires that both parties' magics be loosed into the open. Otherwise they cannot mingle."

She blinked in surprise. None of her research had told her that. Loose magic? Did the wild explosion of her magic following the removal of her suppressor count? "There was a time my magic was, I suppose, loose around him. His wasn't, though."

"Are you certain?" Dom asked keenly. "Think. Were you so focused on this wizard at the time of the incident that you can be sure he didn't loose his in order to affect yours?"

"No," she breathed. "I was only focused on my own magic. Maybe I didn't notice…"

"If he intended to meld your magics inconspicuously, he wouldn't have needed to release all his magic into the air, only a small part." Dom peered at her intently. "How strong was the resonance?"

"Strong enough to turn my stomach," she said, lip curling in disgust.

"Yet the foreign magic itself is not a strong enough presence to cause you daily issue," Dom mused. "If it were a significant amount your magic would have reacted stronger at the initial injection. Is this wizard your enemy?"

"It's Riddle," she muttered, "So yes."

Dom nodded slowly. "Then something must be done. You have come here for my help, yes?"

She nodded. "I don't have the time it would take to examine every drop of my magic in depth. You could, though. Right?"

"You wish me to sift through your magic and attempt to… filter out any particles that do not belong?" Dom asked. His smile was just a little eager. "I would need access to the whole of it, of course."

"I know," she said, trying not to let her unease show. "I… trust you, now, to work in our combined best interest. This is important. If Riddle can simply touch me and identify me as Rigel Black, then I can never meet him as Harry Potter. And he's not exactly the easiest person to avoid. This resonance could undo everything, understand?"

"Of course," Dom said soothingly. "Just leave it to me."

"Thank you," she breathed, more than relieved. It felt surprisingly reassuring to have this boy-construct in her corner. If Dom could handle the search for Riddle's magic amidst her own, she could handle the effort to discover what exactly Riddle's intentions were in instigating it.

"If you want to thank me, tell your friend to stop skimming our emotions," Dom said, sniffing. "It's very annoying."

She chuckled. "It's his gift, so I can't very well tell him how to use it. Still, I'll try to do better with my emotional Occlumency. You're doing great with warning me when it happens."

"It shouldn't be necessary," Dom complained. "You aren't even of age. It says something sad about your society that so many people are interested in the inner workings of a minor's mind. When I first transferred my consciousness to your mind, I thought you were a paranoid little girl. Now, I think your fears are exactly as acute as they need to be."

"Oh." She wasn't sure how to take that at all. "Thanks?"

Dom snorted—actually snorted at her, with smiling lips and quirked eyebrows and the expression was so human it ached in her chest. "Go on, Girl. I know you can't spend all day here."

"I haven't finished my tea," she said, halfheartedly.

"Next time you come, it will be more realistic," Dom said, still smiling at her. "It isn't quite right yet."

"It's close," she offered.

"Close is never close enough. Go."

She went. Her back was stiff and her right foot had fallen asleep when she returned to full consciousness, but despite that she felt much better than she had before. She didn't know if her faith in Dom would pay off or backfire horribly, but she was more comfortable having someone working on the resonance problem with her. It didn't feel quite so overwhelming anymore. Now all that remained was to straighten her backbone and actually ask Snape if he knew anything about it.

Two weeks after the tournament's announcement Rigel saw Riddle again. It was early on Saturday morning and she, Draco, and Pansy were returning to the castle after their jog around the lake when they crossed paths with a group of witches and wizards apparently surveying the Hogwarts grounds.

By silent agreement, they made to skirt around the group, but the recognizable sound of Lucius Malfoy's voice called, "Draco?" in a tone so incredulous it would have been funny under other circumstances.

Draco grimaced and Pansy shot him a mortified look. It was clear the girl had never imagined being caught sweaty and red-faced in front of a prominent member of her parents' social circle. The three of them stopped their fast walk and turned to face Mr. Malfoy, who was striding toward them across the grass with a frown on his pale features.

"Good morning, Father," Draco said airily. "You didn't mention you'd be dropping by today."

Lucius gave his son an unimpressed look. "What are you doing out here, dressed in… rags?"

"Exercising," Draco said.

"Without your Quidditch team?" He didn't seem to believe his son at all. "In the company of Miss Parkinson, no less?" Rigel was offended on Pansy's behalf that Mr. Malfoy found her to be the least likely candidate to participate in exercise of her own volition.

Pansy merely flushed. "We have taken up jogging some mornings to keep in shape, Lord Malfoy. Normally no one is about at this hour. Please forgive my dishabille."

"Jogging." His silver eyes surveyed the three of them slowly, taking in the dirty trainers, baggy clothing, and sweaty faces. His nostrils flared and his nose twitched slightly in distaste. Clearly their collective smell was less than appealing.

"It's helps with dueling if we have good endurance," Draco told his father. "We've all seen notable improvement since we started morning exercises."

"I was under the impression that your Dueling Club had been disbanded," Lucius said silkily.

"Suffice to say that Uncle Snape will not hear of its reformation," Draco said, smirking slightly. To Rigel's surprise, that was what finally caused Mr. Malfoy to relax his stern expression and smirk back at his son.

"Careful, Draco," he said. His voice was more amused than admonishing, however.

"Always, Father," Draco assured him.

"Lucius."

Mr. Malfoy turned his head back toward the group of witches and wizards, who had all paused while he spoke with his son. In the center of the group, wearing an expression of expectant impatience, stood Riddle. Mr. Malfoy inclined his head deferentially before turning back to dismiss them. "Don't be late to breakfast," he said.

"Good seeing you, Father," Draco said.

"Have a good day, Lord Malfoy," Pansy murmured.

Rigel said nothing, merely smiling briefly when Malfoy flicked his eyes once in her direction before turning around and treading back toward the others. Draco and Pansy turned toward the castle but Rigel kept watching Riddle's group for a moment longer. "They're heading for the forest," she said quietly.

Pansy tugged on her arm to draw her toward the castle. "Don't let them see you've noticed. Do you think one of the tasks will be in the forest?"

"It's a good place to hide things," Draco said. "Maybe they're going to store materials there away from snooping eyes."

"They shouldn't disrupt the denizens of the forest with their spectacle," Rigel muttered.

"I'm sure they will take that into account," Pansy said. She didn't sound sure, though.

Seeing Riddle on school grounds, Rigel somehow expected the summons that came for her later that day in the common room. The small Rowle Heiress handed her a note, ostensibly from Snape, requesting her presence in lab three as soon as she was able. Snape rarely sent notes through other students, and he never scheduled a lesson without a specific time. Resigned to whatever awaited her, Rigel rose from the sofa and shook her head when Draco and Pansy shot her questioning glance.

"I'll be back later," she said dully. "Professor Snape wants to see me."

Draco and Pansy were not fools. "Just Snape?" Pansy asked, eyes bright with concern.

"I guess I'll find out." She shrugged.

"Be careful," Draco said, frowning over his Transfiguration text at her.

"Always, Father," she teased, cracking a small smile.

He made to toss the book at her, but she left before he could commit to the move.

The brief amusement left her as she traversed the dungeons with lead steadily filling her heart. She had taken Pansy's earlier advice and written to her parents, Sirius, and Remus, warning them that someone might attempt to put political or social pressure on them in the coming days. The returning owls had carried replies running from concerned to upset, and full of questions. She and Archie had done their best to keep details vague while impressing on their family the seriousness of the situation. At the moment, the adults were under the impression that Archie was being pressured in general to compete in the Triwizard Tournament and was worried the pressure may spill over onto them in some way.

Sirius had vehemently urged his son not to do it. He didn't want Archie in any more harm's way. James pressed for details as to who exactly was trying to influence him. Remus advised caution and offered his expertise and help in the event that Archie was pressed into competing. Lily just wrote Archie to be strong, collected, and stand up for himself.

Rigel was gratified at their support, but she knew they didn't really grasp the magnitude of the problem. Riddle was not one to be dissuaded by a firm, repeated, 'no, thank you.'

She entered lab three with all the joy of someone walking to their own execution. Snape was there, but—as expected—he was not alone. "Mr. Riddle," she said, voice emotionless. "What a surprise."

"So jaded for one so young, Rigel," Riddle said. The way he stressed her name made her twitch slightly. Just what was he trying to prove?

"Professor." She acknowledged the man standing with his arms crossed to one side of the room. "I suppose we aren't brewing today."

"I see you neglected to bring your protective equipment in any case," Snape said flatly. "Lord Riddle is here to speak to you."

"To threaten me, you mean," she said. If either man was surprised by her bluntness, they didn't show it.

"Threats may not be necessary," Riddle told her. He opened his arms wide in a gesture that welcomed her to agree with him. "You've had two weeks to think it over. Tell me you've reconsidered your reticence and will agree to participate in the tournament. Tell me that, and you can get on to your lesson with Severus."

"I'm afraid that's not the case," she said firmly. "If you nominate me, I still intend to decline."

"Then this discussion will be far less pleasant than I'd hoped," Riddle said. His insincerity was unparalleled. She took a moment to study the politician as she waited for him to get to the point. He looked much the same as he had when she first saw him. Suave, confident, dismissive of everything around him, and utterly sure in his ability to manipulate the world to his favor. Even his looks hadn't really changed in the last few years. Not his hairstyle nor his habit of dressing in robes that were cut to make him appear grander than he was.

She wondered if he'd changed at all on the inside, but quickly dismissed the notion. What a naïve child she'd been before, thinking that Riddle might listen to someone like her. Might change his ways at the admonitions of a twelve-year-old. Riddle didn't respect anyone enough to take their words to heart. He understood only power, so she would have to summon every ounce of it inside her to defy him.

The older man seemed to be studying her even as she watched him, but what he saw she couldn't guess, nor did she care to. After a drawn-out silence, Riddle finally said, "You will participate as a pureblood candidate in the Triwizard Tournament. That is not in question. The only question is what it will take for you to capitulate. I know you consider yourself above manipulation, but it simply isn't true. There are things you want. I can help you achieve them. You need only ask."

"I prefer to secure my own victories," she said, slightly confused. Was he trying to soften her up?

"You think things are more satisfying when you earn them?" Riddle chuckled darkly. "That is a Hufflepuffian fallacy. Getting what you want can be simple. You seek a Potions Mastery, do you not? I can secure that for you."

"Mastery is decided by a closed examination at the Guild upon completion of an Apprenticeship. You have no influence over the Guild besides Professor Snape, and he is already Apprenticing me," she said, letting her face display her skepticism openly.

"Examinations can be manipulated," Riddle said idly.

She had to wrinkle her nose in disgust. "I'd rather not have a Mastery than earn it duplicitously."

"And after you achieve this dream of yours?" Riddle pressed. "You'll need capital if you mean to start your own distribution chain. Severus tells me Miss Potter has a talent for inventing. Perhaps you'd like to go into business with her after graduating?"

"If money interested me, I would have wanted to compete in the tournament for the prizes alone." She wondered whether he honestly expected her to be tempted by such common bribes. Then again, she reflected reluctantly, most people probably were. She was fortunate to be born with a modicum of talent and actual work ethic, not to mention her family's considerable fortune. She didn't need to cheat and she certainly didn't need money. She really ought to be grateful to Fate that those things didn't entice her in the slightest.

Riddle inclined his head, not seeming at all surprised. He looked, she thought oddly, like someone running through a standard checklist of interpersonal manipulation. She almost had to laugh at the thought. Perhaps he was simply moving down a mental list: first, attempt to bribe with favors, then with money. What was next?

"Very well," Riddle said, unconcerned. "If self-interest doesn't motivate you, there are other means of inspiring your cooperation." She waited, face blank, though she suspected her eyes were burning. "Your father is an interesting man," Riddle added thoughtfully. "So talented, by all accounts, and yet he languishes."

"He is content," Rigel said warily.

"Would you be content, were he to languish in prison instead?" Riddle's voice was light, as though he'd inquired as to her tea preference.

Rigel felt her breath hitch slightly. "You're threatening to have my father imprisoned? On what grounds? Or were you just going to make something up?"

Social and political pressure she expected, economic, too, but this? Azkaban was no idle threat. Imprisonable offenses weren't exactly numerous. They were restricted to the crimes deemed most heinous by their society. Murder. Torture. Rape. Blood Identity Theft. That constituted the broad majority of inmates. Could Riddle really arrange for Sirius to be charged with something like that?

"Not I," Riddle said, his mocking tone grating to Rigel's ears. "I am a respected politician, Rigel. I would never threaten anyone. It would be a pity if the Ministry were to be informed of your father's… more animalistic tendencies, don't you think?"

"His—" Her mind connected the dots after a confused beat. When she realized what he was driving at, she scoffed. "You mean to accuse him of being an unregistered animagi? Where did you get the idea that would work?"

"Peter was so very helpful before his unfortunate defection. So full of interesting information about his old friends," Riddle informed her. Rigel grit her teeth against the urge to flinch at that man's name. She would not. Not in front of Riddle.

"Pettigrew was an idiot," she spat. It was the only way she could utter his name without stuttering. "Or did he neglect to inform you that Sirius was also briefly a member of the Auror Corps?" Riddle's face twisted in suspicion. She could tell he still didn't get it. She shook her head. Clearly he didn't have any close supporters in the Auror ranks. "To join the Aurors you have to submit to a full background investigation and questioning under Veritaserum. The DMLE already knows that Sirius and James are animagi. Their forms are not a matter of public record because they are classified as special skills more useful to the Ministry if not made common knowledge."

At least, she thought they were. Neither her father nor Sirius had ever admitted as much, but Rigel had pieced together enough of her father's stories to know that his animagi form had come in handy on more than one mission. When she was very young, before she'd resigned herself to underwhelming her father's expectations, she had looked into the requirements for the Auror Corps. Rigel wasn't lying about the rigorous investigations cadets underwent. It was a somewhat shaky deduction, but it solidified as Riddle's scowl twisted into a sneer. She smirked slowly back at him. "The rat wouldn't know that, since he didn't have the guts to join the program with his friends. Go ahead and tell the DMLE about my father's special ability. I'm sure they'd be very interested to know how you came by classified information. Perhaps the fact that you had knowledge of another animagus who actually was unregistered would be interesting to them as well."

"Watch your cheek, boy," Riddle snarled. His open irritation made her suspect that he likely had known that Sirius wasn't as unregistered as it might seem. He'd tried to bluff his way into leverage and was annoyed, but not terribly surprised, that it hadn't worked.

"I think we're beyond pleasantries at this point, Riddle," she said. "Are you going to curse me? Maybe tamper with my magic again?" The surprise in his eyes gave her some small satisfaction. "Did you think I wouldn't notice?" she brazened. A quick look at Snape saw surprise in his eyes, too—not surprise that Riddle had done it, however. He was looking surprised at her, not Riddle. So he had known what Riddle did to her magic. He just hadn't expected her to figure it out. She took a deep breath past the pain and refocused on Riddle. She could ponder Snape's part in that later. "Pretty obvious when your touch makes my skin crawl with resonance."

Riddle looked at her with a kind of pleased fascination. He seemed almost glad she'd noticed. "You were correct, Severus; he continually surprises."

"Why did you infect me with your magic?" she asked. Finally saying it out loud was a relief, but it also made her feel vulnerable, like sharing a secret with someone she didn't trust.

"My reasons are my own," he said, smiling infuriatingly.

"It's my magic," she said, outraged that he wouldn't even deign to explain himself.

"Then you should take better care of it," Riddle said, lip curling.

"I should report you for tampering with another wizard's magic," she said softly.

"You'd have trouble proving that, Rigel," Snape said quietly.

She couldn't look at him. Instead she averted her eyes to the ground. "Whatever you meant it to do, it won't work," she told Riddle.

"We shall see." The bastard chuckled again. "We've deviated from the matter at hand, however. You don't seem concerned for your father's secrets. Fine. What about your cousin Harriet's?

Rigel looked up into his pitiless gaze. "What about them?"

"So you admit she has secrets." He looked amused again.

"Everyone has secrets. I doubt you've found Harry's." In fact, she was sure of it. If he knew anything about the ruse, he would have opened with that, and they would be having a very different conversation.

"She's an intriguing one," Riddle said slowly. "The Heiress of a prominent House, yet she gallivants about her American school in boy's clothing. I understand not even her closest friends there are aware that she is in fact a girl."

"She's a teenager," Rigel said dismissively. She didn't like the idea that Riddle had informants watching Archie at school. It was bad enough when Leo did it. "Harry can experiment if she wants. Cross-dressing isn't illegal."

"It is eccentric, though, isn't it? Strange enough to be considered unhealthy, even. If a psychologist were to look into her mental stability, she might have trouble attaining a Healing license later on." Riddle's eyes glittered at her as he waited for Rigel to react. She honestly didn't know what to say. The idea that cross-dressing could be considered in some way dangerous, or an indication of an unhealthy psyche, was a bit of a stretch, in her opinion.

"I don't think Harry will have trouble proving her mental capacity." Not to mention she had no intention of becoming a Healer in any case.

"Even if she gains a certificate, what hospital would hire her with that kind of doubt and scandal hanging about her head?" Riddle asked rhetorically. "I know all about the correspondence course she's been maintaining—Miss Potter is planning to come back to Britain and make a life here, isn't she? Unfortunately for her, Britain is my purview. Not a hospital or clinic in the entire country would risk endangering their S.O.W. Party donations. A word here, a disapproving insinuation there, and Miss Potter has no future in Magical Britain."

"That would be a shame," Rigel said, unable to suppress the amusement that coursed through her at this tactic. Clearly Riddle didn't know about Maywell, or about Harry's close connection to the Hurst family.

"This can happen in the potions community, as well, Rigel," Riddle warned, nostrils flaring in annoyance at her lack of concern. "I have more influence than you seem to think with the Guilds of London. It is our Party that has tirelessly lobbied for the loosening of sanctions on Dark classified ingredients and materials. If you do not consent to participating in this tournament, her reputation in the academic community will be obliterated. My agents will spread doubt as to her experimental methods, her mental acuity, her penchant for rubbing more than elbows with those in positions of authority to get ahead—"

"That's a lie!" she snapped, furious at his vile insinuation.

"It won't matter," Riddle said softly. He stepped closer, looming over her and lowering his voice in the most menacing murmur she'd ever heard. "People will believe anything, if it comes from a source they trust. A great many people trust me."

Rigel was furious. That he would stoop to such base, filthy lies about her—she exhaled sharply, though she wished she could slap the man. She wouldn't give him the satisfaction. "Go ahead then," she growled, letting her eyes flash. "Tell everyone you know that Harriet Potter is a no-talent slut. I'm still not going to be your show pony."

Riddle narrowed his eyes. "Do not attempt to bluff with me, boy. I know you care for her."

Rigel stared at his superior expression. She wanted to scream. She wanted to cry. Instead, she laughed. Slowly, sadly, she laughed until she could speak through her anger. "No, you don't know. You really don't. You don't understand our relationship at all. It's so much more than whatever self-righteous, martyring, Gryffindor connection you're imagining. I'm not falling on a sword for Harry. And she wouldn't for me. If she were in this room right now she'd tell me to do the selfish thing and sacrifice her, because that's how much she cares for me. And I would expect the same from her. Do whatever you want to us. We won't be leveraged against one another." Riddle was gazing at her in frustrated incomprehension, and she had to laugh lowly one last time. "I know you don't understand. You can't imagine a bond so strong that two people would be willing to do anything for one another. Suffice to say, all your threats are meaningless. Harry would never allow herself to be used against me. She'd die first."

Even Snape looked unnerved at her pronouncement. Was it really so unfathomable? Sure, she had the advantage of actually being Harry Potter, so the idea of Riddle trying to use her against herself was simply ridiculous, but even if she wasn't, even if it really was Archie's future in jeopardy, she didn't doubt her words. Archie would kill her if he found out she'd let someone use a threat against him to compel her into doing something she didn't want to do. And she felt the same. Riddle and Snape just looked at her like she'd told them the First Law of Transfigurations didn't always apply.

"You know a lot of things, Riddle, but you don't know anything about real friendship and love. It doesn't make us vulnerable. It makes us strong. If you have nothing else to threaten me with today, I'd like to leave now." She was exhausted, and tired of talking. She knew by the livid heat in Riddle's eyes that he had prepared nothing else for leverage. He'd underestimated her, likely because she was young and relatively isolated at Hogwarts from her support network. He thought she would do anything to protect her family, because that's what he thought sanctimonious people did. Rigel had set him straight on that account, but it didn't fill her with anything but a dull dread. She'd won a reprieve, a few more days of freedom, perhaps, until Riddle came up with a different plan. There were still two weeks until the tournament participants would be announced. That was plenty of time for Riddle to produce a threat she'd have to take seriously.

"Go, Rigel," Snape said, crossing to the door and opening it. Riddle didn't move from where he was attempting to burn a hole through the stone wall with his glare. Rigel walked out with a grimace. She'd never realized how utterly childish Riddle could be when he didn't get what he wanted. How could a man his age be so unused to things not going his way?

As she strode past Snape in the doorway, she met his unfathomable stare with blank eyes. She wasn't ready to forgive him for not warning her about the resonance, for all that she'd long suspected he knew.

She turned away and began walking toward the common room. The walk became a jog, which bled into a run, and she didn't stop even when she missed the turn to the common room entrance. She was gasping for breath as her feet pounded on the hard floor, but she needed to vent the pent up rage and frustration inside her and she knew if she let herself take out her bad mood on her friends she'd regret it. She ran until she didn't recognize the dungeons around her anymore and she stopped, hands on her knees, to suck in air desperately.

She was much too out of breath for such a short sprint. The shortness of breath didn't go away even as she sank to her knees. Too late, she realized she was in a small, damp corridor that smelled of dust and dank. She'd hit a dead end, and the nearest torch bracket was around the corner. There was barely enough light to see the walls around her, and her breathing would not even out no matter how she tried.

Dizziness overwhelmed her and she heaved, spilling the meager contents of her stomach involuntarily before her. Disgusted with herself, she wiped her mouth and scooted backwards away from the mess, fumbling to take out her wand and vanish the evidence of her panic. She conjured a light while she was at it and the steady white glow calmed her enough to stumble her way back to the main corridor. She took out the Marauder's Map, but found she didn't have the energy just yet to navigate back. She just wanted to sit and breathe for a few minutes. Regain her equilibrium. Her friends would be worried enough without her showing up pale and shaking after what they already suspected had been a meeting with Riddle.

She watched the dots on the Map move around slowly, idly. No one had anywhere pressing to be on a Saturday afternoon. She saw Riddle's dot pacing back and forth in lab three, Snape's motionless dot no doubt bearing the brunt of his displeasure. Good, she thought mulishly. I hope they're both as frustrated as I am.

Her eyes were drawn to the Slytherin common room, where the dots labeled 'Draco Malfoy' and 'Pandora Parkinson' were close together, still on the couch where she'd left them. They probably wouldn't go anywhere until she returned, she knew. They would wait for her, and worry.

Sighing, she straightened and began the walk back to the common room's hidden entrance. She had no time to feel sorry for herself. She should be happy, or at least satisfied. She'd managed to hold Riddle at bay a bit longer. That was enough, for now.

Severus didn't see Rigel Black until Tuesday morning, and even then the boy avoided his gaze, keeping his head down and his back turned as he mechanically shoveled porridge into his mouth. He didn't eat like a boy who'd skipped two days of meals, so he deduced Rigel had taken food from the kitchens. Severus needed to have another serious talk with his erstwhile student about taking one's life into one's hands by baiting a dangerous Dark wizard, among other things, but he knew it was too soon for reasoned words. He hadn't missed the betrayed expression on Rigel's face when Lord Riddle's tampering of his magic had come up. The fact that Severus had been forced to stand there and let his student be bullied in front of him likely hadn't helped soften that perceived betrayal, either.

He didn't have a chance to waylay the boy before he'd scurried off to class, but he would see to it that Rigel attended his extra training lessons that afternoon. Severus had given Rigel a pass Monday afternoon, but he could not afford to again. The boy was going to be finagled into competing, one way or another. Severus would not let Rigel die in this grandstanding farce.

The day passed slowly, as it generally did when the students were distracted and excitable. The tournament was not doing the discipline in his class any favors. His last period was a double, with Rigel's conspicuously less-gifted year mates, no less. Five minutes into the lesson, it was clear from his preliminary questioning that less than a third of the little mongrels had deigned to do the reading. He had a headache before they'd even begun to brew. It was a standard ancestry potion, so simple that the average housewitch could probably produce a passable sample, and yet Goyle's cauldron was smoking before he'd even added the fifth ingredient. If he melted another cauldron, Severus was going to start billing Goyle Sr. for the replacements.

With one eye on Goyle and the other on Longbottom's notoriously nervous fingers, Severus spent the lesson in continuous anticipation of an unprovoked disaster. He had no idea that, when it finally came, it wouldn't be the dunderheads who ruined their potions who caused it.

"You have five minutes remaining," he told the class as the lesson finally ticked to a close. "If your sample is beyond salvaging, save me the trouble and dump it down the sink. If you believe you've made a credible attempt, bottle your samples and put away the rest of your materials."

When the cauldrons and ingredients were cleared away, Severus surveyed what remained. About eighty percent of the class appeared to have viable samples. He supposed it was the best he ought to expect. He passed out wide-lipped bowls and rolls of parchment to each table. "Pour enough of the Ancestry Potion into your bowls so that it coats your parchment completely when you dip it in, thusly." He demonstrated soaking the parchment into the potion and laying it flat on the table.

"Only a single drop of blood is necessary; pray don't get carried away, or you will be carried away to the Hospital Wing. Those without a sample, use the leftover from your neighbor." He pricked his finger on the edge of a clean knife and let a bead of blood fall into the center of his parchment where the students could see. "If you are not as incompetent as I suspect, your parchment will inscribe itself with your family tree, starting with you and working back for as long as the parchment lasts. You may begin."

The fourth-years began tentatively swirling their parchment into bowls of sample and, some gingerly, some readily, one by one pricked their fingers and applied the final ingredient to their ancestry potion. This was one of his most aggravating classes to teach, but its inclusion was mandated by Ministerial standards, despite the relatively high cost of ingredients in relation to the arguably low academic benefit. Aside from the galling experience of having his syllabus audited by the Department of Education, this class was infuriating because inevitably one of the young idiots took offense to being third cousins twice removed to another young idiot. Wizarding families were interconnected to the point of poor taste, in Severus' opinion. Nevertheless, it was a fact, and one every class of fourth-years took issue with.

When the gasp of indignation came, however, it was almost a sob.

Daphne Greengrass stared down at her parchment with bloodless horror. Her breath came in choked gasps and her frequent companion, Davis, looked up from her own parchment in concern. "Daphne, what is it?"

"It's wrong," the blonde girl stuttered out. Severus restrained an eye-roll at her cheap dramatics. "It has to be."

"What is—?" Davis tried to look at the parchment, but Greengrass snatched it away and put it behind her back. A minor scuffle ensued, and while Severus snapped at the girls to regain their decorum, Nott grabbed for Greengrass' parchment when she wasn't looking.

The boy held off his classmate's clawing hands with one arm and held the parchment to his face with the other hand. "Hmm, says Daphne Greengrass. Seems right to me. Daughter of—hang on…"

"Don't," Greengrass pleaded. The desperation in her voice caused unease to stir in Severus' chest.

"Mr. Nott, hand that to me this instant," Severus barked. Nott blinked up at him stupidly. "Now, Mr. Nott," he hissed. The skinny boy complied with a gulp.

"Sir, she's…" Nott trailed off at Severus' glare.

He put eyes to the parchment and felt himself still. Directly above Daphne Greengrass, where should have been the girls' father, Lord Greengrass was not listed. Instead, it read 'Dirk Cresswell.' Cresswell was well known for having been handpicked by the goblins as human ambassador to the British Ministry. He was a Muggleborn.

Greengrass was looking at him with tears streaming down her face. "Pack up your things, Miss Greengrass, and come with me," he said slowly. "Class dismissed."

He had to practically haul the crying girl out of the classroom; she was too distraught to properly move her legs. "Th-Theo is going to t-tell—"

"That is the least of your concerns at the moment," he told her, as gently as he dared. "Do you understand what the potion revealed, Miss Greengrass?"

"M-my father isn't—isn't—" She couldn't even articulate the thought.

Severus cursed the thrice-meddling Ministry and the inept populace that had sanctioned the injustice that was about to take place. "Miss—Daphne," he said, slowing down and attempting to force comprehension into her. "You are not a pureblood. Do you understand? Your biological father is a muggleborn."

"No," she whispered, shaking her blonde curls furiously. "No, he can't be. I—I know what I am. I'm the Greengrass Heiress."

Not for long, unless Greengrass Sr. had changed a great deal very recently. All he said was, "You can be that, and a halfblood."

"Noo," the girl moaned. "What… you're taking me to see Dumbledore, aren't you? You're kicking me out!?"

"We must get you to the Headmaster so he can discuss your options with you before the Board of Governors gets wind of this," Severus hissed. "Think, girl. There is a highly publicized tournament about to occur on these very grounds, the basis for which is blood superiority. What do you think the Board will do to avoid the embarrassment of a scandal like this?"

"I'm going to disappear," Greengrass breathed shakily. Fear led straight to denial. "No, they can't do that. My father—my… they can't."

"Walk, Miss Greengrass," Severus said, dragging at her arm once more. "There is no time to dither."

Several long staircases later, they'd reached the Headmaster's Office. "Licorice Wands," he snapped at the gargoyle. They ascended quickly and Severus spared the door barely a graze of his knuckles before ushering Greengrass inside.

"Severus, what is the matter?" Albus rose from his desk with furrowed brows at their sudden entry.

He thrust the parchment he was still clutching at the old wizard. "Ancestry potion today. Her classmates know." Or they would by now, he didn't doubt. Nott could not keep his mouth shut for a piece of gossip as juicy as this. Severus knew he detested the Greengrass girl, besides. Short of obliviating the boy on the spot there was nothing he could have done to contain her secret without being accused of flouting school regulations on behalf of a student.

Albus sank back into his chair with a pained look of sorrow. "My dear girl, I am so very sorry. It is unfortunate that you have found out this way. You are not alone, however. We will assist you in whatever you wish to do next."

"So that's it? One stupid piece of parchment and now I have to pack my things? Where am I supposed to go?" Greengrass shrieked, fat tears still leaking from her eyes.

"There are a number of schools who will accept your transfer in situations like this," Albus said gently. "Homeschooling is also an option, should you decline to leave the country. First, however, we will need to contact your parents—"

"Which ones?" she sneered petulantly. "My father will disown me if he sees this." At that thought, her eyes went wide and panicked again. "Oh gods, he'll disown me. And Mother—what will he do to Mother?" She began rocking back and forth in the chair agitatedly. "You can't tell him. Just—just say I flunked out or something. Tell him I was expelled, just don't tell him that."

"Miss Greengrass, it is likely that he will find out in any case, and soon," Severus told her. "It is inevitable that this event will circulate the school. If even one student writes home about it, the truth will be released and there will likely be an investigation into why it wasn't reported immediately. The Board of Governors takes incidents like this very seriously."

"But why?" she wailed. "I'm a better pureblood that half of those—those cretins I share classes with. I was raised in the old ways. I know all our customs. I deserve to be here more than blood-traitors."

"It is not a matter of deserving or worth," Albus said sadly. "Miss Greengrass, if it were up to me you would not leave these halls. The law is unforgiving, however. You will no longer be allowed to attend Hogwarts. I'm sorry. We must contact Lord and Lady Greengrass about this situation. If you fear for your mother's safety in light of this revelation, please tell us now, and we will do what we can for her as well."

Greengrass sniffled wetly. "I—I don't know. Maybe she'll be okay. She still had Astoria, so F-Father can't banish her, I don't think. Oh, I—I have to tell Astoria. She won't understand. What if they send me away? What if I n-never see her again? It isn't fair! They did this to me! It's their fault, not mine, but I'm the one who will be punished." Her words garbled as she dissolved into sobs again.

"I will collect the younger Miss Greengrass from her afternoon class," Severus offered. "Headmaster, don't contact the Board until I return."

"Of course," Albus said. He looked every one of his many years in that moment. "Anything you can do to forestall the propagation of this information would be appreciated as well, Severus."

He nodded shortly and left the office and the crying, traumatized girl behind. He couldn't deny a dull pang at Daphne Greengrass' fate. Another life overshadowed by a simple accident of birth.

Rigel was on her way back from Arithmancy, which she had with the Ravens and Puffs that term due to the weird nature of her schedule, when she passed the Slytherin first-years standing outside the common room, loitering. She slowed her steps, wondering if they had all managed to forget the password, and caught some of their hushed conversation involuntarily.

"—can't believe it. My father is going to flip when he hears. A halfblood in Hogwarts! All this time."

"I heard they're kicking her out—"

Rigel stopped listening, stopped breathing, and very nearly stopped walking as well. Her mind went blank with panic. How—? Who—? Only with an effort of will did she get her mind to jump start and reset, unlocking the torrent of thoughts that had screeched to a halt in terror. How could they know? Who figured it out? And most importantly, what should she do?

These thoughts burned through her brain as she mumbled the password and entered the common room. Her eyes darted about the large space as she struggled to keep her breathing steady. She felt like a cornered animal. It was only a matter of time before someone looked her way. She needed to run, to hide. But first—

Her shoes made a beeline for her dorm, where the mirror was locked in her trunk. She had to call Archie, had to warn him, tell him—

Tell him what? She had no idea what had happened. And why was no one stopping her? Plenty of people glanced her way as she crossed the common room, but no one fixated on her, as though they weren't interested in her at all. Rigel frowned and slowed her steps. She was confused, she noticed. Something wasn't adding up. If people knew she was a halfblood, there should be confrontation, shock, a prefect should be escorting her to Dumbledore's office; something more than unconcerned glances should be happening.

"Rigel! Over here." She turned her head to see Draco gesturing impatiently at her from where most of her year group was huddled around one of the fireplaces. They all had serious expressions, but there was nothing accusatory in them. Was it possible they didn't know? Had the first years been joking? She approached cautiously, taking in their tense faces. They knew something she didn't. The questions was what.

"Draco," she said neutrally. "What's going on?" She had such a tight hold on her emotions it was hard for her to feel anything, but she couldn't risk tipping Draco off before she knew what was going on.

"Have you heard?" Theo demanded. There was a light in his eyes that Rigel didn't like. It wasn't happy, exactly, more… exhilarated. She shook her head mutely, and the sandy-haired boy blurted, "Greengrass is a halfblood, Rigel. We found out today in Potions."

Rigel blinked, not sure, not daring to hope that she'd heard him correctly. "Greengrass," she repeated dumbly. They thought Greengrass was the halfblood? "Are you sure?"

"As can be," Theo said, chuckling darkly. "Today was ancestry potions. Saw her whole family tree myself, and her father is actually a muggleborn! Can you believe it?"

Rigel looked at her other classmates, noting Greengrass' obvious absence. The others didn't look quite as thrilled as Theo to have such a secret uncovered. Mostly they looked shocked, some upset. She wondered if they were upset because Greengrass was getting kicked out of school or because they'd been sharing classes with a halfblood. The cynical side of her suspected the latter.

"How can Lord Greengrass be a muggleborn?" Rigel asked, frowning. None of this made any sense. "Perhaps it was a mistake."

"No mistake," Millicent said, shooting Theo a sharp look before he could open his mouth again. "Daphne Greengrass was a by-blow, it turns out. Her biological father is Dirk Cresswell."

Rigel nodded slowly. The implications of what she was hearing were slowly creeping over her like Devil's Snare. "She didn't know. Tell me she didn't know."

The others shook their heads, somewhat bewildered at her insistent tone. "She looked pretty surprised," Draco murmured. His face was closed—she had no clue as to what he was thinking, but his eyes were dark with heavy thought.

"That's good, at least," Rigel said, sighing.

"How is any of this good?" Davis said sharply. "Daphne is being removed from school as we speak. The elves already took her things from our dorm."

"If she didn't know, they can't send her to Azkaban for blood identity theft," Rigel told her. The others exchanged grim looks. Clearly, not everyone had considered that possibility. "Her parents might be prosecuted, though, if they can't prove they didn't know either."

"The Greengrass Family is in the Book of Gold. They wouldn't dare," Pansy murmured. Her face was troubled, though.

Davis let loose a single tear before swiping at her eye angrily. "I still can't believe it. Daphne was more pureblood than most."

"Except she wasn't," Blaise pointed out bluntly.

"More than you," Davis shot back. "At least her parents are human."

"Don't impugn Blaise's blood just because your friend turned out to have a dirty secret," Theo said, scowling.

"She didn't know!" Davis screeched.

Blaise cut in before the two could escalate their argument. "Anyway, she's right, in a way. I'm only pureblood by Hogwarts' definition, which, frankly, is fairly generous. The non-human beings in my ancestry would preclude me from schools like Durmstrang just the same as Greengrass' father precludes her from staying here."

"It's not the same," Millicent said firmly.

"Isn't it, though?" Blaise leveled her with a sardonic look. "After all, if I were to enter the New Triwizard Tournament, it would be as a halfblood."

"What?" Pansy looked appalled but Millicent paled.

"That's right," Millie said weakly. "I'd forgotten."

"That can't be right," Pansy protested.

"It is," Blaise said evenly. "The tournament guidelines as to what constitutes pureblood don't count so-called 'creature' blood and require all-magical heritage up to the great-grandparent level. I'm not the only Hogwarts student who would technically have to compete as a halfblood."

"But why would they design it that way?" Pansy frowned, then made a noise of understanding as she apparently worked out the answer for herself. "It's to make sure no one can claim the pureblood category is less than absolute. No 'pure by definition' candidates, I suppose."

"That may be part of it," Millicent said, "But father told me the stricter definition was actually a condition of Durmstrang deigning to participate."

Draco wrinkled his nose. "Who cares if they nominate anyone? There are plenty of other schools worldwide."

"Durmstrang has a lot of influence in Europe," Millicent told him. "Where they go, other schools will follow. If Durmstrang deems the tournament in its current form as worth acknowledging, the rest of Europe is more likely to consider it favorably."

"None of this matters right now," Theo said, clearly exasperated. "How are you all not more concerned about the halfblood that's been living among us for over three years?"

"Don't see how it matters to us," Goyle said slowly. "They aren't gonna cancel school or anything."

"It matters," Theo said, rolling his eyes, "because anyone could be a halfblood! If not for the ancestry potion we would have never known. What are we gonna do about it?"

"Do?" Pansy shook her head sharply. "We aren't going to do anything, Theo. The Board of Governors will take care of this."

"There should be tests," Theo argued. "They should test everyone in school. Otherwise what's the point of the rule?"

Rigel kept her breath even and her eyes lowered, but she could feel her magic stirring hotly in her stomach at the thought of submitting to a blood test. She wouldn't.

"Everyone fourth year and up has been tested, Nitwit," Millicent said, scoffing. "The Potions curriculum doesn't change year to year. You think this is the first time this has happened?"

"Why don't they test us as soon as we get here?" Theo demanded. "It's an outrage."

"You're the only one outraged," Blaise said drolly. "And it would be an insult of the highest order to test the scions of ancient houses for blood purity. The integrity of the Book of Gold and Silver is unquestioned. If the Greengrasses knowingly forged their daughter's birth records, they will serve time in Azkaban, Theo. That sort of safeguard is supposed to be deterrent enough."

"Why not have the ancestry potion done in the first year curriculum, if they're being so polite about it?" Theo grumbled.

"First years can't brew an ancestry potion," Rigel told him flatly. "It takes a mature magical core to unconsciously imbue at the rate required for the potion's completion. Third year would be the earliest they could have put it on the curriculum, but even then it's slightly more complicated in terms of brewing technique than most third year potions."

Theo huffed. "So the best plan is to kick people out in fourth year if it turns out their mother slept with a muggle?"

"Don't say that about her!" Davis cried. "You've never even spoken to Lady Greengrass, but I've had tea at her house and she came to my birthday party and—and—she can't have done what you're saying."

Davis fled their group in tears and stormed to the dorm room that she would now occupy alone for the remainder of term. Rigel watched her go, and a twisted part of her wondered if anyone would be offended on her behalf, were her own falsehoods to become known.

"This is so messed up," Millicent muttered.

"How could we not have noticed?" Theo added, shaking his head.

Rigel stared at him. "Noticed? What was there to notice? The halfblood shape of her nose? Or maybe the halfblood way she crossed her t's?" She couldn't hold back a sneer. "There was nothing to notice, Theo. Because halfbloods aren't outwardly any different from other people. They don't have 'less worthy' stamped on their foreheads."

"I know," Theo said, indignant, "but her magic—"

"Greengrass is good at magic," Rigel snapped. "Say what you want about her personality, but Greengrass doesn't lack magical ability. She has higher grades than you in some classes."

"Had," Blaise put in drolly.

Rigel shot him a glance that told the boy he was not helpful. She knew she shouldn't let herself get riled, should keep her head down lest someone remember that she hadn't been in the fourth-year potions class and therefore hadn't been 'tested' like the rest of them. She couldn't help it, though. Her emotions would not stay suppressed. Not when she knew how close she had come to walking out the door with Daphne Greengrass. If she hadn't been pulled out of the regular courses, if she'd been there today…

Their group had been drawing attention since Davis made such a scene flouncing out, and Rigel knew she should walk away before even more of the common room started paying attention. She couldn't though. She physically could not move her feet when one of her own friends stood there and spouted such ill-conceived nonsense.

When Aldon Rosier's voice came from over her shoulder, Rigel closed her eyes briefly in resignation. Where Rosier's attention went, other seventh years' would follow, and sure enough, as she turned around to face him, she found nearly the entire common room staring their way.

"Rigel, I'm sure you didn't mean to imply that there was no basis for Daphne's expulsion. Rules are rules, after all," the golden-eyed young man said carefully. She could see concern for her clearly in his eyes. He was giving her an out, a chance to retract some of her more inflammatory words and toe the accepted line. Rigel considered taking it, she really did. In the end, though, she didn't think her integrity was worth so small a price as social convenience.

"In light of today's revelations, I can't help questioning the basis for the rule itself," Rigel said frankly. "Daphne Greengrass was no less magical than the rest of us. She knew pureblood customs and tradition better than most of us. So what's the point of kicking her out? Did any of you feel held back or like you weren't getting the most of your education by having a halfblood in the class?" She turned slowly, daring her classmates to contradict her. "Daphne Greengrass has been in school with us for over three years. Is she a different person today than she was yesterday? Of course not. It's you all that have suddenly changed your opinion of her. Because of her blood."

"She betrayed out trust," someone called out from the crowd.

Rigel openly scoffed. "She didn't even know she was halfblooded. What if it had been you? How would you feel if you found out tomorrow that you were a halfblood and your family lied to you? Would you feel like you didn't deserve to be here? Like it was okay to rip four years of hard work out from under you for something that wasn't your fault? Would you feel like a monster? Or would you feel exactly the same as you do today, and the world would seem monstrous instead?"

Dead silence met her pointed questions. She let it fester for a long moment before saying, directly to Rosier, "The rules are clear, Aldon. But they're also wrong."

She pushed through the crowd toward the common room entrance. She could hear the outbreak of murmurs and angry mutters behind her but she didn't care. Her entire being was choked with rage and resentment at the lot of them. She didn't even like Greengrass, but it was clear to her that the girl was nothing more than a victim of circumstance. If this was how her friends would treat a girl who'd done nothing wrong, how much more unforgiving would they be to Harriet Potter, willful blood identity thief and unapologetic liar first class?

She didn't want to think about it. She just wanted to bury herself in some other pursuit, anything to take her mind off the current situation before she gave into her magic's acute desire to destroy something irreparably. She paced through the dungeons, climbing staircases until she'd reached the entrance hall and could slip the reigns of the castle entirely.

The crisp afternoon air felt like the first clean breath she'd had in hours. She made straight for the forest's edge and was so out of sorts that she'd thundered her way well past the tree line before she knew it. She sucked in air in a slow, deliberate way and kept walking. She was determined to get further into the forest than the last time she'd been there. Every time she came to visit Treeslider she made it a little further. Only when the daylight had been swallowed completely by the canopy and the trunks around her spanned twice her length in diameter did she stop and sink to the soft dirt bonelessly.

Treeslider found her staring listlessly up at the branches above her a few minutes later. The bright green snake barely mentioned her lack of offering before curling up in her lap and singing a hissing song about warm burrows and slow prey. She stroked the snake absently, lost in thoughts she'd rather not be thinking. She shouldn't have gone off on Theo and Rosier. Why was it so much harder this year just to hold her damn tongue? She would have to apologize to them both, probably. She would make some excuse about resenting the school policy on her cousin's behalf. If anyone asked whether she'd done the ancestry potion herself, she would simply intimate that she'd covered it much earlier in her private lessons with Professor Snape. No one would think to question their Head of House about it. This situation would pass, and likely her classmates would eventually forget all about the unwitting halfblood Daphne Greengrass. She wouldn't forget, though. For the next four years at Hogwarts Greengrass would be haunting her steps in every corridor, looming over her shoulder in every exam. Rigel fervently hoped that wherever Greengrass ended up was a kinder place than the one she'd left behind. She wished the best for the girl, but she knew in her heart it was a selfish wish, too. Irrefutably, there stood the fact: there, but for the grace of Merlin, go I.

As if tragedy begot tragedy, the papers the next day painted a grisly fresco of the current state of blood relations in Magical Britain. Rigel hadn't noticed at first the rampant murmurs rippling through the Great Hall. She thought the increase in chatter merely a side effect of the Greengrass scandal, still raw and sharp in her mind. She tried to ignore it, but Millicent thrust a Daily Prophet under her nose. The dark-haired girl grimaced apologetically but shook the paper nonetheless.

"You'll want to see this," Millie said softly.

Rigel took the paper with a frown. The front page was mostly images. A building caved in on one side, where an explosion had bloomed and settled into rubble. A snake-eating skull against a twinkling night sky, as ominous and incomprehensible as the last time she had seen it. The headline read: ATTACK ON NOVUS INDUSTRIES.

She felt a sick dread pool in her stomach as she scanned the article. She didn't care about the details, she only wanted to know the outcome. Three dead. Ten injured. The list of names was incomplete, but Lily was not on it.

Rigel tried to breathe evenly, but she could hear the rattle in the air that her lungs expulsed. Her mother's company had been attacked. Presumably by the same group who had disrupted the World Cup. She wondered at the utter insanity of it. It was difficult to even comprehend: three dead. They had killed people in the name of anti-muggle hate. Why Novus Industries? She answered her own question after a moment of thought. Novus Industries hired muggleborns proactively, despite discouragement from the government and incentives to do otherwise. To a group of people who wanted even scant connection to muggles dissolved, a company that defied the push to hire only those schooled at Hogwarts had always risked censure. Now, apparently, such companies risked mortal peril as well.

Before she had time to reread the article, an owl from home landed in front of her porridge. The slip of paper enclosed in its talons didn't say much. Aunt Lily is safe, Sirius wrote. She's taken a leave of absence. They haven't caught the perpetrators yet. Be vigilant.

Despite its brevity, the word from home was enough to slow her heartbeat and allow her to consider the event almost objectively. The message at the World Cup wasn't a bluff, then. Someone was serious about disrupting the ties between the magical and muggle worlds. And they were willing to kill to see it done. A heavy weight filled her chest at the thought of those whose lives had been taken or twisted, and the many more who would be frightened by this attack. Some would start to distance themselves from their muggleborn acquaintances. Those without muggle ties would reason that anyone who maintained their loyalty had already been warned. Rigel didn't hold out hope that the outcry against this gross injustice would make a difference in tracking the radical group down and neutralizing them. Only real information and dedicated pursuit could accomplish that. James would be busier than ever, now.

Rigel read through the article one more time, slower and more focused. A device of some kind had been recovered from the wreckage, but the DMLE hadn't released any details as to how it might have caused the explosion. At the bottom of the article, in a comment so dry it might as well have been a footnote, it read: To allow the company time to recover its offices and personnel, the Ministry's Patent Office has suspended their contract with Novus Industries indefinitely.

That, more than any of the macabre details or gross speculation in the rest of the article, made her want to rip the paper to pieces. Even the Ministry is scared that their association with Novus will make them a target. Cowards.

She wondered vaguely when she'd become so cynical. Probably about the time she'd learned that humans would do anything for power and, more pressingly, security, she supposed. She set the paper aside, giving Millicent a brief nod of thanks. Standing, she said, "I'm going to write Harry. I'll meet you all in class."

That Hermione had managed to find a copy of the DMGS's press release about the tournament within a day did not surprise Archie. That the driven young woman had proceeded to secure permission not only from all of her professors, the Head of Healing Track, and her own parents within the next week shouldn't have surprised him, but he had honestly expected someone to realize what a bad idea it was. No one stopped her, though. The professors even encouraged Hermione, praising her for keeping abreast of international affairs and volunteering to represent AIM abroad.

By the time Archie realized he would have to be the one to say something, Hermione's course was set. A couple of other students appealed to Professor Willoweed to be nominated, but Hermione's early enthusiasm for the opportunity settled the professors' minds in her favor. She would be AIM's top choice for consideration by the selection committee, whether Archie liked it or not.

"Aren't you worried about keeping up with the syllabi?" he asked her, watching her bundle together all of the materials required for the application. They were in the library, which meant his friend automatically shot him a disapproving look before answering, in a much quieter tone of voice.

"You've told me a dozen times that your cousin, Rigel, keeps apace with our studies. If he can do it, I can too. Why are you so against this?" she added, letting go of the papers for a moment and pinning him with a direct stare.

"I'm not," Archie said weakly.

"You have been from the start," Hermione disagreed. "You think I shouldn't go, but you haven't said why. Do you think I can't do it? I'm good at more than just Healing magic."

"I know that," Archie said, eyebrows raising. He hadn't thought he'd been quite so obvious in his misgivings. Now that he had the opening, though… "If the tournament was anywhere besides Hogwarts, about anything other than blood purity, I'd tell you to go in a heartbeat, 'Mione. I know you'll wipe the floor with those snobs. But it's going to be dangerous—"

"There will be adults there to keep it from getting out of hand," Hermione said reasonably.

"Not the tournament, the whole country," Archie told her. "There's rampant blood prejudice everywhere right now. It's getting ugly on both sides and I don't want you caught up in the middle."

"I already am," Hermione said, tilting her head in the way she did when she thought he was being thick. "Harry, I'm muggleborn. That means that I'm implicated in this ideological battle regardless. I can stay here and do nothing, or I can go there are stand proudly and show the world that muggleborns are as talented as anyone else. Don't you see? If people like me are too afraid to stand up for ourselves, it's seen as an invitation to the rest of society to do whatever they want to us. I have to do this, Harry. I won't forgive myself if I don't go and some bigoted pureblood wins the tournament. The Sow Party will use it as an excuse to pass that legislation you told me about, won't they? Or something worse. It can't be borne."

"I know you're right," Archie said, mouth twisting unhappily. "I just wish it didn't have to be you."

"If everyone waited for someone else to do something unpleasant, nothing would ever get done," Hermione said softly.

"I'll miss you," he said, knowing in his heart that he'd never really had a chance at changing her mind.

Hermione leant over and hugged him fiercely. "I'll miss you too, Harry. I'll write every week. And you'd better send me copies of all the homework assignments."

Archie laughed. "You're exempt from the homework and you still want to do it?"

"How will I be ready for the exams at the end of term if I don't do any homework all year?" Hermione asked, shaking her head exasperatedly.

"You're really incredible, you know that?" Archie had to smile at the way Hermione ducked her head slightly to allow her curls to hide the flush in her cheeks at that. "I mean it, 'Mione. I think you're the most amazing person I've ever met. I—I've thought that for a while. I just wanted you to know."

Hermione's wide eyes filled with undisguised wonder and she blinked hard before smiling at him softly. "Harry, I've never met anyone like you, either. You know you mean more to me than anyone else. I promise I'll come back in one piece, ok? Please don't worry too much."

Archie searched her face for a sign that this was the right moment to tell the beautiful, intelligent witch beside him how he felt. As she turned back shyly toward the stack of papers before her, he knew it wasn't. How could he tell her how he felt right before she left for who knew how long? A part of him dreaded that if he didn't, she would find someone else, someone whose charms she was more susceptible to, someone who would inevitably recognize what a special, wonderful person she was and try to make her theirs. Archie knew such thoughts were selfish, though. His own insecurity was not a good reason to confess his feelings. He could wait a little longer, until she was back with him at AIM and could return his feelings without the complication of long distance or the distraction of a dangerous tournament looming.

Still, it ached to shut the feelings away once more and carefully lock the drawer. It felt like locking a poltergeist in his chest. Every time he looked at her, the drawer rattled.

That night, he lay awake long past midnight, staring up at his ceiling in frustrated longing. Damn, but he adored that witch. As Archie was contemplating giving in to his pent-up desire and releasing the poltergeist in a different sense, so to speak, the mirror dinged and he jumped, startled, from his bed. He ran a hand through his hair and straightened his pajamas uncomfortably before answering the mirror with an awkward cough. "Yes? Rigel?"

"Harry," his cousin said, her grey eyes wide, "Sorry to wake you so early. I have bad news. It's about Lily's job."

Archie shook the fog of embarrassment away and frowned. "What? What's going on?"

Harry's face had a grim cast. "Novus Industries was attacked last night. It made the papers here this morning, but it might make the front page where you are. I wanted to tell you before you found out, though. Lily is fine, but there was an explosion at the office and that ugly snake and skull thing was hanging over the attack site."

"Dear Merlin," he said, feeling shock lance through his stomach. "Was anyone hurt?"

"Yes." Harry looked somber, and the fact that she didn't elaborate only made his gut clench tighter. "I want you to be careful, A—Harry. There's no telling whether these incidents will stay confined to the UK or whether they might spill over to the Americas, but be on your guard. American schools are known for their high muggleborn acceptance rates."

"I'll be careful," Archie promised. He hesitated, but figured this was a good a time as any to tell his cousin about Hermione. "While I have you here," he said slowly, "remember when you told me about the tournament and I promised to ask around about it here?"

"Yes." Harry said again, this time with her eyes narrowed slightly.

"Well, Hermione was with me when I asked, and I may have piqued her interest about the tournament," Archie admitted.

Harry closed her eyes briefly. "Are you telling me Hermione—your friend Hermione who knows Harry Potter likes to cross-dress at school—is going to enter the Triwizard Tournament?"

"I'm not… not saying that," Archie said, trying a sheepish smile. Harry did not return it. "It's not my fault!" he protested. "Hermione is a very determined young woman. When she heard that they were trying to prove purebloods were better wizards than others, she couldn't let it stand. I really admire her willingness to stand up for—"

"Admire it later," Harry snapped. "First explain how you let this happen."

"I don't own her, H-Rigel." Archie snorted. "Quite the other way around, I'm afraid."

Harry's expression softened. "You told her how you feel? Did you tell her about the marriage contract and explain that it isn't permanent?"

He winced. "I… haven't told her, yet. With her determined to participate in this tournament, it didn't seem right to burden her with my feelings on top of everything else."

Harry was silent for a moment. He could tell by her torn expression that she felt bad for him, but didn't know what to say. Harry had no more experience than he did in matters of the heart. Finally, his cousin offered, "Maybe she won't get picked by the selection committee."

Archie shook his head ruefully. "She has three more letters of recommendation than required. Her grades are better even than mine, and her raw magical output is rated fairly high. She'll get picked. Just… please look after her."

Harry nodded slowly. "I will. I'll make sure the others know she's your friend and I won't forgive any disrespect. Tell her to come talk to me if anyone gives her trouble outside of the tournament."

He smiled gratefully. He could always count on Harry. With her at Hogwarts, he didn't have to worry quite so much about Hermione. "Is there anything else I should know?" Archie asked after a moment's pause.

His cousin grimaced. "Actually… I need a vial of your blood."

Archie groaned. "First spit, then blood. Are you making a golem of me, cuz?"

"I wish," Harry grunted. "There was an incident. A halfblood was discovered at Hogwarts and they expelled her."

"WHAT?" Archie's pulse raced and his hands shook. "How could you just now tell me?"

"It happened yesterday," Harry said, frowning. "And they're trying to keep it quiet to avoid a scandal but the whole school knows. If they decide to test everyone, I need some of your blood."

Archie could not believe his ears. "You're staying at Hogwarts? You should leave. Now. I can catch a cab to the airport and use my emergency credit card to book a flight home today. I'll meet you at the Dancing Phoenix and we can switch places—"

"Stop," Harry said, exasperated. "We are not invoking Plan B. There's not any kind of manhunt going on. I don't think it will actually be necessary, but I want your blood just in case. Don't worry. Our goose isn't cooked yet."

"What are you going to do with it?" Archie asked, trying not to panic but seriously wondering if his cousin had just become numb to the risks she ran.

Harry smirked, and it was a devious, beautiful thing. "I'm going to make a skin graft. Only I'm going to do it badly."

"A skin—" he stopped. Thought about the possibility. As it clicked, he had to smile slowly. "You are a terrifying person, Harry Potter."

"Watch it," she said, glancing over her shoulder. "My roommates could walk in any time."

"Then you should go back to class and let me go back to sleep," Archie said, yawning. "Thanks for the heads up about Lily. We can figure out anything else in the morning, though."

"It is morning for me," Harry pointed out.

"Bully for you." Archie made a face at her. "Night, cuz."

"Night."

Despite his words, he didn't fall asleep that night. His mind ran doggedly in circles around everything Harry had told him. There had been another halfblood at Hogwarts. A muggleborn-affiliated company was struck by a deadly attack. And what Harry hadn't mentioned at all was telling in itself. She hadn't brought up her own participation in the tournament. Archie wasn't fool enough to think Riddle had changed his mind, which meant Harry was probably trying to deal with his pressure all on her own. She'd better not be taking any hits for him or their parents. Archie would never forgive her if she got herself wrapped up in that blasted tournament because she was trying to be noble.

The last days of October passed too quickly. Nothing she did, not her studies nor her friends, could erase the hunted feeling she carried with her as first one, then another week passed without a word from Riddle. She knew he hadn't given up; it was only a matter of time before he tried something else. As the announcement of the tournament contestants crept closer, her nerves began to get the best of her.

Every afternoon as she walked to lab three for whatever training Snape had planned for her, she felt dread pool in her stomach that this would be the session that Riddle appeared, armed with real secrets this time, for all that she doubted even Riddle could uncover the convoluted depths of her true vulnerability.

On October 30th, it was almost a relief to answer the summons of her Head of House. There was no more time. The announcement was tomorrow. Riddle would have to make his threats tonight, or forfeit his desire to have her participate. Either way, it would be decided and done with. Rigel was almost looking forward to it. She couldn't take any more suspense.

She opened the door to lab three without knocking. Riddle leaned against a gleaming counter, arms crossed and face closed in thought. Snape wasn't there. Rigel allowed herself a single hard swallow before closing the door quietly behind her and turning to face the man who seem so determined to complicate her already complicated existence.

"Will Professor Snape be joining us?" she asked.

Riddle roused himself from his contemplations but did not move from his somewhat slouched posture. "No. I wanted to speak to you alone. It occurred to me that you might feel somewhat… attacked in these meetings. A less stilted dialogue may benefit us both."

Rigel's eyebrow rose of its own volition. Riddle thought Snape's presence was what made her defensive? No, she decided. That was just an excuse to remove Snape from the discussion. To remove the only witness, she thought sourly. "Professor Snape's presence or lack thereof won't change my mind," she told him. There was no energy in her voice; she was simply stating the truth.

"You've proved remarkably bull-headed," Riddle allowed. To her surprise, the faintest of smiles flickered across his mouth as he considered her. "It's admirable. A man swayed by neither greed nor fear is rare enough; one so young and un-established, nearly unheard of."

He fell silent and seemed to be waiting for a response. Rigel sincerely hoped he wasn't looking for a 'thank you.' "That says more about the world than it does about me," she said carefully. Then, almost hopefully: "have you accepted you can't force my hand?"

Riddle's amusement died. "I could, boy. Never doubt that if I wished it, I could hollow you out to an empty husk and enchant it in such a way that even your closest friends would not notice the difference." Rigel paled, and her wand was in her hand before she recalled drawing it. Riddle flicked his eyes at it, but merely sneered. "Put that away. I have neither the patience nor the desire to see you whittled into a lifeless puppet. You may not believe this, but participating in this tournament is in your best interest, Rigel. Until you realize that, it seems another approach is in order."

This was it, she thought. Now he would reveal just what information he had on her that made him look so supremely unconcerned. She braced herself against the worst. If it was anything short of her identity as Harry Potter, she could—

"What do you want?"

She blinked dumbly. Had they just restarted the conversation without her realizing it? "I… don't want to be in your tournament."

Riddle rolled his eyes at her, and the gesture was so incredibly human she almost choked. "And Severus says you're his smartest pupil. I pity the next generation." She flushed. What was he asking, then? "You care not for the security of either yourself or your family. Gold doesn't interest you. So, then. I'm asking. What do you want, Rigel Black? What would it take for you to participate in the Triwizard Tournament of your own free will?"

Rigel shook her head. "I don't want anything you can offer." She felt like a broken record.

"You must not comprehend what it is I can offer, then," Riddle said firmly. "Do not answer thoughtlessly. Consider for a moment the wide world, child. There is little I would not agree to and nothing at all that I cannot do. Don't think of yourself, for a moment. Look beyond even your own family. Is there nothing in the world you would change, if you could? No dream so big you've scarcely allowed yourself to hope for its manifestation?"

She frowned. This was not the same offer he'd made before, she realized. He wasn't offering something as concrete as gold or even something as straightforward as influence. Riddle was offering to enact a wish on her behalf. If he really meant anything… it was almost unthinkable. Wasn't Riddle the one who first warned her against giving an open-ended boon to another person? What was he playing at?

"Why are you doing this?" she asked, honestly confused. "An offer of this magnitude… there's no way on earth one kid's cooperation is worth this."

"The value of a favor is on its bestower to determine," Riddle said dismissively. "What is costly to another is negligible for one such as I." Rigel had to grimace at his arrogance. He wasn't done, though. "As to why this tactic now, well, I've considered you extensively these past two weeks. I admit at first I did not think you so very different from other intelligent young wizards I have known. You chafe at restrictions, at any suggestion of another's control. You are reckless: overly dependent on your raw talent to make up for what you lack in judicious trepidation in the face of a challenge. Much like Severus, you burrow in academics to avoid dealing with a world you neither respect nor envy. There is, however, one unique facet to your character that I had disregarded as unimportant… until now."

"Do tell," she said faintly. She wondered if other people saw her the way Riddle did. Was she as he'd said? She could be rash, sometimes. Reluctant to surrender control of her life to another, too. Those qualities alone didn't define her, though.

"Your altruism," Riddle said, smiling slowly. "That is the fulcrum that escaped me at first. It isn't obvious, of course. You pretend to apathy with remarkable alacrity, on the surface. Yet when the stakes are sufficiently high, your demeanor shifts entirely."

Rigel frowned. Altruistic? Her? Even Archie knew better than to credit her with an inclination like that. "I think you've misunderstood me," she muttered.

Riddle straightened from his lounging posture and stepped toward her until she could see the secondary colors in his eyes. "Your actions belie you. When I tally the extent of your grandest deeds, the theme is clear; you do for others before you do for yourself. Even the one instance that you asked something of me was on behalf of others. That is your weakness. You do not let opportunities to help others pass you by. Now you have the biggest opportunity you may ever encounter. This time, if I'm right, you won't be able to say no."

She wasn't sure what to think as silence stretched between them. He was bribing her with… charity? This had to be the strangest negotiation ever enacted. Her first instinct was to scoff. The second instinct, on the heels of the first, gave her pause, though. She thought, really thought about the suggestion for a moment. Anything. She could ask anything.

A whirlwind of possibilities crowded her mind. She hated that she was tempted. Hated the way Riddle's smile grew the longer she stood without answering. She had to think faster. This chance—if, indeed, she could view it as an opportunity as he suggested instead of an imposition—could not be wasted. If only she had more time.

What would help the most people? A selfish idea rose to the surface of her mind. I could ask him to open Hogwarts to non-purebloods. The idea caught at her throat. There was no way he would agree to that. Yet, was that not how good negotiations began? With a demand so outrageous that compromise ensued?

"If I agree to the tournament, Hogwarts admits muggleborns and halfbloods again," she said in a rush, determined to get it out before her courage deserted her.

"Out of the question," Riddle hissed. His eyes flashed in cold fury.

"You said I could ask for anything," she said, working to keep her voice even.

"Anything else," he growled down at her.

She favored him with a skeptical look. "You said that before. I no longer believe you."

Riddle's scowl could have curdled milk. "My patience is not endless. Ask. Another. Boon."

Rigel arched her eyebrows and affected her best uncompromising stare. It was worth a try, surely. "Then this is my final offer: if I compete in the tournament, the S.O.W. Party kills the anti-muggle blood legislation."

Riddle stilled, his face suddenly blank. "I don't know what legislation you mean."

"Do not insult me at this stage, Mr. Riddle," Rigel said, frowning. "I refer to the legislation your party has been attempting to pass for the last three years. The increased restrictions on muggleborns and denial of basic rights to any non-pureblood witch or wizard, including healthcare, employment opportunities, and self-determined marriage prospects. I will participate in your tournament only if the legislation gets scrapped completely and never re-introduced at a later date."

The politician seemed more intrigued than surprised at her elaboration. "You think such a price is worth your mere… participation?" A smirk bloomed like a black rose across his cheek.

She felt her heart jump unexpectedly. He hadn't said no. He was actually considering it. Could she really trade her dignity and risk her life in exchange for a guarantee that the awful legislation that had been hanging over the Wizarding World like a cloud would simply… dissipate? She peered into her soul and saw Archie there. Forced into a contract with her for her own protection. She saw Addy, too young to know it, but held under the same threat as any halfblood. Hermione was there too, keen and bright, but destined to struggle for every step she took into their insular society. Even Daphne was there. Poor, prejudiced Daphne struck down by the very uncompromising ideals she'd once held up like a shield between her and the world.

Rigel had to consciously relax her jaw so that Riddle wouldn't see exactly how badly she wanted to make this trade. Unfathomable, that the man had gotten his way in the end. After all her protestations, he had seen the lever she couldn't ignore. Now she had to see that he didn't pull it too far. She tilted her head as though she were still considering. "If not my participation… then my victory. If I win the tournament, the legislation is scrapped."

"Interesting." His face gave nothing away, but Rigel could tell he was taking the offer seriously. She kept her face as cold and unyielding as she could, determined that he believe she would not settle for anything less than the complete eradication of that disgusting legislation.

"That's not all," she said, realizing she needed something else to distract him from attempting to knock the stakes lower. "I'll require something else for agreeing to participate in the first place. No guarantee I'll win, is there?"

"None at all." Riddle seemed more entertained by that idea than by anything else they'd discussed thus far. "What would you have for this additional condition—keeping in mind that I've yet to agree to the first?"

Her mind was racing ahead of her, trying to think of something that would do some good in the world. Riddle was influential. Why not take advantage of that? "For my initial participation, I want you to publicly decry the recent attacks and the anti-muggle radicals behind them. You've been silent up until now, which, from a man as influential at you, is practically tacit agreement. If I allow you to nominate me for this tournament, you will announce to the press that the S.O.W. Party does not support the violent work of these renegades and that their actions are those of a disenfranchised group of madmen, not reflective of mainstream pureblood policies and ideology in any way."

"Well done, Rigel." Riddle's all too pleased expression doused any feeling of satisfaction she might have derived at listing demands of him for once. "I'll make a politician of you yet." Rigel scowled slightly. Trust Riddle to take credit for any minute amount of cleverness that occurred in his vicinity.

"Do we have a bargain?" she pressed. If she wasn't getting any time to think about this, then neither should he.

Riddle gazed down at her in indulgent amusement. "So like Severus," he mused quietly. "Though his interests were always a bit more… personal, of course."

Rigel's curiosity was piqued. Snape had mentioned the dangers of making a deal with Riddle, once. She wondered what he had bargained, and whether he'd been as sure of himself then as she was now. She also had to wonder how much he'd come to regret later, and whether he'd do it again, given another chance. While she wondered about Snape, Riddle appeared to make up his mind.

"Very well, Rigel. In exchange for your participation in the True Triwizard Tournament, I will issue a righteously worded press release disavowing the fringe group responsible for the attack on the World Cup and your dear aunt's company. If you manage to win the tournament—not tie, not merely become the pureblooded champion, but win it outright—I will withdraw the aforementioned legislation and never support its reintroduction." Riddle said all of this with a calm, pleasant expression, as though he were listing the food he planned to eat for breakfast the next day.

Suspicious, Rigel said, "We will take a vow to that effect. Tonight." After all, he'd squirmed his way around a promise to her before. She would not make the same mistake twice. "Professor Snape can be our Bonder."

"You mean to make the Unbreakable Vow?" Riddle's eyes flared.

"I do. Unless you aren't as serious about these terms as you say," she said, lifting her chin in challenge.

He didn't flinch. "I'll summon Severus directly." His wand was in his hand before Rigel had even registered his wrist moving. Wordlessly, he flicked the polished wood and black smoke materialized into the shape of an inky crow. It flew through the closed door and was gone. Rigel couldn't help but stare after it. It was like a sort of anti-patronus. She wondered if it could be used to send messages or only to fetch people.

As they waited, Rigel took a scrap piece of parchment and a self-inking quill from her pocket and set to work. She was not about to allow Riddle to write the vows. As the one setting the terms to which he was complying, she had the right to dictate the exact wording. She would not have suggested it otherwise.

It didn't take Snape long to arrive; he'd likely been waiting impatiently for their meeting to conclude, one way or the other. His eyes swept the room when he entered, assessing their stiff postures and still-spotless surroundings. "Lord Riddle," he said respectfully.

"Severus, young Rigel and I have come to an accord this night. We require you to be our Bonder." Riddle said, smirking once more.

Snape paled before two spots of color bled back into his cheeks. "What have you agreed to, Rigel?"

"He's agreed to my terms, actually," Rigel said vaguely. She could scarcely believe this was actually happening, but she wasn't about to back out now. "As such, I will be setting forth the vows." She handed the piece of weathered parchment to Riddle for his inspection. "I trust this wording is satisfactory?"

Riddle drew a single line with his finger across the parchment near the end of the vow, but otherwise left the wording alone. "Suitable," he said smoothly, handing it back to her. Snape's sharp eyes followed the parchment worriedly, so Rigel handed it over for his perusal. She saw the way his breath stilled and his eyes narrowed. It wasn't what he'd expected, then. Good. That made it less likely that Riddle had walked her into this situation rather than the other way around.

Rigel knelt. Riddle slowly followed suit. She felt her teeth ache in protest when their hands met in the traditional clasp. The resonance was unnerving and distracting, but she had no time to dwell on it. Snape touched his wand to their joined hands and Rigel began speaking, clearly and firmly.

"Will you, in the event that I willingly participate in the New Triwizard Tournament, give a public statement on behalf of your political party disavowing the actions of the group responsible for the World Cup attack?"

"I will."

A ribbon of red light snapped out from Snape's wand and twined around their clasped hands.

"And will you, in the event that I am the outright winner of the New Triwizard Tournament, cease all attempts to introduce, promote, or pass legislation regarding the rights of non-pureblooded witches and wizards in the areas of employment, healthcare, and marriage, including any legislation encouraging or requiring people to marry or not marry on the basis of blood status alone?"

"I will."

A second ribbon was loosed and settled atop the first, and Rigel exhaled a slow breath. That was it. Riddle had made the Unbreakable Vow. Before she could say the words to conclude the vow, Riddle spoke again, his voice hard and his grip on Rigel's hand even harder.

"And will you, in the event that you are chosen to participate in the New Triwizard Tournament, agree to compete to the best of your ability in any and all tasks required of a designated champion?"

She wanted to refuse on principle. One simply did not impose an un-agreed-upon vow in the middle and expect the rite to go on to completion. She narrowed her eyes, feeling the magic build around her as it sought her verbal agreement or refusal. She replayed his words in her mind, but could not see a downside to them, really. She already was going to do her best in the tournament, because she wanted that legislation gone. What did it cost her to stake her life on that intent when she was already risking her life simply by being in the tournament? Snape's stare was burning into the side of her head, but she didn't look at him. She was looking at Riddle, trying to fathom what he thought he was gaining by adding that additional condition last-minute. His face gave her nothing useful, and magic was beginning to stir restlessly between them. Finally, she capitulated.

"I will," she growled, adding quickly, "So mote it be."

"So mote it be."

A third ribbon barely had time to settle over their hands before the rite was complete and the crisscrossing ties of magic sank into their skin without a trace. "Bad form," she commented, rising from her knees slowly. "Still. What's done is done. I trust there will be no more threats or attempts at intimidation regarding my participation in this tournament."

Riddle inclined his head, though it had an ironic tilt. "As you say, Rigel. What's done is done."

"I'll take my leave, then. I wish you luck in convincing the selection committee to choose me as one of the preliminary contestants within the next twenty-four hours," she added, a bit spitefully.

Riddle merely laughed, slow and sinister. "Dear boy, did you imagine we had not already submitted you to the board? You were selected weeks ago. It was simply a matter of gaining your compliance."

She scowled at the man's sheer nerve. Of course he'd gone ahead with the nomination. Riddle always got his way, she supposed. At least this time she'd made him pay for it. "Good evening, gentlemen," she intoned.

"Get a good night's sleep," Riddle said mockingly.

Not dignifying that with a response, Rigel left the lab and stalked back toward the common room.

It was a long hour of explaining to her friends what had happened and listening to them gasp and fret and debate possible outcomes in this or that event considering all that had unfolded that evening between Riddle and her. When Draco and Pansy started arguing over what sort of robes Rigel ought to wear for the ceremony the following night, Rigel stopped listening and took up a book on ailments caused by magic gone awry. She couldn't really concentrate on the words, but she could at least pretend to be absorbed in her reading and thereby discourage any further questioning along the lines of her now-inevitable participation in the tournament.

Rigel didn't tell them about the Unbreakable Vow. It wasn't the sort of thing you revealed to all and sundry. She simply told them Riddle had given a vow to the effect that the anti-muggle blood legislation would not come to pass in the event that she managed to win the tournament. Draco and Pansy agreed that was a generous condition on Riddle's part, and each congratulated Rigel for striking a deal that favored her in the end.

She didn't want to be congratulated, though. She didn't want her friends to be impressed with her at all. What exactly she did want, she wasn't sure. All she knew was that she was in no mood to speculate on likely reactions to her being chosen as a participant. Rigel just wanted to go to sleep, but she had to talk to Archie about what had happened. She could have made her excuses and called him right away, but she'd been interrupting his schedule a lot lately. Better to wait until the hours he'd specified would be best for uninterrupted conversation. The news would keep until then; there wasn't anything he could do about it in any case.

She feigned interest in the magical ailments text until her friends had exhausted themselves and turned in for the night. Rigel kept reminding herself that she only had to wait for the common room to empty, and then she could pass the news to Archie and sleep. Her head felt like a lead balloon, weighty with things she didn't want to really think about until tomorrow.

As the fire dimmed and the dungeons quieted, she stopped even pretending to turn the pages of her book. She simply sat there, eyes somewhat glazed, and let her mind wander. It shouldn't surprise her, then, that Aldon Rosier invited himself to sit beside her on the couch and said, "What's wrong, Rigel? You've been reading the same page for an hour."

She lowered the book to her lap and took in his searching expression. Rosier was always searching for something, she thought. "Evening, Aldon," she said. "Nothing's wrong. I'm just enjoying the quiet."

"You don't look like someone enjoying anything," he told her frankly, golden eyes alight with concern and—she thought, maybe—kindness. She looked away, toward the glowing fireplace, unsure whether she really wanted to answer and go through it all again. Draco and Pansy's dissection of the evening had been almost as bad as living it in the first place. Aldon sighed, drawing her eyes back to his thin frame as he settled back against the cushions. "You don't have to talk about whatever it is, but if you wanted to, I would listen."

Listen. Not question or debate or analyze. Just listen. Rigel wasn't sure if it was just her exhaustion, but having someone just listen sounded sort of nice. Somehow, she didn't think Rosier would mind if she complained a little, either.

"I'm to participate in the tournament," she said after a long moment of thought.

His eyebrows rose, but otherwise his face remained open. "You decided to nominate yourself?"

"No. Yes. It's—it's been decided. The S.O.W. Party ensured I would be chosen as one of the candidates, and I've agreed to cooperate, in exchange for certain… other things." She blinked slowly at him, wondering if she sounded as mercenary to him as she did to herself.

"So you made a deal with them?" There was neither censure nor admiration in his voice, merely a gentle curiosity that she doubted Rosier could turn off if he tried. He was perpetually interested in the world.

"With Riddle," she clarified. "Just now. I refused, at first, but then… he offered something that was worth it, in the end." Her lips twisted in a parody of a smile. "It's funny. You were the first one to tell me about the marriage law, right? You and Edmund. If not for you, I wouldn't have even known to ask. And he said yes. He agreed, which I still can scarcely believe, to abolish the legislation entirely if I won his tournament. Why would he do that?"

She didn't expect him to have an answer, but Rosier surprised her. "He won't need that legislation if you win the tournament, Rigel. It's not really about you winning, per say. It's about a pureblood winning." The older boy appeared to be attempting to explain the situation gently, but Rigel could barely hear him anyway over the roaring in her ears. "If a pureblood wins the tournament, it proves to the world that his party was right, that everything they've been saying for years—that purebloods are better wizards who deserve a better place in society—is correct. With that kind of vindication, and the public support that comes in the wake of the victory, the S.O.W. Party itself won't have to lift a finger. Chances are, the changes he wants to make—the exclusive hiring of purebloods, the disenfranchisement of lesser-blooded people—will happen naturally. That's the power of popular opinion. Weighed against a bunch of legislation he's had great difficulty passing anyway, and you can understand why it's not exactly a bad deal from the party's perspective."

"So I've made things worse," she whispered numbly. There was a tightening in her chest as she ran through the last few hours once again. It had seemed like an inspired stroke. How could she not have considered that the political capital pureblood supremacy stood to gain in general might equal the loss of any legislation in particular?

Rosier let out a frustrated noise. "No, Rigel, that's not what I meant." He took her hands in his and squeezed them. "It was always going to be this way. If not you, it would only mean another pureblood winning the tournament instead."

Rigel squeezed his hands in return as the thought struck her hard. "You think the tournament is rigged."

"I know it is," he said softly. "Lord Riddle does not gamble unless all the odds are already stacked in his favor. If you think for a second that he would give a halfblood or muggleborn even a chance at winning his tournament, then you don't understand the man at all. If it wasn't you, it would be someone else, Rigel. And you secured a sacrifice on the S.O.W. Party's part that I doubt would have occurred to anyone else to even ask. You did good, Rigel. Don't doubt that."

"Should you be saying all this?" she wondered, glancing around uneasily. "Your parents—"

"Are not me," Rosier said firmly, a frown marring his handsome face. "I walk my own path, and I've known for a while that it wasn't going to be the one they laid out for me. This tournament is a manipulation of our society on every level, and I'm not so foolish I can't see that."

She smiled somewhat tremulously at him. "No one else seems to understand. My friends feel sorry that I was pressured into competing when I don't want to, but they don't really understand how very wrong this all is. Risking my life is one thing, but I don't want to be the figurehead of the pureblood elite, playing knight-errant in someone else's twisted fairytale."

Rosier's thumbs stroked over her fingers soothingly. "I know you don't, but you must come to terms with the role you've cast. The world will never know what you bargained on its behalf. You'll be perceived as one more pureblooded lordling looking for glory."

She closed her eyes in resignation. "I know. What people think doesn't matter, though. Reality matters. If I had refused him again tonight, who's to say he wouldn't have just resorted to threats again. I'd likely have found myself in the tournament anyway, but with no compensation to speak of." She felt a bit better, rationalizing her choice aloud. Even if she didn't fully believe it, it was easier to think that she had done the best she could.

"What do you mean… threats again?" Rosier asked, an odd tone to his voice. "Did he threaten you, Rigel?"

"He tried," she shrugged. "More accurately, he tried to threaten Harry. He doesn't know her, or he'd have known she'd never let me sacrifice myself for her sake. It was ridiculous." She snorted.

"Ridiculous?" Rosier shook his head at her, an odd smile on his face. "No. I think you're just a rare individual. No wonder even a master manipulator like Lord Riddle had trouble leading you by the nose. Good for you, Rigel."

"Thanks, Aldon."

They sat there for a little while without saying anything else. Finally, Rosier got up to leave. "Are you sure you'll be all right?" he asked, his gaze somewhat shadowed by his dark lashes as he looked down at her.

"Eventually," she said, smiling a little. "I'm just going to sit a while longer before going to bed. Thank you for comforting me. You didn't have to."

"The things we do because we want to will always outweigh those we do because we have to. Goodnight, Rigel." He left, taking his enigmatic smile and ever-surprising nature with him.

Rigel went back to staring at the grated flames, wondering whether the firestorm had caught up to her at last.

Halloween dawned grey and foggy. Rigel woke feeling stretched thin both mentally and emotionally after too little sleep and too much stress-inducing contemplation. That day, more than any before it, she felt as though she was a ghost possessing a body, living a life not her own. She'd been pushed and hammered and squeezed relentlessly over the past thirty days, and tonight she would be hung up like a prize piñata, at the end of her rope in front of all the world. What's a girl to do? she thought mirthlessly as she trudged her way toward breakfast. The answer came to her unbidden, an automatic retrieval of the second half of an obvious phrase. Tie a knot, of course.

She sat between Draco and Pansy and spooned porridge into her bowl as though it was any other day. Draco must have found her serene emotional state unnerving, as he asked, somewhat tentatively, "Are you really all right, Rigel?"

She tilted a smile his way and nudged his shoulder gently. "Don't worry about me. I've made my decision and I'm going to stick to it." Had to, really. The Unbreakable Vow would see to that. In light of a decision so final, there wasn't any sense in fretting over it further. She was participating in the Triwizard Tournament, and it was best to come to terms with that fact before she was presented to the world.

"What's going on?" Theo asked from across the table.

"I expect you'll find out tonight," Pansy said evenly.

"It's all right," Rigel said, lifting her head from her breakfast. "Riddle didn't forbid me from telling anyone. I've been chosen as one of the preliminary competitors for the tournament, Theo. I found out last night."

The tawny-haired boy gaped at her. "You… you said you weren't even entering!" At Pansy's stern look, he lowered his voice apologetically. "I mean, when did you change your mind?"

"I didn't enter, exactly," Rigel said, grimacing sheepishly. She had decided she wouldn't tell anyone but Draco and Pansy—and Rosier, apparently—about the deal she made with Riddle. If it became common knowledge, she might be viewed as blackmailing a well-respected figure of the community. Worse, it might make his statement regarding the radicals and the backing down on his party's legislation ring hollow. "I suppose when the Weasley twins played their little joke it meant I was technically entered, and when they informed me last night that I'd been chosen, it seemed churlish to say no."

"It bloody well would have been," Theo agreed, looking impressed. "Congratulations, Rigel."

Millicent followed with her own congratulations and was echoed by every other Slytherin in hearing distance. She didn't doubt that the knowledge that she'd been chosen as one of the competitors would circulate the school well before that evening. Good. Anyone who'd been desperately hoping to be chosen instead could be disappointed in private. It was kinder, she thought, than letting anyone hold out hope until the ceremony later than evening.

Snape walked over to their table near the end of the meal. "Meet me in my office directly after last period, Mr. Black. There are a few formalities we must attend to prior to this evening's announcement."

She nodded her agreement, and after a moment her Head of House left. It was a relief that they had another meeting scheduled before the big reveal. She needed to face him, to explain to his satisfaction her actions the night before. It would only fester otherwise.

After breakfast she tried to go about the day as normal, tried to immerse herself in classes to take her mind off the impending side show. Everywhere she went, however, there were reminders that it was not a normal day at all. By lunch, everyone stared at her as she passed. Draco and Pansy closed rank around her wherever she walked, but they could not keep the questioning murmurs and dismissive scoffs from her ears. Rigel couldn't blame them. She didn't look like a champion. She wasn't particularly tall or handsome or poised. She was just Rigel.

The Weasley twins found her after her last class, prying her out of her friends' protective circle and whisking her into an alcove with unusually serious expressions.

"We heard a rumor—"

"—most inglorious, it were—"

"—that we may be responsible—"

"—for your pending elevation—"

"—to illustrious champion—"

"—and we wanted to say—"

"We're sorry!" they finished together. Earnest eyes blinked at her above a sea of freckles. She had to laugh.

"You couldn't have known," she said, smiling up at the tall redheads. "Besides, you mustn't apologize for a prank that exceeds your expectations. Only think what an interesting year it will be with me in the tournament."

Fred and George both grinned, exchanging deviant glances. "Promises, promises, Pup," George drawled, a pleased glint to his eye. "Should we take that to mean you'll be representing Hogwarts with pride?"

"With relish," she said, letting a smirk grace her features. "I daresay the tournament is going to be more exciting than anyone realized. You will help me make an impact, won't you?"

"Our humble services—"

"—are at your service."

She watched them walk away, deep in quiet conversation, and hoped they came up with a few good distractions. Anything that threw a wrench in Riddle's carefully laid plans could only be a good thing, to her mind.

Draco and Pansy had waited for her just down the hall. "Why do you still put up with them after all this time?" Draco grumbled as she rejoined them. "It's not as though they're good for anything besides cheap laughs."

"They remind me of home," she said. "No matter what you think, a good laugh isn't cheap at all. It takes a lot of hard work and talent to make something look effortless. I admire them."

Draco looked taken aback. "It just seems a waste of time. If they're so talented, they could be doing something to better society, instead of just making a joke of it."

"The nice thing about life is that you can do what you want with it," Pansy said diplomatically. "Certainly it can't be said that all my relatives are contributing members of society."

Draco let the subject drop and instead began listing the members he had confirmed for the unofficial dueling club. He wanted to get a few more lowerclassmen, but seemed to understand that the younger students would be less comfortable skirting the rules than the uppers were.

Rigel excused herself when they'd reached the turn-off to the common room, reminding them that she had to see Snape before dinner. She knocked on the door and entered at Snape's command. He set aside a stack of ungraded essays and conjured a chair for her to sit in. She took in the disgruntled set to his face and said, "I suppose you want to know why I did it."

His eyes flared with suppressed anger. "Indeed. Regale me with your reasoning."

"It's simple. He offered me a deal I couldn't refuse, and he knew it. So I took it. In my mind, the alternative was refusing on principle alone and ending up with either a worse offer or a more effective threat hanging over my head." She let him see her resignation as she added, "I knew, as soon as he offered such an open-ended boon, that he was willing to go further to ensure my cooperation than I might be willing to go to resist."

"That you made such a bargain does not surprise me," Snape said, somehow managing to make it sound both complimentary and insulting. "The fact that you felt the need to stake your very life on the agreement is what makes me question your sanity, Rigel."

"It was the only way to ensure he kept his end of the agreement," Rigel said.

"You think he will not find some way around it? There are always ways, Rigel," Snape growled. "It isn't worth your life."

"My life isn't in danger unless I refuse to compete in the tournament," she corrected him. "Anyway, didn't you make a similar deal with Riddle? When I proposed it, he compared me to you."

Snape's face went blank. "What did he tell you?"

"Nothing. Neither of you ever actually tell me anything," she complained. "I have to guess and piece together disparate comments until something resembling sense forms. I can assume that whatever deal you made has to do with why you're a member of the S.O.W. Party to begin with." Snape was silent, his face closed off, but Rigel was frustrated with how reticent he was with his motivations. "Sir, please," she said softly. "If you were in a similar situation to me, then tell me. Give me something besides cryptic warnings."

The Potions Master studied her wordlessly from across the desk for a long moment. Finally, just as Rigel thought perhaps he was not going to tell her anything after all, he said, "I wanted no part of politics, growing up. I was an academic, much like you. Lord Riddle courted me for party membership, the same way he did anyone of talent. He overlooked my blood status because my mother's family is old and I am the last Heir. Despite his attempts, I remained disinterested."

Rigel had to smile. They were more alike than she'd realized. "What changed your mind?" she prompted gently as her Head of House lapsed into silence. He appeared to be deep in thought, not seeming to even see her as his eyes focused on memories she wasn't privy to.

"I learned of an initiative the party was backing. It was to increase incentives for companies that hired halfblood or better and introduce penalties for companies who retained predominantly muggleborns. They called it the Purebloods First Initiative, and it would have meant large numbers of muggleborns laid off or pressured to find more menial employment. I had a… friend once who was muggleborn. Our lives took different paths, but I knew that she'd recently secured the job of her dreams at a private development company. I owed her a debt from long ago, and I saw, suddenly, that I could do something to repay it, and in doing so close that chapter of my life for good."

Rigel struggled to keep her face neutral. Was he just going to pretend the muggleborn friend he spoke of wasn't her mother? And was he seriously suggesting that he'd tied himself to Riddle simply to settle an old debt with Lily? "So you bargained with Riddle," she said. The parallels were eerie.

"Indeed. The legislation was tempered—it targeted government jobs only instead of private companies and the penalties were done away with altogether. I have been a member of the S.O.W. Party ever since." Snape rolled his shoulders as though warding off unpleasant thoughts.

"Does he really still own your loyalty after so many years?" she asked, frowning.

Snape's glare snapped into place in an instant. "As long as Lord Riddle is in a position to revive the Purebloods First Initiative in its original form, I will remain with the party."

"Then… this is your last year," she said, a smile dawning. "If… if I win this tournament, you won't have anything holding you to the S.O.W. Party anymore, will you? Riddle won't be able to pass any legislation about employment that discriminates on the basis of blood. You could sever ties with him."

Snape's eyebrows shot upward. "I doubt Lord Riddle has considered that," he mused, looking oddly lost.

"Something to think about, then," Rigel said, pleased to know that her participating in the tournament might be good for more than she'd anticipated. Struck by a sudden curiosity, she couldn't help but ask, "Does your friend know what you did for her?"

"We are no longer on speaking terms," he told her sharply, "and you will keep whatever conclusions you may have drawn to yourself."

She nodded. She could do that. "Thank you for telling me, sir. I understand your position better now, and why you do the things you do."

Snape scowled at her forbiddingly. "Do not paint me as some sort of martyr. I gained much from the party's influence and connections."

"Of course," she said soothingly.

"I am a selfish man," he insisted through clenched teeth.

She nodded sagely, hiding a smile. "Yes, sir. I understand."

The dark look he gave her said he very much doubted that. "Enough about my past. We were talking about you and your reckless insistence on an Unbreakable Vow."

"In this instance, an Unbreakable Vow favors me, not Riddle," she said slowly. "Unlike the bargain you made with him, my end of the deal is finite; I compete in the tournament, either win or lose, and the deal is over for me at the end of the year. For Riddle, if I actually win the tournament, he is bound for the rest of his life. He can't re-introduce anti-muggle blood legislation regarding marriage, employment, or healthcare ever again. That's a huge capitulation, considering the legislation he's been pushing for the last three years."

Snape appeared taken aback. Evidently he had not considered the vow from that angle.

"It still surprises me that he would go to that extent simply to have me participate in his tournament," she said tentatively. "Others would have done it for less, for nothing, even. Why is he so fixated on my involvement?" It sounded conceited to say aloud, but the evidence was irrefutable.

"There are many reasons why you make an ideal champion," Snape told her, drumming his fingers on his desk agitatedly. "You are the Heir to an old house, traditionally a Dark house whose loyalty, Lord Riddle believes, rightfully belongs to the S.O.W. Party. It is likely he believes that if you win the tournament, your newfound notoriety and the mantel of what you will come to represent may distance you from your family, whether you like it or not. Lord Riddle has long been interested in the idea of… mentoring you, Rigel. His offer last year was entirely serious. He has not said as much, but I believe… he may be searching for an Heir."

Her face lost all color at once. "Surely not," she breathed in horror. "He is young, yet."

"Nothing so immediate," Snape said, shaking his head. "It is merely a long-term consideration. As aware as I am of your own opinion regarding your abilities, to Lord Riddle you are a once-in-a-generation talent. He would be a fool if he were not to attempt to sway you to his camp."

"He's willing to lose all chance of furthering several of his legislative goals just on the chance that I might change my mind at the end of this and come over to his side?" Rigel couldn't help but be skeptical.

Snape snorted in amusement. "There are other contributing factors, of course. You come from a family that is publically aligned against the S.O.W. Party, thus repressing any accusations of favoritism or unfairness before they form. Draco would be a decent candidate in his own right, but as the son of the party's right hand man, the choice looks less than objective. Lord Riddle also knows you function well under pressure. You will not embarrass the party on the international stage, particularly with his assurance that you will do your best to win, Rigel."

"That was a dirty move," she grumbled, still annoyed at his blatant break with common courtesy.

"You agreed to it, nonetheless," Snape reminded her.

She acknowledged that truth with a grunt. "So. What do I do now? You said there was some sort of… formality tonight?"

Her Head of House sat back and folded his hands before him. "Tonight all nine preliminary candidates will be announced in the Great Hall after dinner. You will attend a private gathering with the other candidates while the rest of the school feasts. I will collect you from the Entrance Hall at precisely half past five. Wear formal dress robes."

"I don't have—"

"Borrow from Draco and ask Miss Parkinson to adjust them," Snape said wearily. "And for Salazar's sake don't wear those boots."

She sent her boots a pitying look. No one understood. Looking back up at Snape, she asked, "Will Riddle be at the gathering?"

"If he is, you'd best behave yourself," Snape warned her. "You will be expected to meet the other candidates, mingle, and eat something so you don't collapse when they present you to the press following dinner."

"More press," she muttered, grimacing. "I'd better get used to that, I suppose."

"After the feast you and the other eight candidates will be escorted to the Great Hall where you will each be asked to say a few words to those assembled," Snape went on. "Thank the committee for selecting you, characterize yourself in a way that is neither overbearing nor weak-kneed, and whatever you do, don't mention the political aspects of the tournament in any way. Clear?"

"Crystal," she said, sighing. "I'd better get back to the common room, if that's all. Pansy will want at least an hour to fix me." She stood and took a deep breath before smiling gratefully at the man who had done so much for her and, despite his contrary assurances, the world. "Thank you for explaining everything to me, sir. I'll see you at five-thirty."

She left the office secure in the knowledge that, whatever his professed loyalties or obligations, Severus Snape was in her corner. Not many people could say that, she knew.

The 'private gathering,' it turned out, was a small plate mixer organized in the chamber directly behind the Great Hall. As Snape ushered her into the room and closed the door behind her, Rigel could hear the dull roar of student chatter through the wall that divided them.

A long table of hors d'oeuvres had been lovingly arranged along one wall. She recognized a few of the small dishes, but many of them were foreign to her. Likely a nod at the international nature of the tournament. With a mental sigh, she turned her attention from the food to the young adults milling about the room. She'd have to interact with them at some point, she reasoned, so there was no sense procrastinating further, no matter how reluctant she was to, as Snape had so derisively put it, mingle.

She caught the sea-foam green eyes of a petite girl with brilliant red hair cut to a blunt lob. "So you're the last one," she said, walking over to where Rigel was still loitering by the door to the Entrance Hall. "Hogwarts, I'm guessin'." Her accent was vaguely Scottish, with a hint of something Southern European.

"I'm Rigel." She offered her hand and the redhead took it after an assessing look.

"Antiope," she said. At Rigel's polite blink, she added, "Not my real name, of course. Everyone at Chalcioecus gets a warrior title if they pass their fifth year trials."

"That's in Greece, right?" she asked, despite herself. She thought she'd heard Sirius and James make a joke or two about the Amazonian witches of Chalcioecus. She wasn't sure how much of their speculation held any merit, however. "Is it true it's an all-female school?"

"Of course," Antiope said, shaking her short hair back from her face impatiently. "It's why our graduates are so capable. No romantic distractions, so we are better able to focus on our studies."

"Makes sense," she said politely, though she wondered whether there was an equivalent school for boys in Greece.

"I wonder," a beautiful girl with a veritable curtain of silvery hair trailing behind her sidled up to them and cut in, "if you will find all zes boys… distracting." The girl's French accent was heavy, but the amusement slid through unencumbered.

Antiope scoffed. "Nothing could distract me from winning this tournament. The honor of my school and the Athenai depends on it." The short girl excused herself with a stiff smile and a less-than-friendly glance at the French girl.

"Fleur Delacour," the girl said, extending her hand palm-down. She spoke so quickly that Rigel's brain automatically attempted to translate until she realized the girl had merely given her name.

"Enchante," Rigel murmured automatically, bending over the girl's slender fingers belatedly. "I'm Rigel. Beaubatons?"

"Naturellement." Fleur smiled prettily, gesturing to the signature blue skirt and jacket she wore. "And you would be 'ogwarts. We wondered 'oo ze last pureblood was."

"Are you—"

"'alfblood, apparently," Fleur huffed, letting a sneer briefly disrupt her beautiful face. "'onestly, zes regulations are made by old fashioned bigots."

"They are quite restrictive, I've heard," she offered, wondering whether Delacour was referring to the multi-generational requirement or the disqualification of creature blood as pure. There was something not-quite-human about the way the older girl's hair floated about her. "I was going to ask whether you were looking forward to the tournament, though."

She blinked lovely eyes at her. "Ah. Madam Maxime insisted I participate, but when I saw zes ridiculous regulations I was more inclined to win zan before, I admit."

Rigel smiled. "Best of luck, then."

Delacour favored her with a disbelieving look, but nonetheless said, "You as well, Rigel Somezing." She wandered off, starlight-like hair floating after her.

Rigel rewarded herself for having spoken to two people already by drifting toward the food and helping herself to a plate. She gravitated toward the more interesting ones, choosing an empanada, some sort of triangular cheese pita, and what looked like a mottled boiled egg that smelled oddly sweet. She was about to dip a curious spoon into some kind of soup when a deep drawl stayed her hand.

"I vouldn't try the Shkembe if I ver you. It is not to English taste."

She pulled back from the soup and tilted her head at the rest of the table. "What then?" she asked over her shoulder, eyes still on the array of strange things before her.

"The Lozovi Sarmi." A thick forearm reached past her waist to indicate some sort of little green wrap, so she plucked a couple of them and examined the minced insides with interest.

"Thanks," she said, turning around to smile at the boy who'd helped her. She had to hold her breath momentarily to avoid choking at the sight of Victor Krum, of all people, slouching at her shoulder in fur-lined burgundy dress robes. She smiled wanly.

Krum peered at her beneath a heavy brow. "You look familiar. Ver you at the Vorld Cup?"

Her smile widened with an effort. "You must have met my cousin, Harry. We look very similar."

"Are you talking about Harry Potter?" A voice Rigel recognized piped up from behind Krum, confirming what Archie had already told her. Hermione Granger shifted her weight nervously as Krum stepped sideways to include her. "Harry's my best friend," she added, somewhat awkwardly. "I'm Hermione Granger." She seemed to hesitate between Rigel and Krum before offering her hand to Rigel first.

She took care to inject friendly warmth into her voice as she grasped it and said, "Great to meet you, Miss Granger. As you probably know, I'm Rigel, Harry's cousin. She speaks very highly of you. If you need anything at all while you are here, don't hesitate to ask me. And this is Victor Krum," she went on, automatically introducing the two of them. At Krum's frown, she nearly swallowed her tongue, adding, "to whom I have not been properly introduced. Please excuse my presumption, Mr. Krum."

Krum grunted dismissively. "It happens often. Pleased to meet you, Miss Granger." He bowed over her hand, and Rigel belatedly realized she'd forgotten to do the same. Merlin, she was mucking this up. Now it looked like she didn't afford Hermione the same respect she did Delacour, at least if anyone noticed.

"Just Hermione is fine," the curly-haired witch said, flushing slightly. "We'll all be getting to know one another fairly well, I expect."

"Her-mo-ninny," Krum said carefully. "This is American name?" He was eyeing the AIM crest sewn neatly into her cloak.

Hermione's flush deepened. "No, I'm British, actually. I go to school in the United States because, well, I'm muggleborn." Her chin lifted ever-so-slightly and pride kept her voice firm.

Krum seemed more intrigued than put off by her declaration. "A long vay to travel for school, I am thinking," he said. "In Eastern Europe ve have separate schools for new bloods. Not so far from Durmstrang. Ve do not send them over the sea." He seemed to find the idea funny, though it was hard to tell, as his expression didn't change much.

"Are those schools equal to Durmstrang?" Hermione asked. "Because if they aren't, muggleborns might as well cross the ocean. AIM is nice because it's a top-notch education and they don't discriminate."

"Everyone discriminates." This comment came from a dark-skinned boy with colorfully patterned robes who was making his way steadily down the buffet table toward them. His plate was too full to add any more food, so he paused to eat the top layer down before continuing.

"What do you mean by that?" Hermione asked.

The boy had just stuffed a miniature meat pie in his mouth, and he smiled at them apologetically as he chewed. When he'd finally swallowed, he said, "Traveling so very far for school cannot be an easy thing. If a poor child also wanted to go to this school, could he afford it?" As he spoke, a small stone hanging around his neck flickered with a soft orange glow that faded when he stopped. There was a runic sequence engraved in the stone, and after a moment Rigel realized it was a translation charm. His English still held traces of stiltedness, but was altogether easier to understand than either Krum or Delacour had been at first.

Hermione had bitten her lip to think it over. She admitted, "Tuition is quite steep for foreign students. But there are scholarships."

"Not so many as there are poor children, I think," the boy said, still smiling cheerfully. Hermione was openly troubled, and the boy hesitated before biting into a fried puff. "I hope my words do not offend. I am Tahiil Diric Zahi, of Majeerteen."

Rigel and the other two offered their names in return, and Tahiil's face lit with enthusiasm at Krum's surname. "You I know of," he said, beaming. "Will they let you fly in the competition, you think?"

"Not likely," Krum said gruffly. He didn't seem pleased with his notoriety, a feeling Rigel completely sympathized with. She felt worse, suddenly, for not allowing him to introduce himself before.

"Sorry. Fly?" Hermione asked tentatively.

"You do not know?" Tahiil launched into an excited explanation, but Krum cleared his throat pointedly.

"It matters not for this tournament," he said sternly. "Ve vill be tested on our magic, not Quidditch."

"Well said." A tall, pale boy with neatly coiffed blond hair joined their group with a self-deprecating smile. "Jacob Owens. Muggleborn. From Ilvermorny. What a diverse little group we are. Makes you wonder if the selection is as impartial as claimed." He chuckled at his own joke, not seeming to notice that no one else found it very funny. His blue eyes scanned the four of them and, against the odds, settled on Rigel. "Black, isn't it?" Owens smirked. "I heard you're the one to watch."

"I can't imagine where," Rigel said, face blank and voice cool.

"Your reputation precedes you," he said, eyebrows raised innocently.

She doubted her reputation preceded her all the way to Ilvermorny. All she said was, "No doubt by the end of the tournament we will all have reputations."

"For better or vorse," Krum agreed darkly.

As Hermione opened her mouth to comment, the door to the Great Hall opened, ushering in sound and light. Riddle stood in the doorway, smiling out at the rest of them. "The public awaits, candidates. Muggleborns first, then halfbloods, and purebloods last. Swiftly, now."

The nine of them gravitated slowly toward the imposing politician. He was bedecked in resplendent blue robes as deep as the night sky that somehow made him look both youthful and wise. His eyes caught Rigel's as she waited for the others to organize themselves into a queue. She turned away casually.

Hermione stood at the front of the line, followed by Owens and Tahiil. Delacour was next, with Antiope and a very skinny boy with shaggy black hair. Krum took the lead position for the pureblood group, and a stoic-faced girl in a beautifully embroidered silk qipao stepped into line behind him, leaving Rigel to fall in at the end.

As Riddle led them into the hall in a stilted form of follow-the-leader, Rigel concentrated on the intricately looping hairstyle on the Asian girl in front of her to keep from having to look out at the sea of gaping faces. Then again, with so many new faces to concentrate on, she doubted anyone would be paying that much attention to her. Thank Circe for small favors.

The Great Hall was much brighter than it should have been on Halloween. Normally it was lit only by the glow of jack-o-lanterns, but tonight countless globes providing additional illumination floated about the ceiling instead. When she saw the press jostling for camera space between the middle two House tables, she understood why.

Riddle led them to stand in a horizontal line before the Head table, separated from the students and the reporters by only a dozen feet. She wanted to glance over at the Slytherin table, to see how Draco was managing the riotous emotions around them. She didn't want to appear nervous or distracted, however, so she settled her face into an expression of serene calm and kept her eyes straight ahead, focused on nothing in particular.

"Ladies and gentlemen of the press, students, professors, and distinguished guests, I present to you… your competitors!" Riddle's voice rose in a dramatic crescendo and the entire hall lapped it up excitedly. Applause rang up to the rafters, so loud Rigel was surprised it didn't blow the hair back from her temple. "Each of these talented, deserving individuals has won a place in the True Triwizard Tournament on their own merit. Tonight, the candidates will introduce themselves to the world, and then… the first test will be announced!"

The students of Hogwarts lost their minds. Roars, stomps, and cheers greeted Riddle's words, and Rigel couldn't help but wonder whether they were truly thrilled by the idea of nine adolescents like themselves risking their lives for months on end, or if perhaps they would have cheered anything that broke the monotony of the school year, regardless of the level of its insanity.

The mention of the first test did cause her gut to clench uneasily. It was an unwelcome reminder that all of this was real. She was in the tournament now, come monsters or mayhem.

Riddle retreated to the side and gestured for Hermione to proceed first. Out of the corner of her eye, Rigel saw the girl step forward two paces and lift her chin before saying, "I am Hermione Granger. British native, but schooled at the American Institute of Magic, where I am in the Healing Track. I am pleased to be chosen to participate in this tournament and proud to represent muggleborns everywhere. Thank you."

Uncertain applause broke out as Hermione waited patiently for the photographers to finish snapping photos. Rigel joined in the applause firmly and heard the other candidates join in after a moment's pause. Hermione stepped back into line, and Owens stepped up next, flashing a broad smile at the assemblage and even lifting a hand to wave as though the applause had already begun. "Jacob Owens, born and raised in the United States. I attend Ilvermorny, in the Horned Serpent House, and hope to pursue a career in International Relations following my graduation this spring. Winning this tournament would be a great honor, and I am humbled by the chance to compete. Thank you." He bowed upon concluding his remarks, but the degree was overdone and Rigel didn't think he truly understood how it would be perceived. Nonetheless, polite applause won out and Owens, too, stepped back.

It went on in that vein, with Tahiil cheerfully introducing himself, Delacour proudly proclaiming a quarter-Veela heritage, and Antiope stiffly intoning the honor and glory she intended to win for her school. The final halfblood candidate spoke with a lilt that rose and fell like water over stone, introducing himself as Matheus Sousa. "I am from Brazil, going to Castelobruxo, so this weather I do not love so much, but I look forward to see what else England has to show." His short speech and laid-back grin won him more than a few giggles, and Rigel doubted the smooth way he tossed his hair back as the cameras flashed was unrehearsed.

Krum stepped forward as Sousa's applause was dying out, and the noise ratcheted up again immediately. He waited for the hall to quiet slightly before saying, "I am Victor Krum, of Bulgaria, representing Durmstrang Institute. It is my honor to demonstrate the strength of my school in the tournament, and I vill strive to prove myself equal to the challenges that await."

Rigel found it interesting that he, too, seemed to be more interested in promoting his school than his blood purity. Perhaps he assumed that went without saying, or perhaps he was truly interested in the tournament for other reasons.

The girl beside Rigel waited patiently for Krum's supporters to cease their wild cheering before advancing with demure steps, taking four to everyone else's two. "Good evening. I am called Shang Feiyan." Her voice was soft and melodic, and the way she said her own name was like a brief song itself. "I come from the great Middle Kingdom, where the line of the Yellow Emperor is unbroken for ten thousand years. His Majesty send me as emissary to plant the seed of harmony in foreign soil and reveal the Han splendor to the world." With her right palm clasped over her left fist, she bowed her head, slowly and smoothly, the loops in her hair swinging forward gently as she did. It wasn't until she began sliding backwards that people realized she'd finished speaking and began to applaud again. Rigel waited a few moments to allow her the accolade before stepping forward herself.

For a moment, she blanked. What was there to say, really? She wasn't honored to be participating and she didn't look forward to the challenge. She didn't truly reporesent anyone, though she supposed she owed the students of Hogwarts something for having, however unwillingly, denied any of them a chance to compete on their own.

"I'm Rigel Black," she said finally, blinking out at the sea of expectant faces. "I'll do my best. Thank you."

She stepped back quickly, despite the raucous cheers and whistles that followed her. Against her better judgment, she let her eyes scan the hall just once, and found a great many students actually on their feet as they shouted and clapped. The Weasley twins had signs. One read, 'We Love Black Magic!' and the other, 'Give 'Em A Black Eye!' She suppressed a snort and turned her eyes to the Slytherin table. Every one of her housemates was on their feet. While they didn't scream as loudly or wave their arms as wildly as the other tables, the Slytherins, to a one, looked proud. She swallowed and felt a little guilty for her underwhelming introduction. When she caught sight of Pansy's indulgent smile and Draco's fond but exasperated expression, she changed her mind. Her house knew who she was. No amount of posturing could change that now.

"Yes, thank you, candidates." Riddle was back at the forefront, smiling with all the charm at his disposal. "And a sincere thank you to our selection committee. It could not have been easy narrowing thousands of candidates world-wide down to just a few worthy individuals. Now that we have our contestants, I shall announce the first trial!" After the requisite applause, Riddle continued, his voice pitched low to elevate the intrigue of the crowd. "In precisely one fortnight, under the full moon, these nine candidates will venture into the Dark Forest and retrieve… a certain item. They will face a plethora of creatures native to the forest, as well as a few special additions. Only the candidates who succeed in evading every trap and snare, defeat the creatures they encounter, and return with their prize before the time runs out will prevail."

Murmurs and fearful exclamations met this pronouncement. Riddle looked all too pleased at the reaction. "Come now, you didn't think we'd make it easy, did you?" His amusement found a faint echo in soft chuckles around the hall. Somehow, Riddle made them forget their momentary horror and the tension in the room relaxed noticeably. "One last round of applause for our candidates! Thank you all for your attention this Samhain's Eve. Good evening."

Riddle swept from the hall, the members of the press tripping after him hastily. Dumbledore stood from his seat at the Head table and said, "Students, you are to treat these eight young guests with courtesy and respect while they reside among us. The house elves have been kind enough to prepare four rooms in the staff wing for their stay, and I trust that no student will be found loitering or otherwise trespassing upon their privacy." Rigel thought it was rather astute of him to nip any thoughts of stalking or otherwise spying on the other candidates in the bud at once. "Candidates, welcome to Hogwarts," he went on, his tone much warmer. "While you are excused from your own classes due to the nature of this event, you are welcome to attend any class here that piques your interest. Our esteemed Professor McGonagall will now show you to your chambers and handle any requests or requirements for the duration of your stay."

McGonagall stood from the staff table and made her way toward the Entrance Hall, the majority of the other candidates following hesitantly. Hermione caught Rigel's eye and smiled. She smiled back, even lifted her hand to wave so it was clear to anyone who cared to look that she knew and liked the girl.

The students began to leave themselves once it was clear the excitement had well and truly ended, and Rigel fell in with the Slytherins, trying to pretend she wasn't monumentally out of place in Draco's costly dress robes. Everyone who passed her wanted to shake her hand or clasp her shoulder in congratulations. Though she caught some envious looks, there didn't seem to be any deeply resentful or aggrieved expressions. Maybe, she thought with the smallest amount of hope, this wouldn't be so bad.

Chapter 8

The day following Halloween, Rigel was ambushed in her own common room. The perpetrator, a petite blonde girl with soft blue eyes and a no-nonsense expression, barred her way to the common room entrance with the force of her gaze alone. She gave no care to Rigel's protests that she had brewing to do, ushering her instead toward a low-backed couch by one of the fireplaces. Rigel sank slowly into the cushions, despair creeping into her soul. Her ingredients would shrivel in disuse, she insisted, and her knifes would get up to mischief if left alone too long. Her cautionary words were met with an unimpressed stare as her tormenter arranged a stack of folders on the table before them. When Rigel suggested that her cauldron might be missing her, Pansy fixed her with an exasperated frown.

"Rigel, this is important. I promise you can go brew when we're finished."

"We?"

"Millie is helping, too," Pansy said. "There she is." She waved the dark haired girl over and motioned for Rigel to make room for her on her other side.

She shifted toward the middle of the couch, feeling very much as though she'd walked into a trap she couldn't see yet. Millicent came armed with yet another stack of folders, which she arranged beside Pansy's. "Are we studying for something I'm not aware of?" Rigel asked, looking blankly at all the parchment before her.

"Yes and no," Pansy said, smiling serenely at her. "These are dossiers."

"Dossiers," Rigel repeated. "On… me?" Morgana, she hoped there didn't exist so much information on her in the world.

Millicent snorted. "On your competition, Rigel. Obviously."

"Obviously," she muttered, sighing. She was not going to have time to brew today after all. Not if she wanted to make it to Draco's dueling club later that afternoon as well.

"First up, the other purebloods. They are your biggest competition until the preliminaries are over. Victor Krum you've probably heard of, but don't think his Quidditch ability is the only thing going for him." Millicent pulled the file on top of her pile toward her and opened it. "This is a collection of his stats from last season. Ignoring the ones exclusive to Quidditch, his agility and reflexes are well above average, even for a professional Quidditch player. His training reports all note that Krum is absolutely ruthless when going after the snitch, so we can expect him to be pretty cutthroat in the tournament as well."

"How are you getting this information?" she asked, a bit alarmed. "And when? The participants were only announced last night."

"Here and there." Millicent shrugged. "A lot of it is public record. And we've been compiling information on the most likely candidates in each category since the committee began taking submissions."

"I thought the committee's process was confidential," Rigel said.

Millicent cleared her throat, but pointedly did not answer the unspoken question. "In any case, let's look at his academic performance now. Krum is quite gifted at Transfiguration and the Dark Arts, by all accounts. Don't look so alarmed," she added, seeing Rigel's uneasy face. "Dark Arts is what they call Defense Against the Dark Arts at Durmstrang. They do teach the theory and some practical uses of the Dark Arts to the upper years, but most of the curriculum is just like ours—familiarization and protection against it. Now, Krum is highly favored by his Headmaster, which is likely how he was selected as the Durmstrang representative. That said, his own family has a good deal of influence in Bulgarian politics as well. Got all that?"

Rigel must have nodded without realizing it, as Pansy was quick to move on.

"Next we have Feiyan Shang," Pansy said, picking up a file of her own. "You can read about each of them in more detail tonight, and we'll quiz you at breakfast tomorrow." That sounded like an awful use of her time, but Rigel knew better than to argue with Pansy while she was in the midst of an explanation. "Shang is arguably the most pureblooded candidate in the competition. She might have the purest blood in the country right now, in fact. It's difficult to say, because Chinese records any older than the Qin dynasty are notoriously difficult to verify. Her family claims to date back to the Shang dynasty, of the great Nuxiu's line, and rumor has it she may also be descendent from Qin Shi Huang himself on her mother's side."

Millicent broke in. "No one can prove that, of course, as the ancient wizard went into hiding after faking his death and his descendants lived in obscurity to protect the secrets of their magical heritage."

"Just so," Pansy agreed. "Still, she is not someone you want to offend. Her father is a public figure in the court of the Chinese high mystics. As to her personal skills, we don't know much. Chinese wizards tend to specialize in Herbology, Potions, Runes, and Alchemy, but we're still working to gather information on Shang's particular strengths. There is no established magical school for China, as families tend to train their own sons and daughters exclusively, so we're relying on Millie's international connections and certain other students with foreign affiliations for information on her."

"What about muggleborns?" Rigel asked, frowning. "Do they not get schooled?"

"There is some debate," Millicent said, grimacing back at her. "The Chinese claim there are no muggleborns in their country. Some scholars suspect that anyone discovered with magical ability in China who is not of the established lines is either adopted into one or made to… disappear. China is one of the few countries where the muggle government is not appraised of the existence of magic at all, so it's a lot harder to hold their wizards accountable for their interactions with the muggle community."

Rigel felt sickened. If that were true, it meant blood inequality was not only prevalent outside of Magical Britain, but worse in at least one place.

"As you know, the next candidate, Fleur Delacour, is one quarter Veela, which is why she was placed in the halfblood category instead of the pureblood. She is one of Beauxbatons' top students, and her motivations for entering likely rest on the promised world tour. She has repeatedly expressed the ambition to travel and learn other languages among her close friends."

"How do you know this?" Rigel asked again. "Pansy, tell me true: are you a Legilimens?"

"Legilimency is such a touch-and-go art," Pansy said airily. "People lie to themselves, too, you know. There is little information that careful questioning of multiple reliable sources can't confirm, however. Where was I? Delacour is particularly adept at Charms and Care of Magical Creatures, with a strong interest in Curses and Countercurses that is bolstered by a relatively high level of natural intelligence. Then there is her Veela Charm. It's weak, compared to a fully fledged Veela, but it will distract you if you let it."

"Noted." Rigel would keep her Occlumency strong in Delacour's vicinity.

"Now Matheus Sousa," Millicent said. She waggled her eyebrows. "It is currently unclear how he was selected for this competition. He had glowing recommendations in his application package, but according to a couple of witches I know at Castelobruxo, Sousa is persona non grata there. He's apparently quite gifted, but hardly attends classes. He's some kind of potions prodigy, to hear these two tell it, but they also say he's been repeatedly caught with contraband ingredients and is always causing trouble for the school. Still, you can expect him to be knowledgeable about Herbology and Potions, and he may be at an advantage in the first task, as his school is situated in the Amazon jungle, somewhere in the northern part of Brazil."

"The last halfblood is Antiope, born Aileen Ross, originally from Scotland," Pansy said, reading off the respective file. "Apparently, she's related to Professor McGonagall through the professor's maternal line. McGonagall's grandmother attended Chalcioecus and became one of the Athenai with the name Minerva. That name was passed down to our professor, though she declined to attend Chalcioecus herself. Antiope's school is on an unplottable acropolis in Laconia, and what we know for sure is it's all-female and emphasizes the manifestations of Athena in its teachings."

"Scholar, warrior, maiden," Rigel recited. "I can certainly see the warrior aspect. Antiope is very straightforward and quick to rise at any perceived slight."

"Yes, she's likely extremely competitive," Pansy agreed. "She'll be well-trained in Charms and Transfiguration, and her Dueling will be flawless. We've gathered that Chalcioecus doesn't focus on Arithmancy, Runes, or Alchemy, as those are viewed as male arts and largely emphasized in the equivalent all-boys school in Laconia."

"The competition may not test those subjects in any case," Rigel said thoughtfully. "Charms, Defense, Transfigurations—those are the showy fields, and people will expect the tasks to focus around them."

"True," Pansy allowed. "Now the muggleborns. Millie?"

Millicent frowned at the file in her hand. "Jacob Owens. The other candidates all submitted family trees back several generations at least, so that the tournament coordinators could verify blood status against public records, but he didn't submit anything for his family. I suppose they figured as a muggleborn it wasn't necessary. His grades are consistently good, extracurriculars an impressive mix of academic and athletic, and those who know him at school say he's well-liked and rather boring."

"So what's the problem?" Rigel asked, eyeing her unsatisfied expression.

"Boring people don't end up in international tournaments, generally," she said, scowling. "I just have a feeling he's too good to be true. I'll keep digging."

"Next is Hermione Granger—" Pansy began.

"Don't," Rigel said firmly. "She's a friend."

"Why should that matter?" Pansy asked, raising her eyebrows.

"It's a competition, Rigel," Millicent reminded her.

"Hermione isn't used to this sort of thing—politics and rumors and people digging into your background for no other reason than to better understand you. If she knew I was doing this, it would make her uncomfortable, and I care if she is uncomfortable."

Pansy's eyebrows managed to climb higher, but she put the file aside without another word and moved on. "The last one is Tahiil Diric Zahi from Majeerteen. At first we thought he was representing Uagadou, but he's not registered as a student there. Millie believes he's likely from one of the smaller villages within the Majeerteen Sultanate, but obviously not actually part of the Majeerteen Clan itself, or he would have received an invitation to Uagadou."

"It doesn't help that Somalis don't keep traditional records with family surnames," Millicent complained. "Just knowing that Tahiil's father's name was Diric and his grandfather's Zahi isn't enough to really pinpoint his origin. As far as abilities, though, he will have been trained by his village elders if any were magical. Otherwise, he'll be self-taught. It's strange that he'd even have heard about the tournament, not being affiliated with any major magical school and without apparent political connections to pass the word. We'll keep an eye on him as well, just in case."

The two girls looked at her expectantly, so Rigel said, "Thank you for putting all that together. I'm sure it was a lot of work, and I appreciate your help."

Pansy fixed her with stern look. "We will be quizzing you. Read the rest of it, Rigel."

She conjured a fabulously insincere smile. "At the very first opportunity."

Millicent laughed. "See, this is why you get sat down like a child and lectured to—because we know you won't read any of it on your own."

Rigel gave up a sheepish grin. "I am grateful to have friends who know me so well. I know you guys are working hard to help me succeed. Sorry if I don't seem appreciative."

"We don't need you to be appreciative," Pansy said, eyes fond. "We just want you to survive this tournament. We can't help you once you're out there in the forest, but we can help you prepare. Draco has already written his father this morning, demanding information on the upcoming tasks for you. Edmund is putting together a compendium of magical creatures used in past tournaments similar to this one. Blaise was looking secretive, but I know he's got an idea or two as well. The point is: you're not alone in this."

She felt a warmth in her chest like the sun coming out from behind a cloud. "Thank you," she said, wishing she knew how to convey the depth of her appreciation in a way that wasn't foolish.

Millicent rose, fanning herself sardonically. "Stop, Rigel. You're making me blush."

Rigel laughed. "It's a curse," she told the girl. She helped Pansy collect the stack of folders, but plucked Hermione's out and requested, "Burn this, please. I'm sorry you went to the trouble."

Pansy pursed her lips, but nodded, accepting the folder back while Rigel carried the rest of them toward her dorm room. Draco was sprawled on his four-poster, scrawling furiously on a piece of parchment, ink flying precariously close to his face.

"What did that essay ever do to you?" she asked, amused.

He looked up distractedly, and she saw there was indeed a drop of ink on his cheek. "It's a letter."

"Someone must have offended you grievously," Rigel remarked, eyeing the disheveled handwriting. "It looks like you poked through the parchment in several places."

Draco blinked and scanned the page, scowling. "Damn. I'll have to rewrite it." He pushed it aside with a sigh and stood with a stretch. "Pansy give you the rundown, then? She's been waiting all week for the announcement so she could impress you with her investigatory skills."

"Really?" Rigel frowned down at the folders she'd dumped on her bed. "I'm afraid I could have been less churlish about listening."

"She won't be offended," Draco said, waving off her guilt. "Pansy gets you."

Rigel sort of doubted that, but she did think it was sweet of her friend to try. Now that the folders were dealt with, she gathered her bag once more and was about to walk out of the dorm when Draco stopped her.

"You're not going to your lab now, are you?" He looked quite put out at the idea. "It's the first Dueling Club meeting today."

"I remember," Rigel said, adjusting the strap on her bag. "It isn't for another hour, right?"

"So you were going to brew a potion in the next forty-five minutes?" Draco's voice was dripping with sarcasm. "What are you working on? A Boil Cure?"

She made a face at him. "I was thinking I could at least get the cauldron treated and the ingredients set up—"

"Or you could come with me to set up for the meeting," Draco suggested. His eyes widened entreatingly and the hopeful smile on his face was pure, unregulated warfare.

Rigel felt her shoulders droop. Brewing would have to wait until that evening, it seemed. "Sure, Dray. What are you planning for this one?"

Draco's face was a picture of contentedness as he told her of his plans. He didn't seem entirely sure how many people were going to attend, which was one of the reasons he wanted to get there early. Chances were at least a few people would have trouble finding the place. That, at least, Rigel could help with.

She walked with her friend to the seventh floor, but told him to go ahead inside and get it set up while she watched the door. "I'll make sure no one gets in who shouldn't," she promised. "You gave them all a password, right?"

"Duck Agency," he said, a bit embarrassed. "It was Pansy's idea. Every week it'll be something innocuous or silly that D.A. could stand for."

"Duck Agency it is," Rigel said, smiling. "Do you think I can convince Ron he has to quack to get inside?"

Draco's eyes lit up with humor. "I'll give you a Sickle if you can." He disappeared into the Come and Go Room, and Rigel took up a station outside. She'd told Draco she was going to practice using her sensing ability to monitor anyone approaching, but in reality she wasn't skilled enough to tell the difference between individual people, yet, so she took out the Marauder's Map and let her eyes roam over the hallways around her.

The first to arrive was Pansy, of course, and she smiled at Rigel as she approached. "Has he worked himself into a nervous frenzy?" she asked.

"If he hasn't rearranged the room three times by now, that boy isn't Draco Malfoy," Rigel said. "Calm him down, won't you?"

"Don't ask me for miracles." Nevertheless Rigel knew Pansy would try.

The Weasleys arrived next, Ron apparently engaged in a furious argument with his older brothers over whether or not Draco was having him on.

"You can walk about all day, but we're telling you, Ron," Fred was saying quietly.

"There is no room in this corridor," George agreed. "We've been over every inch of this castle."

"Well, it doesn't hurt to look again," Ron said. He spotted Rigel loitering and broke into a jog. "Rigel! Tell these two that there really is a… Duck Agency up here."

Rigel gave her best mysterious smile. "Only if you say it in Duck."

"What?" Ron's face began to turn red. "Look, is this a joke or not?"

"Quack?" Rigel said, tilting her head in affected confusion. "Quack quack?"

"Uh…quack." Ron muttered weakly, looking entirely certain that he was being pranked.

"Right this way," Rigel said, stepping to the side and gesturing to the nondescript door behind her. The twins had caught up to their brother at this point, but had nothing to say as Ron pushed the door open and revealed the cavernous space beyond.

"Blimey. This is brilliant," he said, flashing Rigel a grin. He disappeared inside and Rigel turned expectant eyes on the other two.

"Are you here for the Duck Agency?" she asked, smiling at their dumbfounded confusion.

"This was not here before," Fred declared.

"Did you somehow conjure a new room inside Hogwarts?" George asked, staring at her.

"What? No. Why do people keep assuming…?" Rigel shook her head with a laugh. "This has been here all along. It's normally hidden, though."

Their faces cleared in understanding. "There's a password?" Fred said excitedly. "Or a secret action? Like the kitchens!"

"Almost," Rigel agreed. She leaned closer and lowered her voice. "I'll tell you the secret, if and only if you promise to use it well."

"We promise," George vowed, taking Fred's hand and placing it over his own heart. "Tell us, oh wise one."

"The room only comes to those who need it," Rigel revealed, quite enjoying herself. "If you have something you require, simply walk past this stretch of wall three times while thinking of what you need, and the Room of Requirement will appear with whatever it is."

Their eyes were like saucers. "It…changes?" George sucked in a breath. He and Fred exchanged a glance and they both exhaled. "Wicked."

She bowed them through the doors and resumed her monitoring of the map. Closer to the appointed time, regulars of last year's club began trickling toward her station. Some, particularly the older students like Rosier and Rookwood, were surprised by the presence of a room along a corridor they had walked before, but most simply shrugged it off as one of Hogwarts' eccentricities.

Neville brought Seamus Finnegan, Parvati Patil, and her sister, Padma. Angelina Johnson came with Alicia Spinnet, and Katie Bell brought Cormac McLaggen. Ginny came blazing down the hallway with a harried-looking Michael Corner at her heels, and Rigel couldn't tell exactly what the look the redhead shot her was supposed to convey, but she got the feeling she hadn't planned to bring the Ravenclaw boy. Also from Ravenclaw came Terry Boot and Anthony Goldstein, neither of which seemed entirely certain of their decision to be there as they hesitantly asked about the 'Duck Agency' meeting place.

Cedric Diggory came, accompanied by a skeptical looking Zacharias Smith and Ernie Macmillan. Susan Bones trailed behind them with a nervous Hannah Abbott. All five Hufflepuffs bid her good day, though she noted Smith and Macmillan were not wholly sincere. Diggory hung back and gave her a rueful smile when his housemates had gone through the door.

"Congratulations on being chosen for the tournament, Black," he said. He looked like he meant it, so she smiled and thanked him. "Sorry about the others," he added, ducking his head with a boyish charm. "They were rooting for me, but I've told them you're a good choice, too."

"It's quite all right," she assured him. "I didn't expect to have everyone's support. I'm only a fourth year, after all."

"Age isn't everything," Diggory disagreed. "Good luck."

She thanked him again, and he joined the others inside. She glanced down at the map, thinking that just about everyone she'd expected, and a few she hadn't, had already arrived. It was nearing the appointed hour, and she was considering leaving her post and asking the room to hide the door when she caught sight of Zhou several corridors over on the map, wandering somewhat aimlessly.

There was no one else nearby on the seventh floor, so Rigel took off at a brisk walk toward the older girl's location. She found her examining a tapestry with a frown. "Zhou," she called, waving the girl over. "Are you looking for the club?"

"Rigel!" She was openly relived. "Yes. I know you gave me directions, but I can't remember which tapestry I was looking for."

"I'll take you." Rigel led her back toward the Come and Go Room. "It's great you decided to come."

"I really do need the practice," Zhou murmured embarrassedly. "Thanks again for inviting me."

"You're welcome," Rigel said easily. When they reached the room, Rigel sent the Ravenclaw inside and checked the map one last time for any stragglers before slipping into the room and asking it to seal the door behind her.

Draco had created an open hall with a high ceiling. Stacks of cushions stood next to a teaching dummy in the middle of the floor, and the students who'd come to the meeting stood in a loose circle around her friend. Rigel raised her hand and gave him the thumbs up to signal that everyone was present, then joined the circle unobtrusively and watched Draco take charge of the room.

"Now that we're all here, welcome to the Dueling Association. If you've been invited to this meeting, you're either a member of last year's club that was unfortunately disbanded or you've expressed an interest in extracurricular Dueling practice." Draco looked around the room with appraising eyes. "To be perfectly clear, this club is not official, and, if the faculty gets wind of it, will be banned in a heartbeat, so I'm asking everyone here to sign this parchment before we begin." He held up a roll of parchment so everyone could see. "This is a binding agreement to keep the location and existence of this club a secret unless given permission by myself, Pansy Parkinson, or Rigel Black to divulge it. Everyone will sign it before leaving this room, regardless of whether or not you intend to continue attending club meetings in the future."

There were a few grumbling complaints, but Draco cut them off.

"You were all made aware of this stipulation when you were invited to the club, so there's no use complaining now," he said loudly. "Line up and sign, then we will begin."

The Weasley Twins were the first in line. At Draco's raised eyebrow, George shrugged. "Seeing this place, we totally understand why you want it kept secret. Signing this is well worth learning such a useful secret about the castle."

Their argument proved persuasive, as the others all proceeded to sign the parchment with more or less good grace.

Draco handed the parchment off to Pansy, who tucked it away. "Great," he said, clapping his hands. "For those of you who were with us last year, you know we usually start with stretching and agility drills, then footwork patterns, and finally practice duels. Since there are so many new faces, however, we're going to split the group in half. Experienced duelers who know the basic footwork and are familiar with at least a few structured spell combinations, to this side of the hall; beginners and those less confident in their skills, to the other."

The students began to sort themselves, though there were more among the two dozen or so who self-identified as advanced than there were beginners. Seeing this, Draco grimaced. "All right, those of you in the advanced group who weren't part of the club last year, speak to Ron Weasley about your level of experience. He'll determine which group you start in. Pansy, you're with the beginners. Go easy on them."

Pansy smiled angelically, and Rigel could see the exact moment several newcomers decided to underestimate her. She almost felt sorry for the fools. Almost. Rigel stayed with the advanced group while Draco outlined his plan for the first term. "The idea is to holistically improve everyone's dueling. To do this, I'm going to be evaluating you for the first few meetings based on random pairings. Once I have a good grasp of strengths and weaknesses, I'll determine the matches going forward in order to force people into confronting styles they aren't as comfortable with. Each meeting, we'll learn a new technique, footwork pattern, or spell and I'll ask you to apply it in your duels. If there is anything in particular you want to learn, bring it to me before or after the session and I'll do my best to work it in. Any questions so far?"

"What qualifies you to teach the club?" Diggory asked. His face was friendly, but his eyes flickered to the back of Macmillan's head as he said it, which told Rigel he was probably asking the question on everyone's mind before the younger Hufflepuff could make a snide remark about it.

"In addition to scoring top in my year in last year's Dueling class, I spent all of last year running the club and most of the summer devising lesson plans and studying advanced dueling techniques from around the world." Draco's voice was even as he said this, not irritated or haughty in the least, and Rigel had to be proud of her friend. He'd come a long way from the boy who had provoked Ron into shooting a jelly-brains jinx at him in first year.

"I can vouch for his ability," Rookwood offered. "We improved a lot last year under Draco's tutelage."

Draco kept his expression blank, but the flush of color along his collar betrayed his embarrassed pleasure at the praise. He really could be rather self-conscious, for someone who acted so self-assured, she reflected.

"Excellent," Diggory said cheerfully. "I retract my question and look forward to learning from you."

"Anyone else? No? We'll get started then. Ron, have you got them sorted?" Draco looked to the tall redhead who had his arms folded stubbornly as he stared down his housemate, Cormac McLaggen.

"McLaggen was just about to join the other group." Ron's face was set, but McLaggen seemed to have no intention of doing any such thing.

"I'm not a beginner," he insisted. "Just because I didn't take the class or join your club last year, doesn't mean I don't know anything about dueling. I went to Dueling Camp when I was twelve."

"You need a proper refresher before jumping into the advanced group," Ron told him. "You can move back as soon as Parkinson says so. This is necessary so you don't end up injured, all right?"

"What if I beat Parkinson in a duel?" the older boy demanded. "Then can I stay in this group?"

"Mate, I can barely beat Parkinson in a duel," Ron said, shaking his head. "Trust me, you do not want to do that."

"It doesn't sound like any of you fourth years are qualified to teach this club. Why don't we take a vote and let one of the seventh years take over?" McLaggen looked around for support, but even the newcomers appeared unsure.

"You don't have to stay, McLaggen," Aldon drawled. "And you certainly weren't invited here to insult our club president."

"That's all right, Aldon," Draco said, looking resigned. "Why don't we have a little demonstration, to ease McLaggen's mind?"

"I'm up for it," McLaggen declared.

"No, I wouldn't duel a beginner," Draco said archly. "It wouldn't be fair. I'll duel Ron. Or Pansy if you like. Since you questioned both of their abilities."

McLaggen scowled, but didn't say anything. Perhaps he realized he'd dug himself into an uncomfortable position.

"Duel Black," Zacharias Smith said loudly.

"I'm not an instructor," Rigel protested.

"Black is the Hogwarts champion, right? I'm sure a lot of us are curious as to what he's capable of," Smith reasoned. "And he's in the advanced group, so it should be no trouble for your conscience, Malfoy."

Rigel waited for Draco to refuse, but instead found him looking consideringly at her. She widened her eyes in a mild glare, lest he have any doubts as to her willingness to participate. While he was thinking, other people chimed in.

"I'd watch that!"

"Let's see the champion duel!"

They'd caught the attention of the beginner's group, too, and now Pansy had come over to see what was going on. "Rigel, Draco, are you dueling?"

"Mr. McLaggen has requested a demonstration of my ability to run this club," Draco informed her.

"Well, there's no better test than a duel with Rigel," Pansy said slowly. "He's by far the trickiest of the group."

"Thanks, Pan." Rigel sighed. There didn't seem to be any getting out of it, with Pansy and Draco in agreement. She stretched her arms out as the students backed away from the center of the hall to give them space. She hadn't dueled Draco since the previous spring. He'd spent the entire summer practicing—but then, so had she. If she could remember not to use any of her freedueling tricks, she would surprise him.

Ron stood as mediator, and when Rigel and Draco had exchanged formal bows, he called for them to begin.

Draco sprang backwards, but Rigel darted forward just as fast. Her friend was more comfortable with a ranged exchange, so she would take the duel to close quarters as often as possible. He spun on perfect footwork around her first spell, but she'd anticipated and already sent a silent Incarcerous to the side after him.

The blond boy muttered a severing curse without pausing, and his unhesitant steps took him directly behind her. Rigel pivoted and raised a shield between them just in time for it to intercept Draco's stunner. She dropped it as soon as the spell dissipated and ran forward after Draco's retreating form. He shot two Relashios in an effort to slow her advance, and Rigel darted in a quick zigzag to avoid them. Draco's next spell came at her feet—a tripping jinx—but Rigel launched herself over it in an athletic leap that would bring her within three paces of her opponent. At the apex of her jump, she overpowered a Lumos directly into Draco's face.

He swore and rolled to the side to avoid her follow-up stunner while blindly erecting a shield between them. He held it while wiping at his eyes with his non-dominant hand. Rigel repositioned herself patiently, slowly stalking in a circle around him, and she heard someone mutter, "Merlin's teats, that was fast" from their audience.

Draco shook his head, blinking quickly. "That was cruel, Rigel."

"Buck up, Dray. We're just getting started," she said with a small smile. She knew her friend could do better. Quick as a snake, Draco shot a Reducto so powerful it blasted through his own shield before continuing toward her in a dark cloud of sheer destruction. Narrowing her eyes, Rigel charged toward it while projecting a Fortis before her like a battering ram. The Reducto parted like water against her shield, and she saw Draco's eyes widen as he leapt sideways to avoid being knocked backward. Rigel thrust her wand hand forward as she dove after him. She rolled on her back and shoulders, and the Fortis rolled with her.

Draco wasn't fast enough to escape the Bubble of Doom, and the force of her sideways momentum knocked him to the ground. A smattering of shocked laughter broke out around them, but Rigel was too intent on pressing her advantage to enjoy it. She broke the Fortis and fired off three stunners in quick succession. She'd been working with Snape to shave off wand movements, so her spells came faster than ever, but Draco's reflexes had improved, too. He blocked the first two and rolled backwards to avoid the third, springing off the ground with one hand and regaining his feet to a round of spontaneous applause from the spectators.

"You've been practicing your floor work," she commented.

Draco's answer was a Flipendo that Rigel had to bat out of her way with a quick Relashio. He went on the offensive with a series of fast spells, and Rigel was pleased to see Draco's repertoire had expanded in the last few months. Among the ordinary dueling spells to disable he sprinkled charms to distract and hinder. A blast of wind from a concentrated weather charm pushed Rigel backwards several feet before she dispersed it with a Ventus cast in counter-rotation. He used her momentary delay to conjure two paper crows and set them on her with Oppungo.

"Incendio!" She met the birds midway with fire and followed it up with a second, "Incendio," before their ashes hit the floor. At least, she said Incendio. Her wand was actually casting an overpowered Flagrate, however, and while a line of fire arched through the air toward Draco, the marking spell wouldn't really hurt him.

Draco didn't recognize the difference in time. His ears heard 'Incendio' and he was casting Aguamenti automatically before he could help himself. Her Freezing Charm met the water on the ground, and an "Accio Draco," was all it took to force her friend forward into it. His feet couldn't find purchase on the ice to resist the Summoning Charm, and he came slipping toward her, right through the line of harmless fire still hanging in the air. Off balance, he shielded instead of attacking, and that was his undoing.

Rigel hit him with a Weightless Charm that attached itself to his shield instead of dispersing against it—only a Depasco could stop a Weightless Charm from taking effect. Her follow-up Flipendo sent Draco shooting upwards like a balloon—up, up he flew until his shield nudged the ceiling and his momentum reversed. He glared down at her from his gently descending bubble, clearly tempted to drop his shield to get rid of the Weightless Charm and risk a nasty fall to the ground.

"Don't do it, Draco," she called, stalking slowly toward him. "I'll stun you as soon as the shield is gone, and I won't cushion your fall."

"Pansy will," he called back, arms folded.

"Interference will cost you the match anyway," Rigel said. She was nearly beneath the agonizingly slow-falling boy-balloon now, and it was the work of few moments to apply a Sticking Charm to the floor where he would land. Draco's shield charm carried him almost lovingly into her trap, which held him fast even as he finally let go of his shield. He tried to get a few more spells off, but with nowhere to maneuver, he was easy to overpower. She caught him with a Petrificus Totalus and disarmed him neatly.

"Winner, Rigel Black," Ron declared, somewhat unnecessarily. The applause was raucous, and most of the students seemed impressed and excited. Good, she thought. They ought to leave Draco be, now. "Good match, you two," Ron added as she returned Draco's wand and they shook hands. "You could have let Draco win, though."

"He'd never forgive me," Rigel said, smiling apologetically at her friend.

Draco shrugged. "I knew when I agreed to the duel that you would beat me."

"Why not duel one of us, then?" Ron asked. "I thought you were trying to prove your leadership."

"A good leader isn't afraid to lose in front of his subordinates," Draco said, tilting his nose up in affected arrogance. After a moment, he broke into a smile. "Also, it was more important for people to believe in Rigel than for them to respect me. Rigel is Hogwarts' champion, after all. This was an opportunity too good to pass up."

Rigel rolled her eyes. "Not you, too. Soon I'll have an entire team of self-appointed public relations experts."

"Draco is correct," Pansy said, joining their huddle. "A lot more of them will support you in the tournament, now. Good job, you two."

"I had no idea you could use the Fortis like a bludgeon," Ron said. "You'll have to teach us that one."

Rigel was about to agree, when a frisson of awareness behind her caught her attention entirely. She snapped her left wrist and palmed the knife in her sleeve, smoothly raising it in the same motion to block the spell that had been shot at her back without looking. All conversation stopped as Rigel slowly turned her head to see Fred staring at her with wide eyes.

"Uh…It was only a Glow Charm," the redhead stammered. "To make you look saint-like. George bet me you wouldn't block it, and I thought it would be funny…" He trailed off uncomfortably.

Rigel looked down at her now-glowing knife and smiled, shaking off her tension. "No worries. I hope you didn't bet anything big, George."

George shook his head with an amazed whistle. "I wasn't that sure you'd miss it. Some reflexes, Rigel."

She grinned. Her sensing ability had been coming along of late. She was almost ready to begin free brewing, but had to keep it up unconsciously for an entire week before Snape would be satisfied. She could feel all the magic in the room, even though she couldn't quite distinguish between individual people or spells unless she concentrated hard.

"Rigel, why are you carrying that?" Pansy said, frowning. "If you use it in the tournament during a duel, you'll be disqualified."

"Better disqualified than dead," she said reasonably. "Anyway, the duel was over at that point."

"Still," Draco said, eyeing the knife thoughtfully, "I'll ask my father about procuring some gauntlets for you. They're considered defensive, so they should be allowed."

"My knife is defensive," she offered. Not one of her friends seemed impressed with that logic. She tucked it away, and looked around. Some of her classmates had alarmed expressions on their faces, but mostly they just seemed intrigued. She suppressed a sigh.

Diggory was the first to break the awkward silence that had fallen over the room. "Well, I for one am ready to learn some Dueling. Satisfied McLaggen?"

"They seem to have some idea what they're doing," the Gryffindor boy said, shrugging. "Let's get on with it, then."

"If that isn't a glowing 'thank you for the demonstration, Malfoy,' I doubt I've ever heard one," Diggory said happily.

Draco snorted. "All right. Beginners back to Pansy. You're going to start with the Colouris exercises, and no more arguments. Nobody gets good at dueling overnight. Advanced group—get stretching."

Rigel rolled her shoulders and winced as a bruise made itself known on her back. She must have landed harder than she realized when she was rolling. She poked at it gingerly. A tap on her shoulder made her look over to see Zhou standing hesitantly beside her.

"Did you injure yourself? I can heal it, if you like," the dark haired girl offered.

Rigel grimaced. "It's just a bruise, I think. I'll get to it later."

"It's harder to heal your own back," Zhou pointed out. At Rigel's reluctant expression, she added, "It won't take but a minute. I can do it right through your robes."

"Thanks, Zhou," she said quietly. "I don't think it's serious, though. I appreciate the offer."

"Oh, all right." The Ravenclaw smiled weakly and headed back over to the beginner's group, where Pansy was explaining the Colouris-Eradere game they would be focusing on for a few meetings.

"Why did you invite her?" Draco asked. He eyed the back of Zhou's head with dislike as he rotated his ankles one after the other.

Rigel frowned at him. "She needs extra practice in Defense, and you have to admit having another Healer around is a good precaution. With the tournament, I won't be able to make every meeting. Zhou is a good Healer."

"Zhou?" Draco scowled. "Is that some kind of pet name?"

"What? No. It's how she says her name, that's all," Rigel told him. She wondered why he was so annoyed at the girl's presence. She wasn't the only new face by any stretch. "Give her a chance. You were skeptical about Ron, too, at first. Now he's your best sounding board, isn't he?"

"This isn't about Ron," Draco grumbled. He left the topic alone, though, and went on with his stretches in silence.

Rigel mentally shrugged off his peculiar irritation. He was probably still a bit sore that she'd beat him in the duel. As Draco walked the group through their first combination, she combed over the duel in her mind, mentally noting where she would have done something different if she'd had more time to consider her reactions. All in all, she was impressed with Draco and not too disappointed in her return to formal dueling in light of her summer focused on free dueling. Granted, a couple of those moves hadn't been strictly in the realm of traditional formal dueling, but she hadn't bent the rules too far. At least no one could say her style wasn't unique.

Toward the end of the first week in November, Rigel ran into Hermione Granger in the dungeons, of all places. The curly-haired girl seemed to be cutting haphazardly across the less used corridors, and if Rigel wasn't on her way back from her lab she doubted anyone would have come across the girl.

"Lost or exploring?" Rigel asked, smiling as Hermione whirled and let out an exasperated sigh.

"You shouldn't sneak up on people," she admonished, tossing her curly hair back from her face in an irritated motion. "As it happens, I am lost. I'm looking for the Library. I asked someone near the Entrance Hall for directions, but I'm beginning to suspect he lied to me."

Seeing as she was in the dungeons, Rigel was inclined to agree. "I'll take you," she said. "Sorry if some of my schoolmates aren't being hospitable."

"It's to be expected," she said evenly. After the barest of hesitations, she fell into step beside Rigel. "Thank you for showing me the right way. What were you doing down here?"

"The Slytherin common room isn't far from here," Rigel told her. "I have a private lab that I use for extracurricular research, as well, and it's just back that way."

"The school lets you brew unsupervised?" Hermione's eyebrows shot up. "That would never happen at AIM."

"Professor Snape makes an exception for me, as I've been excused from regular Potions lessons," she explained.

"Harry did say you were quite gifted at Potions as well," Hermione murmured. "I hear Professor Snape is a world renowned Potions Master, so I suppose he would recognize talent when he sees it. I was thinking of attending a few of his classes, but I'm not sure how our syllabi compare in that subject. I may be behind the other fourth years."

"To be honest, I wouldn't attend Potions class here if I were you," Rigel said, a smile tugging at her lips. "Professor Snape is world class, but he isn't exactly friendly. You'd learn more reading his work for publication rather than sitting through his classes. Mostly he spends them trying to prevent the students from blowing themselves up."

"That's a rather harsh denouncement of your classmates' ability," Hermione commented, sounding disappointed.

"Not at all." Rigel smiled reassuringly. "My classmates are perfectly average in Potions. The curriculum here includes a great many more temperamental brews than are taught at other schools, however. Snape thinks the most important thing to teach people who probably won't be brewing potions for a living is how dangerous potions are, so they don't accidentally hurt themselves later in life trying something unfamiliar. Did you know that since he's been the Potions Master here, the average rate of potions-related deaths in magical Britain as a whole has gone down? Specifically in adults who attended Hogwarts after 1981."

Hermione looked amused. "You admire him greatly."

"I do," she admitted. "He's my mentor, but more than that, he's an exceptional academic in a number of fields. I'd be happy to recommend some of his best articles if you have the time to read them."

"I'd appreciate it," Hermione agreed, looking cheered at the prospect. "If Potions wouldn't be helpful, what classes should I attend? I was thinking History would be interesting, as I don't doubt a different perspective is offered at an all-pureblood school like this one."

Rigel winced. "History might not be a great subject, either. It's taught by a ghost, currently, and he rarely strays from the textbooks that were assigned to the course when he died."

Hermione looked vaguely horrified. "You don't learn any modern history?"

"Most of the old families emphasize history pre-Hogwarts," Rigel said, shrugging. "And the OWLs are dated enough that it doesn't really impact test scores. If you're looking to get the most out of classes here, I recommend Transfiguration and Charms. McGonagall, the Transfiguration professor, was trained by Dumbledore himself. She's an Animagus, you know."

"Really? I've never met one," Hermione said, eyes wide. "I'd very much like to meet her. And Charms, you said?"

Rigel nodded. "Flitwick was a dueling champion in his day, and most of his ability in that arena has to do with his complete mastery of Charms. Another good one might be Defense, since you're in the tournament and all. Professor Dawlish is an Auror, and he has a habit of shooting sudden spells at his students to hone our reflexes—and to make sure we're paying attention."

Hermione grimaced. "That sounds… instructive."

"It's more harrowing than anything, but I have noticed an improvement in my reaction time over the past month. What else?" Rigel thought aloud as they climbed the main staircase. "The Healing class will be open to you, of course. Madam Pomfrey would love to have you. The fifth year class meets Friday mornings, so you should come then. Do you take Runes or Arithmancy? Magical Creatures or Divination?"

"I've looked into Runes and Arithmancy on my own," Hermione said, "But the Healing track doesn't allow a lot of time for unrelated extracurriculars."

"You might try those, then," Rigel suggested. "I can give you the notes from last year if you want to attend the fourth year lessons with us. I don't take Creatures myself, but I've heard the professor this year is very knowledgeable. There are a lot of unique resources at Hogwarts, so don't hesitate to take advantage of them."

"I was looking forward to seeing the Library," Hermione admitted, smiling sheepishly. "It's supposed to be the best collection in Europe."

"That is what anyone who attended Hogwarts will tell you," Rigel said with a laugh. "I'll let you decide for yourself. Here we are."

She gestured to the large doorway and Hermione beamed at the sight of the brass sign hanging above it. "Thank you! Do I need a card to check out a book?"

Rigel shook her head. "I'll show you how to sign one out. Madam Pince is the Librarian, and she inspects every book that goes in or out, so don't ever damage one if you value your life."

Hermione looked vaguely offended. "As if I would."

Rigel led her into the Library and gave her a short tour of the different sections. Then she took out a spare piece of parchment and sketched a quick map for the girl. "This is the best route from your rooms," she said, drawing an arrowed path. She added the Great Hall, the Transfiguration, Defense, and Charms classrooms, and the Hospital Wing for good measure. She handed it over, saying, "If you ever need anything, stop someone in a green tie and tell them Rigel Black asked to see you. They'll find me for you without much fuss. If you're really interested in the pureblood perspective on modern history, I recommend simply asking people. The ones in blue ties are Ravenclaws—house of the intelligent and curious. Your average Ravenclaw is always up for a solid academic discussion."

Hermione's smile was small, but clearly heartfelt. "Thank you, Rigel. You've been a great host."

"It's no trouble at all," she assured the girl. "I'll see you around."

Rigel left the Library with a feeling of satisfaction. Archie would be pleased with her for looking after his friend. She would subtly inquire as to who had tried to trick Hermione into traversing the dungeons alone, as well. That sort of prank was likely just petty mischief, but given certain Slytherin inclinations in regards to muggleborns, it could have gone much worse for the girl if someone else had found her first.

She only had two weeks to prepare for the first task, and by Thursday evening she thought she ought to at least go down to the Forbidden Forest and practice acclimating her senses to it again. Now, more than ever, it was vital that she get past what had happened to her there.

Rigel approached the forest as the sun was just beginning to sink below the treetops. The dark wood seemed to reach out toward her even as she moved toward it, touching some part of her soul that sent a shiver down her spine. She gritted her teeth against the feeling. I am not afraid of a dead man, she told herself firmly. Peter Pettigrew can't hurt anyone now.

When she reached the outermost trees themselves, however, she found her feet unable to carry her further. At first, she thought unbiddable panic had clawed its way into her , but soon realized the problem was not in her mind, after all. An invisible barrier preventing her from moving any further had somehow been erected at the edge of the woods. She stretched out a hand along it, searching for an edge that would indicate a localized shield, but the barrier met her in every direction. A ward, then.

"They won't let anyone in," an accented voice drifted toward her through the fading light. She cast out her sphere of magical awareness warily and sensed a presence moving toward her along the tree line. A few moments later, she saw Matheus Sousa strolling in the shadows, one hand trailing along the invisible ward and the other tucked into his pocket. He stopped beside her with a wry grin. "They don't want us looking."

Rigel had to admit it made sense. The tournament organizers wouldn't like anyone seeing what they'd prepared before the night of the task. "We're to go in blind, then," she remarked, sighing. "I don't like surprises."

"Surprises, I don't mind," Sousa said, eyeing the forest through his shaggy hair with something like wistfulness. "I came to get some Salvia. It grows here, no?"

She blinked. Salvia was a species of mint that could mean many things, from common sage to chia, but most of it wasn't native to Scotland. "I suppose it could, but you would have had to go fairly far into the forest to find it. I've never seen any."

"Ah." His handsome face closed in disappointment and he ran a hand through his thick, dark hair. "I will look another place."

He started to walk away, but Rigel said, "Wait. I probably have a little, if you want it."

Sousa's eyebrows rose. "Really?"

She rummaged into her bag for her potions kit. "What type of Salvia are you looking for? Clary? Danshen?"

"Not sure the English name," Sousa said, cocking his head at her with interest as she found the correct sub-compartment in her kit. "Very tall plant, with big, green leaves. Not many flowers. Used for seeing… seeing things."

"Salvia Divinorum?" she guessed. That was the only type of sage she knew to be used in Scrying Potions. "I have that." She pulled it out of the undetectably expanded compartment and examined the bundle closely. "I bought this a while ago, but it looks all right."

She passed it to him and a crooked smile overtook Sousa's face. "You always have plants in your pocket?"

Rigel secured her kit once more with a slightly embarrassed grimace. "I'm a potioneer, and I've learned it pays to be prepared. Are you going to brew some kind of Seer's Solution for the task?" She had heard that such brews were useful for opening the inner eye, but she'd never tried it herself.

"Something like that," Sousa said, looking amused at her still. "Thank you, Mr. Black."

She let out a laugh at that. "Just Rigel is fine. Good luck in the first task, Mr. Sousa."

"Matheus, please, and good luck to you," he said, bowing smoothly to her before heading back toward the castle.

When he'd gone a fair distance, Rigel called, "Treessslider? Isss that you?" She'd felt what she thought was her friend waiting within the sphere of her sensing ability for most of her conversation with Sousa.

"The ssstranger is gone, Ssspeaker?"

"Yesss, thank you for waiting," she said, smiling when the snake wiggled right up to the barrier and bumped against it agitatedly. "You can't get out either?"

"I am trapped here with all the othersss," Treeslider complained. "How will you give me a moussse?"

His priorities never ceased to amuse her. Still, he was right. She couldn't give him the one she'd brought. "How would you like a live moussse thisss time?"

Treeslider expressed great interest in that idea, so Rigel took out her wand and whispered, "Accio mouse." She didn't put much power behind the spell, but several mice still zoomed out of the forest and bounced against the barrier between her and the trees. Treeslider was quick to neutralize them before the mice regained their wits, and the green snake chortled in a satisfied hiss over his spoils.

"Ssspeaker isss too kind," he said gleefully.

She favored him with an indulgent smile. "You mentioned 'othersss' before. Ssso there are new inhabitantsss in the foressst?"

"Many new creaturesss," Treeslider agreed. "And trapsss. Metal and magic, ensssnaring thossse that ssstray too clossse."

That was interesting. "Can you tell me what kind of creatures?" she asked, a slow smirk blooming across her face. She really did hate surprises.

The snake hissed in wordless agreement as his coils tightened around his dinner. "I have ssseen a manticore, two sssnallygastersss, a quintaped, and sssmelled a troll," Treeslider told her. "The ssstupid runessspoors ssspeak of Sssphinx and Chimera. Ssseveral ssspidersss are alssso trapped, and the thessstralsss, too. Then there isss the dragon."

"A dragon?" Rigel found herself releasing a wordless hiss of frustration. She did not want to face another dragon in this lifetime. "Did you sssee what kind?"

"Sssmall and fassst," the snake revealed. "And rude."

"Naturally," she said on a sigh. "Thank you, Treessslider. You've been a great help to me."

"Always pleasssed to help, Ssspeaker."

She considered the snake, an idea forming. "Would you mind helping me again sssoon?"

"Of courssse." The snake looked up at her with something like interest in its bulbous eyes.

"On the next full moon, meet me near the treeline. There will be othersss around, but do not be afraid to approach me. I will need your help navigating the foressst that night." Rigel spoke slowly so that the snake would understand and remember. "Until then, watch and lisssten to all happeningsss inssside thisss barrier. Sssniff out the trapsss you ssspoke of and remember their location. Take note of any new creaturesss and remember. Can you do that for me?"

"Yesss, Ssspeaker. I will be your eyesss and earsss," Treeslider said gravely. "When you come on the full moon I will ssseek you and assssissst."

"You will not hunger for miccce asss long asss I ressside here," she vowed. Rigel couldn't help but feel a sense of satisfied accomplishment as she bade farewell to the snake and made her way back to the castle. It was a little unfair of her to have an early advantage in the task, but she had promised to do her best, and that meant using all resources available to her, didn't it? Treeslider would be useful in more than one way, she mused. His presence might just be the steadying reassurance that kept her from having a breakdown in the middle of the forest. Surrounded by dangerous creatures. At night. Rigel grimaced. Perhaps she would brew a potion to help her see in the dark. Snape would likely have a good recipe, and if not…well, she hadn't taken her invisibility cloak to the restricted section for some time.

The week before the first task found her in lab three once more, but Snape was not interested in brewing with her. All of his attention was on the upcoming task, and none of Rigel's assurances that she had it in hand made an impact on his single-minded focus.

"If you die in this task it won't matter if I teach you to freebrew," he snapped at her when she complained that she didn't want to go over physical shields again.

"If I die without learning to freebrew I shall haunt you without mercy," she muttered with a sullen scowl. She was supposed to be learning potions from her mentor, not the various viable shields recommended when faced with an Acromantula.

"Do not take this lightly," Snape insisted. "What shield will hold against the fist of a forest troll?"

"None of them for long," she said. Trolls were incredibly strong, and it was always better to simply out-run one or trick it somehow.

"And a quintaped?" her Head of House pressed.

Rigel blinked, then frowned. "What makes you think there would be a quintaped in the forest?" Struck by suspicion, she cast her mind over the creatures Snape had mentioned in the last hour. A Manticore, a chimera, and a thestral had all come up in his 'comprehensive overview.' He knew, she realized with incredulous annoyance. Somehow, Snape knew what the creatures in the forest were. "Did Riddle tell you to cover these creatures with me?" she demanded, outrage dawning slowly.

Snape's eyebrow rose with slow contempt. "Why would you imagine such a thing?

"Maybe because everything you've gone over with me is a recent addition to the closed off portion of the Forbidden Forest," she said, drawing herself to her full height. It wasn't enough to come close to Snape's height, but it gave wind to her indignation. "You're cheating for him!"

To her surprise, her professor merely smiled at her accusation. "So you've discovered the information for yourself? Good, then there's no need for pretense. We must prepare you for an encounter with each potential creature."

Rigel knew her face was mutinous. "I don't need Riddle to spoon feed me," she growled. "Did it not occur to you two that I could do this on my own?"

Snape sneered at her. "It matters not how you survive, only that you do, Rigel. I will see you prepared."

"It isn't fair to the others," she protested. It was a weak argument. The tournament would never be fair, and all of it would be for nothing if she didn't win, regardless of how it pricked her pride and her conscience to accept the sort of help Snape offered.

"All staff members have been instructed to assist any candidate who asks them. Minerva for one has already taken the Athenei and the muggleborn girl under her wing," Snape informed her. "As you've managed to come by information on the forests' newly resident population honestly, I fail to see a difference in my preparing you for the very real eventualities you are to face."

Rigel's frown remained, but she felt a sigh escape her. If Snape was right, the others were getting help, too, and no matter Riddle's intentions, she had discovered which creatures she'd have to deal with on her own. It would be the height of foolish obstinacy to refuse her Head of House's help at this point. "Fine." She ran a hand through her bangs agitatedly. "I'm mostly worried about the dragon, to be honest, so tell me how I should go about defeating a Peruvian Vipertooth."

"A what?" Snape's already chalky complexion whitened further.

It was Rigel's turn to raise her eyebrows at him. "So Riddle didn't tell you everything." She didn't believe for a moment that Treeslider could be mistaken about the presence of a dragon in the forest. "In addition to the ones you've already mentioned, there's the dragon, two snallygasters, and at least one Sphinx. Plus several traps, the nature of which I am not certain."

The potions master swore darkly. "Snallygasters have impenetrable hides and their talons will slice through almost anything. If you see one, I suggest you distract it—they're unhesitantly inquisitive."

"And the dragon?" Rigel reminded him. "A venomous dragon, at that?"

"Avoid it at all costs," Snape said lowly. His eyes burned with anger and something like worry, she thought. It softened her annoyance. "Even you cannot hold a shield against dragon fire indefinitely."

That was heartening. Not that she wasn't aware of that fact after her encounter the previous year. "Do you think the Ministry would approve a special apparition license for me?" It would be nice to have a last resort, considering how many of the creatures in the forest could maim her given half a chance.

"You cannot apparate on Hogwarts grounds," Snape reminded her, eyes narrowing. "Even if you could learn in the next six days."

"No telling how far into the forest we'll have to go, though," she pointed out wearily. "They could put whatever we're seeking well past the wards, if they wanted."

"Let's focus on tracking and hiding, Rigel. If escape is your only option, I'd advise bringing a broom." She couldn't tell if he was joking.

"Are we allowed brooms?" she asked.

He snorted. "If you are not strictly prohibited them, you would do well to consider it."

"Noted," she said, smiling slightly. It wouldn't be much good for out-flying a dragon in a dark forest, but if things did get hairy, she could always go up and out. Then she remembered the barrier. Her face fell. "The ward keeping all the creatures in has to go over the top of the trees as well," she said. "Otherwise the ones with wings would have flown out by now."

"Or else they are chained down," Snape mused.

"Like Pettigrew's dragon," she agreed, grimacing. "That was only an adolescent. I'd hate to be the committee member in charge of securing a fully grown breed to the earth."

"Do not pity your enemies," Snape advised her.

Rigel's nose wrinkled. She didn't like the idea of having enemies. Most of the last few years had been geared toward avoiding that, though she had to admit her track record had room for improvement. "A broom, then," she said. "Anything else?"

Snape's dark eyes appraised her for a long moment. "Have you considered an alliance?"

"Team up with one of the other contestants? It would have to be a halfblood or muggleborn," she said slowly. "Just for the first few tasks you mean?"

"The only ones you are directly competing against until the final round are Mr. Krum and Miss Shang," Snape affirmed. "Anyone else may be receptive to a helping hand, especially considering you are the only one familiar with the forest."

"And I know what creatures are inside," she added. "Still, would I be in violation of the vow if I helped another candidate?"

"An alliance with a halfblood or muggleborn in this task does not impact your odds of being chosen the pureblood champion and advancing in the tournament. Such a move may in fact increase your odds of succeeding. That said, it may be prudent to have an alternate plan, should your blood begin to boil." Snape's voice was light, almost unconcerned, but she could see the sardonic anger still burning behind his impassive features. Her Head of House had not come to terms with her agreement with Riddle just yet.

Rigel inclined her head. "All right. I'll think about that, too. Now can we start freebrewing?"

Snape favored her with a doubtful sneer. "Have you maintained the sphere of awareness for an entire week?"

"Five and a half days," she said, widening her eyes and allowing a hopeful smile to cross her features. "It would have been seven, but I brewed some Dreamless Sleep that ended up much stronger than intended and accidentally knocked myself unconscious the night before last. Now I'm back to two days straight."

"Why are you taking Dreamless Sleep?" Snape asked. His head was cocked in a way that indicated dangerous levels of interest in her answer.

"I…just have been," she said, dropping her eyes to the side in a show of indifference.

He growled. "Still?"

"Not a full dose—well, except for when I over-brew it accidentally. Just a little, to take the edge off my subconscious." She glanced up at his forbidding expression and pressed her lips together in annoyance. "Nowhere near addictive frequencies. I'm fine."

"You should not be going back into that forest," he spat, furious enough to begin pacing the small lab in open agitation.

"That wasn't my doing. Riddle is testing me. He wants to see if I'm still broken, right? Well, I'm not." She fought against the urge to grind her teeth and settled for lifting her chin stubbornly. She needed the Dreamless Sleep to stay rested for the competition. She had too many things to do during the day to waste her hours in sleep-deprived lethargy. It was times like this she missed her time-turner, despite the shiver that the mere thought of the glittering device sent down her spine.

"Try not to undo all the work that went into repairing you in one night," Snape suggested. His voice positively frothed with a roiling venom.

Rigel smiled sweetly in response, though there was acid dripping behind her lips that burned down her throat into her stomach. It pooled there, a fire of resentment that she refused to give voice to. He made it seem as though she'd asked to be kidnapped or strong-armed into a tournament of dubious intent. Left to herself, she doubted she'd ever go more than a few feet into the forest again. "I'll do my best," she promised dryly.

"Go practice your remote sensing." Snape's scowl did not indicate that he found her dissemblance amusing.

She bowed with an unnecessary flourish. "As milord bids."

Rigel could feel the daggers of his glare following her into the corridor, but she didn't have the wherewithal to soothe her professor's ruffled feathers at the moment. Instead, she had a date with a megalomaniacal piece of aluminum oxide.

Her consciousness barely had time to fully manifest into the icy wind of her mindscape before Dom folded the mental space around her and brought her into the cabin-like interior of her mountain. The ceilings looked higher, and various magical creatures of disparate origins hung frozen in intricate taxidermied states of motion amidst the rafters. A black bear stared sightlessly down at her from the nearest beam, its mouth agape in silent, teeth-filled fury. A fire roared cheerfully in the fireplace, which was now framed by a glorious array of stones, some suitable for such construction and others, like an enormous hunk of uncut diamond, too ridiculous to contemplate overlong.

The wood floor shone with fresh wax as she made her way to the pair of chairs—more thrones, now, with great, arching backs of interwoven branches. She looked around for any sign of golems, but either Dom had been smart enough to hide them or he'd envisaged ever-shining floors.

"How have you been?" she asked politely as the construct pushed in her chair. He looked the same, a porcelain doll that resembled her current physical form only vaguely. Perhaps she ought to update his shell, to better reflect her current appearance. The only reason he looked that way was to fool intruders, after all.

"Busy," Dom said, smiling slightly as he claimed his own seat and began carefully pouring tea. "I've run through all the magic you gave me the last time you visited."

She'd decided to go about having him comb through her magic by only giving him access to a portion of it at a time. As long as he didn't have more than a fifth of it at once, she didn't think he'd be able to cause her any trouble she couldn't handle. She leaned forward, ignoring the steaming teacup in front of her for the moment. "What have you found? Anything?"

"You were right." He fixed her with a level stare. "At first it was hard to see, but after some experimentation I noticed that the foreign magic you suspected was just a little slower to react when provoked than your own, vigorously responsive core."

She frowned. "What does that mean?"

He stood. "I've collected it here." He plucked a crystal flask from the mantel and held it before her eyes with two fingers. There was a cold blue fire flickering at the bottom, almost writhing in the firelight. "At first it was invisible, stretched thin within your core and for all intents bonded with your own magic. If I do this—" The construct thrust his hand toward the vial and a flare of power reached out from him toward it. For a moment, the blue fire did nothing, but then it lashed against the side of the bottle without warning. The crystal shook, but held. Dom grinned at her over the flask. "Your magic doesn't hesitate. It reacts immediately to any stimulus, while this blue fire always goes still before striking back."

"Like a snake," she muttered, frowning at the creepy little ball of fire.

"Once I could discern the difference, I began separating the two. When this magic is detached from yours, it tends to stick to itself. I also lose all control over it once it's no longer merged with your core," he explained, shaking the bottle a little. The flames crawled from one side of the container to the other in a strange parody of pacing. "This is essentially useless to you, now. You can't use it for anything, but it can't exert any influence over you, either."

She let out a slow breath. "Thank you. Do you think you can separate the rest of it?"

"With time," Dom said, nodding. He went to place the flask back on the mantel but Rigel shook her head.

"Lock it away, please." She didn't want that stuff just lying around. Dom shrugged, but did place the bottle inside a polished wood cabinet. "Thank you," she said, meaning it. "I'll get you a new section of core to work with before I leave." She still didn't know what the magic had been intended to do, but she felt better having part of it isolated.

She picked up her teacup and sniffed at it, amused to find it still just as warm as when he'd poured it. The tea felt entirely solid sliding down her throat, but in a way that was almost more strange in the mental plane than the illusory impression of tea had been the last time she visited. "This is good."

"It is acceptable," he agreed, sipping at his own cup. "Now, what fresh problems have you for me today?"

She scowled at him. "I don't need you to handle all of my problems."

"Only some of them, I know," he said soothingly. The amusement in his dull grey eyes wasn't surprising, but the concern that underlined it was. "Well?"

Rigel sighed. "There's this tournament," she admitted. "I have to participate." She began an explanation that sounded even more convoluted out loud than it did in her head. Dom listened patiently, but when she came to the vow he scoffed.

"You should not make such deals with your enemies. Nothing you could gain will be worth helping him to achieve anything." Dom's foot tapped restlessly as his gaze floated toward the ceiling in thought. "This tournament will attract prestige, however, and give you a chance to prove your worth on an international level. You could recruit many followers, if you make a good enough showing."

"I am not interested in followers," she said firmly. "I'm only doing this so that Riddle will stop legislating against non-purebloods."

"No harm in collecting multiple birds from a single stone's throw," Dom said archly. "I'm only thinking of your future."

She groaned. "I'd rather you focus on my present. I don't suppose you have any advice for facing a real Sphinx?"

Dom grimaced. "Almost nothing on this earth is worth coming between a Sphinx and her treasure. What are they offering the rabble in exchange for competing in this death trap?"

Rigel laughed. "The usual. Money. Fame. A magical staff of Zumez that supposedly amplifies power but is probably mostly decorative."

Dom choked on his tea. "The Rod of Zuriel?" He stared at her, entirely aghast. "They're giving that hunk of self-important rock to the winner? Why not simply kill them and enslave their will in the spectral plane right off? It would certainly involve less oration."

She stared at him. "Are you saying… you know the Rod of Zuriel?"

Dom rolled his eyes. "Not hardly. I've crossed paths with it once or twice, and I don't relish the memories."

She had a disturbing thought. "Are all large gemstones sentient?"

He ignored her. "You are going to win this tournament, correct?"

"I think Riddle means me to," she said, suspicious of the smile blooming across his face. It worried her when Dom was too pleased. "But seriously, are gemstones above average receptive to magical sentience for some reason?"

Dom ignored her, too busy smirking over his tea. "Excellent. Just marvelous." He started laughing, but caught himself with a cough and simply smiled at her innocently. She was not fooled. "I mean, how wonderful. Will you destroy its physical form as well?"

"I don't have any solid plans for it," she said with a frown. "Why?"

"No reason, just curious," Dom said, still smiling. "Now, you asked about Sphinxes. Do not attempt to cross them physically. They will do anything to guard what they've been assigned to protect, which is what makes them such excellent servants. Unfortunately, they have this penchant for riddles that you can use to your advantage…"

They spent the rest of her time in the mindscape discussing all the riddles Dom had ever heard, but Rigel didn't forget his keen interest in the Rod of Zuriel. It looked as though she'd have to add that artifact to the list of things she needed to research after all. The very last thing she needed was to win the tournament and wind up with another Dominion Jewel on her hands.

Five days before the first task, Rigel came across Hermione in the Library. The bushy brunette stood cross-armed at the bookshelf of Healing tomes, scowling at something only she could see.

"Need help finding something?" Rigel asked. Hermione started a bit and flushed at Rigel's pleasant expression.

"There's no copy of Henderson's Intermediate Approaches to Magical Maladies," Hermione said, gesturing to the stacks with a frustrated hand motion. "I have an essay on diagnosing modern magical mishaps, but no reference material to work with."

Rigel nodded in understanding. "The Hogwarts Library is wonderful, but it isn't as robust in Healing as it is in other subjects." She opened her book bag and rummaged for a moment before pulling out the book Hermione needed. "Here, use this. I already did that lesson."

"What do you mean you already did it?" Hermione demanded, taking the book and leafing through it as though to check it really was the one she wanted.

"I try to keep up with Harry's syllabus," she said, shrugging. "It helps me a lot in my own Healing studies here."

"Harry told me that," Hermione said, shaking her head impatiently. "I mean how can you have studied it already? I just got notice today that we needed to reference this text for our essay. It wasn't in the general syllabus, and there's no way you've written the essay in the last—"

"Five hours? No," Rigel admitted, smiling. "I have a faster way of communicating with Harry than owl post. The book is yours, if you want it." She'd read most of it in any case.

The girl clutched the book close to her chest. "Thank you. Do you often have to buy your own books to keep up with our curriculum?"

"Sometimes," Rigel said, shrugging. "Madam Pomfrey also has a good private collection she's happy to lend to the few students she has. If you have any more books you need but can't find here, feel free to ask me."

"You do like helping me," Hermione commented, a strange look in her eyes. "Are you just being nice to me because Harry asked you to?"

Rigel cocked her head. "What makes you think that?"

She hugged the book tighter to her chest with a pensive frown. "I've seen the way your friends look at me in the halls. Like I'm an animal in a zoo they don't want to get too close to. I understand how prejudice works, you know. It's normally something you grow up with, and it can be very hard to change. If you're just humoring me for Harry's sake, I'd rather you not, thanks all the same."

She had to admire the girl's pride. "At first, I was going to be nice to you for Harry's sake," she admitted, deciding honesty was something Hermione would appreciate. "However, what I've seen of you so far, I like. You speak your mind and you're participating in the tournament for reasons I can respect. Coupled with what Harry tells me of your virtues, I'd consider myself lucky to be your friend."

"What does he—she—" Hermione sighed. "What does Harry say about me?" The girl looked interested despite herself.

"Just that you hung the moon and the sun in the same day," Rigel said.

Hermione scoffed. "Harry is so hyperbolic. I never know what he really means." Hermione shot Rigel a self-conscious glance, adding, "Do you refer to Harry as a boy or a girl usually?"

Rigel felt herself go still. What to say? She took a slow breath. "I… refer to Harry as a girl to those who know Harry as a girl, and a boy to those who know Harry as a boy, as you do. People who don't know Harry at all will say 'the Potter Heiress,' but those people's perceptions don't matter much."

"It's so complicated," Hermione said. She didn't sound like she was complaining, exactly, but she did seem frustrated. "In the alleys it's the same. Some people refer to Harry as a boy, some as a girl who presents as a boy. It's confusing."

"Harry wouldn't want you to be confused," Rigel offered, feeling acutely awkward. "Think of it like… a secret. Think of Harry as a boy, but to protect his secret, you can refer to him as a girl in front of people who don't know him. Does that make sense?"

"It's just—" Hermione broke off, uncertainty painted across her face. Rigel kept her face open and kind. With agonized hesitancy, Hermione said quietly, "I think Harry likes me."

"He does," she confirmed, with barely a moment's thought. If Hermione had already guessed but hadn't said anything to Archie, she obviously needed someone to talk to. Rigel summoned her most earnest expression. "Underneath Harry's excitable personality and lighthearted demeanor, he really cares for you."

"I know," Hermione whispered. Her face sagged with discomfort. "But I don't— oh, I don't know how to say this. I'm… not attracted to females. Physically. I know," she rushed on, "that pureblooded culture is supposed to be non-preferential and emphasizes flexibility for the sake of bolstering population or something, and Harry says most people don't admit to having a firm sexuality these days, but I can't help what I feel. I don't know if I can ever give Harry what sh—he—wants."

There was a white-hot knife twisting in Rigel's heart. In that moment she understood in startling clarity just what the ruse would ask of Archie. Of course Hermione could not be expected to forgo her natural inclinations to entertain a relationship that held no amorous appeal for her. Still, there must be something she could do to help her cousin's cause.

"I understand," Rigel assured her gently. "So does Harry. He won't ever press you, Hermione. Harry values your friendship too much to push you away or make you uncomfortable."

Hermione bit her lip. "I just hate to disappoint him. He's my best friend. It didn't used to be this complicated."

"Apparently, that's a normal teenage sentiment," Rigel said wryly.

Hermione smiled weakly. "Nothing has been normal since my eleventh birthday. I can't bring myself to regret that, though. It's precious, this life." The girl made a vague gesture to the stacks around them, but Rigel knew it was meant to encompass the castle itself, and so much more. Hermione's voice caught as she added, "We're so lucky to be a part of this."

As the other girl took her leave, Rigel reflected that she hadn't felt particularly lucky in a long time.

Just days before the first task, Rigel was in the midst of Healing a perforated pig's bladder when the Head Girl poked her head into the Hospital Wing and told Madam Pomfrey that Rigel was to be excused for the day. The nurse clucked in annoyance, but took over the operation seamlessly and said, "Read up on the rest of the urinary system and next week we'll take a closer look at ruptured kidneys."

Rigel nodded and waved goodbye to Zhou, who smiled briefly at her before returning her attention to the pig. Rigel slipped out of her Healing smock, but was aware of the potent stench that followed her out of the Wing. Pansy always refused her company on Fridays until after she showered, though Rigel didn't think it was that stomach turning. Judging by the wrinkled nose on the Head Girl's face, she might have to reconsider that assumption.

The older girl left Rigel at the doorway to a seldom-used classroom, where she found most of the other champions gathered within, along with the Headmaster, Riddle, several reporters, and, in a twist of reality she'd never imagined, the wand maker Ollivander, of all people. Rigel stared at the white-haired old man with a detached sense of horror. It was like witnessing a broom collision—or being in one, rather. There he was right in front of her all of a sudden, and there was nothing she could do about it.

Ollivander was the one person in all the world who held the unifying piece in the puzzle that had spiraled into her current situation. It was Ollivander who had, for reasons she had been too grateful to question at the time, not revealed to Snape in her first year that she was Harriet Potter, not Arcturus Black. Now, after years of putting the knowledge to the side, she was caught in the realization that she had no idea what the man's motivations might be as far as she was concerned, and she had no guarantee that the wand maker wouldn't reveal her ruse once and for all that afternoon—in front of members of the international press, no less.

She forced her feet forward and her chin up. If these were to be her last moments as Rigel Black, she would not spend them blubbering or begging. Nothing was certain, yet, and all she could do was carry on in the part she played with bare bravado. Besides, what proof did he have? Even if he kept a record of every wand sold, she could easily claim she and her cousin had switched wands before going off to school. It would even explain better why the original ash wand hadn't suited her. This and other arguments began to marshal themselves in her head as she stepped more fully into the room.

"Ah, Mr. Black." Dumbledore smiled at her approach. "Now we have only one left to await, I believe. Miss Granger has become adrift in our rather cavernous Library, I suspect."

"She doesn't waste any time," Rigel said, smiling back politely. "If I may ask, what is the nature of this meeting, Professor?"

"I will let Tom explain, if he so desires," Dumbledore said genially. He raised white eyebrows expectantly at the politician, but Riddle demurred with a cold smile. Dumbledore hummed with amusement. "Well then, Mr. Black, to answer your question, this is a wand weighing."

She blinked in polite confusion. "Is there a weight limit on the wands we may use?"

The Headmaster laughed. "Fortunately not. It is merely a formality that ensures no candidate in the competition is utilizing a damaged or otherwise compromised wand."

"So that no one can say their wand was the cause of their failure," Jacob Owens chimed in, smiling widely. For some reason the American always seemed to be on the edge of a joke only he fully understood.

"If I promise not to make any such claims, can I skip it?" Rigel asked. "Only I've got a pig back in the Hospital Wing that I'd like to see back to full health."

A couple of the others laughed, but most only gave her odd looks. "Is zat what I smell?" Delacour asked, raking her eyes over Rigel's robes as though she could spot the viscera on them if she looked hard enough. Rigel shrugged apologetically.

"The formality is mandatory for all champions," Riddle said firmly. The quelling look he sent her recalled the exact wording of the Unbreakable Vow she'd sworn. As if she needed reminding.

"It won't take long," Ollivander promised. When her eyes met his with wary reluctance, the old wizard winked at her. At least, she thought he did. It was the barest flutter of lash, there and gone before she could be sure.

Hermione was ushered into the room shortly thereafter, and Riddle beckoned the reporters—two men in smart business robes and one neon-attired Rita Skeeter—forward.

"Welcome champions and guests, to the Weighing of the Wands. In addition to the formal registering of your wands today, you will also be giving an interview to one of our three esteemed reporters." He introduced each of them with a politician's smile. "Rita Skeeter, special correspondent to the Daily Prophet, Mark Russel, author of the popular Continental Column, and David Prescott from the Salem Star."

Rigel could not help thinking that it was rather clear who Riddle's intended audience was for his little experiment. All the articles would be published in English, and all three of the chosen papers were geared toward middle class readers with more thirst for entertainment than substance. He was not interested in making a scientific or academic point, but in sensationalizing the subject of blood politics in the popular imagination.

"Before that, I'll open the floor for any questions you have concerning the first task," Riddle offered. His expression was entirely magnanimous, and he waited patiently for the competitors to martial their thoughts.

"Vill ve be allowed in the forest before the task?" Krum asked.

"No."

"Is a wand all we're allowed?" Antiope's eyes were sharp on Riddle as he pretended to think about the question before answering.

"No."

"We can bring anything?" Sousa asked, looking cheered at the prospect.

"Anything you can carry," Riddle allowed. Really, he could have just said 'anything.' A wizard was never limited by space.

The questions went on, mainly about what they should expect to face in the forest, but Riddle deflected them all deftly. Rigel began a mental list of the potions she wanted to brew fresh for the task. It couldn't hurt to have a few extra Blood-replenishers, and while she didn't anticipate relying on it, a Calming Draught would be wise, just in case.

"Should we perhaps commence the weighing?" Dumbledore put in after every champion had the opportunity to ask questions. "I do have a class to teach this afternoon, I'm afraid." He twinkled blue eyes at Rigel, who was his only student in said class. She had to smile.

"I'd like to get back to class, as well," she put in solemnly.

Riddle's expression dripped with such solicitousness she doubted anyone else saw the annoyance laying in its shadow. "Certainly; we must not stand in the way of edification. Perhaps you'd like to go first then, Mr. Black?"

Her eyes flickered toward Ollivander again, but the old man's face revealed only pleasant interest. The wand maker held out his hand expectantly, and Rigel fetched her wand with hands that shook.

"Ah, yes, my old friend." Ollivander grasped the Holly wood almost fondly, running his hands over the length of it and holding it close to his misty eyes to better inspect its condition. "You've not had an easy time with this one, eh?"

Rigel wasn't sure whether he was talking to her or to the wand, but she nodded in any case. "We've come to terms with one another," she offered. Maybe if he thought she was treating her wand right he'd be less inclined to reveal her secret. Or maybe not—it was only a tool, after all, not a pet. Still, the elderly wizard didn't look at the wand as though it were a mere instrument.

"You have," the wand maker agreed. "Holly is a loyal wood, once its allegiance is won. It will serve you well."

He began to hand the wand back, and she had reached to grab it when Skeeter asked, "And the core? The length? My readers will want every detail." Her acid green quill was poised over a pad of paper, ink slowly pooling at its tip like venom welling in its sack.

"Phoenix feather," Ollivander said, face blank. "Eleven inches."

"Is it…?" Dumbledore trailed off, as though he'd begun the question despite himself. He looked equal parts hopeful and uneasy.

Ollivander's eyes flickered toward Rigel and away before he nodded once. Dumbledore's eyes locked onto Rigel's and held them for a long moment, but the Headmaster didn't say another word. Rigel began to frown. What was wrong with phoenix feathers? Surely there wasn't some kind of stigma around that, too. She glanced around the room to try to get a read on the others' reactions, but none of the competitors seems concerned with the information. It only seemed to mean something significant to Ollivander and Dumbledore—and Riddle. Her eyes caught a ripple of pure astonishment before the politician could disguise it, and she wondered.

When it was clear no elaboration was forthcoming, she tucked her wand away and stepped aside for the next champion. She tuned out the proceedings, not really interested in what kind of wands the others were carrying. What difference did it make? Her mind wandered back to that Saturday in first year when Fate had seemed to breathe across the tiny hairs on her neck. What had Ollivander said then? She hadn't been paying close enough attention. Something about loyalty, and something about… another wand? He had mentioned the combination was rare, but also that he had sold another wand that was similar, or something. Was it Dumbledore's wand? Did he also have a phoenix feather core? It couldn't be something so simple, she thought. Draco and Pansy both had unicorn hair cores, but they weren't wide eyed and concerned about it.

Still, there had to be something odd going on. When Delacour revealed that her wand contained the hair from her own grandmother, Dumbledore didn't seem half as intrigued. In addition, she felt the weight of Riddle's gaze fall heavy on her several times throughout the rest of the wand inspections, and while she didn't put it past the man to attempt to unnerve her for no reason, she was certain something else predicated his fixation this time.

Tahiil was the last to step forward, but he did so sheepishly. He held his empty palms out in open apology. "I have no wand, I am afraid. I did not know they were required."

This set the room into a tizzy. Rita materialized in the boy's face with simpering interest. "However do you perform magic, then? A staff? Crystals?"

Tahiil shook his head with a smile. "I was taught without this kind of focus. In my village, the elders cast with their hands. This is my way also."

"Wandless magic, how intriguing," Rita said, batting her vibrantly-lidded eyes at the Somali boy. "Do you find it…effective?"

He shrugged. "It works for me. I cannot say for others."

Riddle bestowed a cool smile on the muggleborn boy, saying, "We look forward to seeing your style of casting in the tournament, then. That concludes the Weighing of the Wands. Each of our guest reporters will now take three champions aside for exclusive interviews. Ms. Skeeter, if you would?"

Skeeter's smile could have burned through concrete with its intensity. "I'll take the Britain-born, if you don't mind, Lord Riddle. My readers will simply adore the juxtaposition—imagine it! One pureblood, one halfblood, and one muggleborn, all from our own magical community. Who will they root for? Who will they fall for? It's just delicious."

It sounded rather nauseating, put in those terms. How hadn't she noticed before that it was just as Skeeter said? Was it just coincidence that one candidate from each category happened to be originally from Great Britain, or was it more of Riddle's careful maneuvering?

The man himself inclined his head as though granting a boon. "Mr. Black, Miss Antiope, and Miss Granger—with Ms. Skeeter, if you please."

Rigel reluctantly peeled away from the group and followed Hermione and Antiope out into the corridor. Skeeter ushered them all into a classroom nearby and shut the door firmly behind them. She shooed Rigel and the others into chairs and took a seat on the edge of the teacher's desk like a finicky cat perching on a dirty limb.

"There now, that's cozy," the reporter said, still smiling brightly at the three of them. "You all don't mind if I use a Quick Quotes Quill, do you? I'd like to really concentrate on you, now."

Antiope cast the floating quill a suspicious look, but nodded. Hermione frowned, saying, "As long as we are quoted accurately." Rigel just tried not to grimace. She could still recall the article this woman had written about the Sleeping Sickness. It had rubbed her the wrong way, painting a more dramatic picture than necessary. She didn't foresee whatever article came out of this strange interview being any less sensational.

"Marvelous. Now, let's start with our pureblood. Arcturus Rigel Black. Scion to the Noble and Ancient House of Black. How does it feel, representing the oldest and most respected institution in this ground-breaking tournament?" Skeeter leaned forward toward Rigel, who was greeted with a rather indelicate view of the reporter's open blouse. She fought against the urge to wrinkle her nose at the excess of cleavage on display before her and instead looked down at her hands.

"I hope to bring honor to my school and my family," she said evenly. "I look forward to a challenging and interesting year."

Skeeter tutted at her answer. "Come now, Rigel—they do call you Rigel, don't they? You can be honest with me. It's a lot of pressure, isn't it? You must be dazzled, knowing most of the country is counting on you to uphold the grand tradition of pureblood ability. Will your family disown you if you disappoint them? The Blacks can be very unforgiving, if rumors are true."

Rigel looked up with a frown. "My father would never do that. He understands that ability, as you call it, is tied to the individual, not to any one group. How well I do in this tournament will be a reflection on me, and me alone."

"Well said, Rigel." Hermione was looking at her with something like pride in her eyes. "That's exactly what ought to be articulated about this tournament. It's not really about blood. It's about individuals of different backgrounds coming together and challenging themselves."

Skeeter favored Hermione with a skeptical expression. "It's the backgrounds we're talking about, dearie. That's why the best of the best were chosen to compete. In the end, the one to win will be the one whose background has best prepared him or her for victory. You're all smart and ambitious, Miss Granger, no doubt about that. You wouldn't be here if you weren't. The difference between you and Mr. Black is just blood. No use disputing that."

Hermione visibly bristled and Rigel had to bite her lip on a groan. Don't do it, she thought urgently toward the girl. It was no use, though. Hermione, eyes blazing, was about to walk into a political quagmire. "The difference, as you put it, is opportunity. Blood has nothing to do with ability. If Mr. Black wins it will indeed be a reflection on Hogwarts—it means he has access to quality education and has made good use of it."

"Then you believe the American Institute of Magic to be of inferior quality, education wise?" Skeeter asked, eyes wide with affected surprise. The implication that Hermione's failure in the tournament was a foregone conclusion rang clear.

Hermione faltered. "That's not necessarily the case. AIM is a wonderful school, with a rigorous curricula. No two institutions will be exactly equal, however. The differences in our educational preparation will be what determine the outcome of the tournament, not our particular blood status, that's all I'm saying."

Skeeter didn't care what Hermione was saying, and it was obvious. As her brilliant green quill scribbled its way across the parchment, the reporter's attention turned to Antiope, who had until this point kept her own council. "Miss Ross, isn't it?"

"Originally, aye," Antiope said. Her red hair shifted against her cheek as a muscle there clenched. "Until I leave the Athenai, however, I bear Antiope's title."

"Yes, all the girls at your school have names of myth, don't they?" Skeeter said, nodding as though she knew a great deal about Antiope's particular situation. "The Amazons of the Modern Day, they call you. It must be very strange for you, suddenly surrounded by young men as well as women here at Hogwarts."

Antiope pressed her lips together. "I'm not sure what you mean. We have young men in Laconia, too. Arguably the finest in the world."

"Yes, but those Spartan wizards are so principled, aren't they?" Skeeter tilted her head in a confiding manner. "And of course the proximity is new for you. Do find yourself distracted here in Britain? Or are the women of the Chalcioecus immune to the more…masculine charms?"

Rigel almost had to admire the woman's sheer nerve. It took a singular kind of gumption to be that unapologetically rude to someone's face. Antiope was ready to impale Skeeter's head on a pike, if the jumping tick in her cheek was any indication. Rigel cut in before the girl could answer—any response would only be twisted beyond comprehension by the reporter's sharp tongue and even sharper quill.

"I do find myself distracted," Rigel said smoothly, an expression of wistful admiration on her face. It drew Skeeter in like a pile of manure drew flies. "When I first entered this tournament, I never imagined so many lovely, intelligent, and talented young women would be participating. It's enough to make the heart faint, isn't it?"

"Are you admitting to a growing interest in any competitor in particular, Rigel?" Skeeter asked, her voice a tad higher in unconscious excitement.

"I really couldn't say," Rigel demurred. "It is a positively dazzling array. Then again, I am genetically more susceptible to the allure of beauty and talent than other young men, aren't I?"

Skeeter laughed, a tittering sound that suggested she was exactly as deep as she appeared. "I know first hand how susceptible the Black men can be, believe it or not." Rigel sincerely did not. "But that's neither here nor there. Tell me, Rigel. Do you think you exploits over the past three years have fully prepared you for this tournament?"

"I'm sure nothing could prepare one for whatever Mr. Riddle has in store," Rigel said, maintaining her polite expression.

"Lord Riddle's plans will be ingenious, to be sure, but you're no stranger to danger, are you? Wasn't it you who cured an impenetrable disease at the age of eleven? And didn't you slay a century-old basilisk the very next year? Then there's that mysterious business last spring, with a professor found dead and you, unaccountably abused and rescued the same day from being buried alive in the very forest in which you are to compete just days from now…well, it's an incredible collection of adventures, isn't it?"

Rigel honestly had no idea how to respond to that. It wasn't even really a question. Skeeter didn't want her to confirm or deny her suppositions. She only wanted Rigel to squirm. Well, she would not give the journalist the satisfaction. "I do seem to have had a string of bad luck, don't I? I hope my participation in the tournament will not be seen as a bad omen."

Skeeter's mouth twisted in sardonic amusement. "If anything, it's ordained," she breathed. Rigel was surprised not to see foam in her teeth. "I'm certain my readers will be positively breathless to see how you perform, Rigel Black. Do us proud, won't you?"

Her smile was more of a wince, but the reporter didn't seem to notice. The 'interview' ended shortly thereafter, but it was a long time before Rigel was able to purge the crawling sensation from her skin. She shuddered to think what monstrosity of popular journalism Rita Skeeter would produce from the afternoon's interrogation. Merlin willing, it would fail to sway anyone with a modicum of good sense.

Her head was still chewing through the likely consequences of the impending article when she arrived at her weekly Alchemy lesson. Dumbledore was waiting for her in his workroom, but a single glance at her expression prompted him to set aside the chalk and call for tea instead. A pair of comfy, oversized chairs replaced the array table with a gentle bell tone and Rigel had to smile. She wondered if she'd ever be so good at magic that she added sound effects just for fun.

"I find a small pot of good tea can reduce many troubling problems to a manageable size," the Headmaster commented when a house elf had delivered the tea tray and poured them both cups.

Rigel swirled the tea pensively, watching the little twister in the center of her cup with detached curiosity. "Would that tea could reduce an entire nation's pride and folly to a more manageable size," she said after a moment.

Dumbledore hummed thoughtfully. "You'd have to poison a great deal of tea."

Startled, she let a snort escape her. The older wizard twinkled at her when she met his gaze. "There's probably not enough belladonna in the world," she said with a small grin. "Ah, well. We'll have to try persuasion after all."

"Using the tournament, you mean?" Dumbledore's smile faded and a serious note entered his voice. "I admit I was surprised you agreed to participate, Mr. Black."

"You're not the only one," she allowed, her grin twisted into a grimace.

"Your father wrote me to ask whether I could prevent it. Alas, it is not in my power to bar specific students from competing. I told Sirius it was your choice to make, and no one else's." Dumbledore held her gaze for a long moment, and Rigel felt inexorably guilty. How could she explain to the man who had dedicated his life to defending the rights of the disenfranchised that she had made a deal with his political rival in a clumsy attempt to prevent further pressure coming to her or her family?

A flash of discomfort in her head snapped her eyes shut and away. Dom was warning her. She lost her relaxed posture and sat up straight in her chair. "If you want to know why, you can just ask, sir."

Dumbledore had the grace to look apologetic, at least. "Are you free to tell me, if I ask?"

Rigel blinked. He thought Riddle might have silenced her? She supposed Legilimency might be one way around an oath that prevented someone knowingly revealing information. It didn't make her feel better about his attempt to scan her surface thoughts, but she understood that if she had been under oath not to reveal anything about her participation in the tournament and he'd asked permission to read her thoughts, she'd have been obligated to refuse. She also would have had to immediately stop thinking those thoughts while around him. "I can talk about it. I'm just not certain you'll approve. My father definitely wouldn't."

He took a sip of tea with an air of innocence that must have been decades in the crafting. "I will probably forget all about this conversation the next time I meet Lord Black. The mind is a sieve in old age, you know."

Sure, she thought wryly. A sieve locked in an iron trunk.

As she'd already told Pansy and Draco, not to mention Aldon Rosier, she supposed it didn't really buy her anything to keep the situation from the Headmaster. Maybe, a small voice whispered, he could even help her somehow. "I made a deal with Riddle," she said at last. "He wanted me in the tournament badly enough to trade for my cooperation. In exchange for my participating in every event to the best of my ability, he released a public statement decrying the actions of the radicals who've been terrorizing muggleborns and their supporters."

Dumbledore's eyebrows rose. "I thought it was unusually farsighted of Tom to distance his political party from those renegades. You show remarkable insight into the world around you for one so young. That announcement has done much to stymie public support for the radicals, though I fear public ennui will be harder to counteract."

She nodded. "That's good. I wanted to tie Riddle's hands, since he was so intent on tying mine. That's why I also stipulated that if I win the tournament, he must cease his legislative agenda against muggleborns."

Dumbledore's hands tightened briefly on his teacup. "In its entirety? Tom would never agree to that in good faith, Mr. Black."

"Not the entirety," she admitted. "I bargained for the specific areas of employment opportunity, healthcare, and the marriage law. I tried to include education, but he modified the vow to discount it. That was a long shot, but I had to at least try."

The Headmaster's eyes began to grow misty, and he set his teacup aside to clasp his hands together before her. "Mr. Black, rare are those willing to put themselves in physical discomfort—much less mortal peril—for the benefit of strangers. You might have asked for anything else from Tom; his platform, while regrettable, nevertheless affords him a great deal of personal power. That you asked for this gives an old man hope for the future of our society. I must commend your selflessness and integrity."

The guilty feeling was back in force. Rigel shook her head helplessly. "Please, don't. It's not like I sought this out or have ever been a strong enough advocate for muggleborn and halfblood rights, even among my own classmates. Riddle was going to make me participate one way or another. I just wanted it to mean something. But I'm not a hero, sir."

Dumbledore's smile widened. "And what do you think a hero is, Mr. Black?"

She cleared her throat. "Well. A hero is someone who sees a wrong and sets out to fix it regardless of the cost to themself. Someone like Hermione Granger, who didn't have to have anything to do with this tournament, but came knowingly to be judged and degraded before the world simply because she knows blood prejudice is wrong and she thinks someone should stand up against it."

"That is one definition," the Headmaster agreed. "In my years, I have seen many types of heroes, however. Sometimes heroism is as simple as ordinary principles that inspire one person to disagree out loud with another. Then there are the silent heroes. You may be forgiven for not recognizing them, for they often do not recognize themselves. The silent hero is one who corrects a wrong quietly, anonymously, and allows the world to turn on uninterrupted, never knowing how the problem came to be fixed."

"Like Professor Snape," she murmured, understanding his point.

His eyebrows rose. "Severus told you of that?"

"I may have dragged it out of him," she admitted.

"You are very like Severus," Dumbledore told her, smiling once more.

She flushed. It was too soon for anyone to compare her to Severus Snape. Maybe in another decade or two. "If my life is half as impactful as Master Snape's, I'll consider it well-lived."

The Headmaster inclined his head. "Well then, Mr. Black, let us see about winning you a tournament." He beckoned to the air with an empty hand and a slim volume materialized in it. "This will be of use to you. Think of it as supplemental reading."

She took the proffered book at flipped the cover back to see the title on the first page. Arrays for the Harried. A quick perusal of the contents showed a series of extremely simplified arrays—no more that two or three runes needed in execution. "Is this Alchemy on the go?" she asked, intrigued.

"Just so," Dumbledore said. "A collection of quick arrays that rely more on magical input than complex definition through runes. They aren't sophisticated, but sometimes you need a fast solution, not an elegant one."

It certainly played to her strength, she thought, looking at the magical coefficients described in the accompanied equations. They were higher than any other array he'd taught her, and the equations weren't very well balanced, either. A significant portion of the magic she put into the arrays would be lost just in igniting them. For someone with average levels of magic, she doubted the arrays would be useful at all. For her, though, and certainly for a wizard as powerful as Dumbledore, they would be invaluable in a pinch.

"Thank you, sir," she said, putting the book into her bag with a thrum of anticipation. "I really appreciate the help." After a moment of thought, she added, "Do you think you could help with one other thing this year?"

"I can certainly try," the wizened professor promised.

"You've probably already thought of this, but could you work on discrediting the tournament? The ideal outcome I think would be if I managed to win, so that Riddle has to uphold his agreement about the legislation, but the tournament itself becomes so controversial that a pureblood winning doesn't necessarily buy Riddle's party anything in terms of social or political justification for continuing intolerance of muggleborns and halfbloods." At least, that was the best outcome she could currently see. Then again, she wouldn't feel too put out if Hermione managed to win, either. Having a muggleborn declared blood champion might just be enough to make people see them as equal. Or, her heart sank at the thought, it might be enough to make purebloods hate them even more.

"Since the World Cup, I have dedicated the bulk of my resources to counteracting the radicals and their propaganda." Dumbledore confided. He appeared calm, which she supposed spoke to his volumes of experience in public affairs. Nothing about the radicals and their erratic string of attacks on muggleborn-affiliated institutions was calming. "It is time, perhaps, to turn some of my attention back to this tournament. Doubtless there will be numerous opportunities to inconvenience Tom in the coming months." He seemed almost cheered by the prospect.

"Are you in some way related to the Weasleys?" she asked, smiling a little. "Only, you sound a bit like the twins when they see a chance for mayhem."

"Thank you for that favorable comparison, Mr. Black. I did have red hair in my youth." He curled his white beard absently. "Anything is possible. I haven't examined all the branches in my family tree."

Rigel did not believe that for a moment, but she offered, "My father could tell you how to make one like ours—be warned, though, as it tends to take over whatever room you put it in."

Dumbledore hummed. "I rather prefer the mystery." He flicked his fingers toward the now empty teapot and cups, sending them to whatever dimension Dumbledore's dirty dishes were banished. "Now, then. We did have a lesson scheduled, but perhaps your time would be better served elsewhere this week, Mr. Black. The first task approaches, after all. Unless there is anything else?"

There was, of course, but Rigel felt a little foolish even asking the great wizard. Then she imagined asking anyone else and realized she would feel foolish in any case. It might as well be Dumbledore. "I was wondering—well, I wasn't until today, but after the wand ceremony today I wondered… is there something strange about my wand? Only you and Riddle and Ollivander were all acting a bit odd about it. Maybe I'm being paranoid." She let out a self-deprecating laugh. What did she expect him to say, really?

Dumbledore did not laugh with her. "What did Ollivander tell you about that wand?" he asked. The neutrality in his voice immediately put her on edge.

"He said a phoenix's loyalty was hard to win, I think," she said, frowning. "There was something about another wand, too, but I don't remember it clearly."

The Headmaster inclined his head. "You've met my phoenix, Fawkes, have you not?"

Rigel nodded, eyes widening. "Is it…one of his feathers? I didn't know Ollivander used materials from familiars; I assumed the feather had come from a wild phoenix."

"Most wand materials are collected from wild trees and creatures. At times, however, a creature or being is inspired to give freely of themselves to a wizard. In Fawkes' case, he has given two such feathers in his long life." Dumbledore fixed her with a level gaze. "The second feather resides in your wand, Rigel. I will not lie to you, however; this fact alone is not so extraordinary as to cause alarm. If I may ask, what do you know about brother wands?"

"I've never heard the term," she said, frowning. She was a little amazed to know the exact phoenix that had given a feather for her wand, but there was a fogginess in her mind that told her she didn't fully understand the implications yet.

"It refers to two wands whose core material was taken from the same creature. Not the same species, mind you. The same exact being. It is rare enough for a creature to give more than one hair or feather in a lifetime. Rarer still for two wands who share a core in that way to ever meet." Dumbledore's eyes clouded with thoughts Rigel couldn't hope to follow."

"Please, sir. Are you saying that you and I have brother wands?" She understood that it was extraordinary, but the fact didn't seem to merit the level of gravity Dumbledore was exhibiting.

The old wizard shook his head sharply. "You misunderstand, Rigel. The first feather my phoenix gave does not reside in my wand, but in Tom Riddle's."

The world seemed to go very still. There was a rushing in her ears and the world abruptly occupied an axis that didn't mesh. She gripped the arms of her chair reflexively, fighting the nauseated feeling in her stomach. "That's mad," she whispered. "What kind of sick joke is that? Riddle and I are nothing alike." At least, she fervently hoped they weren't.

"It is not a question of similarity," Dumbledore assured her. "It is merely a stroke of Fate. It means nothing in terms of your own character, Mr. Black. Its import lies in the implication for any interactions between them. It is said that brother wands must never cross one another."

She grimaced. "Are you saying I can't oppose him?"

"Not at all. Your life is your own to lead. If, however, you should ever find yourself at the end of Tom's wand, or he at yours, even I would not hazard a guess as to the outcome." Dumbledore looked truly apologetic. "I don't wish this to unduly influence your actions. I only mean to make you aware of this accident of chance, that you will not be taken by surprise at some future moment through ignorance."

Rigel wasn't sure what she thought about the idea that she and Tom Riddle shared some sort of wand bond. It must be equally upsetting for Dumbledore to think that his political nemesis was carrying one of his familiar's feathers in his wand, though, so she strove to maintain politeness. She rose and collected her book bag from its place near her feet. "Thank you, sir. I appreciate your telling me the truth. There are a number of potions I need to brew today, so I should go and prepare. I promise when the first task is over, I'll catch back up to our normal lesson pace."

"I never doubt your dedication, Mr. Black. Good luck in the forest. If you get into trouble, don't hesitate to send up sparks." His eyes were earnest, not a twinkle in sight. "You've been very brave, but no legislative victory is truly worth your life."

"I'll be careful, sir," she promised. And she really would. Whatever the reward, there were too many people who would never forgive her if she went into the forest and didn't come out.

The day of the first task dawned grey and dreary. She knew she shouldn't be up at dawn, since there was a good chance she'd be up all night traipsing through the dark forest, but she couldn't sleep past first light. Draco and Pansy rose with her, and all three took it easy on their morning jog. Her friends tried to engage her in conversation a couple of times, but she wasn't in the mood to talk about the tournament and talking about anything else felt forced. With no classes to distract her, she retired to her lab to do one last inventory of her potions kit.

She had made all the preparations she could reasonably expect. She had a plethora of first aid potions, including Blood-Replenishers, distilled Dittany, and Pain Relief. There were also fresh doses of her own Protection Potion, with an imbued Fortis that was as strong as she dared. Looking at her kit with critical eyes, there was one other thing she wanted to put into it. She felt stupid for even considering it, but the anxiety in her chest would not let up, so she made her way to the kitchens.

There was to be a grand feast tonight to celebrate the commencement of the tournament tasks, so the expansive room was alive with activity, but Binny somehow took the time to come sit with her while the others made up the package of food and water she wanted to include in her kit. She knew she wouldn't be in the forest more than a few hours, but she couldn't help the impulse. Rigel thought just having the food and water in her pack would help her keep calm in the woods.

"You is being very careful in the woods," Binny cautioned her. "Binny is hearing all sorts of things about the new beings in there." Her voice dropped to a whisper. "Elves is being called to feed them. Otherwise they is eating one another."

"I imagine the dragon eats a lot," she commented. "Is there only the one?"

Binny's ears drooped a little. "You is not supposed to be knowing about her."

Rigel smiled reassuringly. "I didn't hear it from an elf." She didn't push Binny further for details. She didn't have time to prepare for anything new in any case, so there was no sense risking the elf getting in trouble. "So they've kept you all pretty busy down here, huh?"

"We is not minding," Binny said happily. Then her ears drooped again slightly. "But some of the contestants is being more trouble than others."

She frowned. "Who's making trouble for you?"

"I isn't complaining," Binny stressed, though she twisted her hands in her champagne-cork necklace agitatedly. "Missy Granger isn't knowing any better."

"Hermione's been difficult?" Rigel was honestly surprised. Of all the candidates, Hermione seemed one of the least high-maintenance. She supposed she didn't know the girl all that well, though. "I will talk to her," she promised. "She's really a nice person, so I'm sure she didn't mean to cause any trouble."

Binny's eyes widened. "You is speaking to her? Asking her not to be leaving scarfs and hats around?"

Rigel's eyebrows rose in confusion. Normally a house elf wasn't bothered by a bit of mess—in fact, she'd seen Binny positively rapturous over a sink of food-encrusted dishes. "If I ask her to pick up after herself, I'm sure she would," she offered.

The house elf shook her head so hard her ears flapped. "I isn't meaning tidying. Missy Granger is leaving clothes in piles of other things to trick elves into taking. She is freeing elves."

"Oh." Rigel coughed against the urge to laugh. It was certainly not a laughing matter for the elves, but she could see exactly what had happened when Hermione realized that bonded servants—slaves, really—were cooking and cleaning the castle. No doubt the muggleborn girl was shocked and horrified. If she'd done a little research in the Library, any book on house elves could have told her how to free one. Rigel doubted she'd read any good books on their species, however, or she'd know that they not only didn't want to be freed, but that Hermione had no authority to free them, as they were bound to Hogwarts itself, not to the students. Only Dumbledore could free an elf from Hogwarts. Even still, it was probably horribly upsetting for the elves that she was even attempting it. "She definitely doesn't mean any harm. I'll explain the situation to her, all right?"

"Thank you," Binny said, sighing gustily. "The others is fighting over who is cleaning her room."

Poor Hermione. She really did mean well, Rigel knew. She had to, to be expending energy in freeing house elves when by anyone's estimation she ought to have been spending all her time preparing for the tournament. Perhaps she'd benefit from a different project to focus her free time on while she was at Hogwarts. Rigel would have to think about it after the first task.

There was a flurry of activity at the door as one of the Weasley twins ducked into the kitchens and the house elves flocked to press food into his empty palms.

"Rigel?" He spotted her and wound his way through the activity to where she sat. It was George, she realized, in weekend attire of jeans and jumper. "What are you doing down here? Shouldn't you be preparing for the task tonight?"

She gestured to the bundle of food and flasks of water on the table in front of her. "Just collecting supplies."

George eyed the food with a slight frown. "You'll only be in there for a few hours, right?"

Rigel shrugged. "You never know."

Binny excused herself to continue preparations for the feast and George took her abandoned seat next to Rigel. "Is this about last spring? You never talked about it, and it all happened so fast no one could figure out what exactly happened."

"I can't talk about it," she muttered, annoyed that the mere mention of it was already getting her pulse up.

George looked thoughtful. "Whenever my dad can't talk about something at work, it's because there are Unspeakables involved," he said slowly.

"You're very smart, George," she said without expression.

He cursed. "Look, if you're in there for more than six hours, Fred and I will storm in after you. Ron and Ginny will only be a few steps behind. So don't ever think that you're fully alone in there."

She smiled weakly. "Thanks, George. I really appreciate your support."

"Are you really okay with participating, Rigel?" he asked. "You don't have to do this. We can say you're ill. I'll paint Spattergroit pox all over you and you can go home this afternoon. Wait out the year at home, probably do so much self-study that you take your OWLs a year early. You know, normal stuff. Not this madness."

She laughed softly. "Don't tempt me. I know just the potion to mimic Spattergroit's feverish swelling. Pretty sure I could reverse-engineer a healing technique to give myself pustules, too."

"What a talent to brag about," George said, laughing with her. "You may have a grand career in skiving ahead of you."

"My father will be so proud." Actually, he might be, she thought.

"Just don't forget us little people when you're covered in glory."

"And pustules."

They both laughed again. It felt good to just joke about something nonsensical and stop worrying for a few moments. "You're going to do great, you know," George told her.

"I'll do my best for Hogwarts," she allowed. "For Draco and Diggory and all the others who would rather be in my place." For all the halfbloods and muggleborns I might help if I actually won, she added silently.

"I've something to help with that," George said, fishing in his pockets. He had to pull out several sweets before he found what he was looking for. It was a small packet tied with a green ribbon that expanded with a tap of his wand. "This is for you. From Fred and me."

She took the gift carefully. A tug of the string undid the wrapping and revealed a soft long-sleeved jersey in forest green. She lifted it to see a silver snake, black badger, golden lion, and bronze eagle embroidered proudly down the sleeves. On the back it read 'HOGWARTS' in bold white lettering. "You shouldn't have," she breathed, running her fingers across the embroidered lion with awe. It was simply stunning.

"We can't have any ambiguity about who we're routing for, can we?" George smiled encouragingly at her. "Anyway, Mum and Ginny helped us make it. Go on, try it on."

She frowned. "I…here?"

He raised an eyebrow. "I don't think the house elves will be too scandalized."

She forced a laugh. "Right. Ok." Rigel stood from the table and gingerly slipped her robes over her head, keeping her shoulders hunched forward so that the material of her undershirt pooled around her chest, disguising any distortion that her not-quite-flat chest might create. She slipped the jersey on quickly, relieved that it proved loose enough and straight enough that any hint of curve about her hips was cleanly hidden.

"It's a bit big," George said, sounding disappointing. "I forget how small you are without the robes."

"It's perfect," she assured him, grinning brightly. "See? I can move freely." She twisted and swung her arms to demonstrate. "I love it. Thank you, George. Thank Fred, too, if you see him before I do."

"He'll be sore I gave it to you without him," George admitted. He shrugged his shoulders. "Didn't know if I'd see you again before the task, though." She went to take it off once more but he stopped her. "Wear it to dinner. Show them all that you're proud to represent this school."

She nodded. "All right. I only hope by the end of tonight the school is proud to have me representing them, too."

"And now we come to the second part of your gift," George said happily. She tried to protest, but he waved her words away impatiently. "This one's just from Fred and me." He produced a smaller box from his pocket. "Open it."

Rigel took it with a rueful smile. "I don't deserve a friend like you, George."

"Don't say that until you've opened it," he laughed.

She lifted the lid and saw…she wasn't sure what. It was a grey disk about the size of the palm of her hand, no more than an inch thick at its center. It seemed blank at first, but when she tilted it toward the light, etched runes glinted dully at her. "What is it?" she asked, looking down into George's expectant face. "Sorry, but I've never seen anything like this before."

"I invented it," George said. He took the hand that was holding the disk and pulled it toward him. "Here, feel this dent?" He guided her finger over the indentation in the center carefully. "Press down on it for a few seconds to activate it. Then throw it as far away from yourself as you can and wait for the show."

"Show?" Rigel looked curiously at the innocuous device. "Does it explode?" she asked jokingly.

"Exactly," George said. At her alarmed frown he added, "Relax, pup. It's a firework."

"This little thing?"

"Don't underestimate it. This baby packs a punch. I thought it would be useful in the forest. If you need a big distraction, or if you just want to celebrate when you win, this little pod will make sure everyone watching remembers your performance." George released her hand and she pocketed the disk reverently.

"I don't know what to say, George. I can't thank you enough." Overwhelmed, she leaned down to give the Gryffindor a brief hug.

He chuckled into her ear. "If you use it, that'll be thanks enough. Just remember to tell people where you got it, if they ask."

She nodded, pulling back. "I will. I suppose I should be going," she added, picking up her robes and the package of food and water. "Pansy and Draco will want to fuss over me before tonight. Thanks again for the jersey and the firework. I'm almost looking forward to tonight." She wasn't, really, but the lie felt like the best way to express her gratitude to George for not only wanting to support and assist her, but also for lightening her heart before what was sure to be a draining ordeal.

"If Draco says anything about the jersey, tell him Fred and I will be glad to make a matching one for him if he's so jealous," George offered.

She grinned. "I'll savor the look on his face so that I may describe it to you in detail."

"This is why you're my favorite," George said solemnly.

Feeling lighter than she had in days, she bid the older boy a good day and headed back to her common room. She really did think her friends would want the opportunity to fuss, and she was in a much better mood to accept it than she had been that morning.

Her friends were waiting for her when she reached her dorm. Crowded into the small room, Pansy, Millicent, Rookwood, and Rosier joined her three roommates in greeting her warmly as she closed the door and set her robes and bag down on her trunk. Theo was the first to comment on her attire.

"Have you spent all afternoon coming up with that?" he asked, pacing around her in a circle to get the full effect. "It's a little sappy; why include the other houses at all?"

"The Weasleys made it for me," Rigel said staunchly. "I like it."

"It's lovely," Pansy assured her. "Savvy, too. You'll need the support of the whole school, not just Slytherin, to make it through this tournament with your dignity intact."

Rigel grimaced. "Thanks, Pan. All this time I've been worried about my life and limbs; I completely forgot to consider my dignity." She smiled to let the girl know she was joking, and Pansy swatted her gently on the arm.

"Really, Rigel. You should know that dignity is much more important than limbs." Pansy sniffed.

"You can regrow limbs, after all, provided they aren't cursed," Theo agreed. "Dignity, once lost, is gone forever."

"Or at least until you kill all the witnesses," Rosier drawled.

"How many people will be watching the task tonight?" Rigel asked, her lips twitching.

"More than even you could kill before the paper got wind of it," Blaise calculated.

"Rigel isn't going to kill anyone," Draco said firmly. "He's going to crush the rest of those pretenders and rise victorious at the spearhead of a new age."

There was a moment of silence as everyone processed this. Rigel broke into incredulous laughter, and the others followed. "Really?" she said, wiping at her eyes with her palm. "No pressure then, eh?"

Draco cracked a grin at her. "Don't act as though pressure even phases you, Rye. Sometimes I think you work better with it."

"You're faith in me is terrifying," she told him. The others laughed again. "What are you all doing here, anyway? Come to take one last look at me before a dragon chomps me in half?"

"Don't joke about that," Pansy said, at the same time that Rookwood blurted, "How do you know about the dragon?"

Her friends turned incredulous eyes on Rookwood. Even Rosier looked visibly surprised. "What dragon?" the golden-eyed upperclassman demanded, his voice clipped.

Rookwood's normally stoic face took on an apologetic cast. "My uncle was responsible for procuring a lot of the creatures for the task. I wasn't allowed to say anything, Rigel. I wanted to tell you. I did include the breed in that stack of creature references I gave you."

"I know, and there's no need to tell me," she said, smiling. "I've got my own sources of intelligence."

Rookwood peered at her for a moment, then smiled in realization. "You asked a snake, didn't you?"

"A gentleman never speaks to snakes and tells," she assured him with an innocent blink.

"I see. Well, since you already know, do you need any advice about the creatures you're to face tonight?" Rookwood asked, eyes intent on her face. She kept it relaxed and unconcerned.

"I'm as prepared as I can be," she said. "Thank you, though. I appreciate your offer."

"Then you'll definitely appreciate what the rest of us got you," Theo said cheerfully. "And you won't be churlish or refuse our help on principle at all, will you?"

Rigel sighed. There was no way to contradict him, seeing as she was already wearing the Weasley twins' jersey. "Who, me?" she joked weakly.

"Excellent. Millie and I thought what you needed more than anything was an alternative to your usual death-defying solo stunts." He gestured to Millicent, who presented her with a clear semi-circle of soft, gel-like material. It was smaller than the nail on her finger.

"It goes on your ear," Millicent explained. "You hook it on the outer edge and it's spelled to stay put. It's an emergency beacon. If you're ever put in a position where you've lost your wand, all you have to do it crush it and a signal that no magic can dampen will be sent up into the sky."

"Even if your limbs are secured, as long as your head can move, you can smash it against your own shoulder," Theo added. He looked a bit uncertain. "It may seem like a coward's gift, but it never hurts to have a back-up plan."

"I love it." She clipped it onto her right ear at once and felt the magic gently attach itself to her cartilage. Rigel's throat was a bit tight, so she merely smiled with bright eyes at her friends. "Thank you very much." It was hard not to imagine how differently her ordeal last spring might have gone if she'd had something like this on her person.

"My turn." Blaise drew her attention to a pair of black gloves in his hands. He held them toward her and let her take the thin material. Runes glinted at her as her fingers explored the gloves. "I've been working on these for a few weeks. As long as the runic sequences remain intact, your grip will never slip. They'll also resist summoning, to a certain degree."

Her eyebrows rose. That was not an easy feat to accomplish. "You're remarkable, Blaise. Thank you. I'm sure these will come in handy." She drew the gloves on over her hands and watched the dark-skinned boy smile in subtle pleasure.

Rosier approached her next, a pile of material in his hands. "This is from Edmund and me," he said. The older boy almost looked embarrassed, though she told herself that couldn't possibly be the case. Rosier was always oozing confidence.

She unfolded the material to reveal a midnight cloak of sturdy matte material. "It's very handsome," she said, holding it up to test the length against her height. It was exactly the right size to cover the majority of her form without risking tripping her up.

"The forest is dark at night," Rookwood commented. "We thought you might like a bit of camouflage."

"We didn't realize the Weasleys were making you a garment meant to be seen, however," Rosier added, gesturing to her jersey.

"That's all right," she assured them. "Probably for the best, actually. I can wear the jersey until I get into the trees and then slip the cloak on. The other competitors will be looking out for my bright embroidery, and I'll slip right by them." It would help with the cold, too, she didn't doubt. Rigel had to admire her friends' utterly practical impulses when it came to gifts. She hadn't expected anything so material in terms of their support, but she couldn't deny every item the Slytherins had decided on would be of great use that year.

The two upperclassmen looked gratified, and stepped back to let Draco move toward her next. Her blond friend had a smug look on his face that said he knew she was going to like whatever he was about to present her. Draco held out a box about one foot across with green and silver striping. With curling lips, she accepted the gift and pried back the lid.

"You weren't kidding," she laughed, reaching inside to extract a beautiful black gauntlet that seemed to suck the light into it rather than reflect it. "Will they really reflect magic?"

"They ought to, as they're goblin forged," Draco said proudly. "Flip them over."

She turned the gauntlet she held to its underside, where the Malfoy family crest was etched in dull silver near the wrist. Rigel snorted. "Wonderful, Dray. My father will have kittens if he sees this."

Draco smirked. "It was father's idea. We did put the Black crest on the other one."

Sure enough, when she shifted the box so that she could withdraw the other gauntlet, she saw the Black family emblem carefully pressed into its underside as well. "Thank you, Draco. And thank your father, too, please."

"You can thank him yourself," Draco said. "He'll be at the task tonight. Mother, too. Try them on, then. The right one is supposed to fit over the holster Pansy and I got you for your birthday."

She rolled up the jersey's sleeves to reveal the soft leather holster on her right forearm. Once she loosened the straps, the gauntlet slid easily over the skin-tight holster and left room at the wrist for her wand to pass through to her hand unimpeded. "They're perfect. Help me tighten them?"

Draco and Pansy each set to one forearm, adjusting and tightening the gauntlets with care. "They should be strong enough to absorb all but the most powerful spells," Draco said when he'd finished her right arm to his satisfaction. He rolled the sleeve of her jersey halfway down the gauntlet gently. "Physical objects, too, of course."

She rotated her forearms and clenched her fists. "These are amazing, Dray. I can't wait to try them out." She looked at each of her incredible friends and smiled softly. "Thank you all so much. I don't know what I'd do without you."

"Walk into the forest naked, no doubt," Theo suggested.

"Would that be considered brave or idiotic?" she wondered.

"Both, of course," Millicent said with a scoff. "Thank Salazar you aren't a Gryffindor, Rigel. You'd be maimed within minutes."

"No talk of maiming before the task," Pansy said sternly. "Besides, I haven't given my present to Rigel yet."

"No one could ever forget you, Pansy," Rigel said fondly. "Still, you didn't have to get me anything."

"My gift is immaterial," Pansy declared haughtily. At Rigel's curious look, she settled into a grin. "I'm going to braid your hair."

Rigel blinked. "And that's…not a punishment?"

Her friends chortled. Glancing between Rigel's fearful smile and Pansy's unyielding expression, Theo said, "That's our cue, mates. I'll see you at dinner, Rigel."

He left, followed shortly by Blaise and Millicent. Rosier cast a single, unreadable glance at Pansy before following suit, Rookwood on his heels. They each bid her good luck even as they abandoned her to Pansy's tender mercy.

When it was only Rigel, Pansy, and Draco left in the room, Pansy let out a chuckle. "Honestly, I don't have to braid it if you don't want. I just thought you'd like some time to yourself before dinner."

Rigel sank onto her bed with a sigh of relief. "I would, actually. Some peace right now would be priceless, Pan—but only if you and Draco stay, of course." She didn't want to be left entirely alone with her thoughts, after all. Nothing good would come of that.

Draco sat on his own bed, Pansy primly perching on the edge beside him. His eyes took on an intent focus as they roamed over Rigel's relaxed form. "Have you packed everything you need?" he asked.

She nodded. "It's all in my book bag. Potions kit, first-aid supplies, food and water, emergency portkey, and a few other odds and ends. I'll add the cloak and be all set."

"What about your starlight," Draco pressed. "That'll come in handy in the forest."

Rigel lied. "It's in there, too." It wasn't, of course. Archie's starlight would never shine for her, so he'd taken it to AIM with him. She did have the invisibility cloak, though. Merlin willing, she wouldn't need it.

Draco's intent expression didn't let up. As the phantom pain came from her subconscious, warning her, Draco sighed. "You're worried," he said flatly. "It's upsetting you."

She shrugged her shoulders. "Hard not to be. Anything could happen tonight."

"Let me help," Draco said. He leaned forward and reached across the gap between their beds toward her. "Take my hand."

Frowning, she examined his outstretched palm. "I'm okay, Dray."

He leant forward all the way and plucked her hand from her lap. "Relax, Rigel. You've helped me plenty of time. I've finally learned how to turn it around, I think." She felt it the moment Draco's magic reached out and attempted to wrap itself around hers. At first, she balked at the invasive feeling. Her head grew tight with pain as Dom made his complaints known simultaneously. Draco grunted. "Don't fight it. Trust me, Rigel."

She tried. She consciously clamped down on the urge to throw up her Occlumency walls and instead attempted to allow Draco the control he needed to connect to her emotions with his gift. Almost at once, a flood of calm washed over her senses, momentarily blurring her perception completely. "Can you dial it back?" she gasped, shaking her head against the heady sensation. The feeling of floating receded, and in its place was a peaceful numbness that left her oddly still, as though a wind that she hadn't noticed buffeting her had suddenly blown out. Through the almost eerie stillness, she managed to ask, "When did you learn this?"

Draco sounded pleased with himself as he admitted, "I've been practicing on fish in the Black Lake for a while. It works through the glass in our common room, you know."

"That's great," she said with numb lips. It was impressive that he'd learned to project emotions onto others after only a couple of years with his gift. Impressive, and also a bit terrifying. She couldn't deny that she was a lot less stressed than she had been before, though. It didn't feel entirely natural, but she supposed it wouldn't hurt to let Draco project serenity on her for a few minutes. "Feels good. Is this how normal people feel all the time?"

Draco laughed. "I doubt it. Pretty sure I don't have the ratio of pleasure-to-numbness down yet. I'll try to lighten it up again."

Rigel nodded as the strangely airy feeling slowly dissipated, leaving only staid acceptance in its place. She took a deep breath and let it out slowly. "Better. I only feel a little bit drunk, now."

Draco released her hand as Pansy wrinkled her nose. "You don't drink, Rigel."

"I've been dosed with enough experimental prank potions to understand the feeling," Rigel said. She tilted her head at the girl, examining the fringe that fell across her brow with a critical frown. "Do you still want to braid my hair, Pan?" she offered. "It is getting a bit long."

"I noticed you tossing it out of your eyes in your duel with Draco," Pansy agreed. She crossed to Rigel's bed and climbed up beside her. Sure fingers carded through her curl-prone locks and captured the strands at her temple one by one. "It's really only bad here in the front," she commented. The girl was so close Rigel could feel her breath against her face and awkwardly averted her gaze toward Draco, who met her gaze with a smirk. Rigel narrowed her eyes at him, but otherwise couldn't move under Pansy's ministrations.

"Leave the sides," Rigel requested. "That way I can hide the beacon Millicent and Theo gave me."

Pansy nodded with a hum of agreement. When she had reached a length that satisfied her, Pansy transferred the strands to her left hand. She collected her wand with the other hand, tapping the half-braid firmly and letting go with her hand simultaneously. "There. That spell will stay for at least twelve hours, and it won't slip like a fastener would."

Rigel reached up a hand to feel her fringe gathered into a single braid that hugged her head loosely back to the top of her crown, where it was affixed. After that, the hair hung freely among the rest of her locks. She shook her head firmly and felt nothing slip. "Thanks, Pan," she said, smiling gratefully. "I reckon I'm about as ready as I'll ever be."

"Good thing, since it's almost dinner time," Draco said, standing with a stretch. He looked Rigel from head to toe as she and Pansy rose as well. "Don't forget your cloak."

She collected her book bag and gently pushed the cloak into the space at the top. It would be a good cushion for the rest of the contents, she thought. With everything she needed now secured, Rigel shrunk the bag down to the size of a matchbook and put it gently in her right-side trouser pocket. It fit easily next to George's firework device, and she pulled the string that secured the pocket tight.

"We should get him something more tactical for the next task," Pansy told Draco.

"I agree. It'll take time for him to fetch anything he might need. Maybe some kind of belt pouch?" Draco suggested.

"Still here," Rigel reminded them blandly. "And you two don't need to be acquiring things for me for every task."

"Are you going to get something to better carry your supplies for quick access?" Draco asked her pointedly.

Rigel pressed her lips together in exasperation before saying, "My book bag works just fine."

"We'll see how it goes for this task," Pansy allowed. "During your debrief with me and Millie we can discuss it again."

She let out a small sigh, but knew she would not win an argument on the subject at that time. Instead, she focused on re-tying her boots and tucking the laces away securely so they couldn't catch on anything. Boots. Pants and pockets. Breathable undershirt and Hogwarts jersey. Wand holster. Gauntlets. Gloves. She was ready. "Let's go," she said. She felt strong. Prepared. There was a lightness to her bearing that she had been missing. Draco ought to bottle his ability and sell it in the streets. He'd be richer than Midas in no time.

Draco sighed. "Aren't you forgetting something, Rye?"

She blinked. "No?"

He crossed to her trunk and picked up the robes she'd been wearing before putting the jersey on. When he thrust his hand in the pocket, Rigel realized with a flick of her wrist that she'd neglected to put her wand in the holster.

"Merlin help us," Pansy murmured and Draco produced the holly wand from her robes and held it toward Rigel with a shake of his head.

"I was using it earlier in my lab and just forgot to put it back in the holster afterwards," Rigel defended.

"That's what you have us for," Draco huffed. "So try not to forget your head in the forest if you can help it." When she opened her mouth he held up a hand, forestalling her. "Ah-ah! Don't make any promises you can't keep, Rigel. Just try."

Pansy giggled. Even Rigel had to grin. What would she do without them? She plucked the wand from Draco's hand and tucked it through the bottom of the gauntlet to rest securely in its holster where it might actually be of use to her. "Now, let's go," Pansy said. She looped her arm through Rigel's. "My parents didn't spring for the VIP tent, but I can at least walk you down from the castle."

It was a mark of the diminishing influence of Draco's calming magic on her that Rigel mustered a frown of confusion. "VIP tent? Aren't we going to the Great Hall?"

Pansy cast her a worried glance. "Didn't Professor Snape tell you that the champions are to feast with the distinguished visitors who've come to watch the first task? You go to his office every other day, it seems. I thought you were strategizing."

"We've focused rather heavily on what happens after I go into the forest, for some reason," Rigel said wryly. "What's this special feast, then? Am I required to go?"

"If they're charging 100 galleons a head for the buffet, I imagine the champions are expected to attend," Draco drawled. They stepped into the common room to find a crowd gathered at the entrance. "We're to have an escort, it seems."

When the students began to notice Rigel walking toward them, many broke out into spontaneous applause and patted her on her back as she passed.

"Good luck, Black!"

"Show 'em what for."

"I've got good money on you." This was from Adrian Pucey, who winked at her as she shot him a disapproving look.

Rigel thanked her housemates over and over, nodding her head here and smiling in gratitude there until she, Pansy, and Draco had cut a path to the door. They led the way through the dungeons and up into the Entrance Hall and another rowdy cheer broke out as the students peeled off for their feast in the Great Hall and left Pansy and Draco to walk Rigel out the doors.

The night wind was already snaking questing fingers into their clothes, and Rigel said, "You guys don't have to come all the way out with me. I can see it from here."

Pansy grimaced, but nodded. She hadn't brought her cloak to dinner, though Draco had. Actually, Draco was quite well dressed now that she looked at him properly. The blonde girl moved forward to very gingerly embrace Rigel. "Be safe," she whispered. "I'll see you after. No matter what happens, just come back safe."

Rigel nodded, though she didn't promise anything with words. She knew better than to tempt Fate's hand on a night when chance might have enormous impact on her immediate quality of life. Pansy gave her a last reassuring smile and dashed back indoors. When she turned expectant eyes on Draco, the boy smirked.

"As if my parents would miss this," he scoffed. "I'm obviously coming to the VIP tent with you."

She grinned back at him. "We mustn't be late, then. All those people of dignity will think the Malfoys have had an unduly poor influence on the Black scion."

Draco tutted at her as they strode toward a large, white pavilion that glittered in the setting sun. "If anything, everyone will be grateful I managed to wrangle a Black into even a semblance of punctuality. Wasn't your family one of the last to arrive to the New Year's gala last year?"

"Year before that, I think," she said thoughtfully. "And we were also late to your birthday party last summer, weren't we? It's almost as though my father was an anti-social hermit for a decade."

They reached the fabric-covered entrance and peeled back the flap. However big the tent had seemed on the outside, it was nothing to the space that existed within its magical dimensions. Her eyes followed the milling of a hundred glittering attendees and Rigel looked down at her forest-ready outfit with a grimace.

"Do you think I'm underdressed?"

"Unavoidably," Draco confirmed. He removed his cloak with a flourish, revealing the full immaculate splendor of his outfit. She shot his polished shoes a dirty look. Really, he might have warned her. "Look, there's Mother. Your father, too. I guess you are the least punctual of the Blacks."

"I'll never live down the shame," she intoned.

After handing his cloak off to a house elf standing by, Draco steered her briskly through the throng of people, many of whom did a double take at Rigel's face and attire. Upon closer inspection, they found that Mrs. Malfoy and Sirius also stood near the Minister of Magic and his entourage. James was there, in smart robes that were nevertheless still clearly marked with the DMLE's crest. His watchful eyes caught hers briefly and he nodded.

"Archie, there you are!" Sirius bounded forward and embraced Rigel fiercely. "I wondered if we'd have to send someone to find you. How are you, pup? Nervous? Excited?"

"I'm fine, Dad. Feeling good, in fact. Sorry I'm late; I didn't find out about the VIP thing until just now," she said, affecting Archie's sheepish grin. "Guess I should pay a little more attention to things going on around me, huh?"

"Only if you want to survive the night," Draco muttered.

"Young Mr. Malfoy, it's been too long." Sirius stepped back from Rigel and extended his hand to grip Draco's firmly in a gesture of respect. "I suppose it was you who ensured my son's semi-timely arrival?"

Draco's smirk was positively engorged with amusement at Rigel's expense. "You know how Rigel is; he'd never leave the lab if we didn't lure him out with food."

Sirius's eyebrows rose in amusement. "Our Harry is just the same at home. Seems even when he spends the entire summer away her influence rubs off on him."

"Right here," she tried halfheartedly. Mrs. Malfoy came to her rescue.

"Now is no time to tease the young man of the hour," Narcissa said firmly. Her gaze alone brushed Sirius two steps back so that she could move squarely before Rigel. They were nearly of a height now, she realized with surprise. She could still remember the first time she'd met the lovely lady, when her head had scarcely reached Mrs. Malfoy's chin.

Rigel took Narcissa's outstretched hand with a practiced bow. "I hope you have come to support me tonight, Lady Malfoy. My every step will be sure if I walk with the knowledge of your favor."

"Then I expect you won't stumble." Narcissa smiled.

"If he does, it'll be because the fool is competing in his potions boots instead of his trainers," Draco told his mother with a long-suffering sigh.

"Won't they slow you down?" Mrs. Malfoy asked with a frown.

"Not in the least. Besides, if I step on a runespoor in trainers my stint in this tournament will be very short," Rigel reasoned. "These things will at least slow it down."

Sirius looked curiously down at the boots as well. "Doesn't Harry have a pair like that?"

Rigel nodded cheerfully. "She recommended them a while back. And they're wonderful." And Archie would be getting a used pair for Christmas to collaborate her lie.

Draco looked ready to make some other, doubtless disparaging, comment about her lovely boots, but he was interrupted by the Minister. Fudge came forward and clasped a hand jovially on Rigel's shoulder. "All ready are you, Mr. Black?"

She slid her eyes curiously across his face, wondering whether he was truly asking. The wide smile plastered across his it made her think otherwise. "As ready as can be expected, with so much mystery surrounding the task," she said evenly.

"Yes, devilishly tricky fellow, our Lord Riddle," Fudge said proudly. "I don't doubt you're in for a few surprises. Still, you'll do us proud, won't you?"

"If I don't, I'm sure one of the other two competitors from Great Britain will," she assured the man with false cheer.

"Ah. Yes, of course," Fudge said. His smile was not quite as brilliant as it had been, but he seemed prepared to bluster through his uncertainty. "Marvelous, to have so many competitors together in one event, isn't it? The tournaments of the past had three champions, but we've got nine, and representing the whole world, too."

She wondered if it escaped him that, as three of the nine were citizens of Magical Britain and four spoke English as their native language, the tournament wasn't all that representative of the global magical community at all. She settled for saying, "What good luck that Mr. Riddle felt like arranging such an opportunity this year."

The Minister's face fell a little more at the implied dismissal of the Ministry's part in organizing the tournament, but he recovered quickly. "Yes, we're lucky to have such a civil servant in our times."

"I was curious about something, though," she told the Minister, blinking at him slowly. She saw James grimace at her from the corner of her eye, but she couldn't help herself. It was the same at the World Cup. There was something extremely irresistible about making this small, blustery man uncomfortable.

Considering his part in how uncomfortable her year had become, she didn't feel too bad as he melted under her wide gaze and said, "Ah. Yes? I can't reveal too many surprises, mind you, but you are the first to ask…"

She smiled tightly. "I just meant about the logistics of the tournament, Minister. While we're all wandering around in the Dark Forest, how exactly will anyone watch our progress? Or are we to enter unmonitored?"

"Definitely not," Fudge exclaimed, laughing loudly. "Why, imagine! A spectator sport where no one could see what was happening. No, Mr. Black, we've a very special system in place for this tournament." He winked at her exaggeratedly.

"So the competitors will be monitored," Narcissa prompted.

"Yes, yes, Dumbledore himself insisted on it, you know. It was the major condition to his full cooperation with tournament preparations," Fudge confided. "Very careful, that Dumbledore. His old Alchemy Master is the one who came up with the concept, in fact."

"Nicholas Flamel?" Rigel said, surprised. The famous Alchemist had purportedly been retired for years, living a quiet life on the continent. He didn't take commissions any longer, though she supposed if anyone was worth an exception it was Albus Dumbledore.

"The very same," Fudge said, nodding smugly. "You see he invented some kind of rune pattern that connects two points. Every champion will get a headband with a sort of magical sensor on it, and just across the lawn as we speak there are nine great mirrors on the Quidditch pitch. Every champion's surroundings will be visible on the mirrors, you see?"

"That sounds like Muggle technology," Sirius said, looking curious. "The telly-visy that Arthur is always talking about."

"A television, I believe," Narcissa said. At Sirius' incredulous look, she lifted her chin regally. "You think your friends are the only ones who keep tabs on Muggle affairs?"

"Evidently not," Sirius said, inclining his head with an easy smile. "Tell us more about this televisin, Cissy."

"I'd rather let the Minister explain it," Narcissa said primly. She cut cool eyes toward Fudge and added, "How does it work exactly, Minister Fudge? Will the runic array on the champions' headbands transmit sound as well as images to the mirrors?"

Fudge cleared his throat. "Well, I'm no expert, you understand. Lord Riddle seems to think the sound will… take turns, in a way. So it won't be confusing, see? Just one at a time…I believe."

Rigel had to conclude that Fudge was attempting to repeat an explanation that had only been given to him once—one that he had merely pretended to understand at the time, no less. "That sounds very entertaining," she offered. "A shame I will not get to see it myself."

"Not unless you don't make the cut for the final rounds," Sirius said, smiling unrepentantly in the face of the sour look she shot him for it. "Then you can watch with the other students."

"Something to look forward to, then," Rigel drawled. "If you'll excuse me Minister, Father, Lady Malfoy. I must get something to eat before the task."

"Yes, of course," Fudge said jovially, patting Rigel on the shoulder once again. "You must keep your strength up. It might be a long night, eh?"

"Just so." She kept a polite smile in place until she lost sight of the Minister in the crowd. She'd only just reached the long table of food in the center of the pavilion when Malfoy caught up to her.

"Must you bait the Minister of Magic so blatantly?" her friend asked as they took plates and began a slow perusal of the options.

"He didn't seem to notice, so what's the harm?" Her nose wrinkled as she took in the rich spread before her. It all looked dreadfully heavy. She didn't fancy sprinting through the woods on a bursting stomach.

"Everyone else noticed," Draco told her sternly. "It's fine in front of Mother and your family, but anyone who overhears will get the wrong idea about your political leanings."

Or exactly the right idea, she mused, unconcerned. She settled on a couple of rolls and several slices of cured salami. Draco eyed her plate critically but didn't comment, and the two of them found a table in the corner to eat their fill. Looking around at the crowd of posh partygoers, Rigel had to smile. It was impossible to maintain an air of serious contemplation or deadly anticipation amidst this flock of utterly unaffected fools. She wondered whether it had been Riddle's idea to make the night of the first task such an aggressive money-maker or whether the Minister and the bugetless Department of Magical Games and Sports had grasped the chance for extra funds with both hands.

"Everything felt perfectly solemn until this," she remarked to Draco when they'd successfully inhaled their food without interruption. "How do they expect any of us to concentrate on the night ahead?"

"Maybe this is the first task," Draco suggested. "First you have to traverse the deadly peril of social disgrace and then escape the grasping talons of desperate socialites. Next, carefully avoid food poisoning at a dubious buffet. Then, and only then, do you earn the privilege of actually fighting for you life in a forest infested with some of the most dangerous magical creatures on earth."

"Makes sense," Rigel agreed. "You have to build up to the heart-stopping terror. If we confront it all at once it won't be appropriately didactic."

"And what moral are we meant to take away from these festivities," her friend wondered aloud.

Rigel was stumped for a moment. Finally, she offered, "Never worry about dismemberment now when it might not happen for another hour?"

Draco frowned. "I don't know, Rigel. It doesn't even rhyme."

She tried again. "A feast of poisoned slime saves a whole lot of time?"

He choked on his glass of punch. "That's criminal. Don't ever become a poet, Rye."

"Only for your delicate sensibilities," she promised.

Draco's eyes caught something over her shoulder and he smiled. "Father is here. Let's go say hi."

Rigel rose and piled her plate on top of his. "You go ahead. I'll find the litterbin and meet you in a moment." Her friend eyed her somewhat suspiciously, but she gave him her most reassuring smile. It only made him more suspicious, she noticed, but he did go on without her. Rigel took her time scanning the room for a receptacle of some kind, and instead spotted the person she most needed to speak with before the first task.

Hermione stood alone at the edge of the pavilion, picking nervously at a plate of hours d'oeuvres. Rigel abandoned her plates shamelessly on an empty table and pressed her way hurriedly toward the girl. Draco would forgive her absence for a little while.

"Hermione," she said, catching the muggleborn girl's eyes as she approached.

"Rigel." Hermione smiled in a relieved fashion. "I thought I was the only one in practical clothing for this event. Have you seen Delacour? She's in an ankle-length gown."

"She'll probably change after the feast," Rigel said, chuckling. She eyed Hermione's sensible jeans and sweater. "Will you be warm enough in that?"

Hermione raised her eyebrows. "Did Harry ask you to mother me?"

"No, actually." Rigel took a breath and just went for it. "I think we should team up."

"Tonight? Little late notice, isn't it?" Hermione's eyebrows drew together in a frown. "Aren't there rules against collusion?"

"Nothing explicate, which basically means it's encouraged," Rigel told her. A Slytherin had written the rules, after all.

"Is it really smart to pretend to work together, though? I know you feel like you need to look out for me, but we are competitors, remember," Hermione said sternly.

"Technically we aren't competitors until the final round. Until then, our only competition are the others in our respective groups. This is a good move for the both of us. I'm an athlete. My reactions are quick and I have the raw power to keep up a strong shield around us for some time. You're a veritable genius according to my cousin. You'll be an advantage if there are puzzles we have to solve in there. You be my smarts and I'll be your reflexes."

"Why do I feel like you have plenty of smarts?" Hermione asked wryly.

"Two heads are better than one," Rigel insisted.

"Two wands, too." Hermione looked tempted, but wary. "How would it work, then? We don't know where we'll be entering the forest, or even if it's in the same place."

"I'll find you," Rigel promised.

Hermione narrowed her eyes. "And I'm to just wait for your arrival?" She obviously suspected it might be a ploy to get her to waste time at the beginning of the task.

"No, you should head inward. I'll jog a diagonal path and catch up to you."

"How will you find me?" the brunette wanted to know.

"I can sense magic that's around me. I think I can recognize you from a fair distance," she revealed.

"What if you're wrong?"

"Then you're no worse off," Rigel said. "I really think we could help one another out, though. This task is going to be tough. The creatures in that forest are not ones anyone should have to face alone."

Hermione looked sharply at her. "You know what sorts of things to expect? I found a copy of Hogwarts, A History in the library that mentioned Acromantula and Centaurs. It was a little dated, though. Do those sort of creatures really still reside in the forest?"

"Those are the locals," Rigel confirmed. "There's a bunch of new creatures too, though. I'll tell you all about them if you team up with me."

Hermione made a face. "Tempting me with knowledge—you are a snake."

Rigel laughed. She didn't know if Hermione expected her to understand the Biblical reference or not. "I wouldn't tempt just anyone, though."

"I'm sure you have your pick of alliances," Hermione said shrewdly. "You're the one with the home pitch advantage, after all. I'd be a fool to refuse."

"We both know you're no fool."

Hermione huffed a laugh. "Consider me teamed, then. Do I get a jersey, too?"

Rigel shook her head with a triumphant grin. "Sorry. It's one of a kind. I look forward to working with you, Hermione." She held out a palm between them.

"And I look forward to hearing just what else we're expected to go up against tonight," Hermione returned, shaking her hand firmly.

"Let's talk after the feast," Rigel agreed. "Since we're already so well-dressed, I'll meet you by the forest when this lot heads down to the pitch."

"What's on the pitch?"

"The television screens everyone will be watching us on," she said, smiling innocently at Hermione's scowl of disbelief.

"You can't use electricity near so much latent magical energy," Hermione said briskly. "What's really down there?"

"If we do well enough in the tasks, you may never find out," Rigel mused.

"I want to know now," Hermione protested, an incredulous laugh escaping her lips. "You're just as bad as Harry, teasing me."

"If you see the Minister, you should ask him to explain it," Rigel suggested, eyes lit with amusement. "He's really much better at articulating the complexities than I am."

"Maybe I will," Hermione said, jutting her chin up in response to her challenge.

"He's just over there." Rigel indicated the direction of her father's mop of black hair. "While you do that, I must find Draco again. He gets a little high strung if I ignore him too long."

Hermione let her go, but Rigel felt the girl's intelligent brown eyes trailing after her. An alliance had been an inspired idea. Archie's friend was more than just book smart—she was quick-witted. In a crisis, the latter was where talent turned to ability.

Rigel sank into the crowd, weaving along with its flow until she spotted trademark platinum blond. It wasn't Draco, but his father, crossing the pavilion to greet Lord Riddle as he stepped through the entrance. She had been wondering when Riddle was going to turn up. It was his party, in a manner of speaking, and she never saw him eschew the limelight unless he had business to attend too. Shady business, at that. His path into the tent took him right by Rigel, who waved a bit disingenuously. She expected him to ignore her, but then Lucius stopped and Riddle paused alongside him.

"Rigel. I see Draco delivered House Malfoy's gift," he said, casting an admiring glance over her gauntlets. "I hope you found them satisfactory?"

"More than, Lord Malfoy," she said, bowing her head in thanks. "I am honored by the regard your house has shown me."

"I have not forgotten the debt that binds your house to mine," Lucius said graciously. "Use them well and do us proud."

"I'll do my best," she said. It was all she could offer, really.

"We know you will," Riddle said with a curl of amusement in his voice. "Do excuse us—we have not yet made the rounds." The two men swept away, leaving Rigel to turn in a slow circle.

Draco had grown over the summer, but he might not be tall enough to see in such a crush, she had to admit. Resigned to searching for her friend the hard way, she began to wander. Here and there she spotted the other eight champions making small talk or filling up on the buffet. The expression on most of their faces was universally impatient. If they felt like she did, they'd much rather be mentally preparing for the task, not expending reserves of patience and concentration they could little afford to lose.

"Archie," she heard over the crowd. There were only a couple of people present who would call her that, so she stopped moving and looked about her. It was James. He broke through the milieu with a sigh and put a hand on her shoulder bracingly. "How do you feel, sport? Well-rested? Get enough to eat?"

She grinned. "Did Aunt Lily ask you to check, or did Remus?"

James laughed. "It was one question from each of them. I'm also to ensure that you've not been cursed, confounded, or otherwise compromised mentally or physically."

Her grin softened into a fond smile. "I'm just fine, Uncle. I promise."

His face grew serious, and she recognized the Head Auror now in his searching gaze. "We thought you were trying to stay out of the tournament, Arch. What happened? Did someone from the SOW Party threaten you?"

Her father was often described by others as brave and determined. Many forgot that he was also smart—you didn't get to be Head Auror if you weren't—and those who did forget often regretted it. James had enough information from what she and Archie had sent home in carefully crafted letters to come to his own conclusions. There weren't many who benefitted from Rigel's participation in the tournament; Riddle's party benefitted twice.

"It wasn't threats," she told him, regret lacing her words. "I'm sorry, Uncle James, but this was an opportunity I couldn't refuse. If I win the tournament, if will be good for everyone."

His face was pained. "It's dangerous, Archie. We only want you to be safe. After last year—"

"Last year taught me valuable lessons," she interrupted. "The year before that, too. I'm stronger now, and wiser, too. I'll be as safe as may be. I hope I make you all proud."

"Of course we're proud," James said, deflating. "We'll be cheering harder than anyone tonight. Lily stayed home with Addy—she's in a very clingy stage, but Remus is going to try and come as soon as the moon sets."

Her eyes widened. "He shouldn't strain himself so soon after the transformation. I'll be just fine, D—don't worry." Bugger. She'd almost called him 'Dad.' "Tell Uncle Remus there's no need."

"Rampaging hippogriffs couldn't keep him away," James said firmly. He glanced around the room, eyes cataloguing everything they beheld in a sweeping judgment. He looked back at her with apology in his face. "The Minister has noticed I'm missing. Before I go, is there anything you need for tonight? I've got my Auror kit on me."

She shook her head. "Thanks, but I'm well-prepared. I've got enough supplies for a week of camping out in that forest."

James grinned. "Atta boy. Blow them all away, Arch. I'll see you after."

Rigel watched him go, and a pinched pocket of emotion in her chest that she hadn't really noticed carrying eased. At least one of Riddle's possible intentions had come to naught. Her family may not understand why she was participating in the tournament, but they hadn't pulled away from her for it. She should never have let even the tiniest drop of doubt creep in; she could count on her family's support no matter what.

When she found Draco, he was with Regulus Black, chatting animatedly about something the required hand-motions.

"—and it bounced into me and knocked me right off my feet! I had no idea a Fortis shield could be used that way."

Alarmed, Rigel cut into their conversation with an uneasy lurch in her throat. "Draco, there you are. I saw your father, but you'd wandered off."

Draco spun around and favored her with a scowl. "I wandered off? Father and I waited, but when Lord Riddle came in, he had to go greet him. Luckily, there are some members of your family who can be counted on to maintain social graces."

"Just the one," she corrected him. "Hello, Uncle Regulus. I hope you're enjoying the evening."

"Nephew," Regulus acknowledged. "Heir Malfoy was just recounting a duel he had with you recently. I understand you have been practicing in your free time; that is wise of you. I don't doubt those skills will be called upon before the year is over."

"Draco is a gifted teacher," Rigel said, smiling. "It would be foolish not to take advantage of his talents in preparing myself for the tournament."

"The way he tells it, you could teach in your own right," Regulus said, eyes bright with undisguised interest. "Your use of the Fortis shield sounds perfectly inspired. Where did you learn such a technique?"

The red flag that had risen slowly when she overheard Draco's conversation was now blowing full tilt in the breeze. Regulus had overseen construction of the arena for the free-dueling tournament that summer. If he had stayed to watch the matches, he would have seen the Fortis shield used in the way Draco described. Rigel tilted her head to the side innocently. "Oh, that? My cousin taught me. She said she saw someone down Diagon Alley practicing the move this summer. It seemed like a fun trick, so we figured out how to recreate it."

"Where in Diagon Alley?" Regulus asked. His voice was inflectionless, as though the answer didn't mean a thing to him. As though he were only making small talk. Except Regulus Black didn't make small talk.

Rigel shrugged with a slight frown. "I'm not too sure. I think she said there was a pub just off the beaten path. The Prancing Pony or something. I guess they have a big court right in front and some people were mucking about for fun there."

"I know the place," Regulus said slowly. "Your…cousin should be careful where she wanders. Some of those 'mucking about' down there are dangerous."

Her eyes widened in dismay. "I'll tell her. I'm sure she wouldn't want to get mixed up in anything unsafe. She just goes poking around for apothecaries from time to time. Says there are better bargains away from the tourist strip."

She saw the moment Regulus accepted her story as plausible. His lip curled slightly in contemptuous understanding. Rigel wondered if anyone had ever warned him that his habit of compartmentalizing his conceptions of people would stunt his perception. She supposed he might prefer it stunted. Some people just wanted the world to make sense, never mind whether that 'sense' had anything to do with reality.

"I'd advise you to keep such tricks to a minimum in the tournament," Regulus said, twisting his lips restively. "A proper pureblood doesn't stoop to cheap entertainment when he duels. If you come up against the other competitors, finish them fast, without finesse."

She couldn't help the way her eyebrows rose in response to his remonstration. "That style may work for some, but my dueling style is as natural to me as the way I run. To change it at this stage only risks hobbling myself. Thank you for the advice, Uncle, but if it comes to dueling, I'll simply do whatever it takes to win. Sorry in advance if that embarrasses you."

Regulus narrowed his eyes at her. "Let's hope you're as quick with your wand as you are with your mouth, Nephew. Good evening, Heir Malfoy."

Draco murmured a good evening in return, then turned to stare at Rigel with disbelief. "Are you determined to alienate everyone tonight? Your uncle is an all right bloke, you know. He was only trying to help."

"Regulus is always only trying to help the Family name; he gives little regard for the people who bear it," Rigel said dismissively. "He seeks to control me because he can't control my father. Sooner or later he'll have to accept that I'm my own person."

"You can be independent without being rude," Draco pointed out. "All you had to do is thank him for his advice and then go and do whatever you want. If he brings it up after the fact, you could just say you tried and failed to follow his advice."

"That only encourages more unwanted advice," she said, chuckling. "When did Pansy knock these subtle manners into you, anyway? Last year you would have been insulted on my behalf."

"I just worry you're pushing away allies faster then you can make them," Draco muttered.

"I have all the allies I need," she said, smiling reassuringly at him. "Why, I made a new one not half an hour ago while you were wandering off without me."

"I wasn't wandering—" Draco cut himself off with a frustrated growl. "You are determined to shred my composure at every turn, Rigel."

"It's overrated," she told him. "I like your candidness better."

"You're terrible at this game."

She sighed. "Oh dear. If I won't make a good poet or politician, what's left for me in this world?"

Draco snorted. "You make a passable clown."

"Good point. Maybe I can win over the other competitors with laughter." Rigel tapped her chin in mock contemplation. "Do you think humor translates across cultures?"

"Your humor would make a dog whine in any language," Draco said bluntly. Then he pursed his lips, considering. "Maybe as a last resort. They might groan themselves into defeat."

She laughed, but it didn't last long. Her friend's smile slid off his face in time with hers. Draco looked a little lost as his eyes searched her face worriedly. "Will you really be all right in there tonight?"

She slowly nodded. "Stay with Pansy while it happens," she requested.

He agreed easily. They stared at one another in solemn sobriety for a moment, and Rigel reflected that when it came down to it, there weren't any words that could rationalize or make palatable what she was about to do. Their reverie was broken by the amplified clearing of a full throat. Ludo Bagman was calling the gathering to attention in the most abrupt way imaginable.

"Ladies and gentlemen, champions, Minister, Lord Riddle, thank you all for coming! In a few moments, the champions will leave to prepare themselves for the night's events, and we invite you all to adjourn to the Quidditch Pitch where your VIP stadium boxes await." Bagman waited while the polite murmurs of excitement pittered in and out. "Contestants, you have one hour to make yourselves ready and meet back at the Gamekeeper's cabin. Good luck!"

"An hour," Draco repeated, frowning. "That's a while yet."

"Most of the others have to change," Rigel said. "I have some business to take care of, in any case."

He stared at her. "Now?"

"Yes," she said, blinking innocently. "Now."

Draco sighed and stuck his hand out to grasp hers firmly. "Be careful, Rye. Good luck."

"Thanks." She watched him melt into the churning crowd to find his parents. A steady string of glittering people she'd never met before touched her shoulder or elbow on their way by and offered their well wishes and words of confidence. She tried to smile politely at them, but by the dozenth anonymous congratulation she could feel the expression straining.

Rigel started making her way toward one of the exits, more than ready to get out of the tent and back into the night air. Minister Fudge and his entourage passed nearby her and she heard the portly politician saying irritably, "…better be more stable than the last one," to a blank faced Regulus Black. She supposed the ordinary Quidditch stands wouldn't be sufficient to hold all the extra spectators. It spoke of Regulus' extensive political connections that he was allowed the contract for the tournament after what happened at the World Cup.

Sirius caught her as she slipped outside, steering her away from prying eyes and around the back of the tent where it was quieter. He hugged her hard, almost as though he couldn't help himself. "I have something for you," he said after a deep breath. He let her go to reach into his pocket and un-shrink something a small bag about the size of her head. "James has been asking around the office, and Remus and I have been reaching out to all our old contacts as well. Information on this tournament is being kept close, but we managed to ferret out a few things you should know. I didn't want to risk a letter, since interference in a tournament this political would be bad news for all of us, but—Archie, I don't know how to tell you. There's a dragon—"

"Dad, I know," she said lowly, glancing around to make sure there were no prying ears nearby. "I can talk to snakes, remember? I just asked one of the forest serpents to scout around for me. Thank you, and thank the others for looking for information for me, but you don't have to worry. I have a plan for the dragon." Sort of. If running away counted as a plan.

Sirius's worry melted into surprise before he beamed at her. "Good man! Right, then. This is from Remus and me." He held out the sack to her curious fingers. "Officially, James has no part in it." He winked at her, and she smiled back. Her family was really the best, sometimes. Not everyone's relatives would risk political fallout for one another.

She opened the bag and pulled out items one by one. First was a bundle of barrier buttons. "These will be useful," she murmured, nodding gratefully. Next she withdrew a roll of…stickers? "Do I need to accessorize or something?" she joked.

"They'll muffle the sound of anything you stick 'em to," Sirius said conspiratorially. "For your shoes."

Rigel grinned. "Brilliant, Dad. When did you come up with that?"

"Marauder Inc. has been busy this month," Sirius said loftily. "Keep going."

She took a small cylinder from the bag and held it up to her nose to read in the gathering darkness. "Fire Free Burn Baste? Is it some kind of cooking spray?"

Sirius chuckled. "We originally designed it as a sort of 'impress your friend by walking through fire' gag, but I've beefed up the recipe for you. Mist it over your clothes and skin, and it'll absorb heat that registers above your body temperature. It only lasts about four hours, but I'm hoping it'll hold off dragon fire just long enough for you to run. Granted, we haven't tested it against anything more potent than the fireplace, so don't go thinking you're invincible."

"This is amazing, Dad. Thank you. And thank Remus, and—"

"Pup, you don't have to thank us. Just come back safe," Sirius said, putting a hand on her head and smiling wanly at her. "I don't know what I'd do if I ever lost you, Arch."

"You won't ever have to find out," she promised. At least, even if everything else somehow went wrong in the forest, she knew that she could keep that one promise. Archie would be safe.

Sirius cleared his throat and shook his head embarrassedly. "Anyway, there's one more thing, from Lily." He dropped a perfectly circular disk of obsidian into her hand. It had a small hole drilled through the center where a string threaded through. "To be honest, I don't know exactly what it does, but she was adamant you wear it. I told her it wasn't your style, but you know how women are."

Rigel favored him with an unimpressed look and brought the stone up to squint at it more carefully. "There's some sort of runic shorthand here, but it's miniscule. I'd need a magnifying spell to read it. She didn't tell you what it does?"

"She tried, but it's a bit above me," Sirius admitted. "I gather it's something she's been experimenting with on and off for a while, and since she's been given a leave of absence from work, she's devoted most of her time to perfecting it. Supposedly it can detect different types of magic headed toward you based on its frequency and vector, and some other stuff that sounded pretty technical…and I think it's some kind of defense mechanism. Lily can explain better when you see her next. She says you don't have to activate it or anything; just wear it, and it will work when it needs to."

"That's ominous," Rigel muttered. Still, she dutifully tied the string to her belt as she added, "If Aunt Lily invented it, it's probably both brilliant and terrifying." She stored the rest of the items methodically, placing them in pockets she would remember. Two of the stickers went onto her boots immediately.

"I suppose that's all I can do you for, son," Sirius said, looking reluctant to go.

She gave him her best Archie-smile. The one that said nothing in the world could bring him down. "I've got this, Dad. I'll see you after and we'll celebrate how amazingly cool I look on mirror-vision."

Sirius allowed himself to grin back at her. "I bet it adds ten pounds."

"Of muscle? Try to catch all the girls who swoon."

"It would be a twist of fate if the papers tomorrow weren't about the first task but instead the witches, young and old, who fell to their deaths at the sight of the chubby Hogwarts champion," Sirius mused.

"Dad," she protested. "I'm not fat."

"I'm only saying you'll probably look fat," he corrected her.

She sighed dramatically. "Go, now. I refuse to be tormented so before my big moment." When Sirius hesitated, clearly torn, she said, more seriously, "Really, Dad. I've got to get ready. See you after?"

"Right after," he promised. "Knock 'em out, kid. I love you."

"Love you, too."

He left, and Rigel took a moment to breathe deeply before squaring her shoulders. She still had work to do, and the first task drew near.

She cut through the night toward Hagrid's hut. A twinkling, floating beacon of light hung suspended in the air above it, she supposed in case any of the competitors weren't sure where exactly it was located. Hermione was pacing before the garden gate when Rigel arrived.

"You're here, good," Hermione said with a tense smile. "Give me all the facts, please."

Rigel leaned against the fence and began the rundown of what the girl should expect in the Dark Forest. "You know about the Acromantula and the Centaurs. The spiders are bigger than anything you're probably imagining. The books will tell you they grow about horse-sized, but the ones in this forest can be twice that tall. Their hides are resistant to spells, and their bite will poison."

"Are they fast?" Hermione asked, chewing on her lips.

"Very. And they eat people," she added, grimacing. "So best to steer clear. The centaurs of course are Beings, which means they can come after you with intelligence. The local herd hates intruders and about eighty percent of them will attack a human on sight. Some will leave children alone, but not if they bear weapons—which we do, as they consider a wand to be combative."

"Okay," Hermione said weakly. "Avoid the spiders and the centaurs. What else?"

Rigel leveled a serious look at the other girl. "I'll be honest, Hermione. Most of my plans tonight involve avoiding and running away. Also in the forest are manticores, quintapeds, trolls, chimera, snallygasters, runespoors, and at least one Peruvian Vipertooth. Plus the Sphinx."

"A dragon?" She began to pace again. "What are they playing at? It can't possibly be humane to keep all those creatures locked up in the same place. Then again, maybe they'll be busy fighting one another and won't notice us."

"They'll probably be confined to their own areas," Rigel offered.

"It's still an enormous risk they're putting us to," Hermione muttered. "And this only the first task."

"Riddle wants to start it with a bang," Rigel reasoned. "Also, we'll be monitored while we're in the forest, remember."

"But even if we shoot up red sparks as soon as we see the dragon, it still might roast us before help arrives," Hermione said flatly.

Rigel had to admit, that was probably true. Unless they had Medi-wizards standing by in secret throughout the forest. Somehow, she doubted that would be the case.

"So, we avoid as many creatures as we can, and when we can't, we run away," Hermione reiterated. Her face twisted in concern. "We could never outrun a chimera. Nor most of the other things."

"We use just enough magic to slow it down or stop it long enough to get away," Rigel amended. "If we have to engage something, here's the plan: for spiders and centaurs, target the legs; for quintapeds and chimera, the underbelly; for manticores and dragons, the eyes; for snallygasters, the wings; for trolls, the top of the skull. The sphinx will only try and gut us if we can't answer its riddle, so at least there's a chance for civility there. Got all that?"

"And runespoors?" Hermione asked impatiently. "Which head is poisonous again?"

"I'll take care of the runespoors," she said. "But it's the right head."

"Fine, then. Legs, underbelly, eyes, wings, skull. Got it, thanks." Hermione's face was a lot scarier when she was processing information, Rigel realized as she watched the girl think furiously. She looked a bit like Lily in the midst of a challenging project, actually.

"Step one is meeting up, though," Rigel said. "It's unlikely we'll all be sent into the forest together. If we are, great, but if not I'll find you right off."

"I'll try to travel on a straight vector to help you find me," Hermione agreed.

"Let's talk about strengths and weaknesses, now," Rigel suggested. "Can you ride a broom?"

"I—no," the girl said sourly. "They don't agree with me."

"Ok, I'll teach you that sometime before the next task," Rigel said, making a mental note. "It'll be useful one day, I promise. We won't need the extra broom, then."

"You brought brooms?" Hermione asked, sounding incredulous.

"Of course. Just in case. I already know you can Heal. How fast can you run?"

Hermione winced. "I'm more of a yoga and Pilates girl, but I won't fall behind."

Rigel considered this. Assuming those were workout regimens that didn't involve running, she supposed Hermione could probably sustain a ten or eleven minute per mile pace if necessary. Not forever, though. "Okay. Harry says you're good with Charms and Transfigurations, yes?" Hermione nodded, looking sure of herself. "Dueling?"

"Just in Defense class," she said. "It's normally very structured. I have been working on silent casting, though."

"That's great," Rigel said. "All right. If you're comfortable with it, I'll take lead in the forest. With my sensing ability I can steer us around nearby dangers quickly. Are you fine with taking direction unless you disagree with a course of action?"

Hermione took a moment to think it over, but nodded decisively once she'd made up her mind.

"And one more thing," Rigel added. "If I tell you to duck or get behind me, just do it, okay? It's not a chivalry thing. There just might come a time you don't want to be standing in front of me. Now, items. What have you brought?"

"Basic first aid kit, water, a bezoar…and an extra hair tie." Hermione grinned sheepishly and fingered her wildly curly ponytail. "I thought a wand would be all I needed, though, really."

"It probably will be," Rigel said, "But you never know."

"Were you a boy scout or something?" Hermione asked, amused.

Rigel didn't know exactly what that was, but she smiled back. "Why, are male scouts known to be particularly paranoid?"

"Prepared is the word they use." Hermione laughed softly. "It's not a bad thing. What have you brought, then?"

"My potions kit, which includes first aid potions as well. A cloak to better blend into the forest after the task starts. A could of knives in case I lose my wand, food and water for a few days—"

"Days?" Hermione spluttered.

"Just in case," she reiterated. "You—"

"Never know, I know." The other girl waved her on. "Anything else?"

"Several things," Rigel said, smiling self-deprecatingly. With a sudden thought, she fished the roll of stickers Sirius had just given her out of her pocket. "In fact, here. Put one on each shoe."

"Trackers?" Hermione guessed.

"Sound mufflers," Rigel corrected. She followed the stickers with the canister of Fire Free. "Hold still and close your eyes and mouth real quick."

"What? No way, what is that?" Hermione balked.

"It'll hopefully keep us from being roasted alive by the dragon. No promises, but it should at least lessen the impact." Rigel handed the can over for her inspection. "You can spray me first, if you like."

Hermione squinted at the label dubiously. "I've never heard of this."

"It's not for sale anywhere yet," Rigel admitted. "My family invented it. They wouldn't give it to me if it wasn't safe."

The other girl grimaced, but held the nozzle toward herself gamely and began to mist the thick cloud that emerged over her legs. Rigel helped her cover the areas she couldn't reach, and Hermione did the same for her. When they were sufficiently coated in the substance, which left a somewhat oily feeling on her skin but at least didn't have a noticeable odor, Rigel packed the items in her bag.

Krum was the first of the other champions to arrive. He was dressed in shorts and a fitted, sleeveless top that showed off his fitness. He gave them a suspicious look, but began stretching near the fire without comment. Feiyan Shang arrived soon after, devoid of her usual makeup, with her hair secure in a simple bun at the back of her head. She wore leggings with a long tunic adorned with an animalistic mask in embroidered silk on the back. Krum paused in his warm up to remark, "The Tao-tie, yes?"

Feiyan blinked at him in surprise. "It is. Symbols are important." She gestured to Rigel's Hogwarts jersey and the Bulgarian flag on the pocket of Krum's shorts.

Tahiil came jogging across the lawn in a set of warm-looking sweats, his usual cheerful expression undauntedly in place. "Good night for a walk in the woods," he said, gesturing to the full moon above their heads. Hermione murmured a few words of polite agreement, but in truth none of the others seemed much in the mood for conversation.

Antiope arrived next, wielding a sword as long as her arm. At the incredulous stares she received from Hermione and Tahiil, she grunted. "What? He said we could bring anything." She, too, wore gauntlets, though hers jutted out beyond her elbows in sharp points. Besides Rigel, she was the only other one who'd chosen boots over trainers.

"Can I hold it?" Tahiil asked, looking awed at the redhead's weapon. "Please, Antiope?"

Antiope frowned. "No. But you may touch it while I hold it."

The Somali boy happily did so, running a careful finger along the gleaming blade. "So many etchings. What do they mean?"

"Most of them are runes for protection, strength, and durability," Antiope said shortly.

While they were talking, Sousa, Owens, and Delacour all joined them around the fire. Fleur and Jacob greeted the assembled, but Matheus was quiet. The Brazilian contestant wore denim trousers with a sweatshirt and seemed less than his normal suave self. He stared somewhat listlessly into the fire while swaying ever so slightly in the breeze.

Owens, at least, appeared ready for the first task. His expression was absolutely set, and none of the worry or nervousness that shone on other faces reflected in his. With a set of Ilvermorny shorts and a long sleeve shirt, he looked confident and collected. When he caught Rigel studying him, he winked.

Fleur, resplendent in a deep blue tracksuit, made her way closer to the fence where Rigel and Hermione were standing. "I zaw you two whispering at ze feast," she remarked, hauntingly beautiful eyes glancing between them. "You must have a plan, no?"

"Could be," Rigel said, giving nothing away with her expression. "Hard to make plans when we don't know what the task really is yet, though, don't you think?"

"Oui. I do. Now you understand ze curiosity I feel." Her eyes were definitely suspicious. She thought Rigel and Hermione might know something she didn't. Well, she was right, but Rigel was under no obligation to tell her so.

"I understand," Rigel assured the girl. "Unfortunately we don't know the specifics of the task any more than you do. Hermione was only asking me about the creatures in the forest—since I have the home pitch advantage, it's only fair I share what I know."

"Share, zen," Fleur invited her, smiling mockingly. Her ponytail fell across her shoulders as she tilted her head to show she was listening.

Rigel shrugged. "I'm sure by now everyone knows. There are centaurs, thestrals, spiders, snakes, and unicorns in the forest here. I think the real challenge will be whatever the organizers have added to the forest since they put those wards up."

"I tried to fly over them," Krum put in unexpectedly. "There vas no opening. The vards extend over the trees. I suspect something vith vings."

"Very likely," Hermione agreed, nodding her head slowly as though this fact was new to her. "Excellent deduction, Mr. Krum."

Krum raised his eyebrows at the praise. "Thank you, Her-mee-on. Just Victor, please."

"Should we really be on a first name basis?" Antiope broke in. "We might have to fight to the death in there."

Rigel couldn't tell if she was joking. Just in case, she said, "I think the other competitors are the least of our concern tonight. If I know Riddle, he'll have several very nasty surprises in there. Focusing on anything but the creatures we face could have grave consequences."

"Very true, Mr. Black."

Riddle had arrived. He gestured for the nine competitors to gather around him and produced a delicate cloth bag from his robe sleeve. "I trust you have all made the appropriate preparations for tonight. It is time to reveal exactly what your task entails." He reached into the sack and withdrew a stack of parchment. With deft motions he began to hand them out to each of the champions. Rigel was careful not to let his skin touch hers as she accepted her piece of parchment. Looking down at it, she blinked. It looked like one half of a Teacher Tracker pairing. Just a blank piece of parchment with concentric rings demarking relative distance to the center point. Off toward the forest, a single dot sat motionless on the outer-most ring.

"Those dots represent the prize you will be seeking. While all nine items are collocated, you will know which one is yours when you reach it. You must see to it that your item exits the forest before the sun rises. Taking the item of another champion who has already retrieved his or hers will not afford you points." Riddle glanced around to ensure they heeded his words. "Flip your papers over and you will notice a randomly assigned number. That is your starting position. When you see green sparks fly high above this cottage, the wards around the competition zone will lower for three seconds."

"How will we get back out, then?" Hermione asked.

Riddle's eyes flickered toward the girl. With an empty smile, he said, "If you reach the forest edge and send up green sparks, the wards will be lowered for you to cross."

Hermione nodded, fingering her piece of parchment with worrying hands. "Thank you, Sir."

Rigel caught a glimpse of Hermione's number as the parchment twisted in the light. She was number two. Rigel had five, which she deduced meant she was to start in the middle. Somehow, starting with the easiest position didn't give her confidence in the supposed randomness of the number allocation.

The politician was still explaining, so she put her thoughts on the back burner. "These headbands are to be worn at all times while you are in the forest." He began drawing colored bands from his bag and distributed those as well. "As we speak, the spectators are gathered in the expanded Quidditch pitch. There, nine great mirrors have been erected to display the happenings of this task to the audience. Each of your bands is color-coordinated to match the corresponding mirror that displays your field of view. I warn you: once the inside bands are touching your skin, they activate, and anything you look at from that point on, the spectators see as well. I'm sure I don't have to iterate plainly what activities you shouldn't broadcast."

With varying grimaces and trepidatious expressions of discomfort, they all nodded.

"Does sound transmit as well?" Owens asked, eyeing his yellow band with interest.

"It does, but in order to lessen the burden on the viewers, only one headband's sound is amplified in the stadium at any given time." Riddle handed Rigel her band last. She inspected it carefully, noting the small inset stones and intricate rune derivations running like ants along the outside of it. The material stretched comfortably in her hand. "You have your instructions, champions," Riddle said. A house elf will escort you to your starting position in five minutes. In case of emergency, send up red sparks. Otherwise… I'll see you at the finish line."

He left them to their thoughts. Many of the contestants began inspecting their parchments for more clues, but Rigel didn't bother. She was pretty sure they had just put a Teacher Tracker on the items they were to retrieve. They would have a beacon to guide them through the forest, but no terrain map of any kind to make it easier.

She stepped close to Hermione, and when no one was looking their way, she swapped their parchments quickly. Hermione frowned at her. "I don't think we're allowed to switch," the brown-eyed girl murmured. "Each parchment probably leads to one item."

"They're collocated," Rigel said. "It's better if you start in the middle and I cut my way diagonally across the forest toward you. This way, you can just move straight ahead toward the items until I find you."

Hermione frowned. "I don't mean to take the easy end of our bargain."

"I don't mind the run," Rigel promised. She felt a slight warming under her skin—the Vow wasn't outright forbidding her course of action, but she walked a thin line in trading a good starting spot for an easier time meeting up with Hermione, whose skills she felt would definitely increase her chances of success. The heat settled, and she let out a breath she didn't realize she'd been holding. There was some subjectivity to the Vow, then. Good.

Suddenly, the house elves were there and there was no more time to plan. Rigel showed her elf the number two piece of parchment and she was led quite a ways along the tree line before coming to a stop on a little patch of grass that glowed in the moonlight. Fleur, who had the number one parchment, gave her an unreadable look as she passed. There was enough room between each contestant that Rigel could see neither Fleur nor Krum, who had number three, by the time she fished her cloak from her bag and put it on over her jersey. She took the time to coat her cloak with Fire Free as well, but eventually the moment came to don her headband, which was emerald green. She fit it carefully against her forehead, making sure not to catch her emergency ear piece as she slid it into a comfortable place.

Once it was on, she was careful not to move her head too much. She looked straight ahead into the trees. She kept her breathing light and even, just in case they happened to be transmitting her sound over on the pitch. Rigel briefly entertained the idea of inspecting her fingernails cheekily. She squelched it, though. It was not the time for frivolity.

When the sparks finally came, it was almost anti-climactic. Just a flash of green light in the distance and the barrier before her dropped away. She stepped over the boundary and stopped. She was sure by now the other champions were running, but Rigel needed to listen, first. The sound she needed to hear didn't keep her waiting long.

"Ssspeaker, you have come asss promisssed."

"Treessslider," she hissed, crouching down to the snake's level. "Are you prepared for a long night ahead?"

"Yesss. I have ssscouted tirelessssly for the Ssspeaker." Treeslider wriggled closer and lifted his head up in anticipation. "I will sssteer you true."

"I put my faith in you," Rigel said. She extended her arm to help the green snake coil up it until he was comfortably wrapped around her left bicep, his head near her neck so she could hear him better. "Hold on tight."

She held the parchment map in one hand and her wand in the other. The moonlight just managed to penetrate through the forest canopy and illuminate the dot that was her eventual destination. Sighting a path between it and what she judged to be Hermione's starting point, she began to run.

Treeslider immediately began a litany of tiny instructions, correcting her left, right, right again, and once even bidding her to climb through a particularly dense patch of brush. The routes he insisted she take were not those that would seem appealing to a human; most of the time she was off any semblance of a path. Still, she listened and she stepped wherever he told her: this was his home, not hers, and she didn't doubt the paths would be the easiest places for both large creatures to roam and traps to be set.

At once point, when she stopped to let Treeslider sniff the air with his tongue, she heard a noise somewhere behind them. She focused her attention on her rudimentary magic sensitivity and realized someone was following them, moving steadily through the forest on the trail she'd just blazed with Treeslider. It had to be Delacour, she supposed, since she was the only champion further out than Rigel on their side. She decided to ignore the girl for now. If she knew where she was, Fleur couldn't sneak up on her. Really, it was smart for Delacour to try following Rigel, if she assumed Rigel knew where she was going. It's not as though her trail through the forest was hard to miss, strewn with bent branches and trampled brush as it was.

Treeslider had scented a pack of Thestrals, but wasn't concerned by them. Rigel began to run again, zigzagging this way and that along a path that would look ludicrous if anyone mapped it. Still, she'd made good progress without coming across anything more dangerous than a bowtruckle, so she mentally promised Treeslider a hundred fat mice and kept to his instructions.

"There isss a trap up ahead," Treeslider hissed in her ear. She slowed. "Sssoft sssand that drawsss you in. We mussst crosss, but keep to the fallen treesss."

Rigel nodded her understanding and moved forward at a more cautious rate. It was hard to see in the moonlight, particularly as she'd decided to forego the Night Vision Brew in deference to the possibility of being blinded by an unexpected light, but there was a noticeable difference when the soil gave way to unnatural silt. The quicksand was likely something the tournament organizers had fashioned. She followed Treeslider's instructions and jumped up onto a large log. Carefully balancing, Rigel moved swiftly from one such log to another, ever aware that with a misstep, quagmire awaited her on either side. At an unexpected noise she paused, listening hard. It was coming from the quicksand.

She peered through the darkness and risked calling up a light and brandishing her wand toward the source. It sounded like… cursing. Slavic cursing, she realized. It was Krum, both legs sunk into the quicksand at the thigh. He squinted back at her through the light and cursed again. Well, she couldn't stay too long with the Vow already egging her feet on, but it cost her nothing to conjure a rope and banish it in his direction. He was a strong guy. He could fix it to something with a sticking charm and pull himself out.

Rigel was approaching the vector that Hermione ought to be traveling along, so she projected her sensitivity until it was stretched thin to find the girl. "To the right," she told the snake.

Treeslider hissed unhappily. "Ssspidersss that way. Fassster, Ssspeaker."

Hermione wasn't moving very fast, and Rigel didn't doubt she was worried about their paths missing one another. It was a matter of minutes until Rigel closed in on her location. Hermione's magic was the brightest and warmest against her senses in the area, but as she grew closer and allowed her sensitivity perception to shrink again, she noticed another, much fainter trace of magic right above her. Hermione was not alone.

Rigel barreled into the clearing just as the spider began to descend. "Accio Hermione!" The girl flew off her feet toward Rigel with an indignant yelp. The spider hit the ground and scuttled angrily around to fix its many eyes on them.

Hermione rolled upright and stared at it. "Mother of God," she whispered. Then she shot a stunner toward its harry belly. The red light fizzled harmlessly against the Acromantula, and both girls darted backwards away from it as it reared in annoyance.

"The legs, Hermione," Rigel reminded her. "Tie them on the left side. Now!" Rigel snapped out an Impedimenta just as Hermione mustered an Incarcerous. The Acromantula didn't stop, but it slowed just enough for Hermione's spell to wrap two of its legs together on one side. It stumbled. Rigel followed with a second Incarcerous and down went the other two legs on that same side. Now, when it tried to scuttle toward them, it only managed to turn in a circle.

Already the spider was snapping its fangs in the direction of the rope. It was time to run. She grabbed Hermione's hand and towed her along until the girl's feet caught up with her mind and she was running alongside her. Treeslider's instructions took them off the path immediately and they fought their way through a thick tangle of bramble until the snake said it was safe to stop.

Hermione bent double, gasping for air. "You weren't kidding about the size of those things. That's got to be the biggest spider on earth."

"I think the head of the family is a lot bigger," she said, pulling out water and gulping for a second before adding, "And Hagrid says that one can talk."

Hermione shuddered. "No thank you," she muttered. She sucked down some of her own water before straightening. "All right. You found me, good. How far are we from the items?"

Rigel checked the parchment. "Another half mile, it looks like. We're making good time."

"I didn't run into much before the Acromantula," Hermione commented. "Did you?"

"Just some quicksand over toward where Krum started out. Treeslider here is keeping me out of trouble." Rigel gestured to the snake, which Hermione seemed to notice for the first time judging by her widening eyes.

"Right. Harry did say you speak to snakes. That's…useful." She tightened her ponytail. "Ready, then? I'm recovered."

"Me too. Let's go."

They traveled helter-skelter through the forest, and Hermione, to her credit, didn't complain or hesitate when Rigel relayed Treeslider's navigational instructions in a low, constant stream. At one point they slowed from the jog they'd been maintaining and Rigel listened carefully to what Treeslider was telling her.

"We have to go through centaur territory to get to the items," she told Hermione quietly. "If they catch us, it could be bad."

"Could be?" Hermione said hopefully.

"Depends on their mood," Rigel admitted. "Sometimes they let kids go, sometimes not. Since they're already incensed at being trapped in this part of the forest and cut off from the rest of their territory, I say we don't risk it."

Hermione looked indignant, and it took a second for Rigel to realize it was on the centaur's behalf. "What an awful thing to do to sentient creatures," she said.

They moved forward at a slower pace, listening for disturbances and making as little noise as possible. Rigel pushed her sensitivity out as far as she could, and once or twice she picked up individual sparks of magic across her senses, likely scouts, Treeslider told her. The main herd, or however many of them had been trapped in the wards, at least, wasn't within her sensing range.

The two girls were crouched low behind a ridge of underbrush as one of the centaur scouts passed dangerously close when a runespoor shot out from a burrow beside them and made to take Rigel by surprise.

"Don't you dare!" Treeslider snapped his head toward the attacking runespoor, making it abort the movement mid-lunge. "No one touchesss the Ssspeaker."

The runespoor coiled in on itself, all three heads swiveling to look at Treeslider and Rigel. "A Ssspeaker? Isss it true?" the left head asked.

"It can't be," another head argued.

"Ssshow usss, Ssspeaker," the last head insisted.

Rigel grimaced. The centaur scout was coming closer in her awareness. They couldn't afford to make so much noise. Very, very softly she said, "I am a Ssspeaker." The three heads all moaned their apologies and begged forgiveness. "I will forgive and forget thisss matter… if you dissstract that cccentaur over the ridge. In recompenssse for attacking me, you ssshall not bite any human thisss night."

She wasn't honestly sure the snakes would go for that, since they didn't know her or have any reason to be loyal to her, but figured it was worth a shot. To her relief, the runespoor hissed in pleased acceptance and darted away toward the looming presence of the centaur scout. When the two sparks collided in her awareness, Rigel led Hermione quietly away from the scene.

"Did you just make that snake do your bidding?" Hermione asked tentatively. She didn't sound approving.

"I just asked nicely," Rigel said, smiling innocently. "Snakes are very kind and helpful creatures, you know. Possibly the most altruistic of all animals." She thought the Slytherins watching their progress on the mirrors might appreciate the joke, if either her or Hermione's sound was being broadcast.

Once out of centaur territory, they made it another quarter mile in a handful of minutes. They were so close to the dot on the map, now. Just a little further.

A worldless hiss of warning had Rigel stopping immediately in place, hauling Hermione to a halt beside her. As soon as they stopped moving, she heard it: a crashing wave of disruption headed straight toward them. They dove behind a large tree trunk and froze as the sound approached.

Something immense tore through the canopy and into the clearing they'd just been jogging through. A bellowing roar filled their ears and a stench—so awful it could only belong to one creature—invaded their nostrils.

Troll, Hermione mouthed at her in the darkness. Rigel nodded. Hermione raised her wand and tapped herself on the head. She disappeared before Rigel's eyes, and Rigel grinned. Gesturing to her own head, she silently asked Hermione to do her as well. She felt a shiver like egg yoke going down her spine, and when she looked down she was a mere shimmer in the night. On silenced feet, they crept around the trunk to peer at the troll.

The big, ugly creature sat mournfully in the middle of the clearing, clutching its club in one hand and its head in the other. Blood ran steadily from a gash across its temple. Someone had already had a run-in with this big guy. It bellowed in pain and frustration as it prodded the gash again, and Rigel almost felt sorry for it.

Hermione tugged her wrist and Rigel tried to follow her around the clearing without being able to see her. It helped that she could sense the girl's general location with her magic. They made it halfway around the clearing before the troll jerked its head around and sniffed the air in their general direction. They stilled. Great globs of drool dripped from the troll's clunky, uneven teeth, and it rose unsteadily and began lumbering toward them. The girls ran, darting around trees and foliage, even as the troll roared its displeasure and bounded after its invisible prey.

Rigel spotted a hollowed out root system and tugged Hermione toward it. "Down here," she panted. There were numerous accidental elbows and knees caught in soft places as the two of them tried to simultaneously squeeze under the arching roots and into the hollow left by the soil below. Somehow, they managed it before the troll came lumbering into sight.

It stood there, gaping around itself, sniffing at the air in annoyance. The troll seemed to have no idea what to do next. She gathered it wasn't much of a hunter, really. In the meantime, they were effectively trapped. The soil beneath them was damp, and the entire enclosure smelled of rot. The sensation forced its way into her head, spreading like a damp fog despite her best attempt to clear her thoughts and calm her heart.

The darkness seemed to close in around her. She knew Hermione was next to her, but she couldn't see her. It just felt like a body crammed into the space beside her, and rot rose up in a wave to envelop her in memories and panicked anxiety.

"Rigel," Hermione whispered, nudging her in the arm. Treeslider hissed where she brushed against his scales. The sounds, the movement, called her back somewhat, and she realized she was breathing too fast, and shaking. "What is it?"

Rigel shuddered. "I need. My bag." The words were scarcely more than a sigh. The troll was still there, still shuffling in a dumb circle just outside their hollow. Rigel struggled to focus her mind, but it was like trying to hold burning sand in her hands. She flinched away, the sand slipped out, and she was only vaguely aware of Hermione's hands probing slowly through her pockets.

"It's here, but I can't selectively disillusion it," Hermione whispered. Rigel put all her attention on the words. Those words. Their meaning. Right, her bag was as invisible as she was. That's how a Disillusionment Charm worked. Hermione wouldn't be able to see what was in it.

"Put it in my hand," Rigel mumbled on numb lips. Her heart rate was still climbing, and she could feel her breath getting shorter and faster still. When her bag was pressed into her palm, though, something in her relaxed marginally. Some deep fear was relieved just by the knowledge that her bag and everything in it was already in her hand. She shifted sideways slowly and gave Hermione room to enlarge it. She couldn't focus her magic properly to do it herself, but somehow Hermione knew that.

It was a matter of moments to feel her way around the internal pockets and close her fist around the vial she needed. She withdrew the invisible potion within and uncorked it with a slight snick. Rigel tossed the whole thing back, then reached into her bag and drew out another. She drank that one too, and with the second dose came a rush of pure, numb tranquility that almost brought tears to her eyes. Thank Merlin for Calming Draughts.

Her mind cleared quickly, shoving her back into the situation at hand. She and Hermione were still stuck in a root hollow, there was still a troll prowling the clearing that was their only exit, and now she had some fast explaining to do.

"Sorry," she breathed. She quickly packed the empty vials away and closed her bag. She didn't re-shrink it, though. "I don't like small spaces. I'm fine now. How's your inanimate to animate Transfiguration?"

"My—Oh!" Hermione whisper-shouted. "You want to try to fool it?"

"It does look remarkably thick."

"I've got it."

She couldn't see what Hermione was doing, but she saw when a fallen branch picked itself off the ground and twisted itself into a small deer. The magic-made creature was unsteady on its feet, but remarkably life-like in the poor light. It stumbled into the clearing proper, alerting the troll to its presence. Under Hermione's direction, the deer jerked itself into a mad dash through the brush on the troll's other side.

With an excited bellow, the troll sprinted after it.

Hermione and Rigel immediately clambered out of the hollow and Hermione cancelled their Disillusionment. Rigel dusted a few cobwebs from her hair and pretended not to notice Hermione's critical gaze. She was fine. A little bit too fine, as she'd overdone the Calming Draught while brewing again, but nevertheless. Fine.

She checked the map, looked Treeslider over for injuries, and said, "Good Transfiguration, Hermione."

Hermione sighed, but smiled grimly. "It won't last five minutes. Better get a move on."

They had been so close when the troll waylaid them, and they found themselves nearly on top of their map dots in just a few short minutes of running. The clearing the girls emerged into was vast—artificially so. There were still discolored patches of soil where the trees had recently been ripped out, and in the center of the clearing, between them and a raised dais with a golden chest, crouched a Sphinx.

They approached with caution, wands out. The Sphinx looked nothing like the ones in her mindscape, she realized. Dom had created beings more beautiful than terrifying, but this Sphinx was a creature of death. Her nails gleamed in the moonlight, which shone unobstructed down into the enormous clearing. The Sphinx sprang up from her crouch and prowled menacingly toward them.

Rigel cleared her throat. "We've come for what's in the chest," she said clearly. "Do you guard it?"

"I do." It was a woman's voice that came from the Sphinx's throat, but it carried a lioness's growling undertone.

"Will you let us pass?"

"I won't." The Sphinx smiled a mouthful of pointy teeth at them. "Unless you answer my riddle."

"Just one riddle for two of us?" Hermione clarified sharply. Her voice was high with nerves, but she stood tall beside Rigel, her chin out.

The Sphinx raked the ground with its claws lazily. "Your choice. If you choose one riddle and get it wrong, you both die. If you choose two riddles…better odds of at least one surviving."

"We'll take the one riddle," Rigel said immediately. Hermione's eyes shot to her with a gasp.

"Don't you want to think about it?" the girl demanded.

"I'm pants at word games," she admitted. "Whatever answer you give, I'll take my chances with it. I trust you."

Hermione growled under her breath something that sounded like, "foolhardy boys." She squared her shoulders and faced the Sphinx, though. "Very well. We will answer one riddle together."

"What is always old and sometimes new; never sad, sometimes blue; never empty, sometimes full; never pushes, always pulls?" The Sphinx, having finished her recitation, sat back on her haunches and watched them with bright yellow eyes.

Hermione's brow furrowed in fierce thought. "May we discuss?"

"I won't stop you."

Hermione turned to Rigel, who could only shrug. "It doesn't sound like anything real to me," she admitted. "I've never been good at cryptic stuff. I tried to work out a prophecy last year, and to say it went horribly wrong is a big understatement."

"That's fine, I just think better out loud," Hermione said dismissively. "Not sad but blue means it's sometimes blue in color. Never empty and always old make me think it's the ocean, but the ocean isn't normally defined as 'full' and it's always blue. Push and pull…an ocean pulls in the sense of the tide…the tide! The moon!"

Rigel blinked. "The moon does cause the tides," she agreed.

"The answer is the moon," Hermione said. She turned back to the Sphinx and positively smirked at her. "Right?"

The Sphinx smirked back. "Correct, little girl." The creatures yawned wide, reminded them of her generosity in not eating them alive, and said, "My supper shall wait a little longer. You may pass."

Rigel beamed at her. "Brilliant, Hermione! I would have spent ages working that out." She and Hermione rushed up the steps to large, gilded chest on the dais. It was obvious at first glance the chest was locked. "More riddles," she muttered.

"It's covered in runes," Hermione said, bending down to inspect the chest on all sides without touching it. "There's Greek, Egyptian, Chinese, Mayan, Celtic, Viking, and more scripts I don't even recognize. Sanskrit maybe? I think… all the runes say the same thing, though."

Rigel peered at the lines of runes. Hermione was right. There were three runes in each script. Kaunaz, Laguz, Hagalaz. Huo, Shui, Feng. "What does it mean, though? Fire, water, air… do we filling in the missing element?"

"There's no place to do so," Hermione said. She scanned her eyes over the chest again and pointed to the lock. "There are three distinct mechanisms. One spell for each lock. Fire. Water. Air."

Rigel grinned. "That's easy enough. Any order?"

"Start with fire," Hermione suggested.

Rigel cast Confringo at the lock. A line of fire marked the lock, but otherwise it didn't change. She frowned. "Maybe something more aggressive?" She tried Incendio without luck.

Hermione conjured a blue flame on the tip of her wand and held it to the lock. Nothing. They both deflated, looking back over the script again. The Egyptian runes caught her eye and she said, somewhat uncertainly, "That rune doesn't just mean fire. It means lamp, right?"

Hermione's eyes widened. "That's why there's so many scripts. Different interpretations might result in wrong answers. You have to aggregate the different translations to really know what to try. Here, see? The Celtic rune is also the one for sun. The answer isn't fire—it's light."

"Lumos." Rigel's illuminated wand hovered over the lock for a breathless moment, and then the mechanism clicked open. "Thank Salazar. What next? All the scripts I can read look like water to me."

"Maybe this one is simple. Aguamenti." Hermione let the water spill over the chest and the second lock clicked. "Yes! Now air. That's tricky. We could levitate it? Or a drying spell?"

"The Chinese rune for air is supposed to be this," Rigel said, sketching a different symbol to the one of the chest in the grime on the dais. "This one on the chest is… something else."

"Wind!" Hermione grinned. She shot a Ventus and the third lock popped free. They opened the chest wide to reveal a pile of brightly colored sashes.

Rigel grimaced. "I guess the ones matching our headbands are ours. All this way for a fancy ribbon." She hoped Riddle heard that one loud and clear.

The each grabbed the sashes corresponding to their colors—green for Rigel and light blue for Hermione—and tied them securely around their waists. Just as they closed the lid once more, they heard the Sphinx growl from behind them. Fleur had stepped into the clearing, looking just a little rumpled as she stopped and warily stared at the Sphinx.

"You have to answer its riddle," Rigel called helpfully. She and Hermione climbed down and waved on their way back across the clearing.

"Good luck!" Hermione added, looking cheerful now that they had accomplished at least half of their goal. She turned to Rigel and Treeslider. "What's the fastest path out of this place?"

Rigel grinned. "After you, milady."

They started with a Point Me charm on the gamekeeper's cabin, since their maps were essentially useless now that they carried the thing they had been tracking on their person. Rigel conveyed their general desired direction to Treeslider, who was to take up the navigation once more. She really was going to bring the snake a whole basket of mice the next time she came to visit.

The snake was uneasy, however. He quivered slightly against her skin and his tongue continually scented the air. She stopped walking, and Hermione paused as well. "What isss it?" she asked, broadening her sensitivity once more.

"Sssomething comes. Sssomething new," the snake hissed.

Rigel focused her awareness. There was something big up ahead of them, but it didn't seem to be moving anywhere. Then she felt it—a dense, fast dot of magic heading straight for them. It would be on them in moments. "Hermione, get behind me!"

The other girl moved without hesitation, brandishing her wand in the same direction as Rigel's. "What is—"

There was no time to answer and she threw up a Fortis shield an instant before something sprang from the forest and barreled into it. A growling yelp, and the creature—a wolf—rolled off the shield and regained its feet with a spry twist. The wolf paused to bare its teeth at her and she realized with a start that it was a werewolf.

"What are they playing at?" Hermione moaned. "A werewolf! Of all the irresponsible insanity. "

"He'll be on Wolfsbane, I don't doubt," Rigel said soothingly. They wouldn't let a feral werewolf into the competition zone. That was a recipe for disaster. Then again, he certainly wasn't on the New Wolfsbane, or he would be a lot less alert and aggressive.

"So it's okay if it bites us on purpose?" Hermione's voice was rising again.

"He's a person, remember," Rigel said firmly. "I don't think he'll bite us. Just run us around and scare us, probably."

The wolf leapt again, but Rigel redoubled the magic she had in the Fortis shield and it held firm—though she was pushed backwards several feet, taking Hermione and the shield itself with her. The werewolf prowled the forest on the other side of the shield, watching. Waiting. "It knows I can't hold this shield all night," Rigel muttered. She glanced back at Hermione. "Think you can pull off another free-transfiguration?"

"What would scare off a werewolf?" Hermione asked, huffing out a laugh that was only slightly hysterical.

"Nothing on earth," Rigel admitted. "But we can tempt it with better prey."

"A deer?" Hermione clarified.

She shook her head. "Won't trump a human. Can you do a unicorn?"

"A—but that's barbaric," Hermione protested. "Killing unicorns…even pretend ones…"

"The werewolf is drawn to innocence," Rigel said flatly. "Can't get better prey than a unicorn. Even on Wolfsbane it'll be hard for him to resist chasing after it." It was one of Remus' deepest fears: that he might come across something like a unicorn, something pure, and slay it while under the wolf's sway.

Hermione stood behind Rigel so the wolf couldn't see her wand moving and began to transfigure a tangle of brush beyond the wolf's line of sight. As Rigel held the shield, Hermione breathed life into the fledgling transfiguration, giving it a coat that shone in the moonlight, hooves of glinting silver, and a horn that glowed with its own iridescence. The unicorn was too graceful—even for an actual unicorn. It had an unearthly feel as it moved, and Rigel guessed that Hermione had never seen a real live unicorn, but seen an image or perhaps a moving photograph. When it was ready, Hermione nudged Rigel's back and she prepared to take advantage of the distraction.

The unicorn galloped into the clearing, rearing at the wolf and turning on its hooves to dance away again with a remarkably realistic whinny. The wolf snarled after it, snapping its jaws almost involuntarily. It took several steps toward the transfigured unicorn, but then stopped, shaking its head sharply. It began to circle back toward Rigel, but Hermione made the unicorn dance just out of reach along the edge of the small clearing. It flashed its horn at the wolf, as though giving a dare.

The wolf threw back its head and howled in fury, and Rigel's left hand slipped into her bag and pulled out a Protection Potion in one smooth move. She hid the potion bottle in her sleeve and splashed a quick line across the ground inside her shield. Then she began slowly stepping sideways, Hermione with her, moving the shield bit by bit in a semi-circle around the clearing, pouring potion whenever the wolf's attention was distracted by the transfiguration.

The animal seemed completely torn between chasing the unicorn and remaining to stalk the girls, which led Rigel to think he probably was on Wolfsbane, or else his mind would be completely given over to the wolf's urges. The wolf batted at the unicorn in frustration whenever it came near, but didn't follow it out of the clearing. It snapped at the transfiguration, then turned back to regard Rigel and Hermione with menacing eyes, then swiped again at the unicorn, and back to them. This continued even as Rigel slowly reversed their positions in the clearing. Her circle was almost complete. Thanks to her encounter with Remus the previous year, she knew exactly how to trap a werewolf for the night.

The trickiest part would be closing it. For the ward to spring up into place, she'd have to lower her shield for a split second. She timed it carefully, waiting for the wolf to over-extend in its battle with the imaginary unicorn. As it lunged forward toward the transfiguration at last, Rigel took the opening. She dropped the shield and closed the circle, but—the ward didn't materialize. And in that instant, the wolf sprang back toward her with her death in its eyes. Rigel was too slow. Her legs were jellied with surprise and even as she stumbled backwards she knew she wouldn't get the next shield up in time.

A flash of green obscured her vision for an instant, coming between her chest and the oncoming teeth. Treeslider had flung himself forward from Rigel's shoulder with a battle-hiss. She brought her arms up to shield them both from the onslaught, but she was too slow. The wolf twisted mid-air, claws flailing, to dislodge the snake from his snout and Treeslider flew across the clearing, impacted a tree, and lay still.

"No." Rigel didn't know if she said it in English or Parseltongue. She only knew she was furious. Her magic sprung into her hands with a thought, slamming into the wolf like a physical thing. The canine rolled away from the barrage and came up growling on the other side of the clearing. She knew what she wanted. She wanted the wolf contained. Her wand, almost an after thought, came up to level at the wolf. "Fortiss."

A shield sprang into life—but not around her or Hermione. It formed around the wolf and contracted, pressing the creature in from all sides. The wolf howled his displeasure and tried to beat himself against the inside of the shield, but it was too small to build up any momentum and the shield only slid sideways in the dirt.

Hermione, breathing hard, finally let the complicated unicorn transfiguration drop. "How long can you hold that?" she gasped.

"Long enough to finish the protection ward," Rigel said grimly. "Would you mind checking on my snake?"

"I—sure." Hermione crossed to where Treeslider was crumpled and crouched down to inspect him with a few diagnostics.

Rigel kept her wand trained on the enclosed wolf even as she circled the clearing along the line of potion she'd poured, looking for any gaps. There was an area that had been scuffed through with a paw. She narrowed her eyes. Smart wolf. He had only pretended to be preoccupied with the unicorn. The swipes he made in its direction were used to foil her circle. How he knew what it was, she didn't know. But she would finish it, now. She found three more places in the dirt that had disturbed the circle and poured a little more potion on each. As she closed the circle for good, she let the Fortis shield fade away. The wolf rushed her, but the Protection Potion would not be budged. It threw the wolf backwards, and the animal let out a growling snarl.

"That will hold until morning," she said tiredly. She turned back to Hermione, who was deep in concentration over the snake. "Is he…?"

"Alive," Hermione said quickly. "But, badly injured. Unconscious. I'm not that skilled with animals; I can diagnose, but I don't know if I can heal him."

"I can," Rigel said, moving forward. "You go on without me—" the Vow sang in her blood, hot and immediate. "No. No, that won't work. I have to keep moving forward. Okay, you take over navigating us back to the forest edge, Hermione. I'll heal Treeslider as we go."

Hermione frowned. "Just a straight path?"

Rigel nodded reluctantly. "We'll just have to hope we don't run into anything."

Something ran into the clearing immediately after she spoke and she wanted to groan aloud. It wasn't a creature, however, but Antiope, brandishing a bloody blade, gore streaked down one side of her. She looked a little crazed, but recognition came quickly. "Black. Granger. Is that a—"

"He's contained," Rigel assured her distractedly. "Item chest is that way." She gestured. "If you'll excuse us."

Antiope nodded once and disappeared back into the trees. "I hope she hasn't killed anything sentient," Hermione said lowly. She used the Point Me spell again and motioned Rigel along. "Just follow me."

They were slower going back than they had been in coming through, without Treeslider to guide their steps unerringly. Hermione went ahead and Disillusioned them again when they crept through centaur territory on silent feet. Rigel scarcely noticed. All her attention was on Treeslider. Brave, loyal Treeslider who was not going to die. She cradled the snake's limp body in the end of her cloak as she walked, steadily pumping Healing energy into his form. There was a lot of internal bleeding, but she was determined to stop every bit of it. After a grueling ten minutes, Treeslider was stable, but still unconscious. Rigel tied the ends of the cloak to her belt in a makeshift carrying basket and tried not to jostle him too much even as she and Hermione broke into jogs to make the journey quicker.

To avoid the area where the spiders had nearly caught Hermione in the beginning, they veered to the left on their way out of the forest. Just as they made to course correct again, however, something big and fast as lightning dropped down from the forest above them. Rigel and Hermione both leapt to the side, and Hermione screamed high and fast. Rigel looked over and saw a vicious gash on the girl's arm, but her focus couldn't remain on her friend. What dropped at their feet was not another spider: it was the Peruvian Vipertooth.

Rigel Black was an idiot, and nothing could convince him otherwise after tonight. Draco sat in a stadium box his father had managed to procure and fumed silently at the large oval mirror in the middle of the pitch, the one etched in emerald green. Pansy sat next to him, clutching his hand hard as she had been since Rigel's run-in with the werewolf. A werewolf! Just what was the Ministry playing at, he'd like to know. He tried to blank out the girl's furiously dynamic emotions, lest they overwhelm his already fraying nerves. Rigel was finally on his way back. He would be out in no time, and everything would be fine.

At least with his snake unconscious, he wasn't speaking Parseltongue every five seconds anymore. Half the stadium had gasped or screamed when it first came blaring out of the mirror, and most of them still flinched whenever Rigel's mirror was transmitting the sound. Draco appreciated that his friend wasn't shy about his ability, but did Parseltongue have to be the very first thing he said?

Aldon and Edmund had sidled into the box with him and Pansy as though he'd invited them, and he was reminded of their presence when Aldon muttered, "He needs to drop the bloody snake."

"He won't," Edmund murmured back. "He's loyal."

He's an idiot, Draco thought again. There were a million snakes in the forest. Draco was a bit surprised the Vow hadn't made him leave the snake behind by now, but he supposed as long as healing the animal didn't slow Rigel down, it wasn't technically impacting what would otherwise be his best effort.

Granger's viewer, ringed in light blue and second from the end on the left in the line of mirrors, swiveled around to look at Rigel, and Draco greedily inspected the image. Rigel's face was dirty and sweat-stained, but his eyes were eerily calm as he flicked them between the snake and the path ahead. While Granger seemed vaguely scattered every time Rigel's viewer showed a glimpse of her face, Rigel was collected. He always had worked well under pressure.

It annoyed Draco how often Granger's viewer swiveled toward Rigel. She was constantly checking in with him, looking to Rigel for any and every course of action. If he were cynical, and if he didn't know Rigel at all, he'd think that teaming up with the muggleborn girl had been a masterstroke of public relations. Every time Rigel did something reckless or impressive, the audience got a third person view from Hermione's mirror. It made his journey through the forest all the more entertaining to watch. Unfortunately, Draco knew that Rigel had teamed up with Granger because he trusted her on the word of his cousin and probably didn't want Potter to be upset with him if the girl died in the tournament under his watch.

The sound was making its rounds through the other mirror. Antiope was currently attempting to fight the Sphinx instead of just answering its riddle. The Shang girl had taken out some sort of lute-like instrument and was charming a Snallygaster slowly to sleep. Sousa's mirror was motionless. It had been almost all night, and Draco was trying not to imagine why that was. Perhaps his transmitter had fallen off.

Suddenly the sound was back with Rigel, however, and Granger was screaming. Pansy's hand clamped down tighter on his as Rigel's viewer tilted sideways. It was difficult to see what exactly had happened until Rigel stood straight again and the mirror's image swung to reveal Hermione sprawled on the dirt, blood pouring from her wand arm. Crouched beside her in an attack stance was the dragon.

"No," Draco breathed. He was so close to safety. The Peruvian Vipertooth was smaller than most full grown dragons, but it was fast. It darted toward Granger's prone form, but Rigel's shield was already there, aborting its movements and redirecting its attention toward Rigel himself.

The heavy chain that had presumably once bound the dragon in place trailed slowly across the ground as the Vipertooth stalked toward Rigel, who, for some reason known only to him, wasn't yet running in the opposite direction. Granger's mirror finally shifted to show something other than blood-soaked earth as the girl roused herself and shook her head sharply. From the girl's mirror, he saw Rigel standing, absolutely fearless, in the face of the dragon's wary approach.

"Rigel…" Granger's voice echoed through the stadium. She sounded like a person in a great deal of pain. "Run!"

Rigel ignored the suggestion. "Can you heal yourself?" he asked without looking at her. Granger's viewer dipped down to her arm—or what was left of it. Great, gaping gashes of flesh hung limply where the dragon had raked her. Draco felt sick just looking at it, and from Pansy's choked whimper he wasn't the only one.

"I…think I'm in shock," Granger admitted. "I…yes. I can…" She picked up her wand with her left hand and cast a numbing charm followed by a blood-clotting charm. The dragon had stopped advancing on Rigel, but an ominous tendril of smoke was leaking from its snout.

"It's going to flame," Edmund said lowly. "Come on, Rigel. Shield."

He did, thank Salazar. A Fortis that was so bright it practically blinded sprung up between Rigel and the dragon just moments before a beam of pure fire shot out of the Vipertooth's throat. Rigel's screen went completely white, and only Granger's viewer told them that he hadn't just been roasted alive. Granger could still see the boy behind his shield, unmoved by the onslaught of fire. It was no short burst; the flames went on and on, as though the dragon needn't breathe to sustain them.

Rigel was doing something behind the shield. With his free hand he seemed to be fiddling with something in his pocket. Draco didn't know what could be more important than fending off a dragon, but his confusion was answered when Rigel called, "Hermione, muffle your ears and close your eyes!"

Regardless of whether she did or didn't, they could all still see what was happening through her mirror. Rigel dropped the shield. Pansy screamed into his ear as flame enveloped Rigel completely, but Draco scarcely heard her over his own hoarse cry. But—what—Rigel was still there in Granger's viewer. Standing somehow impervious to the fire, his face screwed into a grimace as he flung something toward the Vipertooth and then clamped both hands over his ears.

The clearing exploded. Both Rigel and Granger's mirrors went white for an instant and a crack had everyone flinching before the mirror operators cut the sound. But the sound kept coming, only far away and muffled. He realized it was coming from the other contestants' viewers, too. Everyone in the forest was hearing whatever it was, and one by one the mirrors all panned up to the sky above the treetops.

"Fireworks?" Draco spluttered. What on Merlin's green earth was happening? There were dazzling red and yellow firework animals erupting over the forest in every mirror. Lions and dragons and unicorns danced across the sky. He stood from his seat and—yes, he could see them in the distance from the box. Rigel and Grangers' mirrors slowly regained intelligibility as the fireworks took on a life of their own and began to separate, swooping around the clearing and shooting up into the air before them. The real dragon was nowhere to be seen.

Rigel's viewer moved to focus on Granger, who was stumbling to her feet with tears in her eyes. Draco couldn't hear her over the still-exploding fireworks, but he saw her mouth, What the hell was that?

In Granger's mirror, Rigel grinned, his eyes gleaming with satisfaction. Dragon repellant, he mouthed back.

Rigel began to assist Granger in patching up her arm, and by the time it looked less like a chew toy the fireworks had almost put themselves out. The sound moved back to Rigel's mirror as he was saying, "—should get moving again, if you can. We've just attracted a lot of attention."

"You think?" the girl said through gritted teeth. She had sliced through her sweater at the shoulder and was now using the torn sleeve at a makeshift sling. Rigel handed her a Blood-Replenisher, which she took wordlessly, followed by a Pain Potion and what Draco thought was an Anti-Infection Draught. "I can't believe we survived that. The burn repellant worked! I thought for a moment you were crazy, Rigel."

Rigel smiled tiredly. "Dad told me not to test it, but the fire didn't look like it was pausing anytime soon, and I think it was starting to cook me alive even through the shield." Rigel went momentarily cross-eyes as he looked down at his own nose. "Does this look sunburnt to you?"

Pansy let out a tremulous laugh. She was still shaking. "Rigel, you idiot," she whispered. Draco was very much inclined to agree.

Granger performed a Point Me and said, "Let's go. I'm done with this forest."

"Right behind you," Rigel agreed.

The sound moved away to Delacour, who'd managed to get herself cornered by a Manticore just shy of the forest's edge. Draco didn't care, he kept his eyes on Rigel's mirror, and as soon as the end of the trees came into view he was out of his seat. Pansy followed him out of the box in silent agreement, and the two of them ran on anxious feet down the stadium stairs and across the lawn.

As soon as she was free of that blasted forest, she plucked the headband from her head and dropped it to the ground so it would stop transmitting. As though her aching psyche had summoned them, Draco and Pansy were there at the edge of the forest when she stumbled across the ward line after Hermione.

She was in their arms before she has time to greet them. Pansy's form trembled against her like a wild thing. Draco just gripped her hard and a moment later she felt his blissful numbing trick envelope her as well. She relaxed. Just let go of all the tension and fear and control she'd wound tight within herself over that last few hours. Rigel wanted nothing more than to shower and sleep, but she knew the night was only half over. She would not be allowed to leave until all of the champions had made it out of the woods. Still, for a single peaceful minute, she allowed herself the comfort of her friends' embrace.

When her friends finally let her go, Rigel noticed Hermione standing awkwardly to one side, looking wistful. She reached out toward the girl and shook her uninjured hand. "Well done in there, tonight. Thanks for your help."

"Me?" Hermione laughed a little helplessly. "Rigel, you're the only reason I'm not spider food right now. Or dragon fodder. I—it was so much more than I was expecting." The girl looked completely overwhelmed. Rigel had to agree, though. The first task was way over the top, even for Riddle.

Rigel nodded toward Hagrid's cabin, where a tent had been set up. "I think Madam Pomfrey is in there. She'll check over your arm."

Hermione nodded. The adrenaline was wearing off and the reality of the last few hours settling in over her. Rigel knew from experience the best thing for her to do now was sit somewhere quiet and let a professional take care of her injuries. Hermione walked numbly toward the medic tent and Rigel turned back to her friends. "So, did I win?"

"You prat!" Draco swore. "Do you have any idea how worried we've been all night? Watching you go from reckless to impossible to somehow even more reckless for hours?"

"Imagine how I felt," Rigel said dryly.

"Rigel, it was awful," Pansy said, earnest. "I wish you'd never agreed to do this. It's a miracle no one's died yet. Miss Granger is not the only one to have been nearly mauled, from what we saw."

"How are the others doing?" Rigel asked, serious. She didn't want to see anyone seriously hurt or killed that night.

"Owens and Krum finished ahead of you," Draco said. "Fleur is close, but ran into some trouble at the last minute. Other than that, we've seen Antiope, Shang, and Tahiil all make it at least as far as the Sphinx. Sousa…hard to say. His transmitter fell off."

"The mirror went dark?" Rigel clarified.

"No, just stopped moving," Draco said.

Rigel frowned. "As long as it's in skin contact it will transmit, but if it fell off it would have gone dark. It sounds like he's been badly injured." She glanced back toward the trees, grimacing. "Maybe I should—"

"No!" Draco and Pansy both snapped the word at her.

"You aren't going back in there."

"You have to rest, Rigel."

Still, what if he was alone and vulnerable in there? Someone had to do something. Draco heaved a long-suffering sigh. "The tournament organizers know how the mirrors work as well as you," he pointed out. "If Sousa is in that sort of trouble, I'm sure they're already handling the situation."

Rigel nodded slowly. That made sense. Her friends attempted to herd her toward the medical tent, but she spotted Sirius jogging across the lawn toward her. He scooped her up and spun her in a circle, the way he'd done with Archie when he was a kid.

"Thank Godric, kid." He stopped spinning and squeezed her so tight she thought she might break a rib. "Who taught you to be so reckless, anyway?"

"I'm okay, Dad. Watch my snake, please." His grip loosened and she murmured into his chest, "Really. I'm all right, I promise. Everything is fine."

Sirius sighed and pulled back to look into her face worriedly. "You were fantastic, Arch. I'm so proud of you. But that situation was out of order. If Riddle thinks he can try and kill my own kid right in front of me, he's got another thing coming."

"I'm sure it was more controlled than it seemed," Rigel said, not really believing it. She added, "The werewolf was a bit much, though. I mean, it dehumanizes the entire community to put one in the mix with creatures like acromantula and quintapeds. Just another monster in the dark."

Sirius grimaced. "You're right, Pup. I hope it's no one Remus knows. No self-respecting werewolf should have stooped to participating in this madness."

Green sparks popped in the sky just then, and Fleur came limping out of the forest when the wards dropped down. They popped back up just as quickly, and Rigel couldn't help but be impressed. It took a lot of power to lower and raise wards so fast. She thought it was unlikely Regulus could have done it alone.

The French girl gasped for air, spitting out curses left and right. "That forest is possessed by an evil curse. I hope someone burns it down."

Rigel winced. "It's not usually that bad," she told the girl. At least she thought she did.

Fleur blinked at her and said, "You sound like my house elf."

Sirius snorted. "Have you been taking love-language lessons from a house elf, Archie? My goodness, I didn't know you were so hard pressed."

Rigel's ears went pink. "Dad! I just hang around the kitchens sometimes, that's all. There's this really nice elf who helps me out a lot and she speaks French, ok?"

"Oh Godric, where have I strayed?" Sirius asked the sky.

Fleur began to laugh lowly. She seemed surprised at herself. "After tonight, I wazn't sure I would laugh again."

Rigel understood the feeling. "The memory will fade soon enough," she told the girl. "There's a medic in the tent over there, if you have any injuries."

Fleur nodded, a hand coming up to prod gingerly at her thigh. Her tracksuit was dark with blood. She began to limp toward the tent, but paused and gave Rigel a grateful look. "Zank you for letting me follow you. I know you zaw me once or twice."

She smiled and shrugged. "No idea what you're talking about."

Draco was scowling when she looked back at him. "You let her follow you all the way to the chest? Why?"

"It didn't slow me down any," Rigel reasoned. "Plus it's easier to keep an eye on people when they're close by. The fewer people end up in mortal peril this year the better, I say."

Pansy rubbed her temple. "We are discussing this in your debrief, Rigel."

"Debrief?" Sirius looked between them, bemused.

"Pansy is my strategist," Rigel said, smiling a little. "And Draco is my tactician."

"Does that make me your armorer?" Sirius wondered, grinning.

"You and the Weasley twins," she agreed. "That Fire Free stuff was amazing, Dad! I could feel it absorbing the heat before it reached my skin. I might be flash-burned in a couple of places, but I'd say the first real test was a big success."

Sirius's grin dropped a little. "I'm glad it worked, but it was supposed to be a last resort."

'That was a last resort," Rigel told him. "With Hermione in no state to run, I had no plan other than the firework disk."

"What was that, anyway?" Pansy asked. "It was so small compared to the amount of explosive power inside."

She shrugged. "You'd have to ask the Weasleys. George gave it to me earlier today. I think it was supposed to be a joke—send up fireworks instead of sparks when I finished, you know? But it was dead useful."

"That dragon certainly scarpered," Sirius agreed, barking out a laugh. "I may have to consult these evil geniuses on a project or two."

"They'd love that," Rigel said.

Antiope was the next to leave the forest, her shoulders slumped with exhaustion. She dropped her sword into the grass and raked both hands through her hair, slowly shaking her head back and forth. She seemed to be muttering to herself with her eyes closed. Then, with a deep breath, she collected the blade, straightened, and strode toward the medic tent with a stoic expression.

Feiyan Shang came out shortly after, and while she was rumpled and dirty, she was the first to emerge without a significant amount of blood on her person. She walked over to Rigel's group and asked, "The others. All are out?"

Rigel shook her head. "Tahiil and Matheus are still in the forest."

Shang frowned. "We wait now," she determined. The Chinese girl removed her purple headband and put it carefully in her pocket before looking around at the others. "I am Shang Feiyan. Pleased to meet you."

"It's a pleasure to meet you, too," Pansy said. "I am Pansy Parkinson. This is Draco Malfoy and Rigel's father, Lord Black."

Shang bowed deeply to Sirius. "Is honorable to meet you, Lord Black."

Sirius shifted uncomfortably. "You as well, Miss Shang. Princess Shang? Or…"

Shang giggled, but stopped almost at once, flushing pink. "I am not princess. My father very far from throne. He is court astrologer. Much honor, but not…not…" She frowned in a frustrated way. "How to say a strength to do whatever is wanted?"

"Power?" Pansy guessed.

"Yes. My family has much honor, little power," Shang concluded. "I thank you your kindness, Lord Black."

Sirius grimaced, "Not at all."

The wait for Tahiil and Matheus was excrutiating. Minute after silent minute dragged on, with Rigel growing more worried by the second. She busied herself checking on Treeslider, but the snake was out of the woods both literally and figuratively. He was in a deep, healing sleep now in Rigel's cloak. Finally, she excused herself for a moment, saying she needed to use the bathroom and making her way toward Hagrid's cabin. When she was out of sight, she rummaged in her bag until she found the Marauder's Map and pulled it out. Only part of the forest was actually included on the map, but it was the part closest to the edge, and she was relieved to see two dots, one nearly on top of the other, making slow but steady progress toward the tree line. Relieved, she opted to use Hagrid's facilities while she had the chance and made her way back to her friends a few minutes later, just as green sparks shot into the sky behind them.

They saw Tahiil first, because he was dragging an unresponsive Matheus behind him. Rigel, Draco, and Sirius rushed forward to relieve the dark-skinned boy of his burden and set Matheus down gently on the grass. Rigel removed his headband and flung it aside, then began her diagnostic charms, but nothing life-threatening or even all that alarming appeared in her scans. He was breathing oddly, but not in a way that sounded as though he had fluid or anything else obstructing his lungs. His heartrate was fast, with no obvious cause. Had he been poisoned?

She peeled back his eyelid and startled when it jerked out of her grasp and blinked. Matheus opened both eyes and stared at her, not speaking or otherwise reacting to her presence.

"He's awake," she said, unnerved, "But… not really responsive. What happened?" she asked Tahiil.

Tahill was still breathing hard, and he pushed aside his headband to wipe his brow with his sleeve as he said, "Not sure. I found him just lying on the ground, but he didn't look injured. Still, he was in no condition to remain in the forest, so I pulled him along with me."

Feiyan bent down to inspect the boy and a moue of disapproval pursed her lips. "Betel-chewer. Fool boy."

Rigel lifted Matheus' top lip and shook her head. "His teeth aren't stained. I don't think this is Betel." Betel was a leaf that, when chewed, had some sort of cognitive effect on the mind. She was vaguely aware that some wizards in Southeast Asia treated it the way Westerners treated tobacco.

"Not certain Betel," Feiyan said. "But like Betel. His eyes, you see?"

The pupils that stared up at them were blown wide. Lots of things caused dilated pupils, however. He could have a brain injury that just wasn't showing up in her scan. Or maybe he had overdosed on Pain Potion. But again, her diagnostics told her he wasn't afflicted with any pain-causing wounds.

"He looks high as a kite," Sirius said flatly. "Give him a Sobering Draught."

Rigel frowned. "Why would he allow himself to face a task like this while incapacitated?" she asked, even as she fished the potion in question from her kit. "Is he trying to kill himself?"

"Can't understand an addict's thinking, if that's what he is," Sirius said, shaking his head. "He's just lucky this young man has a generous spirit. Good work," he told Tahiil.

Tahiil only sighed. "I am the last to return. Even without helping Matheus, I would be last. I do not think I have done good work tonight."

"You saved his life," Sirius disagreed. "That's all that matters."

Tahiil looked only marginally cheered by this. Rigel had administered the Sobering Draught and was watching Matheus for signs of improvement when a party of Ministry officials arrived from the pitch. Riddle, Fudge, Bagman, and Crouch were all there, along with Dumbledore, the Malfoys, James, and two other Aurors.

Riddle approached Matheus and peered down at him just as the boy groaned and winced against the harsh effects of the Sobering Draught. He let off a few choice words in Portuguese, but quieted his curses when he noticed all the people standing over him. He sat up, rubbing at his head.

"I trust you are recovered from your… fall?" Riddle said quietly.

Matheus' eyes widened. "Ah yes," he said slowly. "Very recovered. Thank you."

"Then you may join the rest of us in the champion's tent, where we will announce your scores." Riddle's eyes swept over Rigel, Feiyan, and Tahiil. "If you would all follow me to the tent and re-don your headbands, we can bring this exciting night to a conclusion."

He swept away toward the medic tent, and the others followed after him wearily. Rigel turned to Mr. Malfoy before doing the same, and said, "Thank you again for these excellently crafted gauntlets, Lord Malfoy. As you can see, they held remarkably well." She lifted one to display the claw marks that now raked across its surface.

"House Malfoy is gratified to be of service," Malfoy said, inclining his head to Sirius and Rigel both.

"We're very glad you're safe," Narcissa added. Her face was pale, and Rigel suspected she had not enjoyed the entertainment that evening at all.

"Someone will need to let that werewolf out at dawn," she realized suddenly. Rigel rummaged in her bag until she procured the Ward Disruptor. She handed it to Malfoy Sr. "Please give this to whoever the organizers send."

He took it, but said, "I will pass it to Lord Potter, as I understand he is sending a team to collect the wolf presently."

"The Aurors are?" Sirius stared at Mr. Malfoy with dawning fury. "The werewolf wasn't part of this."

"Decidedly not," Malfoy said. "An investigation will be launched into how exactly the beast managed to penetrate the wards."

Rigel blew out an exasperated breath. "The item chest was well outside the Hogwarts wards," she said flatly. "Since the competition zone overlapped part of the unwarded forest, all he had to do was wait outside Riddle's wards until they dropped to let us enter, then cross them at the same time."

Malfoy stared at her for a long moment before saying, "Very astute, Rigel. That may be."

"Rigel, the scoring," Draco reminded her.

She nodded, and went to collect her headband from where she'd dropped it earlier before continuing toward the tent. It was much bigger inside than it looked. Dumbledore was in one corner conferring with Madam Pomfrey, who wore a ferocious scowl. The nine competitors stood close together around the group of tournament organizers, in the center of which was Riddle.

"Please put on your headbands once more, as this will be broadcast down to the pitch as well," Riddle began. When he had everyone's attention and all their headbands were in place, he smiled. "Well done, all of you. Tonight you have been tested beyond what any of you likely imagined; this was done knowingly. One of the measures of great witches and wizards is their ability to overcome fear and physical hardship and to remain steadfast and true in the face of seemingly insurmountable odds." He moved his head to look at each of the champions in turn as he spoke, except he wasn't looking at them—he was looking into their headbands. Rigel frowned as she realized this was really about Riddle, not them. Right now, every mirror in the pitch would be filled with his face, smiling and self-congratulatory. She deliberately turned her head away from Riddle and toward the others. She let her headband take in Antiope's stony visage, Hermione and Fleur's bandaged limbs, Tahiil's exhausted eyes, Krum's muck-strewn form, and Feiyan's troubled frown. Let them see the truth of what has occurred tonight. In her mirror, at least, let them know the cost of their entertainment.

"Now, to the scoring." Riddle produced a roll of parchment with a flourish. "I'm sure you're all aware that you're to be judged on how quickly you completed the task assigned to you, but what we have not told you is…that is only one of the four categories on which you were assessed."

He paused for effect, allowing the pure sadism of those words to sink in before continuing.

"The four categories are: time taken for task completion, valor in the face of danger, critical thinking in problem solving, and moral fiber." There were a few murmurs at the last category, but most the others seemed too tired and strung out to really care. Riddle elaborated. "The tournament judges chose these criteria because they represent virtues the Wizarding World would see associated with its best and brightest. You must be effective, creative, tough, and ethical. However, we have not weighted every category equally. Timeliness in finishing the task is worth twenty points. Valor is fifteen. Appropriate thinking is worth ten points, and morality, five points. Each champion's score, therefore, is out of fifty."

Rigel wondered at the odd way of scoring. It appeared comprehensive at first, and certainly it was a more in-depth evaluation than she'd been expecting, but it was also…off. Riddle agreeing to give points for moral fiber? She began to suspect that the complicated scoring system was merely a screen; everything about this tournament was designed for a very specific purpose: to ensure a pureblood champion.

"In the category of task completion, in order of success, the points are as follows," Riddle said. The tent was utterly silent as everyone listened carefully. "Jacob Owens, 20 points. Victor Krum, 19 points. Arcturus Black and Hermione Granger, 18 points. Fleur Delacour, 16 points. Antiope, 15 points. Feiyan Shang, 14 points. Tahiil Diric Zahi, 13 points. Matheus Sousa…zero points."

Sousa blinked, but didn't argue. He didn't seem to care at all, and Rigel had to wonder if Pansy and Millicent had been right; maybe there was something odd about his participation in the tournament.

"For valor, first place goes to Antiope, 15 points," Riddle said, smiling ever-so-slightly. "Full marks in this category were given for willingness to face every foe encountered. Points were deducted for running or hiding without engaging. Second goes to Arcturus Black, 14 points, for being the only champion to take on the most dangerous foe in the forest and win. Next, Victor Krum, 12 points. Hermione Granger, 10 points. Tahiil Diric Zahi, 10 points. Feiyan Shang, 9 points. Jacob Owens, 8 points. Fleur Delacour, 5 points. Matheus Sousa, zero points."

Rigel glanced over a Hermione, a frown tugging at her brow, but the curly-haired girl only shrugged unconcernedly back at her, mouthing the word 'shield.' Rigel grimaced. If she'd known they were going to count Hermione off for it, she might not have shielded her so often. Then again, she probably would have, she admitted. Rigel was not one to take unnecessary chances with other people's safety.

"In the category of problem solving, full marks are awarded for applying the appropriate response to each situation or problem set. Marks were deducted for inefficient or unwise use of force." Riddle cleared his throat. "Jacob Owens, 10 points. Hermione Granger, 9 points. Fleur Delacour, 8 points. Arcturus Black, 8 points. Feiyan Shang, 8 points. Tahiil Diric Zahi, 7 points. Victor Krum, 6 points. Antiope, 5 points. Matheus Sousa, zero points."

She wondered with amusement whether the judges had found her use of fireworks against the dragon unwise.

"Finally, for moral fiber: full marks to Tahiil Diric Zahi for saving another champion at no benefit to himself, and to Feiyan Shang for completing the task without harming a single creature or fellow being. 5 points each. Jacob Owens, 4 points. Arcturus Black, 4 points. Hermione Granger, 4 points. Victor Krum, 2 points. Antiope, 1 point. Fleur Delacour, 1 point—while she did not harm anything excessively, she did use underhanded means to complete the task. And Matheus Sousa, zero points." Riddle rolled the scroll and tucked it away. "So where does that leave us? Minister, if you would?"

Fudge stepped forward, his chest thrust out. "Thank you, Lord Riddle. Ahem. In ninth place, with zero points due to failure across all four categories, Matheus Sousa. In eighth place, Fleur Delacour, with 30 points. In seventh place, Tahiil Diric Zahi with 35 points. Tied for fifth, we have Feiyan Shang and Antiope with 36 points. Fourth is Victor Krum with 39 points. Third, Hermione Granger, with 41 points. And our winner, with a total of 44 points, is Arcturus Black! Well done, Mr. Black. Jacob Owens, then, is our runner up with 42 points. A quick thank you to all the sponsors of tonight's events, and a round of applause for our champions, please!"

No one in the tent applauded, but presumably, down on the pitch, there was some measure of cheering. Rigel found it hard to believe that she'd won the first task, but it was difficult to pin down which category, exactly, she had been scored unfairly in. Somehow, she was certain the scores had been manipulated, but the subjective metrics themselves made it difficult to contest.

A few of the others congratulated her on their way out of the tent. She tried to smile politely, but was afraid it came out a grimace. Krum noticed and grimaced back at her.

"Strange tournament ven I come back second and place fourth, no?" He shook his head irritatedly. "Still, even knowing the scoring ahead of time, I vould not do anything different. There is no path for strategy in such a dangerous situation."

Rigel nodded in agreement. "Tonight was mostly luck. Some probably had a harder time than others just based on starting position or the creatures they happened to encounter. I think we all did well."

"I thank you for the rope," Krum said. He left the tent, and Rigel followed.

Hermione sidled up beside her on the way out, "You think you didn't deserve to win, but you did," she told her. At Rigel's grimace, Hermione nudged her. "I'm serious. No one else took on a werewolf and a dragon. I asked around. The others encountered one or two creatures each. We ran into four, not including the Sphinx. I'm not so blind I can't see that you did most of the heavy lifting tonight, either. Don't think I won't return the favor, Rigel. Thanks again."

She trotted off toward the castle, still cradling her newly-healed arm close. Rigel found James and Sirius waiting for her, along with Pansy and Draco.

"Father took mother home," Draco told her, "But he said to tell you congratulations for winning."

She nodded. "I appreacite your family's support. Would you two mind going ahead to the castle without me? I need to talk to my dad and my uncle for a minute. I'll be back in the common room soon, though."

Pansy and Draco exchanged a resigned look and both nodded. Pansy hugged her again gently. "Congratulations, Rigel."

They both began the walk back to the Entrance Hall. Rigel turned to the older men with a serious face. "Did you get the werewolf?" she asked James. "What was he trying to do here? I'm sure he was on Wolfsbane, so he must have had a purpose."

James frowned. "I shouldn't tell you."

"I'm the one in danger if I don't know," she said firmly. "Uncle James, if someone is targeting the tournament, it affects all the competitors."

Her father sucked in one cheek and chewed on it. He always did that right before giving in. "All right. Don't spread this information too far, Archie, but we didn't apprehend the wolf. By the time my team got there, the barrier was gone and the wolf with it."

She shook her head. "You can't break one from the inside without a wand or the disruptor potion. There's no way it got out on its own. But if one of the other champions let it out, you would have seen on the mirrors."

"Whoever helped the werewolf free is probably the same one who gave him the information that helped him in," Sirius said grimly.

"That means someone on the organizing committee," Rigel said.

"We don't know that for certain yet," James cautioned. "Just… be careful. You did good tonight, Arch, but there's no knowing what all there is in store for you lot this year. Just keep your head on a swivel and we'll do our best to help out from our end."

She smiled. "Thanks, Uncle James. I couldn't have done it without you guys."

"Don't thank us, Pup, you're just our little advertisement project," Sirius said archly. "Why, every kid in school is going to want some Fire Free Burn Baste now."

Rigel tilted her head. "I don't know; I think more people will remember the Weasley twins' firework display. Now that was some impressive magic."

Sirius laughed. "Challenge accepted! Next time we'll give you something to really knock their socks off."

She blanched. The Marauders and the Weasley twins trying to out-do one another… now that was a terrifying thought. A yawn clawed its way up her throat and she stifled it on her grime-coated sleeve.

"Go to bed, kid," Sirius said fondly. "Remus will be sorry he missed you, but you're too knackered to stay up till dawn. Rest up, remember to eat well and get your strength back before the next task. We'll see you soon." He hugged her fiercely, and James followed suit soon after.

"Good work tonight, Archie. I mean it. Not many can take on a werewolf like that and come out unscathed. We think…well, we think it might have been Greyback, himself, but it was difficult to get positive ID through the mirrors. Anyway, sleep well. Addy and Lily send their love." James ruffled her hair.

"Send them mine, too," she said, her voice trembling slightly. She only had to keep it together for a little while longer, she sternly told herself.

She trudged back up to the castle, her feet as heavy and silent as her heart. Her housemates would want to celebrate, she knew. Probably a party had already begun in the common room in her honor. She wouldn't be good company that night, however, so she would beg off, plead exhaustion, wash the night away in the shower and crawl into bed. Maybe, if Fate was kind for once, she wouldn't have to get out of it until the following night. Maybe she'd feel better when she woke. Maybe…well. Maybe a lot of things.

Chapter 9

Any expectations of tournament fervor having died down after the completion of the first task were abruptly doused the following morning, as Rigel entered the Great Hall to a wave of rowdy applause. She lifted a hand uncertainly in response and hurried over to the Slytherin table, where her friends, merciful beings that they were, quickly blocked her in with firmly planted bottoms and icy glares.

"We missed you at the party last night," Theo said, grinning at Rigel's disgruntled expression. "Congrats again on your win."

"If that's what winning feels like, I want no part of it," she said halfheartedly. "I'm sore all over, and I'll be digging dirt from my fingernails all week."

Pansy set down her utensils at once and picked up Rigel's hand to consider its cleanliness. "Your gloves appear to have done their job and preserved the sanctity of your nail beds. Could it be you're simply grumpy because the party kept you up last night?"

She had slept fitfully, visions of bright fire and sharp claws having followed her to dreamland. Even now, surrounded by people she largely trusted, it was difficult to fully relax. Still, that wasn't any of her friends' fault. "Could be," she allowed. "Don't let my poor mood sink everyone's spirits. What were you talking about before I sat down?"

"You," Millicent said, smiling unapologetically at the grimace this drew from Rigel. "The next task is a month out, and we were speculating what kind of challenge it would be."

"Already?" Rigel groaned into her porridge. "No more talk of tasks for a while, please."

"The other champions, then?" Millicent suggested. "Pansy and I will be adding our observations to the dossiers this week. There's a lot you weren't able to see from inside the forest. Tahill, for instance, really is proficient at wandless magic, and we didn't recognize any of the spells he used. Feiyan, on the other hand, appears to know a surprising amount of Latin-based magic in addition to—"

"I'm going to go brew," Rigel muttered, abandoning her meal and hefting her bag over her shoulder with a wince. She really was sore all over.

"Rigel—"

Whatever Pansy was going to say was cut off as Draco said firmly, "Let him go."

She shot a grateful smile at her blond friend, pretending not to notice the worried look in his eyes as she retreated from the table. She'd only gone a couple of steps when a slight girl with long, brunette hair scrambled up from the table and into her path. Rigel paused to let the girl pass—a first year, she thought, vaguely remembering the kid from the Soring Ceremony—but instead the little slip of a girl stopped and gazed up at Rigel with wide, half-hair-covered eyes.

"Good job yesterday!" the girl piped up at her, a tremulous smile creeping across her pale features. "I—" She fumbled in her pocket for a moment before producing a flat green stone and presenting it proudly for her inspection. "I got this! To support you. It's a basilisk scale, see?"

It was…not a basilisk scale. Rigel returned the girl's smile awkwardly. "Thanks, ah, it's Rowle, right? Thank you. For your support. I think that might be a shard of jade, though." Rowle looked down at the rough stone with dismay, and Rigel hurried to add, "Still, green is our color, isn't it?"

Rowle nodded timidly. "Yes. I guess it still works. Well, I'll be cheering for you."

"Thank you," she said again, feeling incredibly stupid. All she could think as the girl stepped aside was she hoped Rowle hadn't paid too much for a fake basilisk scale. Probably one of the older students had played a prank on her. She certainly better not find anyone selling counterfeit potions ingredients in her name.

Rigel left all thoughts of the tournament behind as she walked through the door to her lab. It was like stepping through a portal to her own little world. With the door shut firmly behind her, she didn't have to think about tasks, politics, or even her friends' well-meaning support. In her tiny lab, she was just Rigel, potioneer, and nothing more.

Her current project was simmering innocuously in the corner, the only clue to its incredible difficulty the sheen of pure magic that hovered over the surface. It had taken an inordinate amount of pure magic to stabilize the brew, and there were still a couple weeks to go before the double batch of Animagus Revelation would be ready for consumption. Deep in her potions kit, the final ingredients had already been set to soak in twin vials of her and Archie's saliva. By late-November, it should be finished.

There was nothing else she could do for that project at the moment, so Rigel began to set up the cauldron for a batch of Protection Potion—Krait was still selling through them like love charms—and turned her mind to something she'd been working on since the summer holidays.

Her all-inclusive first-aid kit was coming along slowly. Epidermal healing was only the beginning. Muscle repair had been relatively simple, with nearly the same sort of magic going into the imbuing. She'd managed to replicate a Bone-Knitting spell with the variable base Master Snape had come up with and the use of powdered Erumpent femur as the signifying ingredient, but she hadn't found a way to actually apply it to the bone if the skin wasn't pierced. She could easily spell the potion into the body at the site of the bone in question, but most people didn't know how to do that, and the kit was supposed to be usable by anyone.

So most of the magic that needed to go deeper than muscle was causing her trouble. The organs weren't easily accessible by any of the usual means—potions ingested tended to stay in the digestive system and salves only penetrated the body so far before the magic dissipated. Organs were delicate, too, in a way that skin, muscle, and bone were not. Too much magic, and their homeostasis would be thrown out of balance.

Her hands worked on autopilot, chopping, shredding, and stirring in smooth motions while her mind wandered. How could she get the imbued magic to where it was needed while still carrying it in a potion? Only pure magic could pass through the uninjured parts of the body without repercussion. If there was a wound in the abdominal cavity that wasn't exposed to the air, it seemed as though magical transportation was the only way to reach it without cutting the body open. How did muggles treat those sorts of injuries? Rigel supposed they probably did just cut people open.

As the Protection Potion came to life beneath her fingers, Rigel's mind drifted. There was something niggling in her memory. She knew Archie's Healing texts had mentioned something else that muggles did besides cutting people open, only she couldn't remember what it was.

A movement in her pocket had Rigel pausing in her ingredient preparation and carefully peering into the recently enlarged space. Treeslider was curled up inside, a warm ball of comforting heat at her hip. He was shifting restlessly, but under her patient eyes he subsided into sleep again. The snake still hadn't woken. She knew he was only regaining his strength, but it pained her to see the usually energetic boomslang reduced to a near-catatonic state.

Her memory offered up a scene from the night she'd first met the brave little snake. Alice had sent her into the woods to gather a specimen from a magical animal for her game with Edmund. Treeslider had happily provided his venom. She saw in her mind's eye his fang piercing the thin cork in the vial. Then it played again, slower, and Rigel began to smile.

Of course. That's what she'd forgotten. Muggles used a piercing apparatus to go through the skin without damaging it overmuch, and they administered potions—or something like potions, at least—through the hollow tip! Her brain raced along the trajectory of that revelation with giddy excitement. Could the average person be accurate enough with such a device to get a potion in the general vicinity of an internal wound? With the right precautions…she thought maybe they could. She could spell the things—needles, she thought they were called, only not the sewing kind—for accuracy, or maybe charm each individually to find a specific point on the human body. Really, it was no different from hexes that targeted eyes, bowels, or feet regardless of the caster's aim. The magic existed. Applying it was only a question of perseverance, then.

Visions of self-propelled pointy things filled her head until she finished the Protection Potion. Only once it was neatly bottled and labeled did she rummage for spare parchment on which she could regurgitate the flood of ideas. The devices would need to be pre-filled with the potions that corresponded to the part of the body they would be spelled to target. Then there was the added necessity of the needle distinguishing between the injured person and anyone else who happened to be nearby. That would be tricky…but not impossible.

Her quill roved across the page, writing and re-writing and looking for inconsistencies. By the time lunch rolled around, she had come up with a handful of rudimentary runic sequences that approached the concept she'd set out. The final product would be a lot more complex, but it was a good beginning.

She stowed her notes and cleaned up the lab before locking it behind her. It wasn't until Rigel's feet carried her back into the more commonly traversed areas of the dungeons that she remembered why she'd fled to her lab in the first place.

"Rigel!"

Adrian Pucey's voice stalled her progress toward the Great Hall. She slowed and waited for the older boy to catch up to her. "Hi, Pucey," she offered, wondering what the upperclassman needed.

"Great job last night." He clapped her on the back hard and she had to bite down on the urge to cough. "Using the muggleborn to get a leg up was inspired, you know. Everyone is still talking about it."

Ah. Yes. She cleared her throat and smiled serenely up at the tall young man. "I'm pleased to have done well in the eyes of our House. I must admit, however, that I teamed up with Hermione because she's my friend."

Pucey blinked at her. "Your…friend." He seemed unsure whether he was meant to laugh. "Sure, Rigel. If that's what you told her."

Rigel's smile melted into a more serious expression. "Really, Adrian. Hermione is my cousin Harry's best friend. It's only natural that we'd work together."

"But you aren't going to help her win, surely," Pucey pointed out, now frowning. "I mean, this little alliance only works in the short term."

She conceded the point with a slow nod. "At some point we'll have to compete in good faith, it's true. She'll still be my friend, though."

The upperclassman gazed at her searchingly for a moment before shrugging. "If you say so. Anyway, good job, Rigel. Keep it up, yeah?"

"Yeah."

Pucey pulled ahead as Rigel hung back. She wondered how many people thought she'd been using Hermione instead of working with her. Did Hermione feel that way? She blew out a frustrated breath. It was an odd feeling, having the choices you made to stay alive judged and evaluated by a thousand outside eyes. The ordinary dangers of her past were nothing compared to the tournament's gargantuan, political, and public nature. Every time she felt she had a handle on it, some aspect of perception she hadn't considered reminded her that she had no idea what she was doing.

Classes resumed Monday, but the façade of normalcy that came with them was just that. The aftereffects of the first task were not so easily shaken off. Treeslider had woken intermittently, but only to feed on a couple of small mice before sinking back into energy conserving slumber. She kept him close to her side, and, despite snakes not being on the approved list of familiars, the professors allowed it with pity in their eyes.

Draco positively hovered whenever Rigel allowed it. He'd become something of a personal specter, glaring away anyone who tried crowding her in his presence. Sometimes she was grateful for the interference. Other times, she wondered whether she really seemed so fragile to him. She was fine, after all. The first task had been…intensely discomforting. But it was nothing a good night's sleep couldn't salve.

The Weasley twins had stopped her in the hall the day after the task and crowed their delight at the number of orders they'd already received for the firework display. None of her slightly concerned protests had stopped them promising to top it with whatever they gave her next. She wondered if Riddle would consider accidentally blowing up everything around her to be 'doing her best.' Still, Rigel had to admit she wouldn't have fared so well against the dragon without the twins' device. When she'd said as much, Fred cackled in a distinctly worrying fashion before muttering something about marketing a line of dragon deterrents.

The only professor who didn't move on tiptoe around her was Auror Dawlish. Defense Against the Dark Arts on Tuesday kicked off with a Severing Charm aimed directly at Rigel's nose. While the students seemed to stiffen around her, anticipating—what, she wasn't sure: a meltdown? A blowup?—Rigel blocked it automatically. She blinked in confusion at the Defense professor; he didn't normally begin to fire hexes until he'd at least called roll.

The tall man leveled his arresting eyes at her for a long moment before turning toward the blackboard with no more explanation than a flare of his olive trench coat. The lesson proceeded normally, or at least as normally as any of Dawlish's lessons ever did, but when the class was over he said, "Black. Stay behind."

Pansy and Draco had twin expressions of protective outrage. She laid an exasperated expression against them until they grudgingly packed up their things and headed for the door. The sharp look Draco shot her over his shoulder on the way told her they would be waiting just outside. Good friends were equal parts blessing and curse, she thought wryly.

Rigel approached the teacher's desk with healthy apprehension. She didn't think it likely that he'd kept her behind to hurl more offensive spells at her, but she wasn't going to discount the possibility outright. "You required me, Professor Dawlish?"

The man was pulling something from his desk drawer. It was a slim book with a well-worn cover. He passed the volume to her wordlessly and when she opened her mouth to question he shook his head sharply. "That's all, Black."

He turned his back to her, pulled out his wand, and began rearranging the desks for his next class. Rigel looked down at the book in her hand. It was a copy of the Auror's Field Guide. A well-used copy, at that. She flipped it open and noted that a number of passages were highlighted. Her fingers tightened as the thought came to her unbidden: who had asked Dawlish to give this to her? James or Riddle?

Troubled, she pocketed the tome and left the classroom. Pansy and Draco had expectant expressions, but Rigel only shrugged in response to their unasked questions. She didn't know what to say about the handbook. It would undoubtedly come in handy in the tournament, but without knowing whether it was her father or her enemy who wanted her to read it, characterizing it as a gift seemed hasty.

"Is Auror Dawlish affiliated with the S.O.W. Party?" she asked instead.

"Not that I know of," Pansy said slowly. "It's difficult to say with certainty, however. Not all those with membership patronize the social events. Professor Snape is a good example of that."

She nodded. "Is there a way to find out?"

"I'll ask Father," Draco offered. "Did he say something to make you think he's working for Lord Riddle?"

Rigel frowned. "Must you call him that? He's not a lord."

Draco lowered his voice. "Just because he hasn't claimed the lordship doesn't mean it's not his, Rigel."

"What lordship?" she asked, frowning. "There's no House of Riddle."

"The Slytherin lordship," Pansy said softly. "Everyone knows he's the heir, Rigel. He's a Parselmouth—my mother told me she heard it once." Her voice was no more than a whisper by the end.

"If everyone knows, why are we whispering?" Rigel asked.

Pansy pursed her lips. "If Lord Riddle hasn't advertised it, he has a reason for that. No one would bring it up without his permission."

"Except he obviously has advertised it, or no one would know," Rigel said. She could feel a familiar frustration building. Why did no one else see how odd this all was? Were they just used to it, having grown up in awe of the politician? "And have you forgotten I'm a Parselmouth, too? That doesn't automatically make someone Lord Slytherin."

"But you're already tied to another House," Draco said, sounding impatient. "Lord Riddle's House must be Slytherin, because he isn't tied to any other."

"That you know of," Rigel muttered. She shook her head in exasperation. "Have you even seen his family tree? Has anyone? Maybe he's not tied to any House—"

"Rigel, be quiet." Pansy shot a glance up and down the hallway. Her face was pale and her voice shook as she carefully added, "Speculation of that kind is dangerous."

"But that's just it," Rigel hissed, trying to keep her voice low. "He's got everyone so scared of his retribution that no one asks the obvious questions."

"Parselmouths don't come from nowhere," Draco said firmly. "Only the oldest pureblood Houses carry the gift, and not many of them are left in this age. Think, Rigel. Have you ever heard of a Parselmouth who wasn't the lord or heir to one of those Houses?"

She scowled. "No, but—"

"Lord Riddle is waiting for the right time to reveal his origins. That's all. Gossiping about it before that time will only get us all politically blacklisted." Draco's words were steady but his eyes were worried—too worried to be thinking clearly, she thought.

"Fine, then. I'll drop it," she allowed. Her tongue stung with the bitter admission. There was something fishy about Riddle's backstory. She hadn't much cared before, but the more his elitist agenda was bandied about in her face, the more it irked her. "I'm going to the library," she said.

"We have History of Magic," Pansy protested.

"Binns won't miss me." The ghost never even took roll, and Rigel was several weeks ahead of the syllabus in any case. "See you at lunch."

Draco spluttered as she left them in the corridor but didn't chase after her, at least. It probably wouldn't amuse him to know that she was headed for the genealogy section.

The library was incredibly quiet, being that it was the middle of second period on a Tuesday. Only a handful of harried-looking NEWT students were scattered among the tables. Rigel wove her way through the stacks, but slowed to a halt when she recognized a head of curly hair in the Healing section.

"Hi, Hermione. Looking for anything in particular?" She smiled in a friendly way as the girl looked over distractedly, thinking she was probably looking for a text to go along with that week's AIM assignment.

"Rigel, good morning." Hermione barely glanced over from where she was perusing the shelf. "Ah, sort of. There's not a lot on early childhood diseases here."

Rigel frowned in thought. None of Archie's current assignments related to that topic. "I have a couple of books on childhood syndromes in my dorm, if you'd like them. Doing some extracurricular reading?"

Hermione abandoned the bookshelf to shoot Rigel a considering look. "Yes, actually. I assume you're aware of the Fade?"

"Of course." She grimaced. "Everyone knows of the Fade. I'm afraid a lot of the literature on it is speculation still. Most of the articles I've seen in recent journals report little progress beyond diagnosis."

"I've noticed the same," Hermione said. Exasperation crept into her tone as she added, "I'd think in the nation where Wizarding children are most affected there would be an abundance of information. Instead, I'm having the same trouble finding anything concrete here that I had at AIM."

"You could ask Madam Pomfrey, but our lesson on the Fade was rather straightforward," Rigel said slowly. "Children are sometimes born without enough magic to sustain their life force. All experiments to stymie the magical bleed-off only prolong the inevitable. I've not seen anything indicating that it affects offspring of at least one muggleborn parent, though, so you don't have to be concerned."

Hermione gaped at her in open outrage. "Not concerned? Children are dying. Why wouldn't I be concerned?"

Rigel winced apologetically. "Right. I didn't mean to say that you shouldn't care, of course. Only, there's not much anyone can do right now."

"There's always something," Hermione said staunchly. "Even if it's just thinking as hard as you can about a problem in case you have an idea no one else has."

"That's a good point," Rigel allowed. She of all people should know that qualified professionals didn't have a monopoly on new ideas. Quite the opposite, in fact. "What have you been thinking about so far?"

After a slightly narrow-eyed stare that seemed to gauge whether or not Rigel was teasing her, Hermione waved her over to a nearby table and sat, waiting patiently for Rigel to take the seat across from her before speaking. "To be honest, I'm not sure I fully understand what is even causing the death of the afflicted." Hermione blew out a breath that floated a strand of curls away from her face. "All the publications say that the children are born without 'enough magic,' but squibs are born without access to much magic, and they don't die. It's as if something is actively sucking the life out of the infants."

"In a way, it is," Rigel said. "Squibs fall into two categories, remember. Some never develop a core or a magic circulation system in the womb, and are born essentially muggles. Others are born with a damaged magical core, incapable of processing or channeling magic correctly. Type two squibs still have a normal amount of magic in their veins; it's enough to fill the circulation system, even enough to produce an aura, but the squib normally can't consciously manipulate it to the degree an average witch or wizard can."

"So you're saying the Fade children are something in between? Born with a magic circulation system but without enough magic to fill it?" Hermione tapped her fingers against the desk as thoughts made a rapid march behind her eyes.

"Exactly. The Fade produces a child with the internal magical infrastructure of a type two squib—fully operable magic circulation system and a damaged core—but much less than the usual amount of magic in that system. To put it in numerical terms, children born with the Fade have natural magical coefficients somewhere in the teens. The regular scale only goes to 10," she added, in case Hermione hadn't gotten that far in her Arithmancy studies. "It's as though—" she struggled to think of an appropriate analogy for a moment. "As though you tried to take a child-sized amount of blood and fill a fully grown adult's circulatory system with it. None of the adult's organs or extremities gets enough blood, the heart can't maintain adequate pressure, et cetera."

"But the healthy body produces more blood if it loses some," Hermione muttered. "Up to thirty percent of total volume, if need be. And our cores can be expended to incredibly low levels—magical exhaustion is rarely fatal."

"Above a certain percent of blood or magic loss, the body can't sustain itself, though," Rigel said. "And a witch or wizard is usually unable to access more than eighty percent of their magic. The twenty percent kept subconsciously in reserve is enough to support your magic circulation system in an emergency, but if a wizard's levels don't recover to at least fifty percent in forty-eight hours, they will die. These infants are going much longer than two days without healthy levels of magic. They're essentially born with magical exhaustion, and their cores go into overtime attempting to fill the void. Magic isn't made from nothing, though. The core uses physical resources to rebuild, resources that newborns don't have."

"The core is sucking the life from them," Hermione said, eyes going wide. "But then—why don't they remove it?"

"Remove it?" Rigel could not stop the incredulous horror that came instinctually at the thought. "I—" She swallowed. "You know that a Wizarding child's major organ systems become dependent on magic within a week of the core's activation at birth."

"And the Fade can be diagnosed within the first two days," Hermione argued, eyes flashing. "That gives you three days to remove a core before the infant is dependent on the magic."

"You're talking about purposely turning an infant into a squib," Rigel said quietly, glancing around to make sure they weren't overheard.

"I'm talking about saving their life," Hermione hissed fiercely. "Don't tell me no one's even suggested it?"

Rigel shook her head. "Not that I know of. Such a radical idea would likely not be welcome in most magical circles."

"A limb that can't be saved is amputated before it poisons the rest of the body," Hermione growled. "It's an obvious solution."

"One that no magical parents would agree to," Rigel told her firmly.

"If a muggle child had to lose a leg or perish, his parents wouldn't let him die just because they'd rather he became a football player." Hermione pulled at her hair in frustration. "Life as a squib is still a life."

"Purebloods don't see magic as a limb, Hermione. It's intrinsic to who a witch or wizard is, not just what they can do. You may as well suggest removing a child's soul at birth. That's how disturbing an idea it would be to the families the Fade affects—old, conservative families, that is." Rigel held Hermione's gaze until she could see reluctant understanding creeping into the brown-eyed girl's expression.

"I suppose it would be a difficult and risky procedure in any case," Hermione grumbled. "The magic circulation system is entwined with most of the other organs. Separating the core from the body without sending it into shock…well, maybe it couldn't be done. But if it could…"

"It's worth exploring," Rigel said. Mentally, she added, very quietly.

"As long as we're talking about it," Hermione began, shifting her weight forward in her chair and lowering her voice a little. "Why do you think the Fade is disproportionately affecting pureblood families in Great Britain?"

Rigel tilted her head. "Some people would call that a dangerous question, but I believe fear of inquiry is more dangerous than any question. To be frank, I suspect it's a byproduct of inbreeding. That's not a popular opinion, as you may imagine, but there's some evidence for it."

Hermione held up a hand to forestall Rigel's words and produced quill and parchment from her pocket before gesturing impatiently for her to continue. "What evidence?"

"Most of the families I know have been affected have been 'hyper-pure,' i.e. intermarried with only other pureblood families, for multiple consecutive generations, while some families who are pure by definition now but who have muggle blood in their recent ancestry have not been affected yet at all."

"That's anecdotal, though," Hermione said, frowning. "Do you have statistics?"

Rigel shrugged. "Some studies have been done, but mostly the research is into ethnicity, nationality, and light/dark affiliation more than blood purity. Even though blood purity is an obvious variable, no one seems keen to fund or publish such a study openly. I can only tell you what I've observed, which admittedly isn't all-encompassing."

Hermione pursed her lips in thought. "How many students at this school would you say know of at least one child afflicted with the Fade, whether in their family or another?"

"All of them," Rigel said at once. "I can't imagine anyone not knowing someone who has lost a child. My own grandmother lost several, I believe."

"Several?" Hermione inhaled in acute sympathy.

"That's the price of siblings these days," Rigel said grimly. "At least in those families it affects."

"That's another thing," Hermione said, jotting down another note onto her parchment. "Why does it affect subsequent siblings more than firstborns?"

"Some speculate that it depends on the power of the mother," Rigel said softly. "That hasn't been proven, but people still believe that powerful witches are more likely to keep a second child alive."

"That suggests that the mother has an influence on the amount of magic the child is born with. There have been cases reported of mothers' magic compensating for infant defects in the womb." Hermione nibbled on her quill absently. "For instance, sometimes all magical scans show a baby is healthy until birth, when the infant is detached from the mother's support system. Maybe…maybe a powerful witch could unconsciously compensate for the lack of magic in the child's system, sacrificing a bit of her own magic to see it born with more. Then, perhaps that can only happen once or twice before the mother can't afford to lose any more magic herself."

"That's a lot of speculation," Rigel pointed out. "It's possible, but you'd need some evidence."

"That's easy to test," Hermione said, scribbling furiously. "Just note the rate of maximum expenditure before pregnancy and after birth in all women and if those from families statistically more likely to be affected by the Fade have measurably less magic after childbirth while those unlikely to be affected by the Fade remain the same…well, that's pretty strong evidence. The trouble is determining which families exactly are more likely to be affected by the Fade. Rigel, do you think…if I start asking around the school about the Fade, will it spark undue animosity toward me?"

"Quite possibly," she admitted. "But if you make it clear you're attempting to solve the problem, not just morbidly curious about it…and if you don't ever mention removing the core as a possible option…you may find people willing to talk to you about it. Let me make a few inquiries first, though. I'll talk to my friends and have them spread the word that you're a brilliant medical prodigy who is researching this matter in good faith, not as a means of discrediting pureblood values."

"Is that really their primary concern? Even if such reticence might prevent a cure being found?" Hermione asked, looking pained.

"If it wasn't, there'd be a lot more families following the Weasley model right now."

"What is a Weasley?"

Rigel smiled widely. "I think you should meet them first."

Later that evening, after Snape had released her from a gruelingly practical lesson in silent counter-curses, she found Blaise in the common room and asked if he had time to assist her with a personal project.

"Your projects are always interesting, Rigel," he said, putting aside a slim volume on curse breaking and steepling his fingers in a show of full attention. "How can I help?"

She took out the necklace that Sirius had given her the night of the first task. Sweeping the chain over her head, she held it out to Blaise's curious fingers and allowed him to examine it carefully. "I'm having trouble unraveling the exact purpose of the runic configuration that's embedded in this pendant. The shorthand is too advanced for me to get an impression, and the expanded sequences are dizzying."

Blaise frowned in concentration as he peered at the shorthand runes etched on the surface of the circular obsidian disk. He took out his wand and waved it over the necklace, murmuring the magnifying charm. "I've never seen this form of shorthand. It looks like a variation on the Norse system. Latentia Revelare." The revealing charm expanded the hidden sequences into a block of runes that hung shimmering in the air before Blaise's widening eyes. "Merlin, Rigel, where did you get this? I haven't seen anything so complicated outside of sentient objects."

"My aunt made it for me. I assume it's some sort of protection for the tournament, but my father didn't have a full explanation for its purpose." Rigel tilted her head and smiled self-deprecatingly. "I don't recognize half of these runes, to be honest. I was hoping you'd be able to decipher more."

He didn't look away from the runes, but his voice was a little awestruck as he said, "Lady Potter made this? From scratch?"

"I assume so," Rigel said, shrugging. "She's had some free time while her company is rebuilding."

Blaise summoned a piece of parchment, ignoring the yelp of an annoyed second year as it zoomed off of the unlucky boy's table. He cast a copying spell to commit the sequence to parchment, carefully ensuring every rune was transferred correctly before letting the revealing spell go and handing the necklace back to her.

Rigel slid the warm disk over her head once more as Blaise murmured under his breath, jotting down notes and underlining lines of runes as he perused the parchment. She took a seat in a chair across from him and waited patiently as he worked. Several minutes later, he set the parchment down and rubbed his eyes.

"It's definitely for protection," he said, leaning forward as he explained. "The reason it's so complex is that it's been designed to react only to very specific stimuli. There's some sort of threshold that the runes are describing, and if whatever that represents is detected, the necklace will respond instantly with…something. It's difficult to tell. It seems as though a spell has been…trapped, for lack of a better word, in the necklace. It's strange, though. Normally when a specific effect is required, something like a curse attached to an object, for instance, the magic is explicitly described and shaped by the runes on the object. Here, though…" He shook his head, bewildered. "There's magic inside the necklace, but there are no runes specifically to guide the magic once it is triggered, and it doesn't feel wild. Does that make sense?"

She raised her eyebrows in surprise. That almost sounded like…shaped imbuing. Rigel wondered if it would work the same for an object as for a potion. No reason it wouldn't, as long as the object already had magic to contain the imbued spell. It was brilliant. "I think I understand," she said, smiling slowly. "It sounds like Aunt Lily has adapted Harry's concept of shaped imbuing for potions into something altogether more versatile. Thanks, Blaise. I'll write to my aunt about the specifics. I bet she'll be impressed that you worked it out."

"Not entirely," Blaise said, leaning back with an unsatisfied shrug. "I'd very much like to know what the magic is intended to react to. It must be something incredibly complex, for it to take so many rune sequences to describe. A very specific situation, maybe, or a long list of different things."

"I'll let you know what she says if she writes back," Rigel promised. "I appreciate your help, Blaise."

"Any time," the boy said, his dark eyes alight with interest. "Like I said, you're always interesting."

"I'm not sure whether that's a compliment or a curse," she said, smiling wryly.

"Definitely a compliment. You're not cut out for an ordinary life, Rigel. The sooner you face that, the less annoyed you'll be at the inconvenience of being extraordinary." Blaise's voice was light, but his expression was serious.

"I strongly believe that extraordinariness is a quality imposed externally on unsuspecting people largely minding their own business," Rigel grumbled. "There are no extraordinary people. All people are basically the same, but some of them get more attention."

"Because some of them work hard, apply their natural gifts judiciously, and change the world in the process," Blaise said, smiling widely. "Oh Rigel, however did you get yourself into this mess?"

"I ask myself that question all the time." She sighed. "I suppose it's bad grace to complain when plenty of others would take my place in a heartbeat."

"Less than you might think, after the first task," Blaise told her, his amusement fading away. "It was shockingly violent. You handled yourself well, but many of the other champions did not. Krum cursed his way through the entire evening, Delacour broke down into tears for five minutes after slicing open a Manticore, Sousa obviously couldn't handle the pressure, and Antiope almost killed Tahiil when he came across her unexpectedly. The amount of blood and suffering in that one night certainly turned a great many stomachs. Not enough to wish the entertainment to come to an end, of course, but enough to be less than disappointed about not being chosen themselves."

"In truth, I wouldn't wish it on anyone," Rigel admitted. "It's a load of utter bollocks."

"Must be, to have you cursing. Any idea what the next task will be?" he added, smiling in response to her sharp look. "Just asking. Theo and I have a wager. You did work out most of the first task ahead of time."

"It's been less than a week," she pointed out. "Riddle hasn't given us any hints yet."

"Well, he's been very busy, I suppose," Blaise drawled.

Something about the way he said 'busy' pricked at Rigel's suspicions. "Busy how?" she asked, attempting nonchalance.

The other boy shot her a surprised look. "You haven't heard." He hesitated visibly before saying, "The S.O.W. Party is dusting off a bit of legislation. That marriage law they've been trying to pass for a few years, you remember? Lord Riddle has spent most of the week between promoting its merit at Ministry working groups and socializing with influential members of the Wizengamot."

"That's not possible." Rigel's face felt frozen as Blaise's words sank slowly to the bottom of her gut. She had an agreement with Riddle. He couldn't put forth such legislation. He—he could, though, she realized with an ugly jolt. She'd bargained for the end to such legislation on the condition of her winning the tournament. There was nothing to stop him from attempting to pass it before the tournament had even concluded. That bastard. She hissed wordlessly, digging her fingers into the arms of her chair in helpless fury. "He thinks he can have it both ways. We'll see about that."

She dove both hands into her book bag, producing parchment, ink, and quill with fingers positively shaking with anger. Muttering an apology to Blaise, she began a swift letter to Sirius. There had to be something that could stall the legislation at least until the end of the year. She would talk to Dumbledore, too. Somehow, Riddle would not get away with this.

Rigel's letter was almost finished when the others found them in the common room. Draco, Pansy, Theo, and Millicent claimed the chairs and sofa on either side of them. She felt her friends' curious gazes but only murmured distractedly in response to their greetings as she scribbled out the last couple of lines.

"What's Rigel working on, then?" Theo asked Blaise.

"I believe it's a letter. He didn't know about the recent revitalization of the Party's marriage legislation, it seems." Blaise's explanation was succinct, but there was a breadth of implication between his words.

"You told him?" Millicent groaned. "Rigel doesn't need to be distracted right now. He has to focus on the tournament."

"Rigel needs to know these things," she said sharply, turning her gaze on Millicent as she signed the letter with a flourish and set it aside for drying. "I'd appreciate it if my friends didn't filter relevant information on my behalf."

"It's not relevant yet," Millie argued. "There's no guarantee it will pass, even with the popular attention from the tournament to bolster support."

"If it does, my participation in this tournament is for nothing," she snapped. She regretted the angry words as soon as they'd slipped out and grimaced at Millicent's open shock.

"Rigel…what do you mean?" The dark-haired girl frowned slowly, her heavy brow making the expression naturally more intense. "I knew there was something odd about you entering the tournament. You didn't do it freely, did you? You've got some kind of…arrangement going on, don't you?"

Rigel pressed her lips together, but it was a little late to try and fool the girl. Millicent was too savvy, and Rigel had been too careless, incensed as she was at Riddle and herself in equal measure. She couldn't believe she hadn't seen this coming.

"Rigel, you can tell them," Pansy said gently. "Millie, Theo, and Blaise won't spread the information around." She accompanied this assessment with stern looks at all three, and each nodded seriously in response.

"I suspected as much," Blaise offered. "Rigel is many things, but glory-seeking is exceedingly out of character. To be honest, I assumed you were being blackmailed by someone."

"They tried that too," Draco said with a smirk. "Rigel is un-leverageable, it seems."

"Nearly," Millicent contradicted. "Obviously someone found something that worked. Was it about this legislation?"

"In part," Rigel admitted, running a hand through her hair. "I didn't tell you all because it puts you in an awkward position. Draco and Pansy have it bad enough."

"It was Lord Riddle himself you bargained with, wasn't it?" Theo's words cut to the heart of the matter. He scowled at the surprised looks the others shot him. "What? I'm not a complete idiot, you know. If it was anyone less powerful, Rigel could have ignored it. If it wasn't to do with the S.O.W. Party, he wouldn't feel he needed to hide it from us. You didn't want to conflict our loyalties, right?"

Rigel nodded. "To be frank, I'm working in opposition to the Party's goals. Riddle wanted me to participate. The condition was, in part, that he cease attempts to pass such openly anti-muggleborn legislation if I should win."

"Oh, Rigel," Millicent said, sighing sharply. "That gives him nearly six months to pass anything he deems important enough. And that's assuming he lets you win at all. He controls almost every aspect of the tournament, after all."

"We believe he does want Rigel to win," Pansy put in. She glanced around the common room and, after ensuring no one was near enough to overhear, went on. "Originally we thought it was because the propaganda victory would outweigh any legislative loss, but you're right, Millie. If he spends all of his political clout, he could very well win on both fronts by the end of the year."

"Wait, I'm sorry, but it sounds like you've been strategizing with Rigel against the Party," Theo said. His voice was hoarse with discomfort. "I mean, no offense Rigel, but that could get us and our families in very hot water."

"I know," she said weakly. "I'm not asking—"

"You don't have to ask," Draco said firmly. "Regardless of the Party's agenda, what Lord Riddle is doing personally to Rigel is wrong."

"He threatened his family," Pansy added quietly.

"Then he won't hesitate to go after ours if he gets wind of this," Theo shot back, just as quietly.

"Hold up," Millicent said calmly. "No one is talking disloyalty to the Party right now. All Draco and Pansy are doing is giving political advice to Rigel, who is in a delicate situation. We've not said a word about actively moving against Lord Riddle's goals, and we won't. We're just discussing a situation."

Theo didn't look reassured at the distinction. "I sympathize with Rigel's situation, but he got himself into it." He shot her an apologetic look, but didn't temper his words. "If we help him outmaneuver Lord Riddle, if we even talk about it, it's as good as saying we don't support the legislation he's trying to pass. Is that what you're saying?" He looked around at all of them, but no one said a word. "What? Rigel isn't an idiot, either. He knows where we stand on this. Where we've always stood. The Party is trying to curb the influence of muggle culture on our society. When did that become something you all oppose?"

"It's not," Pansy said, looking acutely uncomfortable. "Of course Lord Riddle is doing what he thinks best for our world. But Rigel is our friend."

"Rigel opposes the Party in this; he just said so," Theo said. There was regret in his voice. "I'm sorry, but I don't think you can stand in the middle of this. You're all going to get caught between it."

Before either of her friends could defend her again, Rigel said, "He's right. Theo's absolutely right. You all can't be involved in this any more than you are. I'm sorry that I lost my temper. And I'm sorry that I ever told you lot," she added, keeping her voice strong in the face of Draco and Pansy's mutinous expressions. "I'm grateful for your support, but this is a path you can't follow me down any longer. You'll lose everything you care about."

"You're one of the things we care about," Draco said. "Don't shut us out again, Rigel. It's our decision to take the risk, not yours."

She shook her head. "I appreciate and welcome your help in preparing for the tournament; Riddle wants me to win anyway, so it's no conflict. As for the legislative issue, please let me handle it. I have plenty of support elsewhere in this matter." She could see her words hit home with wounding bluntness. Draco's face darkened and Pansy dropped her gaze to her hands, subdued. "I'm sorry for involving you all. Excuse me."

She rolled up her letter and strode toward the common room door, feeling incredibly lonely for all that she was certain she'd done the right thing.

After their Healing lesson on Friday, Rigel invited Hermione to sit with her at the Slytherin table the next morning. Most of the tournament champions did not take meals in the Great Hall, preferring to eat back in Hogsmeade where their lodging was. It was hard to blame them, when the Hogwarts students went out of their way to be less than welcoming. Rigel wanted to introduce the girl to her friends properly, however, and she'd cleared the idea with them before asking.

Everyone promised to be on their best behavior; even still, there was a beat of absolute silence when Hermione approached their table that morning and said, "Hi, Rigel," in a voice that was determinedly cheerful.

"Good morning, Hermione," Rigel said, standing to bow over the girl's hand at once. Hermione flushed with more discomfort than pleasure and cleared her throat briskly.

"I've invited Tahiil as well, if you don't mind." Rigel saw the dark-skinned boy standing just behind Hermione and stuck out her hand with a smile.

"Tahiil, welcome. Chaps? Can we make room, please?"

Draco huffed quietly with annoyance but shuffled left a foot nevertheless. Pansy politely made room at the other side of the gap, students shuffling down in a ripple effect until there was more than enough space for the three of them to sit comfortably. Rigel took an extra moment to make sure Treeslider was not being squished in her robe pocket before returning to her breakfast.

"Thank you for having me," Tahiil said brightly, wasting no time in filling his plate with anything in reach. "I have been wondering what sort of food you ate here at the castle. What bounty! How fortunate we are this day."

"The elves have outdone themselves, as usual," Pansy agreed.

"The house-elves cook all this every day?" Hermione said sharply.

Rigel, remembering her promise to Binny, answered quickly. "Yes, aren't they brilliant? Hogwarts is lucky to have so many talented elves volunteering to work here."

"Volunteering?" Hermione repeated, frowning slightly. "I was under the impression they were bound to serve the castle."

"They are," Rigel said, smiling serenely. "It is a great honor for them, you know, to be bonded to such a prestigious place as this. It probably seems odd to you, as I've heard AIM doesn't house any elves, but house-elves have their own interesting values and cultural practices. I don't know if you've any interest, but I'd be happy to introduce you to a few if you have any questions."

Hermione blinked at her, then nodded slowly. "Yes, I would like that. I've been…wondering about them. Thank you."

"I think that's one of the best parts of this whole tournament," Pansy put in. The perfect smile on her face made Rigel uneasy for some reason. "The chance to learn about other cultures and their magical inhabitants is priceless, don't you think?"

"I quite agree," Hermione said, nodding. She began to choose breakfast items from the offerings before her, speaking all the while. "AIM's curriculum is top-notch by any standard, but it's been fascinating to get a different perspective on magical education. For instance, Transfiguration is taught entirely differently here than it is at my school."

"How can it be different?" Draco asked. He sounded interested despite himself, but when he caught Rigel's slight smile he scowled at her and fixed his eyes back on his food.

Hermione answered him regardless. "Each lesson here seems to focus on a different, very specific Transfiguration. Toucan to teacup, rose to writing desk, and so on. Professor McGonagall tends to let students work out for themselves the amount of magic necessary, doesn't she? And she doesn't explain how exactly one ought to shape one's intent to achieve a given effect. She encourages you all to come to that conclusion on your own. I think that's just fascinating. At AIM the approach is quite different. First we learn to describe the processes of a given subset of transformation—animate-to-inanimate, for instance—using descriptive runes. Then, we calculate the energy required based on magical coefficients of the materials involved and the complexity factors of the chosen process, and only then do we actually put magic to the task."

"Why would you want to complicate it so much?" Theo asked, his jaw slightly agape.

Hermione blinked. "It's always complicated. At AIM we are simply taught to enumerate that complexity before learning a spell, while here at Hogwarts the focus seems to be—and forgive me if I'm mistaken—but it seems to be on developing an instinctual feel for magic on a level that the equations and runic descriptions don't really instill. I bet none of you have to mentally calculate coefficients when you cast a spell, do you?"

"Co-what?" Theo blinked at her, utterly comprehensionless.

"Magical coefficients are only taught in Arithmancy and Alchemy here," Rigel explained. "Hermione is right. We learn Transfiguration the same way we learn Defense, Charms, and Potions. Once we learn a spell, we have a feel for how it should be cast, and refine that impression over time. AIM teaches students to be efficient from the outset, but it sounds as though the trade-off is additional mental acuity required when actively casting. Do you find it slows you down?"

Hermione grimaced. "I wouldn't have said so, before coming here. Seeing how fast you cast during the first task, though…I have to admit, I can't cast so quickly."

"No one is faster than Rigel," Blaise drawled. "You shouldn't use him to determine the average casting rate of Hogwarts students."

"How did you become so fast, then?" Tahiil asked around a mouthful of muffin. "Is it something special about your wand?"

"My wand?" She frowned at him. "There's nothing special about it." At least, nothing that he should be apprised of.

Tahiil shrugged good-naturedly. "I know not much of wands. My people do not use them. I thought perhaps it was like a talisman; a stronger talisman often means stronger magic, no?"

"Most wands are created equal," Blaise offered.

"Most?" Hermione's eyes narrowed. "Not all?"

"He means the Elder Wand. It's just a legend, though. All regular wands are basically the same, despite what a wandmaker will tell you." Millicent took in Hermione's intrigued expression and added, "Seriously, the Elder Wand is just a children's story. No study has ever shown that the average witch or wizard's wand is more or less powerful of its own merit. It's always the witch or wizard that determined the power."

"I would like to try a wand some day," Tahill said thoughtfully. "It will be interesting to see if my magic is more or less powerful with a channel."

"How did you learn magic without a wand?" Theo asked curiously.

"'How' is a difficult question," Tahiil said, favoring the sandy-haired boy with a forthright look. "I suspect it is not so different from how you learn. My people say that all wizards have magic within themselves alone, and a tool to manipulate it is just a crutch. I am not learned enough to say either way. I come from a very small village, with only a handful of elders to teach me the mystic ways." He tilted his head and shrugged. "It is true that perhaps they do not know everything of the world of magic."

"How did you hear about the tournament?" Pansy asked. She blinked wide, pretty eyes at Tahiil. "Coming from such a small village, I mean."

Tahiil smiled widely. "It was most fortuitous! I met a man in Mogadishu when I was collecting supplies for my shaman. He somehow recognized the magic within me, though I gave him no cause to suspect. He offered to make my dreams come true."

"Really?" Millicent leaned forward, exchanging a look with Pansy as she took up the thread of questioning. "What a strange offer."

"Indeed. I did not know how he knew of the Dream Messengers, as he certainly did not appear to be a Uagadou sorcerer, but I was curious. And hopeful," he admitted, shaking his head sheepishly. "It is beyond the fate of one such as I to be invited to the great halls of Uagadou, but my foolish heart did yearn."

"Is Uagadou like Hogwarts?" Hermione asked. "Restrictive in whom they accept, I mean."

Pansy and Millicent shifted uncomfortably, but neither Hermione nor Tahiil seemed to notice.

"In a different way," Tahill said, his cheerful manner fading into seriousness. He lifted his hand to envelope the hall around them. "A school such as this it is, but only the very wealthy may attend. For most, for me, the tribal elders will take in ones who exhibit magic. There is no…no secrecy, as there is here, you see? In my village, everyone knows. My mother and father had no magic, but they recognized it easily in me when I was seven, and in my brother when he was just three. I have been training with my shaman ever since."

"The man who found you in Mogadishu," Pansy began, her tone nonchalant. "Do you remember what he looked like?"

Tahiil grinned. He set down his utensil and lifted both hands before his face, swirling them in a series of gestures too complicated to call a pattern. In the air before him, the figure of a man materialized. Drawn out of light and air, the picture grew rapidly more clear, until Millicent sucked in a breath of surprise.

"Crouch," she muttered, eyes wide.

It was, she realized, peering closer at the translucent image. Tahiil had made a perfect likeness of Barty Crouch Jr., the sallow-faced man she remembered vaguely from the World Cup.

"He must have been sent to recruit for the tournament," Pansy murmured.

"I didn't know Crouch's son was a Party member," Millicent said, eyeing the image with undisguised intrigue. "He's certainly not working for the Department of Magical Games and Sports."

"How do you know?" Theo asked.

"His father doesn't trust him to tie his own shoes," Millicent said dismissively.

"Someone trusted him to find Tahiil," Blaise pointed out.

Riddle. It must be, but why? She was under the impression that he hadn't intended to broadcast the tournament too widely before the candidates had been decided. For some reason, he had specifically sent one of his lackeys to find and recruit Tahiil, a muggleborn from East Africa. For what? The appearance of diversity? Somehow she didn't think so.

It made her wonder who else in the tournament was not a chance submission. Were there others who had been specifically recruited, according to criteria that only Riddle understood? The idea that Riddle was leaving nothing up to chance passed unbidden through her mind.

The morning post momentarily stalled any discussion that might have flourished on the subject. Rigel automatically moved her goblet as an owl descended with a letter. She unrolled it curiously—Krait had no reason to be corresponding so soon after her last shipment, and Archie used the mirror almost exclusively to communicate these days. It was from Lily. She hadn't expected an explanation for the necklace to arrive so soon; her mother must have sent off a reply nearly as soon as the query arrived.

Dear Archie,

Your observations on the Dark Defense Disk (your Uncle James named it) are entirely correct! It doesn't surprise me that Sirius was less than articulate in relating its purpose. Essentially, I've designed it to respond to any attack that meets a certain threshold for power, malicious intent, and Dark energy. It's more than just a very fast shield, however—the magic embedded in the disk is, in fact, an entire ward, anchored to the necklace alone. Remus helped me cast the ward over a three-day period, and I developed a ritual that transferred and sealed the ward semi-permanently within the obsidian disk.

Harry's research on the concept of Shaped Imbuing certainly influenced the breakthrough in my work; as I am not personally proficient in the skillset, I instead constructed a runic configuration that imbued the magic for me into the vessel of my choosing. The rest of the project—the exact language used to describe the sort of magic the disk needed to detect—has been the ambition of several years of study. Letting a magical object determine intent is particularly challenging, but using inspiration from muggle advancements in algorithmic decision-making, I was able to produce this prototype. I must warn you it won't protect you from mild or even moderate Dark Arts. The necklace is a last resort, and will respond only to attacks likely to maim or kill. I don't anticipate you needing it during a public tournament, Archie, but I want to give you every assurance of safety that I can.

As to the other matter you wrote us about: we are aware of the recent attempts to revisit that legislation. Alice tipped us off in time to marshal what political resources we can to stall. It is difficult to discredit it entirely in the current atmosphere. On the one hand, the legislation encourages stronger ties between pureblood and halfbloods, and in doing so grants rights that are in themselves attractive to halfbloods. There are many who believe that consolidating magical power in established families may be a good thing in the face of increasingly violent anti-muggleborn sentiments. People are scared. On the other hand, the tournament itself has lent at least a little credence to the argument for blood superiority, though that credibility may weaken or strengthen with time, depending on how the event unfolds.

We don't want you to worry about any of this, however. Just concentrate on being safe, and don't neglect your studies. In the worst case, Harry is already protected from any ill effects the legislation might bring, and Addy is blessedly young, yet. The menfolk send their best regards. You have all of our love and support.

Aunt Lily

Rigel tucked the letter away slowly, lost in thought. Lily would never say so outright, but she could read well enough between the lines. The very fact that she, a 'pureblood,' was in the lead for points in the tournament was lending momentum to efforts to reintroduce the marriage law. If she made a poor showing in the next task, it might lower popular opinion of the blood supremacy argument, but winning the tournament was the only way to see such legislation gone for good. That, and she was already bound to do her very best in every task. She took a moment to reflect darkly on her own hubris. Had she really thought she could outsmart Riddle? The man had lived and breathed politics and manipulation for longer than she'd been alive. Maybe this entire thing had only been the worst kind of folly. It was hard to think otherwise when her every victory now actively worked against her.

"You look like someone just kicked over your cauldron," Draco said from her left.

"Letter from Aunt Lily," she said. At Blaise's curious, half-lidded glance, she added. "You were right about the pendant. The runic arrays were describing powerful Dark magic. It's designed to defend against it."

"With a shield?" Blaise pressed, eyebrows raised.

"A ward," she said, nodding. "Anchored on the disk itself."

"My, my, that is impressive," Blaise said. "If it works, at least. I wouldn't have said that 'Dark' was quantifiable in that way."

"I almost hope I never find out whether it works," Rigel said, grimacing. "It sounds as though it'll only react to the most dangerous of curses."

"Do you think it would protect you from an Unforgivable?" he asked. His mild tone belied the implications of the question.

"I'm not sure," she admitted slowly. "Lily didn't specify which ward she and Remus imbued it with. It took them three days to cast it, so I imagine it's quite powerful. A ward like that might stop a lesser Unforgivable, but the Killing Curse…well, I don't know of any ward that claims to stop that. Do you?"

Blaise shook his head. "Even still, immunity to the Cruciatus is nothing to sniff at."

"We don't know that for sure," she said. He was right, though. If Lily's imbued ward was sufficiently powerful, it was a priceless protection. Imagine: all the security of painstakingly anchored wards, available in an instant and automatically erected in response to a sufficient threat. It was nothing short of revolutionary. If it worked, every Auror in the country would want one.

It got her thinking about her first aid kit. What if she could apply the same principle, but instead of a ward, a powerful ritual of Healing? There were some rites of Healing so potent that it took several Healers working in concert to realize them. If such a thing could be performed in advance, then bottled for emergencies…her head felt heavy with the implications. She shook it briefly. There was no use getting ahead of herself. Most Healing rituals were extremely specific, and couldn't be applied to general emergency situations.

"That's not what had you upset, though," Draco said. She felt Dom's warning too late—her friend had already determined that something else was preying on her mind.

"Is everything all right at home?" Hermione asked, concern for Archie no doubt prompting the question.

"Just fine," she assured the girl. "Harry and everyone else are well. My aunt just had some news about the marriage law. It's rather put me off my breakfast, I'm afraid."

"The what?" Hermione asked.

Rigel winced inwardly. Of course, Hermione wouldn't know. Archie had probably never thought to bring it up. After the scene in the common room earlier that week, she wasn't keen to hash it out in front of her schoolmates, either.

"It's just a law that's being proposed right now," she said. "My family is attempting to stymie it."

"Why?" Hermione gazed solemnly at her, the breakfast on her plate momentarily forgotten.

"We believe it is disadvantageous to halfbloods and muggleborns," she admitted. At Hermione's fierce frown, she realized there was no way to avoid the girl's questions. She gave in gracefully, explaining as succinctly as possible. "The law incentivizes purebloods to marry halfbloods and vice-versa. It is an attempt to fold halfbloods back into pureblood families, reabsorbing their wealth and any magical gifts in the process. It leaves muggleborns to essentially marry within their own community or else marry muggles, thereby diluting their blood and, consequentially, their influence in society further."

Hermione's jaw was gaping by the time she was finished. "Is it not bad enough that we aren't allowed equal education or employment? We're to be excluded in love, too? Why would anyone support a law that limits their own choices just to spite another group?"

She looked around the table expectantly, as though waiting for a reasonable answer to materialize. Rigel's year mates displayed various stages of discomfort, but none volunteered an argument. Likely they knew it would be met with ferocious disagreement. Tahiil looked interested as well, but he was nowhere near as visibly invested in answers as Hermione. Rigel was about to offer to talk about it later with Hermione, away from the uneasy ears around them, when Adrian Pucey spoke up from a little way down the table.

"You know, I actually agree with the muggleborn." Silence fell in a pool around him as a number of Slytherins stopped pretending not to listen to the discussion and turned to stare. Pucey made a face at the alarmed expressions of his own year mates. "What? I know I'm not the only one thinking it. The law restricts us the most. Our generation is being sacrificed in this giant chess match, expected to marry and procreate with halfbloods just so that subsequent generations retain the power our parents have been steadily allowing to slip through their fingers. It's utterly unfair."

"Careful, Adrian," Bole hissed. "The Party is always listening."

"If we don't voice our concerns, how can the Party take them into account?"

Rigel really doubted the Party cared one way or another what the youngest generation thought about Riddle's grand plan to project pureblood power into the future. Her classmates were expected to carry it out, no questions asked.

"It's not all halfbloods," someone else pointed out reasonably. "Just the ones with two magical parents. Our children will still be purebloods."

"Technical purebloods," Pucey sneered. "I'm not talking about our kids, even. I'm talking about us. Do you want to mate with a halfblood?"

"What's wrong with halfbloods?" Hermione said sharply. At the disbelieving looks her question prompted, she huffed out an annoyed breath. "I'm serious. I really want to know what your exact objections are. Do you see them as lesser wizards? Less human? Both? No one has articulated the precise issue to me. Do you consider me a different race? A different species? Is it a caste issue? I'm just trying to understand."

Rigel could see what it cost the girl to refrain from outright accusing the students around her of ingrained bigotry and irrational prejudice. When Pucey adopted a patronizing expression and began his explanation in the most insulting tone imaginable, it took everything Rigel had not to drop her head into her hands and groan.

"Purebloods and lesser bloods simply don't belong together," Pucey said. He spoke just slowly enough to imply that Hermione must be simple or hard of hearing. "I mean, do you breed roses with wildflowers?"

"What does that have to do with anything?" Hermione's voice was flat and unimpressed.

"A garden must be weeded for the plants that belong to grow healthy and tall. Let the weeds grow in the wild if they must, but they ought not be brought in to infect the garden." Pucey seemed to think he had mustered an impenetrable argument, but Rigel had to suppress an incredulous laugh.

All he'd managed to prove to her was that he had never gardened a day in his life. She leaned forward around Hermione so that Pucey could see the steel in her eyes when she broke into the conversation. "A lot of extremely useful plants grow in the wild, you know. At first sight they don't appear as valuable as common herbs and florae, but in fact the wild ones are much hardier, more likely to cure diseases, and by crossbreeding garden plants with wild ones more variety is achieved, and therefore greater usefulness is gleaned from plants as a whole."

Pucey spluttered, and Hermione added, witheringly, "Every so-called 'garden' plant is just a cultivated version of a plant that once grew wild."

"Well, the useful ones can be grown somewhere else until they're cultivated enough to put in the garden, then." His voice grew in confidence as murmurs of agreement sounded around him. "Just don't introduce them in the garden before they're ready, is all I'm saying."

Rigel openly scoffed. "You think a lot of gardens. In truth, most garden flowers are fairly useless, though, aren't they? Pretty, but poisonous to eat and utterly without redeeming qualities that excuse their delicate constitutions and the extra care required to tend them. Then there are those 'garden plants' that, if grown unchecked, can strangle the garden entirely despite 'belonging' there. No, Pucey, I don't think this is what you're trying to say at all. Quite simply, I think you mean to say that you feel personally disgusted by the idea of consorting with someone of lesser blood. You believe, deep in your gut, that to marry a halfblood would somehow infect you with the stain of the lesser. You're instinctively repulsed by the idea. And that's fine. I doubt you can help it. But you ought to just say so."

She pushed away her plate and gathered her book bag. No one at the table said a word as she stood and left their presence. Hermione and Tahiil retreated as well, just as silently. She tried to feel bad for turning an already awkward conversation into an open attack on her classmates, but she couldn't muster any regret.

"That was very well said," Hermione told her once they'd reached the Entrance Hall. Rigel glanced at her to see if she was being sarcastic, and noticed the girl's lip was bruised where she'd bitten it to keep quiet. It was embarrassing to realize that the AIM girl had more self-control than she did. Rigel had once prided herself on her self-restraint, hadn't she?

"I should not have got so upset," she said, sighing.

"You were filled with conviction, not just anger," Tahiil said. He smiled at her and laid a hand on her shoulder reassuringly. "In such times, it is a disservice to yourself not to speak your mind."

She smiled back weakly. "Thanks, I suppose. I doubt it will make any difference in their opinion, though. And everyone at that table will be just a little less likely to broach that topic with me, which only inhibits my ability to reach them in the long run. No, I should not have said all that. Most days I don't. Lately, though…" Rigel shook her head. "This tournament is getting to me."

"It was designed to get to everyone, I think," Hermione said, frowning. "It's not a coincidence that the legislation you mentioned is coming to light at the same time as the New Triwizard Tournament pits blood categories against one another, is it?"

"No," Rigel said, a slightly hysterical laugh bubbling up in her throat. "No, it isn't."

She excused herself, stalking down into the dungeons with restless strides. She needed to talk to Archie, no matter that it was currently the middle of the night at AIM. She thought she might lose her mind if she didn't talk to someone who understood exactly why the issue was eating away at her insides.

Rigel was nearly jogging with impatience as she reached the common room, and it was a matter of moments to locate the mirror, close her bed curtains, and silence them.

"Harry," she called. Even she could hear the weary desperation in her voice. "Harry, please, are you there?"

"Rigel?" Archie's face—his own, not the twin of hers—swam into focus in the mirror and he blinked at her sleepily from its depths. "What's wrong?"

"Riddle is pushing the marriage law," she blurted. It all came out in a frustration-choked rush. "He's using the time before the tournament is concluded to pass the legislation he'll lose the chance to support if I win. What's worse is that my performance in the tournament is the very thing he's going to use to garner the support to pass it. I've become the wand turned against the people I wanted to help by getting involved in this mess in the first place. Riddle outsmarted me." That was really the crux of the matter, wasn't it? "He wins either way. And all my schoolmates are either supporting the law or against it for exactly the wrong reasons. I have to listen to them disparage my kind, watch the disgust on their faces as they contemplate being bound to people like me, and it's infuriating."

Archie's face had lost its sleepiness, but his voice was still thick as he asked, "Is that all?"

"It that all?" she repeated numbly. "Isn't that bad enough? Or do I have to add in my own bleak future if this law gets passed, not to mention Addy's?"

"I just want to be sure I'm addressing everything when I tell you that it's going to be okay, cuz. I agree that you're in a horrid position, but, well, we always knew you would be, didn't we? It hasn't bothered you so much before." Archie frowned worriedly at her. "Are you sure there isn't anything else? I'm afraid this tournament may be weighing more heavily on you than you're admitting to me."

Rigel let out a long breath and rubbed at her eyes irritably. "Maybe," she said lowly. "Maybe you're right. It's nothing really new, is it? Except I'm afraid Riddle might actually get his law passed this time."

"Even if he does, you'll be all right," Archie said soothingly. "We're already betrothed. No one can force you into any contract. And besides…" He trailed off, grimacing. "Never mind."

Her eyes narrowed. "What?"

Archie hesitated, bit his lip, then said slowly, "Have you considered that it would actually be a good thing for you if the law passed?"

She felt her eyes widen into an incredulous glare but stilled her tongue just in time. This was Archie. He would not say such a thing flippantly. "What do you mean?" she asked, when she was certain she could give a level tone.

"If the legislation passes, any halfblood betrothed or married to a pureblood is automatically afforded equal rights to a pureblood, aren't they?" Archie still sounded reluctant, as though the words were being pulled out of him.

"Yes," she said shortly. "That's what incentivizes halfbloods to go along with it."

"And isn't the biggest danger in our situation that you are a halfblood, and therefore subject to harsher penalties and fewer rights should the ruse be exposed?" Archie grimaced, but forged on to the end. "If the marriage law passes, you'll be in effect a pureblood. That means you can't be sent to Azkaban—can't even be questioned under Veritaserum—in the event that everything we've done for the last three years comes to light. So, in a way, it would be safer for you if the law passed, wouldn't it?"

Rigel's mind raced. She had never thought of it like that before. He was right, though. Somehow, awfully, ironically, if the legislation meant to enhance the inequality in their world did pass, she would be better protected from the consequences of her own actions.

Archie's eyes were pained as he asked, "Would it be so bad then, if we let it pass?"

Her stomach lurched. "Yes, it would. I know what you're saying, Archie, but—I can't. I can't sacrifice the rights and happiness of so many for my own security. If I start to use the advantages given to purebloods for myself, then the Party wins." The words struck a chord deep inside her, and a truth she'd been ignoring for too long reared up and slapped her. "Every minute I spend here, disguised as a pureblood, is a minute the Party wins." She whispered the words, her voice suddenly too weak to give sound to them properly. "Oh, Archie. What have we done?" For a long time, she'd told herself that she was using the pureblood system, playing it. Really, she'd just been playing along.

I am just as culpable as any pureblood, she thought.

In the beginning, she'd rationalized the ruse easily. They weren't hurting anyone, after all. Just getting the education each of them wanted and, she thought, deserved. Somehow, they had crossed a line. If she accepted the passing of the marriage law because of the benefit it bestowed on her as a pureblood's fiancé, however, then the line would be so far in the distance she might never find it again. Maybe they'd messed up from the start, but that didn't mean they couldn't start mitigating. She had to do something. She owed it to every halfblood and muggleborn who wasn't blessed with the means to do as she had.

In a way she felt stupid, actively undermining her own security by deciding to continuously oppose the marriage law. In the end, though, it was simply a question of the kind of person she wanted to be.

"We can't let this law happen," she said firmly.

Archie blew out a breath of relief. "In truth, I didn't want to let it go without a fight, either. I had to say something, though, in case you hadn't thought of that."

"Thanks," she said, meaning it. "It's always better to consider everything, even if it makes the decision harder."

"How's Hermione?" he asked after a moment of silence.

"She's just fine," she assured him. "Stirring things up around the castle, though you probably won't be surprised. Did you know she's researching the Fade?"

"Yeah, she's been on about that for a while," Archie confirmed. "She wants to specialize in perinatal-neonatal Healing."

Rigel grimaced. "I'm not sure I helped her this morning. Probably alienated everyone in Slytherin who might have spoken to her about it." She ran a hand over her face tiredly. "I'll try to make amends later today."

"You don't have to single-handedly do everything," Archie said. A yawn so wide it cracked his jaw interrupted whatever else he was going to say.

"Never mind all this, Arch. Get some sleep. Sorry I woke you," she said.

"You call on me anytime, cuz. Are you doing all right? The first task had you pretty rattled last time we talked." The soft worry in his eyes left an uncomfortable feeling in her chest. She didn't need him worrying about her, too.

"I'm just fine. Promise. Talk to you soon."

"Night."

She slid the mirror underneath her pillow and sighed. For just a brief moment, she tucked her knees into her chest and buried her head in her arms. She was supposed to be reining in her opinions, not getting increasingly worked up at the breakfast table. How many times since the beginning of the year had she lost her temper with her friends? More than the rest of her years at Hogwarts combined, she thought.

Maybe I need another outlet. She didn't always make it to Draco's dueling club as it was, though, so she didn't know when she could find the time for another de-stressing activity. It already felt as though every hour she wasn't spending preparing for the tournament was an hour that actively increased the relative level of risk she would take in the next task. At least, that's how Snape made it seem. She didn't want to think what he'd say to her if he saw her flying aimlessly around the Quidditch pitch on her broom.

Rigel rolled her neck with one last self-indulgent sigh and canceled the silencing spell around her curtains. Immediately, she realized there was someone else in the room, quietly shuffling near the foot of her bed. With a jolt of discomfort that smoothed into wariness as she reminded herself that they couldn't have heard what she was talking about through the silencing spell, Rigel peeled back the curtains and dropped down from the bed.

Draco looked up at her from where he was rummaging in his trunk and stood swiftly. "Rigel. I was just, well…should I come back, or…?" He trailed off, his eyes dipping down across her rumpled clothing before darting over to the curtains and back to her face, awkwardly quick.

"What?" She frowned in confusion at the flush that was creeping up his neck from his collar. She looked back toward the bed, to where her rumpled covers lay innocently behind mostly closed curtains. What was he…? She blinked, whirling her head back around to gape at Draco in surprised embarrassment. "Oh. No. I—no."

She could feel the blush that bloomed across her cheeks like a hot brand, sudden and irrepressible. He thought she'd been…she shook her head at the thought. She could sort of understand how silenced curtains in the middle of the day might be misleading, but at the same time, did he really think she had stormed out of the Great Hall to do that?

Draco's discomfort shifted slowly into amusement as she cleared her throat in acute mortification. She didn't know why she was even embarrassed—she hadn't been doing anything, and even if she was, what business what it of his?—but something about the way Draco's eyes drank in her flushed expression made it all worse. He tilted his head with a slight smile. "You don't have to be embarrassed," he said softly.

"I'm not," she said. Her voice came out thin and breathy, as though she'd just run several miles. "I wasn't—I was just—" She broke off, not quite embarrassed enough to tell him about the mirror.

Her friend went still, eyes focused on something she couldn't see. "Hmm." Dom's mental warning came just then, and she winced against the pain. No kidding, she grumbled internally, belatedly called up her Occlumency as Draco openly scrutinized her emotions.

"Stop reading me," she said, scowling. "There's nothing there."

"I wouldn't say 'nothing.'" He chuckled, eyes skating across her still-present flush. He lifted a hand to her cheek, almost absently touching the heat there. When had he moved so close? The feel of his fingers against her face summoned more warmth from her stomach, and she inhaled sharply. Knocked from whatever trance had momentarily taken hold of her, Rigel whirled away to grab her book bag.

"I—have to go brew," she lied, keeping her head determinedly down, eyes fixed anywhere but into Draco's stormy grey.

"Rigel, wait." Draco called after her as she darted for the door, but she kept going.

She knew if she made it to the common room, he wouldn't make a scene. If he was even going to. She didn't know what to make of him at the moment. He wasn't…was he? First Leo, now Draco. No, she thought stubbornly, shaking her head to rid it of such a ridiculous thought. Draco had never indicated any of that sort of interest in Rigel. He was probably just poking fun at her embarrassment.

Even knowing that, her cheeks didn't cool until she was safely cloistered in her lab. She pushed the odd encounter forcefully from her mind; she'd rather think about how phoenix tears might be used as an amplifying ingredient in potent healing potions. In fact, she might have to think about that all morning and most of the afternoon.

That evening, Rigel finally got around to the genealogy section of the library. She still felt there was something off about Riddle. It was time to arm herself with facts.

It only took a few hours to confirm what she'd already deduced: there were no Wizarding records of a Riddle family in Britain. Since she'd never heard anyone suggest Riddle might be foreign, she turned her attention to the one thing she knew for certain about the man. Riddle was a Parselmouth. If she assumed that he'd come by the gift honestly, then he must have a connection to the Peverell family somewhere, just as she did through the Potters.

The Peverells were an old family, but theirs was a tree twisted with tragedy, and there weren't actually many branches left by the twentieth century. The Peverells were entirely extinct in the male line. The only two families with noted connections in a tome from the end of the nineteenth century were the Potters and the Gaunts.

She'd never heard of the House of Gaunt. They weren't mentioned at all in the most recent editions of the books of Gold, Silver, and Bronze. Had they died out in the last century? Or was there some other reason the family had faded into obscurity?

Frustrated by the dead end, Rigel tried tracing Slytherin House instead, since so many of Riddle's followers were convinced he held some secret claim to that lordship. Slytherin's line was descendent from the Peverells maternally, which was how the famous wizard had been blessed with the serpent tongue, but Parseltongue alone couldn't prove the relation in Rigel's eyes. Not when she knew the Peverells had left non-Slytherin branches as well. Riddle couldn't claim that Lordship unless he came from Slytherin's male issue. The Hogwarts founder had never been prolific, and it wasn't long before she found the surname Gaunt in his family tree as well. The Gaunts had a double claim to Parseltongue, then. She reluctantly traced the family's tree further, closer and closer to the modern day.

The family seemed to split at some point, with Rionach Gaunt's daughter journeying to America in the seventeenth century, where she would go on to found the Ilvermorny School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. That secondary branch never returned to Britain, but the titled branch, which the author of Founder's Legacy: Heirs and Heirlooms had painstaking traced, went as far as Corvinus Gaunt, who was confirmed a student in the Hogwarts registry in the eighteenth century.

With both Peverell and Slytherin lines dead-ending in the House of Gaunt, it was more than likely Riddle was connected to the family. The only alternative was Riddle coming from an unknown branch on the Potters' side of the Peverell tree. She shuddered at the thought.

Rigel stretched out her neck as she began stacking the books she no longer needed for re-shelving. It was nearly curfew, but she still had several more books she wanted to check. She cleared away her workspace, found a secluded isle and, after ensuring that nobody could see her, drew out her Invisibility Cloak.

Hidden from prefects and librarians alike, Rigel found an older version of the Book of Gold, this one from the middle of the eighteenth century, and there she found Corvinus Gaunt again, this time listed in possession of the lordship of the House of Gaunt. His son was listed below him, and in the next two editions of the Book of Gold, she found his grandson and great-grandson, too. That was where the line seemed to end, however. The Hogwarts library didn't have every edition of the Book of Gold—it was published every five years, but the genealogy section only had editions marking every twenty-five years, likely to save space. In 1925, the House of Gaunt was extant in the person of Marvolo Gaunt, but in 1950, the family was dropped from the Book of Gold without explanation.

Anything could have happened in those fifty years. The heirs might all have died. The lordship could have been withdrawn for legal reasons or transferred to another family through marriage. Normally, however, the lordship would still be listed in that case, with the transfer made plain. It was odd that the family simply disappeared. She looked back in the 1925 Book of Gold and frowned. Marvolo Gaunt had two children. A son, Morfin Gaunt, who should have taken over the lordship, and a daughter, Merope.

Merope was the first daughter in several generations. If Riddle had been descendant from the male line, his last name would be Gaunt. Merope was the only candidate in recent history to have passed on both Peverell and Slytherin genes to an alternate family name. Born in 1907, she should have been a student at Hogwarts by 1919 at the latest. When Rigel made her way over to the school records, however, there was no Merope Gaunt to be found.

A squib, maybe. Or else she'd been schooled abroad. There was no record of Morfin Gaunt at Hogwarts, either. The family was still in Britain in 1925, however, or Marvolo Gaunt wouldn't have retained the lordship at that time. Was it possible both children had been squibs? That would certainly disqualify the family from the Book of Gold. It might also explain why Riddle never claimed an open connection to them. He didn't exactly hide it, though, did he? His middle name was Marvolo, she recalled with dawning certainty. She'd looked it up herself in second year. It couldn't be sheer coincidence.

She had one last avenue of attack, though she was reluctant to take it. The library kept copies of the Daily Prophet for posterity, but there were so many issues of the paper they were actually nestled in undetectable expansion charms in the relevant stacks. It would probably take her weeks, possibly months, to go through the ones from 1925 to 1950 one at a time, and she didn't know any magic that would speed the process.

May as well start tonight, she thought, resigned. The mystery would only eat at her otherwise. The Book of Gold was published in April, so she began with May, 1925. Most of the headlines were utterly mind-numbing. It was at once amusing and depressing to realize that all the problems of modern society had been persistent for at least three-quarters of a century. Corruption, crime, and scandal blared up at her from the faded pages, in between routine human interest pieces and Quidditch scores.

As the night wore on, she realized it was going to take much longer than a few weeks at the rate she was going. She'd only reached September, 1925, and her eyes had already begun to droop. With a sigh of defeat, she promised herself sleep after finishing the expanded box she was arm-deep in.

Then, almost unfathomably, she found it. FATHER AND SON SENTENCED SIMULTANEOUSLY. HOUSE OF GAUNT NO MORE! Her eyes, now wide with alertness, skimmed the article with mounting perturbation.

Marvolo Gaunt found guilty of child abuse and obstruction of justice…stripped of lordship…son declared clinically insane…facing six months and three years in Azkaban prison respectively.

The once ancient House's remaining issue, Miss Merope Gaunt, is currently unlocatable, this according to Ministry officials assigned to collect her from the Gaunt residence in Little Hangleton for the trial. Marvolo Gaunt declared his daughter a squib, which disallows her the option to inherit the lordship herself. Without a declared heir, the House of Gaunt will join many other pureblood families in noble extinction.

That answered the question of the Book of Gold. The House of Gaunt was declared extinct after the disqualification of both Lord and Heir for criminal behavior and mental unfitness. Merope had been declared a squib by her own father, thus prohibiting her from taking up the mantle in his absence, and the young woman had apparently disappeared after her father and brother were taken into custody.

Rigel returned the newspapers to their stacks, her mind spinning with the implications. She was almost positive Riddle was the son of Merope Gaunt. His family, while ancient and pure, was also disgraced, plagued with the stain of insanity and squibhood, whether the allegations were true or not. To take up the mantle of Slytherin's name, Riddle would also have to claim the sordid Gaunt family history.

Then there was the fact that she'd seen no Merope née Gaunt in any of the modern books of Gold, Silver, or Bronze. Merope Gaunt had never married into any of the established families. That could only mean one of two things: that Riddle was born out of wedlock—a scandal all its own, which would disqualify him from inheriting the Gaunt Family title regardless, much less the Slytherin lordship—or that Riddle's father wasn't a pureblood.

In either case, it was obvious why Riddle had never tried to publicly claim to be Slytherin's Heir. Instead, he hinted at it behind closed doors, gave just enough justification to keep people from looking too closely. Who would be inclined to disbelieve polite, attractive Tom Riddle? Riddle, whose magic hung around him in a cloak of sheer power, Riddle, who spoke Parseltongue and whose brilliant mind and perfect manners kept him always beyond reproach.

Rigel scowled as she stalked out of the library under her Invisibility Cloak. Maybe everyone else was falling for it, but she refused to be impressed.

The next time she saw Hermione, she decided, she would ask the girl to help her post a muggle letter to the public records office in Little Hangleton. If she pretended to be an estranged relation looking for family connections, she might be able to find some evidence of where Riddle had acquired his distinctly muggle surname.

With an admittedly vindictive smile on her face, Rigel crept into the Slytherin common room and slid off the Invisibility Cloak. The fires were low, and even the most dedicated of NEWT students had long gone to bed. It was only when she drew even with the cluster of chairs and couches that surrounded the fireplace closest to the fourth-year dorms that she saw him.

Draco was fast asleep on the couch closest to the fire, a troubled frown marring his otherwise smooth complexion. Rigel paused, tempted to simply continue to her room and pretend she hadn't seen the boy. She was too exhausted to deal with him. Then she sighed. He'd probably tried to wait up for her. They had left things somewhat…strange, that morning.

She told herself there was no use avoiding her best friend forever. It had probably been a misunderstanding. Rigel tucked her cloak away in her bag and reached out a hand to shake Draco gently by the shoulder.

The blond boy murmured disgruntledly, but didn't wake.

"Dray," she said softly. "Come on, you can't sleep here."

"Rye?" Draco's face scrunched in unconscious complaint before he blinked sleepy eyes open and fixed them blearily her way. "What time's it?"

"Time for bed," she said vaguely. "Here, let's get you up." She began to bustle him into a standing position. He took several slow steps toward the dorm before stumbling to a halt.

"Wait," he murmured, shaking his head sharply. "I was waiting for you. I wanted to talk to you." He pulled his arm from her helpful grasp and reversed the grip, at once pulling her to a stop beside him and stepping too close. His breath stirred her fringe with the gentlest of breezes. When had he grown so tall, exactly? "You ran off earlier." His voice was still thick with sleep, but the words were growing increasingly articulate. "I didn't mean to make you run."

"I just remembered something I had to do," she said quietly. Her eyes trailed down to the side, neither toward him nor away, exactly.

"I went to your lab. The door was locked."

"Was it?" She cleared her throat. "Well, we can talk about it tomorrow. It's late."

Draco shook his head with a grimace. "I want to say it now. Rigel, you're my best friend. I wouldn't—I didn't mean to make it weird."

Rigel cursed the fluttering in her belly. Somehow, the soft feelings swimming around inside her at the vaguely defined question of what, exactly, Draco meant were enough to strangle her courage completely. She didn't ask him how he felt about her. She didn't think she wanted to know. Didn't know what answer she would prefer. Instead, she stole a glance up at him and said faintly, cowardly, "It's not weird. We're good."

Her friend's face, so familiar to her, was alien in that moment. She knew those eyes, those cheekbones, that mouth. Yet in that moment she couldn't read his expression at all. "Do you…forgive me?"

"Of course," she said without hesitation. She would willingly pretend the electric moment between them had never happened.

"I wonder," Draco whispered. He leaned toward her, his eyes so intent with unspoken possibilities she found herself caught between contrary impulses. Part of her wanted to back away, but the other part was caught in a breathless curiosity. She stared back at him, as though she might discern the nuances of his motivations if she could only untangle the emotions in his eyes. "How far will your forgiveness extend, Rigel?"

She knew what he was going to do—it was obvious, really—and the shock was no excuse for what she didn't do. She didn't pull away, didn't twist her head. She held very still and let him kiss her.

It was the barest of pressure, his lips against hers. The softest of sighs, hers or his, she wasn't sure. Her eyes dipped against the feeling without conscious effort, but when his hand came up to graze the smooth skin of her neck she gasped and retreated, reason flooding back into her brain at last.

She stared up at him in slowly dawning horror. "Oh, Dray. We can't. I can't. I'm sorry." What had she been thinking? Where had careful, deliberate Rigel gone and who was this hormone-inflamed psycho who'd taken over her body? Was she really so tired that she'd let her guard down completely? And what did it say that, when she let herself, this was how she acted around her closest friend?

Draco's expression was still soft as he gazed down at her. She wondered if he felt as dazed and confused as she did. "Was it so wrong, Rigel? I know you feel this, too."

Irritation rose up over the embarrassment and fear and she clung to it with both hands. "Don't read me. It isn't fair."

"How else am I to know? You never show your true feelings." Draco was frowning now, hurt creeping into his tone.

"My feelings are irrelevant. Listen to my words, Draco. This can't happen again." Rigel took two steps backwards, pointedly firming her stance as she reclaimed her space.

He narrowed his eyes at her, visibly gathering himself. "If that's what you want."

"It is."

The words nearly choked her. She had no idea what she wanted. What did it matter? The only thing that mattered, all that ever had, was the ruse. Whatever was hanging in the air between them like a siren's call, it could not be allowed to grow stronger. She couldn't afford any distractions, now of all times, and Draco could not afford to tangle his heart up in hers, regardless of whether he knew it or not.

"Fine, then. Goodnight, Rigel." Draco turned and strode down the hallway with measured steps, the firm line of his back an argument against any concern she might have that his feelings were hurt or his pride irredeemably shattered.

He would be fine, she told herself. They would be fine. In the morning, all of this would seem like a nonsensical dream. She gave her friend ten minutes before following him to their dorm room. Sneaking through the darkness, trying not to listen to the sound of his breathing, she felt like the worst sort of coward. No matter how many times she repeated to herself that she'd done the right thing, for both of them, she couldn't drown the self-reproach that crawled its way into her chest. Weary and regretful, she fell into an uneasy sleep.

She spent Sunday morning in her lab. She told herself she'd meant to work on a few things for Krait in any case, and that she wasn't hiding from Draco. He'd pretended nothing was wrong that morning at breakfast, but his coolly polite demeanor only made the churning in her own stomach more confusing.

The second task was only a week away. She couldn't afford any distractions. That was the mantra that echoed in her mind as she took out the ingredients to an emotion suppression potion and stared at them. It would be easy, and take her no time at all. All the poorly defined emotions swirling around inside her would go away, calmed beneath the blanket of magical control. Occlumency could help her conceal them, but it didn't prevent her from feeling.

Only the fear that emotions, like magic, might somehow get stronger when repressed stopped her from brewing a double batch then and there. As disturbing as her new, unwanted awareness of Draco was, it might be best to let it eat at her until it ran out of steam.

She set the ingredients aside. Rigel knew she could always change her mind later, if the odd tension between her and Draco became too disrupting.

After a peaceful lunch with Binny in the kitchens, in which she attempted to listen more closely to the elf's explanations of human-French grammar, Rigel made her way to lab three for yet another non-potions-related lesson with Snape.

Her Head of House must have noticed the resigned, cheerless set of her face when she trudged into the lab, as he adopted a long-suffering expression and said, "Don't pout, Rigel. It's unbecoming of a Slytherin."

"I'm not," she said, aware that this only made her sound more put out. What did he expect? She couldn't pretend to be happy about the direction her apprenticeship had taken.

"Have you kept the projection ability up all week?"

"Today is my last day," she confirmed quickly, hope rising irrepressibly in her chest.

Snape considered her for a long moment before inclining his head. "Then, after the second task, we will begin freebrewing."

"After?" Rigel frowned, mildly outraged.

"There will be plenty of time after," Snape said firmly. "It's important that you do well in this task."

"Why this one in particular?" she asked. "Aren't they all important?"

"It will cement your supremacy at the top of the pureblood category if you outperform both Krum and Shang in the second task," Snape explained. The frown above his gaze told her she should have already worked this out for herself. "Then, regardless of how far you make it in the third task, there will be a strong argument for your being chosen as the pureblood champion."

She mulled that over for a moment before saying, "What about after Yule? Is Riddle so confident that I can beat whoever wins out in the other two categories?"

Snape's face closed, and Rigel's eyes narrowed. There was something there, she knew. Her professor proved unwilling to speculate further, however, as the dark-haired man swept across the lab with a flourish and changed the subject. "We've been covering counteractive magic the last several lessons."

"I've noticed," she said dryly. It hadn't been hard to deduce that whatever the second task was, it involved counteracting spells, wards, and curses. That was all Snape had emphasized since the first task's conclusion.

Snape was not amused by her levity. "Then you'll be well-prepared for today's test." He produced a small box from his robes and laid it on the counter. Rigel approached slowly to look it over. The wooden cube looked innocuous enough, but she'd learned in the last few lessons that the most dangerous wards and curses were supposed to look harmless. That was how they caught a witch or wizard unprepared. "You have fifteen minutes to open this without destroying its contents."

Rigel nodded and took out her wand. A general revealing charm produced no reaction. She cast Alohomora and immediately had to shield herself from a roiling bolt of magic that shot out at her from the box. It now glowed an ominous red, and subsequent attempts to get a spell through its little red aura failed and fizzled upon contact. Sometimes the spells she tried prompted an attack, and sometimes the box simply sat there.

She paused in her casting to consider a different approach. One of the principles Snape had been attempting to teach her was that most protections were focused in certain directions. A ward, Snape said, was often like a bridge. A bridge can withstand an enormous amount of force—from certain directions. Bridges are designed to hold immense weight before collapsing, because carrying weight it what a bridge does, and sometimes a bridge can withstand sudden stress from the side, if the builder was very clever and anticipated storms or earthquakes. Very few bridges, on the other hand, are intended to bear load from below. A proportionately small amount of force can crack a bridge from beneath, when the same amount of power applied from any other direction wouldn't shake it.

Most wards were like bridges, because they'd been designed to keep something in or something out, but rarely had protections focused in both directions.

Maybe the box was like a bridge, too. Rigel tucked her wand away and placed her hand on the counter next to the box. After a glance at Snape, she thought better of that, and wandlessly levitated the box onto the ground, instead. Kneeling, she laid the palm of her hand against the stone floor beside it and channeled her magic into the flagstone.

The stone slid away from the box in ripples, and the box, after a moment's silent resistance, broke apart as portions of wood were pulled into the void left in the stone beneath it. When it fell still, the wooden box was melded to the floor, all four sides warped beyond its intended shape. With its structural integrity went the integrity of the magic sustaining its protections, and Rigel was able to pry the lid off with relative ease. She pulled out a bright blue robin's egg and grinned.

Snape stared down at her, eyebrows raised. "What, precisely, was that, Rigel? We haven't covered transfiguration as a destabilizing technique."

"It's something Professor Dumbledore taught me," she said, rising from her crouch with the egg in her hand. She realized after hefting it that it wasn't a real egg; it was a hollowed shell and light as a feather.

"Alchemy without runes?" Snape's thoughtful gaze slid from the box to Rigel's face.

"It's a bit like wandless magic," she offered. "Instead of the runes there to shape the reaction, you have to guide it with will. The amount of raw magic required in the technique makes it prohibitive to complex reactions, but for simple stuff it's a lot faster than drawing out the runic array. The more runes you omit, though, the more individual shaping intents you have to replace with your own will."

He lowered his lids sharply. "You mean to say that it requires simultaneously projecting multiple, separate intents in your mind as you cast?"

She nodded. "Exactly. It's kind of tricky to conceptualize, but Occlumency helps. I can cast while holding six or seven separate shaping ideas at once, provided they aren't too contradictory. It helps that most runes in a single array will be complementary."

"Incredible," he breathed. "What else can you do with it?"

"Besides fusing adjacent things, I can light a fire, dissolve most substances into particulate matter, and do basic phase shifts—water into ice, that sort of thing." She was pretty proud of how quickly she'd managed to apply the most basic of concepts discussed in Dumbledore's supplementary textbook. It helped that shorthand alchemy was a combination of several other skills she already possessed. In fact, it was sort of like shaped imbuing, only with multiple spells at once.

"Can you undo it?" he asked, eyeing the box again.

She winced. "Not really. I could separate it from the floor, but the portions of wood that have been melded with the stone won't un-meld without painstaking arrays."

He didn't look terribly pleased that his floor was now marred, but she thought he ought to be glad she had the foresight not to ruin the counter, at least.

Snape had her practice several more shorthand alchemical reactions, this time with materials of his choosing, before declaring himself satisfied with her efforts for the day.

"You promise we'll start freebrewing as soon as the second task is over?" Rigel checked. She didn't want to leave without confirmation of that much, at least.

Her Head of House sneered at her, amusement in his black eyes. "Do you even remember how to brew? It's been so long since I've supervised you. Perhaps we ought to start with a Boil Cure, just in case."

She glared at him, but then a thought struck her and she frowned. "Actually, sir. There is something lately… I've over-brewed a number of potions without meaning to. Does that happen to potioneers as they become more capable?"

"Quite the opposite," Snape said flatly. "Have you been imbuing too much magic?"

She shook her head. "Same as always. It's automatic for most potions, now. I haven't had to actually check for a while, but lately when I do check, there's too much magic in the potions, even though I haven't imbued any longer than usual."

Snape pressed his lips together in displeasure. "Your rate of imbuing should not be noticeably faster, unless, of course, you've been repressing your magic again and it has grown stronger."

Rigel shook her head quickly. "I haven't."

"Have you changed your ingredient source?"

"No."

Snape evidently did not believe her, as he held out his hand expectantly. "Your kit."

She pulled it out of her book bag with a sigh. The potions master extracted a few ingredients at random and bent his attention toward them with a scowl. He let them fall to the table almost at once. "These are brimming with superfluous magic, Rigel. Where did you get them? The Forbidden Forest?"

"The same apothecaries as always," she told him, utterly bewildered.

Snape began to pace the lab, stalking slowly as he turned the problem over in his mind. After a few minutes he stopped and grimaced. "You've been practicing your magical awareness with your kit on you."

She blinked. "Yes," she said slowly. "I always have it one me. You think my magic interacted with the ingredients when I projected it out around me?" She hoped not. She really didn't want to have to replace everything in her kit. It was countless Galleons worth of ingredients.

"It is likely that you lose small amounts of magic to the air when you practice the sensing technique. Over time, with repeat exposure, the ingredients have been slowly absorbing it. With more potent ingredients than usual, the amount of magic you're used to imbuing will saturate the brew. You're lucky none of these ingredients have become unstable." Snape looked satisfied with the explanation. He raised his eyebrows at her, as though inviting her to challenge him with some other problem.

All she could think about, though, was Matheus Sousa. "I lent him the salvia," she muttered in horror. She could feel the blood drain away from her cheeks.

"Come again?" Snape demanded.

She groaned. "Sousa. Before the first task. He was looking for salvia and I gave him some of mine, but it was probably saturated, too! What if it's my fault he failed the first task?"

"There's nothing you can do now," Snape said, sounding unconcerned.

"I can apologize," she murmured, scowling. She hated to think that she was the reason the boy had wound up insensate in a forest full of dangerous creatures, but it made sense. Divination potions were incredibly delicate, as any mind-altering potion would be, and an imbalance in magic that stressed the properties of salvia divinorum would certainly be enough to tip the effects of such a brew closer to 'comatose' than 'enlightened.'

"Don't admit to anything in haste," Snape cautioned her.

She wasn't really listening. She had to find Sousa now and apologize, and possibly warn him against using any more of the too-potent salvia.

"Thanks for the lesson, Professor. I've got to go."

He called after her, but she hastened out of the lab to find an out-of-the-way alcove. Once alone, she dug out the Marauder's Map and scanned it methodically for the dot she needed. 'Matheus Sousa' hovered near the edge of the Forbidden Forest, and Rigel sighed with relief. She'd rather sort this out immediately than dwell on it until she saw the boy again.

It was late afternoon, and the trees at the very edge of the forest seemed utterly unremarkable, leaves shifting innocently in the chilly winter breeze, as though they hadn't housed the terrors that still brought a feeling of panicked foreboding even though she wasn't planning on re-entering the forest anytime soon.

Treeslider poked his head out of her pocket with a tentative flick of his tongue. "You are bringing me home, Ssspeaker?"

Rigel frowned. She'd grown quite used to the comforting weight of the snake dozing in her pocket or curled in her lap over the last week. Her professors had all been incredibly lenient with his presence, probably more out of pity than any real desire to tolerate an exception to the rules about acceptable pets, and Rigel had no desire to release the boomslang snake into the wild again when he'd only just woken up from his Healing sleep a few days ago.

"Only if you desssire to return. You may stay will me asss long asss you wisssh." She put a warming charm on him wandlessly, and told herself she wasn't bribing him to stay with her. A chill wouldn't be good for the cold-blooded creature while he was still on the mend.

Treeslider peered up at her in silent contemplation before retreating into her pocket with a contented hiss. "Ssspeaker needsss looking after," he added quietly from the depths of her robes.

Pleased that he wasn't eager to go back to the forest, Rigel took out the Map again and followed the edge of the forest around behind Hagrid's hut, where she found Sousa lying on his belly, his head pillowed in a bed of wild clover. To all appearances he was simply taking a nap, but Rigel found herself hurrying toward him in concern, nonetheless.

The dark-haired boy shifted his head as her footsteps crunched across the dry grass. His shaggy hair flopped back to reveal a considering eye that followed her approach curiously. When she stopped a couple feet from his prone form, Sousa let out a gusty sigh and flopped over on his back.

"It is the boy with plants in his pocket," he remarked. His arms reached up in an indolent stretch before coming to rest behind his head. "You are come to rain green gifts on me?"

Rigel grimaced. "I actually came to ask you about the sage I gave you. I think there may have been something wrong with it."

"The salvia?" He raised his eyebrows at her. "Good stuff. I didn't guess it so good."

"It was over-saturated with magic, I think," she admitted, frowning down at his unconcerned expression. She felt decidedly awkward standing over him while they had a conversation. "It may have made whatever you brewed with it too strong."

He nodded slowly. "Good stuff. You have more?"

"More?" She struggled against the impulse to splutter. "I'm worried I accidentally poisoned you."

"I can handle it," he assured her. An amused smile tugged at the edges of his lips. "I make no mistakes in potions."

Rigel pressed her lips together. "You never know, Sousa. Maybe you're misusing it somehow. I could look at your recipe if you like."

It was odd to realize that someone could look patronizing while they were lying at her feet, but Sousa managed it with effortless enjoyment. "Just ask," he told her, eyes alight with mischief.

"Fine. Did you intentionally dose yourself with a mind-altering potion during the first task?" She felt bad voicing the question, but the Brazilian boy was deliberately egging her toward this blunt engagement.

"Yes."

"I—you did?" Rigel shook her head, uncomprehending. "But why?"

Sousa sighed, letting his eyes drift away from her troubled expression, up toward the golden afternoon sky. "I am not angry, if you fear it. Your salvia is very strong, but it did not ruin my potion."

"You can't have meant to leave yourself so vulnerable during the task," she argued. Why she was arguing against his own self-proclaimed motivations, she didn't know. It just didn't seem possible that anyone could be so reckless, or so utterly blasé about such an ignoble use of potions ingredients.

"I never had so intense a high," he said. His voice was smooth and low, as though fondly recalling a treasured memory.

Rigel could feel a frustrated scowl creeping its way across her face. "Why did you enter the tournament if you weren't going to take it seriously? You could have got yourself or someone else killed."

A shadow crossed Sousa's face for the first time. "I did not enter," he said, his voice clipped.

She felt her irritation wither on the vine. Sousa, too? That made three of them, then, if she included Tahiil. "Were you recruited?" she asked, sinking to her knees on the ground beside him. "Tahiil was, too."

Sousa looked mildly interested in that fact, but shook his head. "My school gave them my name. The school board wanted rid of me for a year. They say if I want to stay enrolled next year, I have no choice."

"That's horrid," she murmured. "No one should be forced into a competition like this."

"It is not all bad. I have more time for my research this year with no classes."

"And what are you researching?" she asked, curious despite herself.

A tranquil smile bloomed on his face and he looked up at her with rapture in his eyes. "Euphoria."

Rigel huffed a laugh despite herself. "Right. Well, try not to get yourself killed with my ingredients, Sousa."

"Matheus, please," he said cajolingly. "You mean not to give me more salvia?"

"Not on your life," she said sweetly. Rigel rose and dusted her knees. "Good luck in the next task."

"You as well. Really," he added at her rueful look. "You make an odd face when you win. It is funny."

She left him to his relaxation and trekked steadily back toward the castle, her thoughts awhirl. How many of them were really in the tournament by choice? Rigel had her own reasons for participating, of course. Tahiil was grateful to be here, but hadn't sought it out. Sousa had been entered as a way to foist him away from Castelobruxo for a year. Delacour had hinted that her Headmistress strongly influenced her decision to participate, and Shang had as much as admitted that she was there as a junior diplomat, tasked to raise awareness of the power and skill of the Middle Kingdom's magical community.

That left Krum, Antiope, Owens, and Hermione as the only champions here to compete for themselves. Even Hermione had a bigger reason for competing, though—she wanted to prove to the world that muggleborns should be taken seriously and treated as equals.

Rigel had to wonder whether Riddle knew that Sousa had been entered in bad faith. She also wondered why Tahiil had been recruited, when there were plenty of muggleborns around the world who'd probably thrown their hats into the ring. Maybe he didn't want the best candidates worldwide. Riddle liked to prove his points on his terms, after all.

And I'm helping him do it, she thought morosely. The cloud of self-recrimination had been descending regularly since her mother's letter. She knew she wouldn't be able to live with the guilt if she helped to pass the very legislation she was competing to quash. She just didn't know what she would do about it, yet.

Much too soon, the morning of the second task was upon her. Because Riddle wanted the first three tasks completed before Yule, there was just two weeks between each of them. Once the final three champions were decided, the tasks would be spread more generously over the Spring term. For now, though, it felt as though she'd barely caught her breath from the first task when the last Sunday in November dawned clear and cold.

Rigel spooned porridge mechanically into her mouth as chatter and speculation flew in convoluted arcs over her head. She was attempting to keep an even emotional keel that morning. She didn't know exactly what the second task would entail, but she did know it was to take place on the Quidditch pitch. No forest meant it couldn't possibly be as bad as the first task.

"Cheer up, Rigel," Theo said bracingly. "At least you don't have to wait around all day this time. It'll be over by dinnertime."

He was right. The task was scheduled to begin after lunch, which left her with only five hours to fret. That was nothing, really.

The morning post was normally accompanied by a flurry of noise, as students exclaimed over packages from home, admonished owls for nipping bacon off their plates, and generally reveled in the distraction from daily life. That morning, however, the usual roar cut off almost abruptly, choked by shock and fear that was delivered to their tables on indifferent wings.

She lifted her head from her bowl as the Slytherins around her grew silent and still. Her eyes met Millicent's across the table, and the solidly built girl's face was drawn with coiled tension. She, Pansy, and Blaise all had copies of the Daily Prophet.

"What's happened?" she asked quietly.

Eyes dropped to the side and no one offered the paper immediately. Rigel's eyes widened and her breath caught. It wasn't her family. It couldn't be.

Seeing the alarm in Rigel's eyes, Pansy leant over and offered the paper with a murmured, "It's no one you know."

Only slightly relieved, she took the paper with stiff fingers and flipped it over to read the headline. She didn't even get that far. The snake-eating skull glared up at her in moving black-and-white. Beneath it, a building lay in ruins.

MUGGLEBORN OUTREACH CENTER LEVELED

In the dark hours of Sunday morning, the London Center for Muggleborn Outreach, a charitable organization run by the Dumbledore Foundation, was attacked. Believed to be the work of violent extremists, the collapse of the offices from which dozens of muggleborns are contacted every year occurred after repeated exposure to Fiendfyre irreparably damaged the foundations.

As of this printing, one woman has been found dead and several others injured in the rubble. The deceased, Arabella Doreen Figg, was a registered squib and long-time employee of the Dumbledore Foundation. She and three other magically challenged individuals lived above the outreach center and were caught in the attack as they slept.

Aurors have contained the scene and Obliviators were called upon to modify multiple memories of muggles who witnessed the magical fire in action. A Dark Arts expert, who wishes to remain nameless, explains that Fiendfyre would normally be expected to incinerate much more than the foundations of a single building when unleashed. "Either the attackers are very sophisticated users of the Dark Arts and have exceptional control, or these vigilantes aren't powerful enough to summon full-fledged Fiendfyre at all."

The Center for Muggleborn Outreach was founded to educate British muggleborns about the magical world, and to provide assistance in applying to alternative magical schools in the wake of the pivotal 1981 decision to limit Hogwarts acceptance to pureblood magical children only. When asked previously how the organization goes about contacting these children, most of whom would have no idea otherwise that they are in fact witches and wizards, Albus Dumbledore, Headmaster of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, has said that he allows his charity access to the school's ancient registry, which automatically tracks the births of all magical children within Great Britain's shores.

"No matter what laws come to pass, Hogwarts still calls to them."

The perpetrators of this grievous act are still at large, and are believed to be associated with the same group of anti-muggle extremists who conducted a similar attack on Novus Industries in late October.

For more on the activities of the Dumbledore Foundation, page 3. For more on previous attacks by this extremist group, page 8.

Rigel pushed the paper back toward Pansy with a mute nod. She glanced toward the Head Table and saw that Dumbledore's seat was conspicuously empty. She wondered if he'd known Arabella Figg well.

She wasn't going to eat anything else, so she rose from the table and said, "I'll be in the common room."

On her way out of the Great Hall, she was waylaid by Professor Snape.

"A word, Rigel."

She followed him down the hall, out of the way of curious passersby. "Yes, Professor?"

"The tournament organizers will be inventorying the items carried on a champion's person before the second task," he informed her. "If you've anything you don't want examined, I suggest you leave it in your dorm."

"They didn't do that last time," she said, frowning.

"Last time you nearly burnt down the forest," Snape drawled. "Did you imagine they'd let you do that twice?"

She felt her lips twist in dark amusement. "I suppose not. Thanks for the warning, sir."

He inclined his head. "Naturally." The Potions Master swept off, leaving her to mentally list the things she needed to take out of her bag before heading down to the pitch.

It was moments like this she really appreciated being in Slytherin House. None of the other Heads of House would stop to think she might have something she didn't want to be discovered if her pockets were unexpectedly turned out.

In the end, she removed her Invisibility Cloak, the Marauder's Map, all the correspondence that was tucked into her potions kit, and a number of questionable brews that were still in the experimental stage. She also left behind the Mandrake leaves swimming damningly in their vials of spit. There really weren't any innocent explanations for trying to become an animagus without telling anyone.

She kept the Fire Free Sirius had given her, as well as Lily's Dark Defense Disk and the emergency beacon from her friends. She doubted they'd even notice the last one. The last thing she had to figure out was what to do with Treeslider; she didn't want him in the task with her.

When she brought the lethargic snake out of her pocket in the common room later that morning, Blaise volunteered to keep him for the day. She smiled in genuine gratitude as she transferred the snake to Blaise's waiting arms, with a whispered promise of mice if he behaved. Blaise was the least excitable of her friends, and she told herself that Treeslider would be fine with him until she could take him back.

Rigel had lunch in the kitchens, with only Draco and Pansy to keep her company as she attempted to center herself for the trial ahead. Draco outlined his plan for the next Dueling Club and Pansy described her latest suitor from the continent in devastating detail.

"Why do you let your parents set you up with such buffoons?" Draco asked, wrinkling his nose. "I told my mother not to even think about matchmaking until I left school."

Pansy allowed a rare, patronizing expression to cross her face. "And when she does, you'll have a dozen offers before you can say 'I'm a catch.' Some of us have to think ahead."

"You're a catch, too," he protested. Realizing how that sounded, he added, "I mean—you know what I mean."

"You're the son of two ancient houses, Drake, your father effectively runs the Ministry of Magic, and most important of all you are under no obligation to marry young."

"You shouldn't be either," Rigel said firmly. "Pansy, you have your whole life to marry."

"It's not the marriage," Pansy said quietly. "It's the children. You both ought to open your eyes. Pureblood women have a responsibility to the next generation, and births are becoming more and more difficult. Many believe starting younger and waiting longer between each child is the key to better odds at survival."

"What?" Rigel hadn't known that. "When did this idea come about?"

"It's relatively recent," Pansy admitted. "I've heard it whispered more than once of late that girls should be getting on with it sooner, rather than later. The point is that I have a pressure to procreate that you boys simply don't. It's not your fault, but it means I have to consider my future now."

"That's barbaric," Draco said flatly. "It isn't the Middle Ages."

"Is there any substantiating evidence for starting younger?" Rigel asked.

Pansy shrugged. "I don't think so. People are getting desperate, though. Isn't it strange that there are six dorm rooms in our hallway and only four are being used?"

"What are you saying? The population's declined that much?" Draco frowned, pushing away his kidney pie. "I reckon…there are a lot of families with only a single branch remaining."

"That's a long-term trend, though," Rigel pointed out. "Pureblood families by definition can't grow the way other populations do—the pool of potential partners just isn't that large. Eventually, families merge and old names die out."

"It was fine when families were having at least two children, but these days…I think we're reaching a critical point," Pansy said, her eyes tight. "No one wants to admit it, but I saw an article in Arithmancy Today in my father's study this summer. The calculations don't look good for the future of pureblood society. We need more children."

They needed to stop being pureblood, Rigel thought cynically. The problem might be a simple as expanding the gene pool.

They were interrupted by Binny coming to clear their dishes. The house-elf patted Rigel's arm with a tutting noise as she placed a comically large plate of strawberry tarts in front of Draco. "Young sir is being safe today, yes? This tournament is not being worth a wizard's life."

"Right you are, Binny," Pansy concurred.

"It's on the Quidditch pitch, presumably in full view of the whole school. I don't think it'll be so dangerous," Rigel reasoned.

"Nevertheless, you will be careful." Pansy's tone was absolute.

Rigel nodded with a small smile. She didn't need people worrying about her, but it was sort of nice when they did anyway.

With no more time to procrastinate, Rigel changed into her green tournament jersey and laced up her trusty boots. She didn't think she'd need Aldon and Edmund's cloak that afternoon. After checking to make sure her wand was in the holster where it belonged, she slipped on the gloves Blaise had given her and let Draco help her into the long fingerless gauntlets.

"Any idea what it's going to be?" Draco murmured as his fingers tightened the laces.

She shook her head. "Something to do with counter-spells. No point wondering now, though. We'll see in a few minutes."

His eyes met hers and the close proximity took her mind back to that night, when his eyes had burned so brightly in the firelight and her breath had been so loud in her ears.

She stepped back with a closed expression, muttering her thanks for his help. Her bag waited patiently by her bed, and she made a show of double-checking everything inside was as it should be.

"We really have to get you something better than that satchel," Pansy said from her perch on Draco's bed.

"It worked just fine in the first task," she said, shrugging unconcernedly.

Her friends exchanged a look that said they didn't agree, but didn't press the issue just then. On her way out from the common room, she once again picked up a crowd of students. Her fellow Slytherins escorted her out onto the lawn like some sort of very short honor guard, and only at the entrance to the Quidditch stadium itself did the majority of them break away and make for the stands.

She caught a glimpse of something odd set up on the other side of the stands, but Rigel didn't get a chance to look closer before her attention was pulled by Ludo Bagman and Bartemius Crouch, who appeared to be standing guard at the stadium entrance.

"Mr. Black, if you please," Crouch called, gesturing her closer. She peeled away from the stream of students headed into the stands and walked his way, closely flanked by Draco and Pansy. "The champions are not permitted to go inside just yet. If you'll make your way to that tent, you can wait with the others for the event to begin." He checked something off of the clipboard he held and waved her toward a large covered pavilion that was situated out of the way.

"Can my friends come?" she asked.

"Family only, I'm afraid." Bagman said apologetically. "Not enough room in the tent for all your friends, I daresay." He chuckled grandly, as though a much larger group of people was listening, before snapping his fingers. "Before you go, though, we've got to do a check of the items you want to bring in the stadium."

Rigel opened her bag for them, not volunteering information on either the necklace under her jersey or the earring hidden by her hair. Bagman picked out a few potions at random, but he seemed rather overwhelmed by the sheer amount of potions and ingredients inside her magically expanded bag.

"You could start an apothecary with all this," he exclaimed. "What do you imagine this task will entail, Mr. Black?"

"Rigel always carries that stuff," Draco said, openly amused at her expense.

"All of it?" Bagman shook his head in bewilderment. "Why?"

"He likes to be prepared." Pansy smiled serenely into Bagman's uncertain expression.

"Right. Well, there doesn't appear to be anything, ah, untoward," the big man said, handing her bag back. "You haven't got any more of those fireworks hidden away, eh?"

"Not today," she assured him.

"Right then." Crouch broke back in with an impatient wave toward the striped pavilion.

Rigel accepted careful hugs from Pansy and Draco and bid them farewell. She was halfway to the tent when something Bagman had said caught up to her brain. Her family would be in the tent. She dug a hand into her bag, hoping she had some left from the year before. With a relieved grin, she produced a small vial of concentrated Eau de Archie. Holding her breath against the smell, she tipped a bit of the oil onto her fingers and tapped it against her neck and wrists. The moon's pull on Remus would be weak in the middle of the cycle, but it never hurt to be cautious.

That settled, Rigel continued to the covered pavilion and swept through the entrance to find a large, comfortable space that someone had thoughtfully plied with warming charms. Most of the other champions were present, as were a host of other people she didn't recognize; she assumed they were the champions' respective families. Her family was, somewhat predictably, by the refreshment table.

Sirius spotted her as soon as she stepped inside. "Pup! Is there a reason you're always the last to arrive?" He handed a plate of fruit off to Lily and hugged Rigel hard; she thanked the double layer of constricting undershirts she wore for letting her sink into it.

"Draco and Pansy like to fuss," she murmured into his chest.

"How do you feel, Arch? Ready?" Remus took her by the shoulders when Sirius released her and smiled down at her. His nostrils flared and sympathy crept into his gaze. "Nervous?"

"A little," she said, glad he'd mentally supplied a reason for her stench. "I've been practicing hard all you showed me this summer, though, and learning new things with my friends, too. I'm sure whatever happens, I'll get through it."

"You're going to do great," James said confidently. His gaze assessed her briefly, and he appeared satisfied with her overall health. "This one won't be as bad as the forest."

"You aren't supposed to tell him anything," Lily said halfheartedly. She shoved Sirius' plate back at him and stepped forward to give Rigel a hug of her own. The familiar scent of her mother wafted over her, and it was all Rigel could do to keep her face relaxed against the pang that thrummed through her. "Sirius says you were splendid in the first task. We're so proud, Archie."

"Thanks, Aunt Lily," she said, her voice—or rather, Archie's spell-copied voice—was thick in her throat. "Where's Addy?" she added.

"We left her with Alice," James said. "Didn't think she ought to see this."

"She's extraordinarily attached to us lately, but a little time apart will do her good," Lily said. "Remus and I didn't want to miss another task. It's a shame Harry can't see you now. She'd be so impressed."

"And jealous." James grinned.

"Harry wouldn't want this kind of attention," Rigel disagreed. "With the press and everything, she'd go spare."

"True enough." James chuckled. "Did you hear what they've done with the mirrors for this task?"

Rigel frowned. "No. I assumed they wouldn't need them, since the task is taking place on the Quidditch pitch in front of everyone." No one had given her a headband, after all.

"You're half-right," Sirius said, wrinkling his nose in distaste. "They've distributed the mirrors to major magical commerce sites worldwide."

"What?" Rigel's eyes widened in dismay. "You're not serious."

All four of them nodded apologetically. "There's one up in Diagon Alley as we speak," Remus told her. "And guess who's having a fundraiser this afternoon in Diagon as well?"

"The Party," she growled. "Those opportunistic exhibitionists."

Sirius shrugged. "The Ministry needs the funds from ticket sales, so they won't say no to whatever advertisement strategy Riddle suggests."

It was crazy to think that witches and wizards all over the world were going to be watching the task as it happened. Trust Riddle to milk the tournament for all it was worth. She wondered how it would work. Would a single headband be rekeyed to all nine mirrors and kept somewhere with a good vantage point? She felt a moment of pity for Nicholas Flamel, and hoped the famous alchemist hadn't been pressed into personally reconfiguring the mirrors every two weeks.

"Rigel?" It was Hermione. Behind her stood a kind-looking couple with Hermione's eyes and chin.

"Hi Hermione. Dad, this is Hermione Granger; in case you don't remember, she's Harry's friend from AIM. My friend too now, I suppose." Rigel smiled at the girl and she returned it after a startled beat.

"Pleased to meet you, Miss Granger," Sirius said. "These must be your parents?"

"Yes, Mr. Black," she said. A moment later her ears turned pink and she blurted, "Lord, I mean. Sorry."

Sirius laughed. "You can call me Sirius, if you want. Leave the lord stuff to people who give a Hippogriff's hoof."

"Right, ah, my parents, Wendell and Monica Granger. You remember Harry's parents from the airport, of course." James and Lily smiled in friendly recognition and nodded at the couple. "And this is Rigel Black, Harry's cousin, and his father, Sirius. Um, and I think you must be Harry's Uncle Remus, right?" Hermione smiled tentatively at Remus, who looked surprised to have been recognized. "Harry talks about all of you so often, I feel I almost know you," she added.

"Pleased to meet all three of you. Harry keeps forgetting to bring you over to the house, Miss Granger," Remus said.

"I see Harry in the alleys anyway." Hermione shrugged.

"Diagon Alley?" James said, eyebrows rising.

"Where else does Harry spend all summer?" Rigel cut in quickly, forcing a laugh. Remus joined in, only a half a beat too late to be completely natural.

"Are you ready for the second task, Hermione?" Lily asked kindly.

Hermione grimaced. "Since we still don't know what it is, that's hard to say. I'm as ready as I can be, I suppose. How about you, Rigel?"

Rigel shrugged. "Like you said, it's impossible to know. I'm ready to get it over with, though."

A chime sounded through the tent, and Sirius sighed. "That's for us, champ. We've got to go."

"Already?" The word came out before Rigel could stop it. Seeing her family was like finding a well of certainty in a desert of indecision. It reminded her what she was here for.

"Next time, don't show up at the last minute," Sirius said, ruffling her hair with exasperated fondness.

"Next time, tell me you're coming ahead of time," she said, mildly indignant. It's not as though anyone ever told her these things were happening. Was there a bulletin board somewhere she hadn't been checking?

The adults all gave her words of good luck before slowly making their way toward the tent's entrance. She and Hermione watched them go, and the muggleborn girl said suddenly, "I almost didn't let them come. If they'd seen the last task, I'd be out of this tournament already."

Rigel grimaced sympathetically. "The Wizarding world is a lot on a normal day."

Hermione turned toward her, and her eyes were much harder than they'd been before her parents left. "Did you see the paper this morning?" The reminder sent a shard of ice through Rigel's veins. She nodded mutely. "It's the same agency that reached out to me when I turned eleven, you know. I remember Mrs. Figg. She gave me the pamphlet about AIM's Healing track when I told her my parents were dentists." Moisture gathered in her eyes but she dashed it away impatiently. "This whole tournament is an invitation for people like the ones who orchestrated that attack to do whatever they want to muggleborns, squibs, and muggles alike. We're not people in their eyes."

"That's why you're here, though. To show them they're wrong," Rigel reminded her gently.

Hermione pressed her lips together. Her eyes were flinty with bleak certainty. "People like that can't be persuaded. They've already decided to hate. I'm here for everyone else. If enough people see reason, the legs will give out from under this madness."

"I hope you're right," Rigel offered.

Bagman and Crouch stepped into the tent, calling for the champions to gather round. Rigel and Hermione drifted toward the center of the enclosed pavilion, where Crouch began arranging them according to his preference. Rigel was herded into a group with Shang and Krum, at which point she realized they were being sorted according to blood.

"This task will be undertaken individually," Bagman told them, smiling widely in cheerful anticipation. "Muggleborns will go first, then halfbloods, and finally the purebloods. You will wait here until it is your turn to try the challenge, and after you either finish or fail you will be escorted to a box from which you may watch the remainder of the task. You will not be permitted to leave the stadium until the scoring is complete."

"You may now decide amongst yourselves in what order you would prefer to compete," Crouch added. "Muggleborns?"

Hermione's face could have been set in stone, were it not for the fire that burned in her eyes. "I'll go first."

Tahiil shrugged and Owens inclined his head, saying, "I'll go second, then."

"Halfbloods?" Crouch looked expectantly at Sousa, Delacour, and Antiope. None of them looked well pleased at the manner in which he had referred to them.

Antiope stuck out her chin and said, "I will lead our group."

"'Zen me," Delacour said quickly. She looked at Sousa as though daring him to argue, but the Brazilian only smiled disinterestedly.

"And, our purebloods?" Crouch prompted.

Rigel opened her mouth to volunteer, but Krum cut her off. "You von the last task. You should go last."

She wasn't sure how that followed, but Shang's blank face didn't give her any clue as to whether she agreed or not.

"Excellent idea, Mr. Krum," Bagman said, clapping his hands together. "More dramatic that way, eh?"

Rigel was certain that hadn't been Krum's train of thought. The scowling boy grunted. "I vill go first, then."

Shang inclined her head. "I agree."

There didn't seem a point to arguing, even though Rigel would really prefer not to have to wait through eight other people's attempts before she got the task over with. Seeing no further deliberation, Crouch nodded his head and scribbled the order down on his clipboard. "Very well. Miss Granger, if you would?"

Hermione followed him out of the tent, her wand gripped tightly in her hand. A few minutes later they heard the roar of the crowd accompanying her entrance into the stadium. Rigel grimaced as she realized just how nerve-wracking it was going to be, waiting in this tent, listening to every ooh and aah the spectators produced and wondering what was happening.

She grabbed a glass of water from the buffet and claimed a seat nearby, slowly sipping at the water as she tried to block out the sounds of the stadium. Rigel worried about Hermione having to compete while in the midst of grief. She hoped the girl wouldn't do anything reckless.

"WELCOME TO THE SECOND TASK!"

Bagman's magically modified voice rang out in the distance and Rigel stifled a groan. They had to listen to the commentary, too? Riddle was unquestionably sadistic.

"OUR FIRST CHAMPION, HERMIONE GRANGER, NOW TAKES THE PLATFORM."

"Platform?" Antiope was listening hard.

After a few minutes of relative quiet, a collective gasp from the crowd washed over them. Bagman's voice followed it with, "WHAT A CLOSE CALL! GRANGER BARELY AVOIDS A NASTY FALL!" The commentary went on in this vein, with numerous exclamations and sometimes screams, punctuated by Bagman's vague and decidedly unhelpful additions.

"He must know we are listening," Tahiil mused, pacing the length of the tent with restless energy.

"I'd say the task involves some sort of elevation," Owens commented, his tone more curious than concerned.

Shang's face, however, went white. "I do not like heights," she said softly, dark eyes wide with fear.

"Maybe it's not—"

"GRANGER SAVES HERSELF FROM FALLING AGAIN! HOW MANY TIMES CAN SHE KEEP THIS UP?"

The Chinese girl put a hand to her stomach and swayed slightly on her feet. "I cannot do this," she whispered.

Antiope scoffed. "Why would you join a competition like this if you're afraid of something as simple as heights?"

"They tell my father it will not be a factor," Shang said, her breathing faster than normal.

"Who told him zat? Ze tournament organizers?" Delacour narrowed her eyes in suspicion. "Surely zey would not be so unfair, giving information to some alone."

Shang shrugged helplessly. "I said if there is heights, I will not compete."

"If they lied about it, then the information vasn't meant to help her," Krum said. He exchanged a look with Delacour that was hard for Rigel to interpret. They seemed to be in agreement over something.

"What are you saying? That someone doesn't want Shang here to win? I thought everyone wanted you purebloods to win," Antiope said sharply. Her hand clenched on empty air, and Rigel wondered if it was a habit she'd picked up from carrying a sword in that hand. Clearly Rigel was not the only one whose tools had been subject to censoring this task.

"What gave you that idea?" Rigel asked, genuinely curious to see whether the girl had worked it out.

Antiope shot her a scathing look. "It's obvious to us all. Britain's blood politics are notorious the world over, Black, and it's no secret which side Lord Riddle's Party falls on."

"I am confused," Tahiil said, raising his hand. When the rest of them stared at him, he smiled awkwardly and put his hand down again. "Mr. Riddle has said the tournament is an experiment. Even he does not know who will win."

Before anyone could answer, Professor Flitwick poked his head into the tent and called, "Mr. Owens? They are ready for you."

Owens left with him, and Rigel frowned as she realized she'd been blocking out the sounds of the stadium to focus on their conversation. She had no idea whether or not Hermione had succeeded in the task.

Sousa, who until that point had been content to lean quietly on one of the corner tent poles, was the one to answer Tahiil's question. "It is a trick, no? The seeming of objectivity is very convincing. For me, there is no surprise if Mr. Riddle chose every person in this room."

The seven of them looked around at one another, and Rigel wondered if the idea that they were not being given equal expectation of winning angered any of the others.

Antiope rolled her shoulders restively. "I don't care what Lord Riddle thinks he's doing. I'm going to win this tournament regardless. If he wanted one of you three to win—" she shot a fierce look in Rigel, Krum, and Shang "—then he made a mistake including me."

Tahiil's eyebrows rose, and a thoughtful look entered his eyes. He met her gaze and, after a moment, smiled at Rigel with a shrug. "We all must do our best no matter what."

Krum and Delacour both made noises of agreement, but Sousa merely sighed. Rigel noticed Shang was still on the verge of an anxiety attack, and pulled her shrunken bag from her pocket to look through it. She produced a Calming Draught, one of several she'd re-brewed after learning that her ingredients were oversaturated.

"Here," she said, pressing it into the girl's hands. "It's a Calming Draught." Shang's face showed no sign of recognition, and she supposed they had some other name for it in China. Perhaps they even used a different brew altogether for the same effect. "It will reduce your fear," she explained.

Shang frowned at the vial mistrustfully, taking it gingerly into her hands and attempting to examine it carefully. Her hands shook so badly, though, that she clenched her eyes shut in frustration and said, "Sorry. You can open please?"

Rigel uncorked the vial for her, and the black-haired girl tipped it back. After only a few moments, a look of peaceful relief smoothed the lines of tension from her face. "Thank you," Shang said, surprise in her voice. Rigel wondered if she'd honestly expected her to poison her. Then she wondered how bad Shang's fear must be, that the girl had accepted the risk anyway for a chance at relief.

Owens finished surprisingly quickly, with Bagman's shouted, "THAT TIME WILL BE TOUGH TO BEAT!" signaling the end of his run. Professor Sinistra collected Tahiil shortly after, and Rigel once again attempted to block out the sounds of the stadium.

Frustrated by every gasp and groan echoing out of the pitch, Rigel finally turned to Shang and said, "Will you wake me when you go?" Shang nodded, looking puzzled, and Rigel settled herself in a corner of the tent and sank into her mindscape, where the howling of her mind's wind greeted her. All other sound was washed away in its wake, and Rigel felt something approaching relaxation creep into her.

As she willed herself into the cozy cabin-like interior of her once icy mountain, Rigel caught Dom in the midst of weaving what appeared to be a tapestry out of pure magic. It was only just begun, too early to guess what the overall design would be. The construct looked over as she materialized and said, "If it isn't my gracious hostess. To what do I owe the pleasure?"

"I just needed to get away from reality for a moment," she said, sinking into an armchair with a sigh.

Dom made a noise of understanding deep in his throat. "Your emotions have been especially volatile of late. Is everything all right?"

At mention of her emotions, her mind went to the night Draco kissed her. She pressed her lips together against the remembered feeling and grimaced. "It's been a strange week. The second task is today, so try not to use too much magic," she added.

He paused in his weaving and gave her a sidelong glance. "You have more than enough."

"No telling what I'll be facing though," she said. "Maybe I'll see the dragon again—I'm sure it wasn't cheap moving one out here."

Dom stood from his task with a long-suffering look. After conjuring a pot of tea and flawlessly pouring Rigel a cup, he leaned back in his chair and said, "I've finished sifting this batch of magic. The foreign magic behaves the same as the last batch. I've stored it together." He indicated one of the closed cabinets with a careless flick of his fingers.

Rigel nodded in understanding. "Remind me after the task, and I'll get you another batch. Thanks for doing this, Dom. It takes a lot off my mind."

"You should still be concerned with its purpose," he said sternly. There was something about the smile he tried to hide behind his teacup that told her he was pleased with her gratitude, however.

"I'll worry about it later," she mumbled, sinking deeper into her seat. He nudged the second teacup toward her and she took it. Her eyes traced the surprisingly detailed pattern on the china. "Was Pettigrew really the first English wizard you possessed?"

"Possession is an inexact word for it," Dom said, fingering his own teacup idly. "Peter invited me into his mind, and in return I provided him power beyond anything he'd ever been capable of. To your question, however, yes. I was created in Egypt—at least, I was given conscious form there. I don't know where the stone I inhabited was originally found. I ruled through various pharaohs, until I was betrayed and entombed for upwards of two thousand years. Then Peter came for me." There was a faraway look on his face as he added, "I don't mourn his failure, but I am not ungrateful for his hand in my destiny."

"Anyone would be glad to be free, after such a long imprisonment." Rigel was surprised the jewel had retained any semblance of sanity. Looked at it like that, Dom's implacable rage and entitlement was almost understandable. She wondered whether it was even fair to judge the magical construct by human standards. After considering how much time he'd spent leeching knowledge from human minds and using that power to influence the world around him, however, she thought he probably ought to be held to some standards for a change.

Dom's eyelids fell to half-mast as he regarded her carefully. "I wasn't referring to my relocation from Egypt. I am indebted to Peter for bringing me to you, Harriet."

Rigel blinked. She couldn't help but feel somewhat incredulous. "I bound you to my mindscape, Dom. I took away any chance you had at ever ruling again."

"You gave me a form of my own," Dom said quietly, staring down into his teacup. "You gave me a name."

Those seemed like small things to her, in comparison with an eternity of power. If it gave him a sense of peace with his situation, though, she wasn't going to discourage his existential development. "I appreciate your presence here more than I thought I would," Rigel admitted after a moment of contemplation. Once she'd said it out loud, she couldn't quell the cynical thought that perhaps that had been Dom's intention, and the reason he'd been so cooperative of late. To voice that suspicion wouldn't do her any credit, but she wouldn't forget it, either.

A jolt that inexorably came from her physical body shuddered through her, and she put down the teacup and rose. "I have to get back," she told him. "I'll drop by again soon."

"Good luck in the task," Dom said, smiling up at her. "Try not to die."

"I always try not to die," she said with false cheer. If her returning smile was a tad brittle, he didn't comment. Rigel allowed her avatar to dematerialize as she followed the tug of the physical realm back toward its source.

Feiyan Shang was standing over her, a gentle hand on her shoulder. Professor Snape was beside her, his black gaze revealing nothing as he watched Rigel roll her stiff neck.

"Thanks," Rigel murmured. "Good luck, Shang."

The Chinese girl grimaced. "Thank you. For the Calming Draught as well."

Snape's eyes sharped with disapproval, but Rigel smiled unrepentantly. "Anytime." To Snape she asked, "Has everyone made it through so far?"

"No. Mr. Zahi was knocked from the course, and Antiope failed to counter the final challenge." Snape turned his attention to Shang, saying, "If you're ready?"

They left, and Rigel was alone in the tent. She began to stretch slowly, starting with her shoulders and by the time she'd made it to her ankles, Bagman's voice boomed out. "SHANG TAKES A SPILL! IT'S ALL OVER FOR OUR SECOND PUREBLOOD FOLKS!"

Rigel winced. That didn't sound good. Just what was this task, that thirty percent of the participants had already failed? It wasn't long before Professor McGonagall stepped into the tent and gestured for Rigel to accompany her. "It's time, Mr. Black," she said.

Rigel peered up at her as she left the tent behind. "Is it going to be bad?" she asked.

McGonagall's face softened and her lips relaxed from where she'd had them tightly pressed together. "It will be a challenge, Mr. Black, but it isn't like the forest."

Rigel nodded, letting her gratitude show through her eyes. "All right. Thank you."

They walked to the stadium entrance, and as Rigel passed beneath the bleachers she caught sight of the task for the first time. It looked like a very strange sort of obstacle course, and it hung suspended in the air, hundreds of feet above her head. There was a square platform on the ground near the entrance to the pitch, and Rigel judged it would lift her up to the course when she stepped onto it. The task itself seemed relatively straightforward, as there was another, much bigger, platform on the far end of the pitch that was, presumably, her goal. Between the two platforms, however, was a maze of narrow pathways, sometimes intersecting, sometimes continuing uninterrupted for long stretches. She could see no obvious obstacles along the network of paths, but she didn't fool herself that balance was the only thing being tested that afternoon.

Then she noticed something else. "There's no net," she breathed, horror lodging in her throat.

"There are spells in place to catch anyone who falls," McGonagall assured her. "Still…it is not a pleasant experience."

She swallowed somewhat shakily. She wasn't afraid of heights per se, but she had no desire to test the catching spells herself. The crowd roared around her when she came into view before the platform. Everyone was so high above her, and she supposed it made sense from a presentation standpoint to have the task elevated so spectators in the high Quidditch stands could better view the excitement. Rigel still suspected that Riddle had done it solely for the added element of fear.

"Good luck, Mr. Black," McGonagall said, placing a thin hand on her shoulder in a brief squeeze. "When you are ready, ascend the platform. The task is over when you reach the end, fall, or become too injured to continue."

Rigel nodded once and stepped forward with a confidence she didn't feel. Remembering her family's warning that her every move was being transmitted to mirrors worldwide, she kept her head high and her expression calm.

The starting platform was a slab of stone about the size of a typical doorframe, and no more than a half-foot thick. She stepped to the center of the rectangle and bent her knees in preparation for its movement. Rigel didn't anticipate the speed at which the stone would rise, however, and she found herself forced into a crouch as it ascended with a whoosh. Her stomach felt as though it had been left behind on the grass. When it came to a stop, she stood slowly, taking a deep breath as Bagman's voice rang in her ears. "OUR LAST COMPETITOR REACHES THE PLATFORM! LET'S SEE IF HE CAN BEAT OWENS' TIME!"

Rigel could see the course more clearly now, and she realized the 'paths' she'd seen from the ground were actually a series of floating tiles, none quite connected to the next. There was a small chance between every tile for Rigel to misstep and fall. There was only one way off the platform, so she took it, lightly jumping onto the first tile, then the next, steadily making her way toward the first fork in the course.

She had just landed on the sixth tile when it disappeared beneath her feet. Rigel plummeted, her heart stopping in that instant of free fall before her fingers caught the edge of the seventh tile and stuck. Her left arm was wrenched painfully as the no-slip spells on her gloves fought against her downward momentum and won. Magic bless Blaise Zabini, she thought, grimacing with the strain as she swung her right arm up to catch the tile as well.

Rigel tried to ignore the screams and shouts of the crowd as she slowly—painfully—pulled her body up enough to get her knee over the edge of the tile, too. With a last heave of effort, she collapsed on the seventh tile and panted, shaking her left arm out gingerly with a scowl. That was stupid of her. She had given into the temptation to move through the task quickly, and naturally it had cost her.

She took her feet again quickly, but this time pushed her magical awareness out in front of her, instead of letting it rest relatively near her skin as she'd become unconsciously accustomed. Rigel could project her magical sensitivity a good dozen feet without straining her endurance, and as soon as she focused on it she could feel the magic holding up the course, clinging to every tile. It felt more delicate than was reassuring. It took her a moment to filter the information she was receiving, but when she ignored the magic that was keeping the tiles afloat, she could sense the next trap.

Three tiles down there was a small ball of malignant magic lurking. She took the next two steps confidently and stopped, pulling out her wand to cast a revealing charm. It was just a trip jinx, attached to the underside of the tile, but even that simple thing could be dangerous on a course like this. Rather than spend the magic disarming it, she pushed her awareness out to check that the next tile was clear of spells and then leapt forward over the trap tile.

Gasps accompanied her jump, but Rigel easily cleared the distance. "WHAT A LEAP!" Now she had a choice to make. Two tiles led in different directions before her, and the innocuous, winding tiles gave no indication of which path would be better.

She took the right path, sending her magical awareness out ahead of her, and tried not to feel alarmed when a good number of spectators groaned at her decision. There was something new up ahead. When she got closer to it, she saw a tile that was bright red and she stopped, heeding the warning despite being two tiles away. The basic revealing charm told her nothing except the density of magic present. It certainly wasn't a trip jinx. Rigel took her bag out of her pocket and enlarged it before slinging it across her shoulders. She took an empty vial from one of the deep pockets and tossed it forward toward the blue tile.

The vial was met with a jet of flame that burst upwards out of the tile. The glass was resistant to heat, so it only blackened a little and fell off the edge of the course. Rigel would probably be able to walk through it if she applied a coat of Fire Free. No sense in wasting it, though. Instead, she cast a Fortis shield around herself like a bubble. It would hold against even dragon flame for a few seconds. The fire coming out of the tile was nowhere near that strong, and Rigel didn't feel a thing as she once again leapt over the problematic tile.

Really, the second task wasn't so bad, she thought as she moved forward once more. With her sensing ability, she was ready for the next three traps she encountered, even though only about half of the tiles were color in warning. She supposed they wanted to give the competitors some chance of succeeding, especially against the more dangerous obstacles. Rigel countered one more fire-related trap, a spell that would have bucked her off its tile if she'd stepped on it, and a runic array that tried to blow her off the course with a sharp gust of wind. Then she came to a tile that was acid green. Her trick with an empty potion vial produced no reaction, and she lamented the waste of a good vial as it tumbled sadly to the ground.

The revealing charm did provoke a response, however. From the center of the tile sprouted a flower, unnaturally tall and slender, with a single, bright pink bloom. It looked a bit like an Anemone, but the center was wrong. A sickly green cluster of something was nestled in the center petals, and she could feel magic trapped there, too. Rigel was torn. She could cut it with a severing charm, but what if that triggered the magic? She tried to vanish the plant; her magic bounced off the petals. Incredulous, she figured she'd have to burn it, and hopefully destabilize whatever the magic was grounded to.

She cast Incendio on a spare bit of crumpled parchment from her bag and tossed the small fireball gently toward the black tile. It came to rest at the plant's base, and after a moment caught the flower's stem, spreading quickly toward the head. The fat, pink petals took an eerily long time to burn, though, and Rigel kept her wand at the ready, unnerved. Her suspicions were rewarded when the flower suddenly convulsed and the center exploded outward. Acid greed spores rained down on her, and she jumped back a tile while casting a hasty Bubble Head Charm. It wasn't fast enough. She felt a burn at the back of her throat and immediately turned her wand on her airways.

From her fight with Ralph in the Lower Alleys, she knew what to expect from this kind of attack. It wasn't exactly the same as sleeping gas, but the process of identifying the foreign substance in her lungs and metabolizing it before it could be carried any further was similar.

The poisonous spores were potent. Even though she'd only breathed in a small portion of what was spewed from the still-burning flower, her vision was already narrowing at the edges. She fought back against the temptation to close her eyes and kept at her self-healing. After a brief, confused moment, her magic had flushed as much of the invasive substance as was possible. Rigel shook off the lingering drowsiness and moved forward again. The flower was just a pile of ashes, now, and the tile had turned back to an innocuous tan color.

She stepped past it, and the crowd erupted into cheers. "BLACK SHAKES OFF THE SLEEP SPORES! CAN NOTHING STOP THIS CHAMPION?" Rigel was about a third of the way along the right-hand path now, and ahead of her was another fork. Left would take her back toward the center of the course, which meant a relatively straight shot toward the finish line. There seemed to be more colored tiles on that path, though. After a moment's indecision, she went right.

Almost immediately, her magical sensitivity flared with warning and Rigel dropped into a crouch so fast her knees popped. An arrow of fire whizzed over her head, and another followed it as she half-crawled, half- jumped to the next tile to avoid it. They were coming from the red tile on the middle path, and she scowled at the unfairness of being waylaid by something not even on the path she'd chosen. Rigel cast a Fortis shield as she stood, but a moment later she was flat against the tile again as a third arrow shot through her shield. The only thing that saved her was its deceleration as the arrow met resistance. Muttering a curse at whoever designed the obstacle course, Rigel channeled her frustration and consciously summoned a Depasco Shield instead. She waited until a fourth arrow fizzled into nothingness as it met the shield before standing. Somehow, it seemed nothing she did would be effective twice. She wondered whether the course was evolving as she went, but doubted even Riddle was that good.

The red shield hung hazily around her as she very carefully moved forward. She had to hold it several inches off the ground or risk dissolving the tiles beneath her feet. When she was clear of the arrow tile's range, she dropped the Depasco immediately; it was too draining to justify keeping up, even though she doubted anything the course threw at her could penetrate it.

Two tiles after she'd dropped the shield, a non-colored tile let out a hiss beneath her feet and white mist sprang up all around her, choking her senses before she could so much as hold her breath. She froze as her vision went completely dark. Why didn't I sense anything? she thought, trying and failing to keep her breathing light in response to the utter blackness surrounding her. It must not have been a spell, she reasoned. If it was a potion with a mechanical trigger, the traces of magic in the brew itself were probably too weak to notice amidst the tile's levitation magic.

Rigel couldn't detect any poison in her system—and yet, she'd definitely inhaled the mist. Her vision certainly hadn't deserted her of its own accord. She realized with a sickening stomach turn that her hearing was gone, too. The world around her was silent. At the same time, though, she could feel the stone beneath her feet. She hadn't been transported, then.

She racked her brain for potions that could take away sight and sound but leave her able to feel the breeze on her skin and smell the sweat on her clothes. There were two that she knew of. Monistra's Malediction could cut off any of the five senses depending on how it was brewed. She supposed someone clever enough could combine two of the five into one mist, or perhaps the mist was a combination of two potions released simultaneously. The other one was Prisoner's Poison. It was once a popular potion in law enforcement, before the runic sequence to bind a person's magic to their skin was discovered. Prisoner's Poison deprived sight and hearing both, in addition to cutting off the conscious use of a person's magic. It didn't prevent accidental magic, which was part of why it fell out of favor.

Rigel very carefully cast a warming charm and felt the corresponding rush of heat. Monistra's Malediction, then. She sagged with relief. Rigel had hoped even Riddle wouldn't be sadistic enough to bind someone's magic mid-task, but she was constantly relearning not to underestimate him.

The cure for Monistra's Malediction was tree sap, specifically from a grove of wand wood trees. Rigel had both Black Walnut and Sycamore in her kit. Slowly, aware that she could easily lose her balance on the path without sight to orient her, Rigel felt for her bag's opening and groped her way along the extended inside until she came to the compartment she wanted. There were two vials inside, as expected, and she brought first one to her nose, then the next. She drank the Black Walnut, even though the Sycamore was sweeter, because Black Walnut was only seven Knuts an ounce.

Her vision cleared just as her hearing came rushing back. She winced as the silence was blasted into a hundred, screaming pieces and Bagman's voice roared in her ears. "LOOKS LIKE SOMEONE CAME PREPARED! BLACK BECOMES THE FIRST CHAMPION TO OVERCOME THE ANTI-SENSORY MIST!"

Rigel summoned her magical awareness around herself like a cloak and moved forward once more. A brown tile was the next in her path, and without needing to be provoked a wall at least twice her height sprang into place before her, blocking the rest of the path entirely. She could double back and try a different path, but she was almost to the end. Running a hand along the surface of the wall confirmed her suspicion that it was too smooth to climb. The wall was coated with some kind of wax, and almost slippery to the touch. She considered it. The wax was thick enough to draw in.

With a smile, Rigel used her wand to draw a simple, linear alchemical array. She bound the array in a wide circle at waist height and wiped her wand tip clean. As she pulsed magic into the runes to activate it, the stone within the circle cracked and crumbled until it was nothing but a pile of fine sand. She pushed her way through easily and continued.

The roar of the crowd was picking up once more as she neared the last colored tile. Before she could get there, her sensitivity shivered as it brushed up against something powerful in a nondescript tile just in front of the obviously colored one. She tossed a vial at it, with no reaction. A revealing spell came up blank as well, but she knew something was there. Maybe it needed a little more provoking. Instead of wasting magic on a blasting curse, Rigel dug out a handful of dried chimera eyes from deep in her bag. It took only a moment to imbue enough magic into the volatile ingredient. The eyes grew hot in her hand and she flung them forward at the suspicious tile. They exploded on contact, and something huge and metal reared up out of the tile.

It was a contraption like a steel shark, and it closed with a sickening snap over the air where Rigel's foot might have been, had she stepped on the tile unwittingly. She couldn't help but be glad that no one else had made it so far down that particular path. Someone could easily have lost a leg in the monstrosity. Now that she could see it, Rigel banished the trap over the edge of the path and watched it fall to the earth with relieved satisfaction.

Only one obstacle left, she thought, crossing the remaining tiles and coming to a stop before the last, which was a brilliant violet color. She didn't need to trigger this one at all. A magical barrier shimmered into being between the purple tile and the final platform. Then, a white stone basin rose from within the tile, climbing slowly upward until it was as high as Rigel's chest. There were runes inscribed all along the edge of the basin, and Rigel narrowed her eyes as she deciphered the sequence.

It wasn't conveying a terribly complex message, so it only took her a minute to work it out. The barrier would dissolve only when she added the key to the basin. The key was…blood. Rigel could feel a cold sweat breaking out over her temple. There was no way she could risk spilling her blood into the basin. What if it somehow tested for blood purity? She shook her head impatiently at the thought. It couldn't, if all the other champions were to have a fair chance at passing the barrier. Still, who knew what would happen to the blood she put into the bowl? What if the organizers saved it for some reason? What if it was analyzed later? The runes specified human blood, not animal, but there was one thing in her potions kit that could help her. She had a vial of Archie's blood. Rigel swallowed hard. She couldn't. Could she? No, she definitely couldn't. Archie had given her that blood willingly, and willingly spilt blood was too dangerous to leave lying around, no matter the circumstances.

But what to do? She could turn back, make her way to the last fork in the road and then fight her way forward again through all the obstacles in the center. Even as she considered the course of action seriously, she felt a wave of heat without a source stirring inside of her extremities. The Vow would not allow her to turn back.

"Shite." She needed to think. There had to be another way. Maybe she could overpower the runic barrier: bypass the instructions and somehow dismantle it without triggering any negative effects. Her eyes strayed over to the center tiles, and she wished desperately that she'd taken that path instead.

A crazy thought came to her, and Rigel seized it with both hands before the Vow could assess her intentions and tell her otherwise. She tossed an empty vial over toward the center path, a distance of some thirty feet, and it scraped against the edge of a tile before tumbling down. Her eyes didn't follow it, however. She'd learned what she needed to: there was no physical barrier between the paths. Rigel produced a Modified Weightless Draught from her bag and downed it with a wicked grin.

"WHAT IS BLACK DOING NOW? HE SEEMS TO HAVE GIVEN UP ON THE FINAL OBSTACLE COMPLETELY!"

She ignored Bagman's incredulity—ignored also the voice in her head telling her this was probably not a good idea—and jumped.

The stadium erupted with screams, but Rigel was not falling: she was floating. The Modified Weightless Draught left her lighter than air, and she drifted in a smooth arch toward the center path. It neared, she tried to slow, but her control was less than perfect. She overshot the path and started to descend between the center path and the left-most path. With a grimace, Rigel pointed her wand at the place she'd meant to land and said, "Accio!" The stone tile was anchored to the air with magic, but Rigel was not anchored to anything. There was a reason you weren't supposed to try summoning objects that weighed more than you did. In a vacuum, the lighter object was the one to move. Unless a witch or wizard was grounded with magic, whether consciously or unconsciously, a summoning spell could backfire.

Rigel was counting on her spell doing just that. There was a violent tug at her navel and then she was zooming toward the tile. She connected hard and held on with both hands to still her momentum. With the Weightless Draught still active within her, Rigel had to rely on her non-slip gloves to keep her from floating off the path with every movement. She scrambled forward on her fingertips and toes in an awkward crab shuffle, and was very grateful that there were only four tiles between where she landed and the end of the center path.

She was so focused on not drifting off into space that she misread what her magical sensitivity was telling her. The final obstacle came not from the blue tile at the end of the path, but from the plain tile just before it. A ward sprang up around Rigel's crouched form, trapping her in a dome of pure magic. Her muscles clenched in surprise that turned to terror as the ward began to shrink steadily inward. Something inside her screamed in vicious protest. Memories of that rotting pit, days of torture and hunger and pain, rose up in her mind like a tidal wave, and the only coherent thought Rigel could produce was never again!

She felt a spasm of pain in her head and had the vague impression that Dom was attempting to communicate something, but to no avail. Her magic flooded the bubble around her, pouring from her so fast and in so many directions that Rigel closed her eyes against the intensity of the resulting light. Pressure built, forcing Rigel down onto the hard tile, and when she could press herself no closer to the stone, when the space beneath the ward was so thick with her magic that something—and Rigel was very much afraid it would be her bones—had to give, her magic suddenly found direction. It sharpened, for lack of a better word, against the ward, and the blue barrier burst like an overripe fruit. Magic exploded in all directions, Rigel gasped for air, and the stadium of spectators swelled with a deafening roar.

Rigel felt more than saw the spells holding up the path crumple in the wake of her magic. The tile she was on slid sideways and Rigel pushed herself off in a desperate lurch. She shot toward the final platform with more speed than grace, but her hands found purchase before she could bounce off it, and she rode the rapidly destabilizing stone to the ground. She impacted more heavily than was likely intended as the magic animating the platform gave a final death rattle. The jarring change in momentum tried to bounce her weightless form back into the air, but she rolled sideways instead, grasping at the long grass to keep her anchored to the ground. Hard earth and brittle clumps of weeds had never smelled so good.

Dimly, she was aware of Bagman's voice ringing through the stadium, of hundreds of people high above her, shouting and cheering her name. She was even aware of the sickening booms that came as tile after tile tumbled to the ground around her. How long until one crashed into her head and finished the job the course had started?

A shield sprang into being above her and she twisted her head around to see Snape striding toward her in a walk so fast it was nearly—almost—a run. Her Head of House dropped the shield just long enough to grasp Rigel firmly by the wrist, and then he was towing her through the air toward the edge of the stadium, where a set of stairs awaited them.

When they were out of immediate danger of being brained to death by falling stones, Snape let the shield fall completely and put his wand away in favor of holding Rigel down with both hands. "How long does this last?" he demanded, his mouth in an unamused line.

"I have a counter potion," she said.

"Then why haven't you taken it?"

Rigel scowled up at him. "I've been using both hands to not float away. Normally I can control the movement a little better, but—"

"Allow me a guess: you over-brewed this one, too." Snape's expression could have withered the Whomping Willow.

She flushed. "I—well, I got all new ingredients, but I may have neglected to replace all the potions I made since starting to practice my magical awareness."

"The counter potion," Snape reminded her sharply. "There's an entire stadium waiting on you."

Rigel huffed, but obediently dug into her bag for the imbued Finite potion, Snape tethering her to the earth until its effects kicked in. She felt gravity catch up with her in an unpleasant rush and caught herself against Snape's shoulders to steady her balance until she was certain she wouldn't fall onto her face. "Thanks," she said, almost sighing with relief. "I can't believe it's over."

"What strains credibility is that you made it through the entire course almost unscathed," Snape said. She couldn't tell for sure, but she thought he almost sounded proud.

"It was my sensing ability that saved me," she said, drawing herself up to full height so she could look him sincerely in the eye. "I'm sorry I ever complained about having to learn it. Thank you, Professor. For everything."

Snape's face softened infinitesimally. "Foolish boy. Keeping you alive would be easier if you cooperated now and again."

"I will from now on," she promised. Rigel thought she even meant it. "How are the others?" she added. "Is everyone all right?"

"See for yourself," Snape said. He swept up the stairs and Rigel followed quickly, despite how bone-tired she was.

At the top of the stairs was a special box, obviously set aside for the competitors. Seven of the others were present. She took a quick accounting and asked Snape, "What happened to Antiope?"

"She was unable to escape the shrinking ward. It crushed several of her bones before she fell unconscious and forfeited by default. Madam Pomfrey is seeing to her. The girl will be fine," he added after a moment, clearly reading in Rigel's pale expression the horrified concern she felt.

Snape told her to wait there while the scoring was deliberated and left. Rigel stepped forward toward the front of the box, where the other seven competitors stood at the balcony's edge. Hermione smiled grimly at her as she approached.

"You did really well," Hermione said bracingly. "Faster than most."

"Was it?" She couldn't hide her surprise. "It felt like I was up there for ages."

"I felt the same," Hermione said. "I think we all did. All that adrenaline. And every second you spend thinking about what to do just feels like a lifetime, doesn't it?" Rigel nodded. She looked Hermione over subtly, but the muggleborn girl caught on and smiled wryly. "I'm fine, Rigel. I had a few rope burns from an unexpected Incarcerous and boils down my left side from a jet of bubotuber pus, but nothing I couldn't heal myself. Are you all right?"

Rigel shrugged. "No real injuries, except for the poisonous flower."

Hermione nodded sagely. "Those sleeping spores are fast acting. I'm impressed you counteracted them so quickly. Feiyan and Tahiil took the same route, you know, but the spores got them both. Tahiil fell off the course in his sleep, but Feiyan landed on the tile. The spores wore off after ten minutes or so, but I think they made her dizzy; she lost her balance when that anti-sensory mist hit her."

Rigel nodded slowly. "The mist takes away sight and sound but leaves the other senses. It's enough to give anyone vertigo, and coupled with the after effects of the spores and her fear of heights…" Rigel glanced over to where Shang stood, pale, but not visibly injured, on the other side of the box. Tahiil was with her, and they seemed united in an unspoken misery.

"Exactly." Hermione looked down onto the pitch, where the remains of the obstacle course were scattered in pieces all over the ground. She smiled suddenly, and it was a terrifying, fierce thing. "I'm glad you destroyed it."

"So am I," Krum grunted. He had sidled up to Rigel's other side while they were talking. Krum had burn paste slathered up and down his right arm. Judging by the pattern, she guessed he'd tried to protect himself from an unexpected jet of flame with it. "That task vas more luck than skill."

"'Zome people had less trouble, it eez true," Delacour added. Clearly the box was not big enough to prevent her from hearing their conversation. The French girl's eyes lingered briefly on Rigel but turned sharply to land on Jacob Owens, of all people.

The American boy raised his eyebrows and smiled. "Me? I was pretty lucky, I suppose. Maybe they went easy on me for going first."

"Could be," Delacour allowed, but Rigel could tell that she was not convinced. She wondered why the girl was even suspicious of Owens—none of them had seen his run, since he'd gone first. Was it just because he'd got a better time?

Come to think of it, she had no idea what her own time had come out to be. Sheepishly, she asked Hermione, "Did you happen to catch my time, by chance?"

Hermione blinked at her in surprise, but it was Delacour who said, "You weren't even paying attention?"

Rigel frowned. "I had rather other things on my mind, at the end there. What with the entire obstacle course coming down around my ears."

"How did you do that, anyway?" Owens asked, eyes bright with curiosity. "Even Antiope couldn't break out of that ward, and brute strength is sort of her specialty." He smiled in that strange way of his, and Rigel had to wonder again why she never found his humor amusing.

"I just panicked," she said flatly. "My magic was completely uncontrolled, I'm afraid."

"Hence the chain reaction," Owens said thoughtfully. "Interesting."

"This is vhy you go last," Krum said. The smallest of smiles ticked up the corner of his mouth.

Rigel scowled. "There was no way to predict that would happen."

"After the dragon, ve knew something vould happen," Krum argued. Hermione snorted with laughter then turned pink as Krum's amused eyes turned on her as well.

"They've finished scoring," Sousa said suddenly, drawing everyone's attention to the pitch once more. Rigel let her eyes linger on the Brazilian for a brief moment, but he, too, seemed to be in reasonably good health, though there was something utterly drained about his expression that she sympathized with. It was how she felt internally, after so much magical expenditure in so short a time.

Across the pitch, directly on the opposite side of the stands, there was a golden box that jutted out from the rest. She could make out the vague features of those inside—not enough to identify them all, but enough to know that Riddle, Crouch, and Bagman all stood within. Dumbledore, too, she thought, though the old wizard was keeping to the back of the box.

As though in confirmation, Bagman's voice boomed out over the pitch once more. "LADIES AND GENTLEMEN! THE JUDGES HAVE DELIBERATED AND THE SCORING IS CONCLUDED!"

Rigel's attention was interrupted by a hand on her back. She whirled around and found Pansy and Draco standing behind her. She grinned at them and fell into Pansy's brief embrace. After an almost immeasurably short moment of awkwardness, Draco clapped her on the shoulder and said, "Great job, Rigel."

"You were splendid," Pansy added.

Hermione turned around with a look that was as good as a pointed hushing noise. The three Slytherins fell silent to listen and Rigel turned back toward the announcer, but neither Pansy nor Draco retreated from their close proximity to her shoulder blades.

"…JUDGED ON THREE CATEGORIES FOR THE SECOND TASK! TIMELINESS IN COMPLETING THE COURSE, PROBLEM-SOLVING, AND DEGREE OF RESILIENCE! AS WITH THE FIRST TASK, PROBLEM SOLVING IS DETERMINED BY THE COMPETITOR'S ABILITY TO MATCH APPROPRIATE RESPONSES TO THE CHALLENGES ENCOUNTERED. IMPRECISE APPLICATION OF MAGIC IS NOT THE GOAL! THE FINAL CATEGORY, THAT OF RESILIENCE, IS MEASURED BY THE STATE OF HEALTH IN WHICH A COMPETITOR COMPLETED THIS TASK. CHAMPIONS WITH FEWER INJURIES WILL SCORE HIGHER, AS IT DEMONSTRATES SUPERIOR REACTIONS, EFFICIENCY OF CASTING, AND QUICK THINKING! BEFORE WE SCORE THEM, LET'S GIVE ALL THE CHAMPIONS ANOTHER ROUND OF APPLAUSE!"

Rigel rubbed her ears as the stadium erupted around them. She wouldn't be surprised if every person present went home harder of hearing from listening to the obnoxiously overpowered Sonorous Charm.

"FOR TIME, OUT OF TWENTY POINTS, SCORES ARE AS FOLLOWS: JACOB OWENS, 20 POINTS. ARCTURUS BLACK, 19 POINTS. HERMIONE GRANGER, 18 POINTS. FLEUR DELACOUR, 17 POINTS. VICTOR KRUM, 16 POINTS. MATHEUS SOUSA, 15 POINTS. ANTIOPE, TAHIIL DIRIC ZAHI, AND FEIYAN SHANG ALL RECEIVE ZERO POINTS!"

The crowd roared its approval or displeasure—it was impossible to tell which—and Rigel felt a hand on her shoulder again as Draco's voice dipped into her ear. "Second place. You would have been first, but Owens didn't even trigger some of the obstacles in his path."

Rigel tried to listen, but the feeling of his breath against her ear distracted her completely. Her attention was yanked back to the stadium as Bagman's voice started up again.

"IN PROBLEM SOLVING, OUT OF FIFTEEN POINTS, WE HAVE: JACOB OWENS, 15. MATHEUS SOUSA, 14. HERMIONE GRANGER, 13. FLEUR DELACOUR, 12. VICTOR KRUM, 11. ANTIOPE, 8. FEIYAN SHANG, 6. TAHIIL DIRIC ZAHI, 6." There was a pause in which Rigel wondered if Bagman had forgotten to call her name. Then he went on. "AFTER SOME DELIBERATION, IT WAS DETERMINED THAT ARCTURUS BLACK'S DESTRUCTION OF THE OBSTACLE COURSE WAS NOT A CONSCIOUS ACT OF WILL. NEVERTHELESS, AS AN OVERREACTION, IT WAS TAKEN INTO ACCOUNT IN HIS SCORE. RIGEL BLACK THUS RECIEVES A PROBLEM SOLVING SCORE OF 10 POINTS!"

"Ten?" Draco's voice was incredulous. "Five points off for one bit of overzealous magic? And anyway, that ward could have killed you. How is anything an overreaction to threat of death?"

"Are you finished?" Rigel turned to smile ruefully at her friend. Honestly, she wasn't surprised they'd docked points for what her magic did to the course. Probably it had taken someone a very long time to assemble it. She couldn't dredge up any regret.

Draco grumbled something under his breath, but did fall silent when Bagman got around to the final category.

"AND OUT OF FIFTEEN FOR RESILIENCY: MATHEUS SOUSA, 15 POINTS! JACOB OWENS, 15 POINTS! ARCTURUS BLACK, 14! FLEUR DELACOUR, 13! HERMIONE GRANGER, 12! VICTOR KRUM, 10! TAHIIL DIRIC ZAHI, 6! FEIYAN SHANG, 6! AND ANTIOPE, 3 POINTS!" Bagman waited patiently for the cheers to die out before concluding, "IN FIRST PLACE THEN, WITH A TOTAL COMBINED SCORE FOR BOTH TASKS, JACOB OWENS WITH 91 POINTS! SECOND PLACE WITH 87 IS ARCTURUS BLACK! THIRD PLACE, HERMIONE GRANGER WITH 84 POINTS! VICTOR KRUM IN FOURH WITH 76 POINTS! FLEUR DELACOUR, FIFTH WITH 72 POINTS! SIXTH, FEIYAN SHANG WITH 48! ANTIOPE IN SEVENTH WITH 47! TAHIIL DIRIC ZAHI IS IN EIGHTH PLACE WITH 46 POINTS! AND BRINGING UP NINTH PLACE IS MATHEUS SOUSA WITH 44 POINTS! WELL DONE TO ALL THE CHAMPIONS, AND GOOD LUCK IN THE NEXT TASK!"

Finally, mercifully, Bagman's voice cut out and left their throbbing eardrums in peace. Rigel turned back to her friends and smiled somewhat ironically. "There now, that's not so bad. Congratulations, Owens," she added, raising her voice so the muggleborn could hear.

He shrugged in a way that would have been self-deprecating, had his chin not been held so high. "Like I said, it was mostly luck."

"Still, congratulations," Hermione said, smiling brightly. It was evident how pleased she was for two muggleborns to be represented in the top three champions. "You too, Tahiil," she called to the still disappointed-looking Somali boy.

Tahiil shook his head grimly. "I was not fast enough to counter the flower. Just as I was not fast enough at overcoming the puzzles in the forest. Truly, I see the advantage of a formal education."

Hermione had a dismayed look on her face, but she said, bracingly. "Just think, though—after this tournament you'll be somewhat famous, Tahiil. I'm sure many schools would be happy to sponsor you if you wanted to attend."

The boy's open face melted into a cheerful smile. "You are right. Perhaps I can also bring my brother. I must not forget that to compete at all is a bright opportunity!" Rigel had to smile at his newfound enthusiasm. Shang didn't look nearly so ready to bounce back from her disappointment. Tahiil noticed too, for he said, "Will your sponsors be very upset, Feiyan?"

A flush of shame crossed her pale cheeks. "I think yes. I make a bad attempt."

Even Fleur, normally rather callous, winced at Shang's downtrodden face. "It eez not your fault you are scared of heights."

Shang nodded, but it was obvious she wasn't convinced. Sousa huffed a laugh on his way out of the box. "Cheer up, Feiyan. You're still three places ahead of me." Sousa caught Rigel's eye as he passed her and winked.

She felt Draco stiffen at her shoulder. A moment later he said, "We should get going, Rigel. My parents will want to congratulate you." Rigel nodded agreeably and bade the rest of the champions farewell, giving an extra smile to Hermione, who grinned back, still visibly pleased with her performance.

Her friends were quiet as they made their way down the stairs from the competitors' box, but as they made it to the pitch Pansy said, "Very well done, Rigel. Second place looks good strategically at this point in the tournament."

"Second place to a muggleborn?" Rigel clarified, her eyebrows raised. She didn't quite understand Pansy's reasoning.

"The points are close, and you're still firmly in the lead of the pureblood category. Having other categories represented in the top three makes the whole tournament appear more legitimate," Pansy said quietly, checking first to make sure no one was near enough to hear.

"It helps that you're only in second because they docked you five points for destroying the course," Draco added sardonically. "Now the tournament seems fair, and you'll still have people who secretly believe you deserve to be in first. It's a win-win."

Rigel sighed. "Of course it is, with Riddle determining the scores."

Pansy frowned at her. "Lord Riddle doesn't get a say in the scoring," she said slowly. Realization dawned and her scowl deepened. "You didn't read any of the supplemental reading Millie and I gave you, did you?"

"Ah. Not exactly," she admitted, wincing.

It was Pansy's turn to sigh. "There are five official judges. Mr. Bagman and Mr. Crouch, of course. Then there's Griselda Marchbanks, head of the Wizarding Examination Services." Rigel looked sharply at Pansy, wondering if she'd misheard. Misinterpreting her surprise, Pansy added, "Who better qualified to judge relative adolescent magical ability?"

Rigel nodded. "Makes sense." It seemed like a conflict of interest, though, considering the life debt the elderly witch had once pledged her. "Who else?" she asked, more out of obligation to satisfy Pansy's disgruntlement than out of real interest.

"Horace Slughorn and Lord Raoul Goldentower."

"Slughorn? The Potions master? I've read his work on Felix Felicis. It's brilliant," Rigel said. Despite herself, she appreciated the idea of a potioneer on the tournament judging panel.

"Of course that's how you know him," Draco said, chuckling a little. "Slughorn isn't just an academic. He's an incredibly well-connected politician, too."

Rigel hummed uninterestedly.

"He was a Hogwarts professor from the thirties to the eighties," Pansy told her, amusement lurking in her eyes. "I hear he called in a number of favors from former students to be chosen for the honor."

"How'd Goldentower get chosen, then?" Draco asked. His tone didn't indicate a surplus of good feeling toward the name.

"Lord Goldentower is notoriously Neutral, and his partner founded that correspondence school for the lesser bloods. Including him and Madam Marchbanks together makes the judging panel above reproach."

Rigel wasn't so sure of Pansy's assessment. "Even if Riddle doesn't get a vote, he's still in the box with them while they're deliberating, isn't he? I bet he's still influencing the scores."

"I'm sure Lord Riddle is the picture of impartiality," Pansy hissed, warning in her eyes as they neared the center of the pitch where a group of adults stood in a loose cluster.

Rigel picked out her family easily, as well as the Malfoys, the Grangers, and a number of other men and women who were probably related to the other champions. A tall, thin Asian man with a grim countenance caught her eye in particular, and she supposed by the constellation patterns embroidered down his sleeves that he was Shang's father. She hoped he wouldn't be too hard on the girl.

Sirius met her with open arms but Rigel, realizing she hadn't had a chance to reapply the Eau de Archie, shook her head with a wide grin. "No, Dad! I'm all sweaty!"

Sirius let his arms drop and settled for ruffling her grimy hair instead. He grimaced at the feel of dirt and sweat and said, "You weren't kidding. Still, great job, Arch! You nearly gave me a heart attack when you jumped off the edge of the path, but I have to admit using Harry's potion was clever."

"It was," Lily agreed, leaning around Sirius' form to smile at Rigel warmly. "We'd seen it at the World Cup, and it still caught us by surprise."

Remus elbowed Sirius to the side so he could smile down at Rigel and put a light hand on her shoulder. "You were brilliant, Archie. Had a little trouble with the runic barrier on the right-hand path, did you?"

Rigel grimaced. "Not exactly. It was a straightforward sequence. I just didn't want to do what it said."

"What?" Draco's alarmed voice had her glancing over to where he was waiting beside his parents, who had hung back to give Rigel's family the first chance to congratulate her. Rigel frowned at him and Draco frowned back. "How could you—I mean, weren't you worried about doing your best?"

The odd way he phrased it told her he was concerned about the Vow but didn't want to say so openly. She smiled reassuringly. "A little, but in the end the way forward was intolerable. So I chose another course very quickly, without dwelling too much on the consequences."

Draco did not seem reassured by that explanation, but Lord Malfoy looked terribly intrigued. "What was this intolerable way forward, then? A spell too costly to perform, perhaps?"

"Rigel has plenty of magic," Narcissa disagreed, smiling indulgently in her direction. "I think we all saw that when he overcame the shrinking ward."

"That was an incredible flare of magic, wasn't it?" James added, grinning proudly. "Reminds me of you, dear," he added to Lily, who swatted him without heat in retaliation.

"But what did the runic sequence want to you do?" Remus asked, frowning.

Seeing that he would not be distracted, Rigel grimaced. "It wanted blood. Human blood, specifically, so I couldn't just use my potions kit."

The adults grew sober around her, and James said sharply, "That's Dark magic."

The Malfoys all stiffened. "A blood ward itself isn't necessarily Dark," Narcissa said carefully, quelling her husband's fierce expression with a look. Lucius' nostrils flared but he didn't say anything as his wife added, "Nevertheless, we should not be encouraging children to spill their own blood so cavalierly."

Pansy made a noise of realization. "Rigel, you said once that willingly spilled blood can be quite dangerous if it falls into the wrong hands. Is that why you didn't do it?"

Rigel nodded, remembering the day she'd spilled blood into a goblet in the Malfoy gardens quite clearly.

"Smart lad," Sirius said, nodding firmly. "You made the right choice."

She wondered if all parties would see it that way. Rigel knew she was prone to paranoia when it came to Riddle, but she couldn't help but suspect that barrier had been there for a reason. Internally, she could justify the decision to move laterally in the task with the thought that if the barrier somehow had a recognition component to it, then it was a greater risk to her odds of winning the tournament to go through with it than it was to try another route. After all, if she was outed as a halfblood in the second task, there was no way she could 'do her best' in the rest of the tournament. The explanation could not be shared with Riddle, however. Would he wonder why the Vow had not stopped her from taking a different path? Would he believe that she had simply made the decision too fast for the Vow to react?

The other champions eventually made their way to the center of the pitch as well, picking out routes around the fallen debris of tiles. A few of them were still ominously colored, and Rigel was glad to see the tournament organizers coming toward their group. Surely they would take care of the hazards.

To her bemusement, however, Bagman and Crouch seemed more interested in socializing with the friends and families of the champions, and Riddle was nowhere to be seen. A tall man with greying hair, bright eyes, and a rather generous middle inserted himself into their group with a pleased, "Lucius Malfoy! It has been too long!"

Mr. Malfoy had an odd expression on his face when he greeted the newcomer. It was something between amusement and carefully jaded appreciation. "Horace, well met. I trust your duties have not been too taxing this day?"

"Taxing? It's an honor," the man said jovially. "I haven't had this much fun in ages. James, Sirius, so glad you could make it out today. Pitch looks a bit different than it did in your days at Hogwarts, eh?"

"You could say that," James allowed.

"I wouldn't call it an improvement," Sirius added wryly, looking around at the rubble in false consideration.

Delighted laugher poured out of the taller man's throat. "Always quick with a joke, this one. Yes, I remember well. And who might this young man be?" He peered down at Rigel with unconcealed fascination, and she wondered if he meant to be as alarmingly interested as he came across. There was no way he didn't know who she was, either.

"As if you couldn't guess," Sirius said, wagging his eyebrows. "This is my son, Arcturus Black, who prefers to go by Archie—or Rigel, for his friends. Arch, this is Horace Slughorn, best Potions professor who ever lived."

Ignoring the subtle dig at Snape, Rigel extended her hand politely and said, "It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance, sir. I'm a great admirer of your work."

"Oh?" Slughorn's eyebrows quivered as his smile curled upwards. "What work might that be, young man?"

"Well, all of it," she admitted, "but I particularly enjoyed the essay on your demonstrated improvements to Zygmunt Budge's centennial recipe for Felix Felicis."

Slughorn raised a hand to his chest dramatically and cried, "My word! A potioneer indeed! I admit I suspected Severus might be exaggerating just a tad. Your work with the dried chimera eyes—if I'm not mistaken—was a delight to witness today, Rigel."

"Thank you, Master Slughorn," she said, smiling a little. "I hadn't expected anyone to recognize the ingredient in that context."

"I've a sharp eye," Slughorn agreed.

"Those weren't exploding beans?" Sirius looked genuinely surprised.

"It is good to know someone with an appreciation for talent is on the judging panel," Narcissa said smoothly. Sirius shot her a scowl, but oddly, he didn't seem to mean it.

Slughorn's smile was irrepressible. "Oh, Narcissa, you do flatter an old man. I must say it is a delight to have a potioneer in the competition. Your handling of the werewolf in the first task was quite admirable, you know. And of course that leap you made! Why, I don't think I've seen a potion with quite the same effect before,"

His curious gaze waited for an explanation. Rigel smiled. "Both potions are my cousin's invention. I'm sure she'd be happy to send you a sample."

"Miss Potter, yes of course," Slughorn said, shooting James and Lily an emphatic look. "Your daughter has been keeping us all on our toes at the Guild."

"That's Harry," James said weakly. "Full of surprises."

"I wouldn't have done so well without her help," Rigel put in for good measure. She wanted no one to think it odd that she'd used so many of 'Harry's' skillsets in the tournament. "Every week she sends me more potions that might be useful."

"No amount of potions can teach level-headedness in the face of danger," James said firmly. "You've got that all on your own, sport."

"Well said! And a very Gryffindor attitude," Slughorn remarked slyly. "I daresay old habits are hard to kick. I myself was in Slytherin as well when I attended this grand school," he told Rigel in a confidential tone. "But of course, I didn't discriminate based on House as a professor. I pride myself on recognizing talent wherever it comes from."

Rigel couldn't help noticing Lily and Remus exchanging a wry look behind Slughorn's back. She didn't miss the fact that Remus had not been included in the conversation at all, despite having been at Hogwarts with James and Sirius when Slughorn was teaching there.

"Then it's no wonder you were one of only five wizards chosen to judge the tournament," she said, letting a light of admiration enter her eyes as she looked up at him.

The ex-professor wagged a finger at her obsequiousness, but there was an undercurrent of satisfaction there nonetheless.

Slughorn didn't seem like an overly bad sort, and his potions work was unquestionably superb, but she wondered how a man so transparently easy to please could do so well in politics, too. Perhaps it really was that simple, she thought. If you had no ulterior motives, people were more likely to trust you and solicit your help or advice. Maybe Slughorn's desire to be praised and acknowledged was effective precisely because it was so seemingly easy to oblige.

The Potions master left their company shortly thereafter, off to wrangle an introduction to the other champions he considered interesting, she didn't doubt. The Malfoys stayed just long enough to convey their sincere congratulations to Rigel on the completion of the second task before they, too, made their goodbyes.

Draco and Pansy hesitated, clearly not wanting to leave Rigel's side, but she gave them a reassuring smile and said, "I'll catch up with you in the common room. My family will probably stay a while longer, if they're allowed."

"We've got another…twenty minutes before we're escorted out of the wards," Sirius confirmed after a quick Tempus Charm.

Pansy gave Rigel a quick smile and gracefully bade the adults farewell. Draco was less smooth, nodding without saying anything but casting a long, lingering look her way as Pansy took his arm to leave the pitch.

Rigel kept her face even, not willing to reveal even the slightest amount of her internal discomfort in front of her family. Archie would never hear the end of it if Sirius or James picked something up about her increasingly complicated relationship with Draco from her expression or voice. She just knew Sirius had been eagerly awaiting the day he could tease his son about his first crush, but this was not something she was willing to allow. The circumstances were too confusing. Too personal.

She pretended to listen to her family's exuberant recounting of the second task, including all the parts she'd missed while stuck in the tent, but her mind kept wandering back to Draco. Why couldn't she find an equilibrium with regards to him again? Would it be like this between her and Leo when she went back to the alleys over winter break, too? Romance was so annoyingly intrusive, she fumed silently. It ruined otherwise perfect friendships, burdened her relationships with both Leo and Draco with some kind of vague expectation that she felt incapable of meeting. However patient or understanding their regard—and she had to admit that both Leo and Draco had been very understanding, in their own ways—it was still there, hanging in the air between them like the ghost of what could have been.

Rigel forcibly refocused her attention on her family. Family was a different kind of complication these days, she thought. The crisscrossing weight of different personas, lies, and truths all mixed together was getting heavier. Every task they attended was a risk that she might expose herself—might be forced to reveal a skill that Archie had no way of recreating—in the name of winning.

With that in mind, she thanked them profusely for coming as their twenty remaining minutes dwindled to a close. Then, she paused, biting her lip in the way Archie often did when he didn't want to say something but didn't know how to hold it back, either. Sirius, of course, noticed at once.

"What is it, Arch?" He searched Rigel's eyes for some hint of the source of her sudden reticence. "Are you handling everything okay?"

She nodded, though she did it unconvincingly. After a worried look between Sirius, James, Lily, and Remus, she said, "I was just thinking, the next task is going to be harder, isn't it? They keep getting harder, and I'm so grateful that you all keep coming to support me, but…"

"But what, Archie?" James looked concerned now, too.

"I just…" She sighed, just as Archie would have when he was on the verge of giving into his own, irrepressible honesty. "It's hard sometimes, knowing you're all watching me compete. Sometimes I get so nervous. I don't want to disappoint you."

"You could never disappoint us." Sirius said it so fiercely that Rigel had a hard time continuing. She knew she had to, though. The more her family saw, the more elaborate the lies would become.

"But what if I did?" She let her eyes grow wet, thinking of how Archie would feel to know she was straining his relationship with his father again for her own ends. "Sometimes I want to try things, take risks, but knowing you're watching I just can't."

"What are you saying, Archie?" Lily asked, a soft sympathy in her tone. "You'd rather we didn't come to the tasks?"

Bless her for saying it. Archie would not have been able to. Rigel didn't have to fully affect the miserable expression on her face as she shrugged helplessly. "I don't know. I just—I don't know."

Remus, insightful and empathetic to a fault, said softly, "We don't want to add to the pressure you're already under. If it's easier for you to focus on the tasks without us watching, just tell us. All we want is for you to get through this tournament safely. None of us want you to feel as though you have to perform well for our sake."

"He's right," James said firmly. "Whatever will help you concentrate on what's important—that's what we want."

Rigel smiled tremulously. "I don't want you to think I don't want your support. It means more to me than you can know." She let her voice crack just slightly. "It's hard to disregard your presence, though. Everyone else I can block out while I'm in the task, but you all…you're too important to me. Wondering what you're thinking as you watch me compete is sort of…" She trailed off into a whisper for the last word. "Distracting."

As Sirius' face crumpled, she felt like the worst sort of monster. Surely, there was a special circle of hell reserved for people who brought that exact expression of dismay and crushing helplessness to a parent's face.

"I'm sorry," she whispered, turning her face down in shamed remorse.

"No," Sirius said, a hitch in his voice. "Don't be. It's…okay. I understand, Arch. If it will help, we won't come to the tasks. As long as you know that we do support you. We're here for you, whatever you need."

Rigel flung herself into Sirius' arms, pretending to stifle a sob in her throat. "Thanks, Dad. I know you'll love me no matter what. I'll tell you everything that happens, and I promise I'll be safe. I just…I have to do this on my own. You know?"

Sirius tucked her head under his chin and squeezed her tight. "I know, Arch. I wish I could fight this battle for you, but I know I can't. If you need us to support you from afar, then that's what we'll do. Right, everyone?"

Rigel pulled back to see James, Remus, and Lily all nodding solemnly. She didn't have to summon the tears that filled her eyes at their unwavering understanding and support. They came all the same.

It was a tearful goodbye all around. Rigel watched the four adults whose unconditional love she didn't deserve move toward the gates and took a moment to compose herself. There in the center of an empty stadium, surrounded by the physical remnants of her own magic's destructive capabilities, she'd never felt so alone.

By the time she felt ready to rejoin her classmates in the castle, the other champions had long gone, and Rigel was the last one on the pitch. The sun was beginning to set, and in its wake a brittle cold settled over the evening. Rigel trudged toward the exit, turning the day's events over in her mind and marveling at the idea that she was a third of the way through the cursed tournament. That was something, at least.

As she passed under the stands on the way out of the stadium, a voice that might have been conjured from her nightmares floated toward her on a hiss that was almost a sigh.

"You were incandescent today, Rigel. You're well on your way to achieving everything you want."

She almost kept walking. Only the thought that he must be truly desperate to speak to her if he'd been lurking under the bleachers for an untold amount of time, and the subsequent deduction that if that was the case he would be willing to follow her up to the castle, stayed her feet.

"You're the man of the hour, not me," she said, turning to peer into the shadows. "Isn't this tournament about accomplishing what you want, and nothing else?"

"I never do anything for just one reason," Riddle said, emerging from the shimmer of a strong Disillusionment Charm and stepping close enough to discourage speaking at a normal volume. He wore a deep shade of midnight blue, and whether he meant it to or not the fabric seemed to disappear at the edges, so that Riddle almost looked as though he was floating within the shadows, rather than in front of them. "That is something you are too young to understand as yet. Still, you're far from hopeless. I see Severus has been training you well."

She had nothing to say to that, and kept her face blank. Rigel was as yet still furious at the man for attempting to circumvent the Vow they'd made by pushing through his odious marriage legislation early.

He took in her expressionless silence and tilted his head, allowing his cold eyes to narrow thoughtfully. "You do not approve of Severus' lessons?" he guessed.

Rigel fought against a sneer. That's what he thought she was annoyed about? "I don't care about that."

"What do you care about, Rigel Black?" Riddle loomed over her, so close she would swear she could feel the unwanted resonance between them, buzzing under her skin. It was probably in her head.

"You lied to me," she bit out after debating the wisdom of keeping quiet.

"Careful what you accuse me of, boy." Gone was the silken, indulgent tone. Riddle's voice could have cut glass.

"I know what you've been doing, what the S.O.W. Party's been doing to push the Marriage Law through." Her face was growing warm with the effort of keeping her anger in check. "You said you would withdraw that legislation—"

"If you win," he hissed. It took her a moment to realize he had slipped into Parseltongue. Whether from fury or a desire for secrecy she didn't know. "I sssaid I would withdraw the attempt if you win. And I will. Unlessss it passsesss firssst."

"The implication—" she tried, but he cut her off again.

"Don't be a fool. Did you really think I'd let it go—the work of yearsss—without ssso much asss a fight?" Riddle dropped the Parseltongue to laugh low at her frustrated expression. "Oh, Rigel. I know you're more intelligent than this. In any case, you are mistaken if you think your protest will sway me. We've already struck our deal. While you may hinder my efforts for future legislation after this tournament, the Marriage Law is too important."

"There are other ways to consolidate your power base," she snapped. "Ways that don't step on individual freedoms."

Riddle shook his head, almost pityingly. "You can't begin to understand my reasons. And you don't have to. You don't get a say at all, I'm afraid." At her mutinous expression, his smile, if anything, grew. "Think of this as a learning opportunity, Rigel. A lesson on formulating agreements. One day, you may even thank me."

I'll never thank you for anything, she thought, her eyes flashing with the force of her defiance.

"Speaking of lessons, the offer still stands, you know." Riddle's face was open, expectant. Rigel couldn't fathom his meaning.

"What offer?"

Impatience clouded his expression before he tossed it off with an annoyed jerk of his head. "Your magic, Rigel. I can help you train it. Severus has been very helpful, but his preparation is methodical. Thought-driven. You won't be able to think your way through the next task."

"Is that so?" Rigel had to wonder if this was his true reason for forestalling her when she was alone. Was he here to warn her about the next task directly? It still irked her that he thought she needed his intervention to win, but she was not so prideful as to refuse the information. In this, at least, their goal was the same, and the sanctity of the tournament's moral ground meant little to her when she understood the purpose behind its fair façade.

He seemed to know that she couldn't resist listening to whatever information he deigned to give her, for he was smiling once more. "The third task will test your reflexes, your magical ability in the most immediate and dangerous of circumstances. And your opponent won't be a creature or runic array without the intelligence to fight back."

Rigel blinked, almost surprised at its simplicity. "You're talking about a duel."

"Very good." He smirked down at her. "Given enough time, I can make you unequaled in this arena. Even with just a handful of days under my tutelage, you would be nigh unstoppable."

This time, Rigel smirked back at him. "I can handle my own training for this one."

His subtly cajoling smile turned sour. "Have you stopped to think about the opportunity you're spurning out of this childish spite? There are a great many wizards who would be grateful to be in your position," he snarled.

"Then go find one of them," she breathed, utterly perplexed as to why he insisted on…what? Mentoring her? It was absurd. Did he think her hatred for him was something changeable? Some fleeting fit of adolescent pique? He would learn otherwise.

She stalked away from the stadium, from Riddle, and from the unbridled aggravation he kindled in her heart. In fact, she thought as she made her way swiftly up the long lawn, he'd already given her the perfect platform from which to cement her opposition, hadn't he? If she made it to the final round, she wondered how many people would be interested in hearing the pureblood champion's take on the new legislation the S.O.W. Party was so confidently proposing. More than none, she thought darkly. And that's a start.

Chapter 10

December landed on wings of ice and roared with the breath of an irritable grizzly. The first Thursday afternoon after the second task found Rigel bundled to her ears, making a slow tunnel through the soft snow toward the Forbidden Forest. Treeslider was curled against her chest, hissing a litany of doubtful words under three layers of clothing.

"The wind isss much too sssearing, Ssspeaker." The boomslang snake's voice came floating up to her ears, and Rigel tucked her chin in response.

"Thisss wasss your idea," she hissed into the neck of her jumper.

"Your nessst isss ssso warm," Treeslider said plaintively. "How wasss I to know thisss monssstrousss ssstorm awaited usss?"

"I sssaid it wasss cold," Rigel said, chuckling a little at the snake's dramatics. It had long since stopped snowing, and was now only blowing the fresh powder back and forth.

"Ssspeaker isss known to have a poor underssstanding of heat."

Rigel thought Treeslider had a poor understanding of words, but she didn't want to argue with the snake. Instead, she stopped moving toward the forest and said, "Doesss thisss mean you don't want to sssee how your nessst isss doing today?"

Treeslider shuddered against her torso. "It isss lossst under thisss messss. We mussst return to the ssstone foressst before we freeze."

"All right." She sighed. Would that the snake had made this determination before she'd slogged halfway across the grounds.

A familiar voice called out from the swirling winds, an unfamiliar tone of urgent amusement in its pitch.

"Save me! Rigel, stop them!" Hermione was tearing across the lawn, bright blue scarf trailing behind her like the tail of a kite. She rounded Rigel and ducked down behind her, as though Rigel's unimpressive girth was capable of shielding her from sight in this expanse of white.

Only a dozen paces behind her, two bundles of burgundy were committed in a headlong charge. Rigel felt mischief curl within her. "When I say so, jump to the side," she murmured to the girl doubled over in breathless laughter behind her.

She waited until the Weasley twins were near enough to see the whites in her eyes. Her arms outstretched, she said, "Guys, we can talk about this like reasonable—now!"

Rigel and Hermione leapt out of the way, and the twins, who'd each taken a running lunge to cover the last several feet, fell in an explosion of powder and spluttered outrage. Fred came up first, spewing, "Traitor!" alongside a mouthful of snow.

George shook himself like a dog, sending wet misery everywhere in a three-foot radius. "N-no fair!" he said, taking his feet with some difficulty. Rigel schooled her face to blankness, refusing to give sympathy to the boys who would have cheerfully plowed her into the snow.

"What are you doing, chasing Hermione?" Rigel asked them, folding her arms in a posture of mock sternness. "When I introduced you, I'm sure I mentioned she was under my protection."

Fred scowled up at her from his seat in the snow. "You can't have all the good ones, Pup!"

"I left you Ron, didn't I?"

Fred pursed his lips. "Ron doesn't squeal like he used to."

Hermione let out a helpless laugh. "Why is everything here so weird?"

"It's Hogwarts," the twins chorused. The looks on their faces indicated the statement should be self-evident.

"You get used to it," Rigel offered. After a moment's thought, she frowned. "Actually, you never should. Harry won't forgive me if I send you back weird."

"Harry is even weirder," Hermione muttered.

From her point of view, that may very well be the case, Rigel allowed. She turned back to George, who was now helping Fred brush the powder from his pants. "Why chase Hermione when there are so many more deserving souls in this world?"

George smiled, and it was so innocent she automatically suspected a lie. "We just wanted to invite her to the Burrow this summer."

Rigel allowed that to sink in for a moment before asking, "In what language is pursuit equivalent to an invitation?"

Fred's expression was pitying as he drawled, "If you don't know the answer to that by now, Pup, you may never figure it out."

Before she could retort, George punched his brother lightly in the arm and said, "No! Bad, Forge, corrupting the Puppy."

"Did they not see you face down a dragon?" Hermione's tone was altogether bewildered.

"Fred and George have known me too long to be in awe," Rigel said. She found she was grateful for the thread of truth woven behind the humor as she spoke. "I can say the same, though. They try to pretend they don't care about anything except fun and chaos, but these two once braced a first year's fractured wrist when he was too scared to go to the Mediwitch."

"Aww, Puppy!" Fred fell into her arms, and subsequently windmilled backwards just as quickly, once Treeslider made himself heard from the confines of her shirt. "Why is your shirt speaking in Parseltongue!?"

She brushed a soothing hand over the front of her jumper, murmuring comforting nothings to her familiar until he stopped threatening to eat the clumsy sack of flesh that had disturbed his slumber.

"Is that the snake from the first task?" George asked, leaning close and peering in the general direction of her torso as though he could see through the layers to the irritable boomslang snake within.

She resisted the urge to shy backwards from his gaze, knowing intellectually that there was nothing but a lumpy jumper to see. "His name is Treeslider," she said. "After the difficulties in the forest, he's been somewhat…resistant to rehabilitation." Not that she minded, really. Rigel felt rather selfish, but part of her wanted to keep the snake. He was a wild creature, not some pet. Still, each time he declined to go back to the forest her heart warmed a little more toward the idea of enjoying his companionship indefinitely.

"He was very brave for you," Hermione said, frowning thoughtfully. "Did you know him before the task, or did you use your gift to find him when you learned the task was in the forest?"

"I met him my first year here," she admitted. "He's been a better friend than I probably deserve."

"Friendship isn't about deserving anything," George said firmly. "It just is."

Rigel smiled, but she knew it was wan. Easy for some to say, she supposed.

"As long as we're on the spirit of friendship," Fred declared, looking between Hermione and Rigel with a deviously innocuous expression. "We really did want to invite you over to the Burrow this summer. Both of you, actually. Bring Harriet too, Rigel. It'll be fun."

She could honestly say she'd never spent a day at the Burrow that wasn't fun. Hectic, farcical, and exhausting, yes, but unmistakably fun.

"They keep telling me this mythical 'Burrow' is somehow held together with magic alone," Hermione said, openly dubious. "It isn't possible, though, to build something out of magic like that." Her eyes darted to Rigel's and she added, almost against her better judgment, "Is it?"

Rigel considered her answer carefully. Hermione was, she had noticed, painstakingly correct in all things. "It has to be done slowly, over time, but yes, eventually it is possible for magic to compensate or even take the place of regular materials. It just depends on how much magic is regularly imbued into the foundational wards. Hogwarts is a great example of that, actually."

Hermione looked vaguely disturbed. "Are you saying the castle is only held up by magic at this point?" She didn't seem comforted by the idea.

"No, don't listen to Pup!" Fred exclaimed. "He doesn't live in a centuries-old house stitched together with magic and love."

"But…you do?" Hermione clarified.

"Sure!" George said cheerfully. "And we can tell you all about it."

"You can?"

Rigel grimaced as Hermione took the bait like a starving guppy. It's a trap, she thought at the poor girl. Don't do it.

Alas, Hermione was no Legilimens.

"Boy, can we!" George looped one of his arms through Hermione's, and it was the beginning of the end for the girl. "The Burrow's primary wards date back several centuries. As you probably know, when subsequent wards are added within an existing set, the two works can be fused to become a single ward. This is the principle behind the Burrow's magnificence."

Fred appropriated Hermione's free limb, picking up the narrative seamlessly. "Indeed, Milady, and the more wards you add to the original as the years pass, the stronger the original ward becomes. Anyone trying to take down the Weasley wards now would have to not only break the power of the original Weasley who cast them, but also overcome the magic of every additional ward that's been cast there since!"

"But what if the wards are contradictory in nature…?" Hermione was gone before Rigel could send a prayer to Merlin for her sanity.

She returned to the castle at her own speed; a part of her enjoyed the bracing bite of the winter wind against her face. It felt real, in a way that the surrealism of the tournament and all the drama orbiting in its sphere never did. Sometimes it was hard to remember what she'd entered this absurd competition for. Just as sometimes it was hard to remember how deeply she was entrenched in the ruse. She tried not to think about it, mostly. It would only overwhelm her to consider the true implications of the wide, furrowed web she and Archie had managed to weave.

Rigel found her plate positively buried beneath packages Friday morning. A heavy parcel from Flourish and Blotts contained several books on rituals that she'd catalogue-ordered after running through most of Hogwart's unrestricted references on the subject. Lily's use of a ritual to imbue the obsidian necklace had refocused her interest in the subject, and she was certain there was a connection between Dumbledore's story about a witch who transferred her magic to another and the bottle of Riddle's magic slowly accumulating in her mindscape.

She set the books aside and took the letter from the next package curiously. It was from Archie, and he advised her not to open it at the table. She heard the rattle of potions vials as she tucked the small rectangle into her bookbag and smiled. It seemed her cousin had sent the additional samples of blood she'd asked for. Rigel already had enough for one unexpected blood identity test, but after the barrier she'd encountered in the second task, she wanted enough for each of the remaining tasks, too.

The last parcel was soft, and contained both a letter and a number of pages from a Muggle newspaper that were yellowed with age. Rigel couldn't help but smile in anticipation as she perused the politely-worded reply to an inquiry she'd sent to the Little Hangleton public records office. Hermione had helped her find the correct address, and after that it was a simple matter of dropping it into the muggle-mail slot at the Hogsmeade owlery.

Dear Mr. Riddle,

Your research has led you to right place, but I regret to inform you that the search for your estranged family is not yet at an end. The Riddle family did indeed have a prominent branch seated in our town for a number of generations, and in fact owned much of the town itself at one point. In 1943, however, Squire Riddle sold the family holdings to the town council and moved his entire family with very little warning.

Unfortunately, Thomas Riddle did not provide any forwarding address. We have heard no news of the family since they left Little Hangleton. In order to facilitate your search, I have included every mention of the Riddle family I could find in our town archives. If you do discover where the subsequent generations of the Riddle family ended up, I hope you'll write again and let me know. It would be a satisfactory conclusion to a mystery that has interested the townsfolk for many years!

Best of luck in your endeavor.

Sincerely,

Agatha Spool

Little Hangleton Archives

Rigel's grin was threatening to spill over her face as she set the letter aside and thumbed through the muggle newspaper clippings. She had no interest in the many articles about Squire Riddle's shady business dealings or Mary Riddle's social proclivities. As she flipped past an article about the acquisition of a large tract of land that had been originally set aside as a primary school, she found it: an edition from 1926 with the brazen headline 'Squire's Son Elopes With Local Tramp!' splashed across the front page. It was exactly the sort of gleefully salacious article one might expect from a small town with no love for its richest constituents.

The text contained more speculation than fact, but one thing appeared to be indisputable: Tom Riddle, handsome son of Squire Thomas Riddle, had absconded suddenly and most perplexingly to London with one Merope Gaunt, daughter of local vagabond Marvolo Gaunt. The picture painted of Merope was not pleasant, and it was clear to Rigel that the townspeople suspected there was much more to the story. Dashing and wealthy young men did not often take up with the backwater, squalor-bred women of the world without the impetus of blackmail, villainy, or both.

It's indisputable, she thought. The feeling of triumph that rushed through her was almost giddy. Tom Riddle is a halfblood. Given the Riddle family's sudden relocation, she reckoned he'd tried to cover his heritage up by sending the Riddle family somewhere far away, but he couldn't obliviate every townsperson in Little Hangleton.

Her next thought cut through the giddiness with wariness. How in Merlin's name could no one else know? It had taken her less than a month of serious searching to put the pieces together. Was it really possible that no one else had ever wondered? Maybe he's silencing them, a grim voice offered. Or disappearing them, like he did his whole Muggle family.

With that ominous possibility ringing in her mind, she rolled up the newspapers and tucked them into her bag with the letter. As she straightened, she met Pansy's eyes, and the blonde girl leaned in from her seat beside her to ask, "What have you done, Rigel?"

The girl had probably caught the name Riddle on every newspaper article as Rigel flipped through them. Still, Rigel tilted her head carefully and asked, "Are you certain you want to know?"

Pansy stared hard at her for a long moment, but in the end, she shook her head and turned her worried eyes back to her own breakfast. "Be careful," was all she said.

Rigel smiled reassuringly, but inside she was torn. On the one hand, Riddle was a dangerous man, and he probably wouldn't hesitate to retaliate if he knew what she was up to. On the other hand, she thought too many people had been careful around him for too long. If those around him had been a little less careful and a little more suspicious, he might never have built the powerful mystique that let him waltz through the world without any regard for it.

There was, she supposed, at least one person she could speak to freely about it. All that morning in her Healing class she was semi-attentive at best, and she barely managed to choke down a few bites of food at lunch in her excitement. It was only after impatiently giving the gargoyle the password and hurrying up the spiraling stairs that she realized Dumbledore was still down in the Great Hall and she would have to wait for him to finish his meal before she could share her grand theory.

The wind in her sails sufficiently snuffed, Rigel sank into one of the soft, oversized chairs that littered the Headmaster's office and took out one of her new books to pass the time. It was titled Rituals of Transference and the table of contents told her it was broken into sections pertaining to familial and non-familial magical transfer.

She settled in to read, on the lookout for any use of transference magic that sounded potentially malicious. The subject matter turned out to be too interesting to skim, however, and she found herself nose-deep in a chapter about Bloodline transference when Fawkes trilled out a welcome. Rigel glanced up to see Dumbledore twinkling genially down at her.

"Are my clocks running slow today?" he asked curiously.

She flushed. "No, sir. I'm running early. There was something I wanted to ask you about before we began today's Alchemy lesson."

"Ah. In that case, why don't we address your question in comfort before adjourning to the workroom?" He rearranged a chair so that it was facing hers with a whimsical flick of his fingers and called for tea and biscuits. The soft, gooey sweets wafted chocolate fumes her direction and Rigel, who hadn't eaten as much as she should have at lunch, accepted one with chagrined gratitude. "Now, to this lunch-averting matter," the Headmaster said with a wink. "What can I help you with today, Mr. Black?"

Rigel opened her mouth, and suddenly realized she had no idea where to start or how to explain her recent obsession with Riddle's genealogy. After a moment's hesitation, she pulled the bundle of newspaper clippings from her bag and selected the relevant one for Dumbledore's perusal. "I've been looking into Riddle's background," she said, grimacing. "I know it's a bit gauche, but I'm so tired of my friends calling him 'Lord Riddle' and acting as though he's the next coming of Salazar Slytherin."

Dumbledore's eyebrows rose as he rapidly scanned the paper's contents, but when he leveled his piercingly blue gaze at her, he showed no real surprise. "So you have discovered Tom's somewhat ignoble roots. I'm certain you're aware that he would prefer this knowledge never see the light of modern day."

"You knew?" Rigel frowned. "Sir, forgive me, but I don't understand why no one else does. This undermines everything he's been trying to do for the last fifty years. If it was leaked, it could change everything." As Dumbledore continued to look impassively grave, she added, "Couldn't it?"

Dumbledore sighed. "I am aware of Tom's heritage, in part because I was the professor sent to introduce him to the Wizarding World. While at Wool's Orphanage, I spoke with the proprietress about the circumstances of young Tom's arrival there. His mother only lived long enough to name him for his father and grandfather, but this information was sufficient to trace his origins the very same way you have now done."

"Why isn't it commonly known?" Rigel asked, still confused. "I mean, wouldn't people have asked while he was in school?"

"Tom himself was unaware of his lineage until very late in his school years, I believe," Dumbledore said slowly. "He was thought to be a muggleborn, at first, but when rumors of his Parseltongue ability began to circulate the school, that belief changed. After all, who ever heard of a Parselmouth who wasn't a pureblood?" The question, eerily reminiscent of something Draco had said, sent a thrum of unease through Rigel. Sometimes, it seemed Dumbledore's gaze was too perceptive. If she didn't have faith in Dom's ability to warn her of even the subtlest attempt at Legilimency, she might worry for her secrets.

Rigel considered the old man's words, but had to ask, "If you knew, why haven't you said anything? This could drastically affect his support base."

Dumbledore regarded her almost pityingly. "Tom will only deny it. All evidence aside, he will claim the Riddle name comes from the mystery of his origins, and that the muggles you traced until their disappearance were a mere coincidence."

"But if the speculation is made, he'd have to give some explanation, wouldn't he?" she asked. Even though part of her balked at essentially treating the halfblood label as an accusation, she knew that his supports would see it that way. Why not use it, then? "His mother is certainly Merope Gaunt. The Parseltongue gift, as well as the orphanage's records, would be proof of that. He'd have to give some account of his father. Who else could he claim?"

"I believe he would probably name Morfin Gaunt, if pressed." The Headmaster said quietly.

Rigel gaped at him. "His uncle?"

"Incest is more palatable than the truth, to those who would care in the first place," Dumbledore reminded her gently.

She grimaced in distaste. "But even still, Morfin was in prison for three years." She shook her head. "It just isn't possible. Riddle's birth date is listed as a year and a half after his uncle's imprisonment. Unless you're suggesting Merope went to Azkaban for conjugal visits with her brother…" She attempted to say it sarcastically, but as the words came out of her mouth she realized with horror that it was exactly what some might suggest.

"There are those for whom even that explanation would be preferable." Dumbledore didn't seem disgusted or disappointed by that fact, merely resigned.

Rigel let out a huff of revulsion. "That's just…ugh. What is wrong with the world?" No matter which way she looked at it, Dumbledore was absolutely right. If she came forward with the information, not only would she paint a giant target on her back, but Riddle wouldn't even flinch. He'd probably play the embarrassed pureblood card and cagily admit that his parents had been siblings in unsanctioned lust. Better than that allow the whisper of a possibility that he, Lord Riddle, head of the S.O.W. Party and preeminent bigot in all of Britain, could be a halfblood.

All her research, for nothing. She bit through the biscuit in her hand with an annoyed growl. After chewing it over both literally and figuratively for a moment, she said, "I don't suppose we could force him to do a blood test." She didn't need Dumbledore's regretful look to tell her it was impossible. Riddle was simply too powerful to make him do anything he didn't want to do. Back to square one, then. Unless…she shot the Headmaster a considering look. "Maybe we could trick him, somehow. Is there any magic that only a pureblood can perform?"

Dumbledore frowned thoughtfully. "Apart from very specific inheritance magic, I'm not aware of anything. That is, of course, what makes the distinction largely superfluous in the first place."

Rigel flushed. "Yes, sir." Really, what had she been expecting? If there was an easy way to undermine Riddle, no doubt the Headmaster would have done it long ago. She glanced down at the book in her lap thoughtfully. "When you say inheritance magic, do you mean familial rituals? I'm reading about them now. There are a few that sound incredibly powerful, but it strikes me that I don't know any purebloods who would actually want to use one."

"How you do mean?" the Headmaster asked, a mild frown on his face.

"Well, a lot of the inheritance type rituals in this book seem to require significant sacrifice on one side. For instance, this line circumvention ritual—" She turned to the page and tilted the book so that Dumbledore could see the description. "—was designed around the transfer of familial gifts to an unrelated, lesser-blooded witch or wizard. The idea was that the last heir to a family could pass his or her gifts to a halfblood or muggleborn. This way, rather than allow the magic of an old line to go extinct or fade into obscurity as it blends into other strong pureblooded lines, the magic lives on even when the family dies out."

"I can't say I've ever heard of such a ritual being performed," Dumbledore said, his slow, elderly voice contrasting sharply with the speed at which his eyes roamed over the page.

Rigel nodded. "Exactly. Because what pureblood in existence would be both utterly selfless and utterly unprejudiced to the extent that they would sacrifice their own gift in order that another, less pure wizard might wield it instead?"

"All who come immediately to mind are also those for whom the passing on of family magic would not be a strong priority." As he said it, she wondered if he was thinking about Sirius. Even if her uncle had a family gift to pass on, he would never consider that it might be his duty to do so.

Really, there was something tragically ironic about it all. Purebloods liked to think of themselves as so very unique, but the type of magic that was truly exclusive to them was also that which would require them to give up that part of themselves in order to make use of it. She shook her head ruefully as she put the book away. "I suppose you've listened to me rail against the system enough for one day, Professor. Shall we, as you put it, adjourn to the workroom?"

"The system might be better-tempered if it had more occasion to resist a good railing," Dumbledore said with a chuckle. "Nevertheless, your father is paying good tuition for me to educate you, rather than the other way around."

"A wise man once said, 'education is a journey, not a destination, and as such may not be rushed,'" Rigel said, standing along with the aged professor.

"Which wise man was that?"

"Uncle Remus," she admitted, grinning briefly. "It was a shame he couldn't keep teaching here. Something should really be done about that curse."

Dumbledore inclined his head regretfully. "The only two cursebreakers to try their wands at lifting it were both irreversibly altered by the attempt. Since then, I have ceased commissioning the work, though I admit it is especially difficult to bear when it means bidding farewell to so dedicated an educator as Mr. Lupin." They crossed to the bookcase where Dumbledore pulled the secret lever to reveal his workspace. It never ceased to amuse Rigel that a wizard who was taken so seriously by so many had an irrepressibly whimsical streak. "Tell me, has your uncle found alternative work to satisfy him?"

She nodded slowly, recalling the last couple of letters from Remus. "I think so. He's begun tutoring a group of orphan kids who live in London. Not as structured an environment as Hogwarts, of course, but I think he enjoys the challenge and the chance to pass on what he knows to those who didn't receive the same opportunities he did."

Dumbledore smiled, but there was something incredibly sad about it. "Many are the risks that turned to regret over the years, and few the gambles brought to vindication. When I balance the scales of my life, however, I do believe the decision to admit Remus Lupin to Hogwarts will be one of the heaviest achievements in the basket of absolute good."

His words brought a lump to Rigel's throat, and she was abruptly reminded of her purpose in coming to Hogwarts in the first place. It hadn't been to challenge the system or prove herself to anyone. She had only come to learn, and sometime this year she had begun to lose sight of that ambition, a guiding star lost in a meteor shower. In the midst of everything raining down around her, she had to wonder if she would ever get back to that girl. And when all of it came to an end, in which basket would her decision to become Rigel Black fall?

Rigel walked into lab three the next morning ready to demand that Snape honor his bargain to teach her freebrewing in exchange for her making it through the second task and mastering projected magical awareness. She wore the unshakable determination like a cloak; this time, no matter how dangerous he claimed the next task would be, she would not be put off with more ancillary lessons. This time, they would brew. Snape was already within, and as he turned to greet her, she cut him off sternly.

"We are freebrewing today or I will transfer to Durmstrang and take up an apprenticeship with Master Montmorency," she declared.

The dark-haired man drew his spine in, increasing his already imposing height, and raised an unimpressed eyebrow at her. "Master Montmorency will never take an apprentice who can't even use his own eyes before speaking."

Rigel blinked. She leaned around her Head of House to see a cauldron sitting innocently at its brewing station and an array of ingredients laid out on the large countertop. "Oh." She felt the blood move into her cheeks and her chin drop an inch as her indignation lost its direction abruptly. "Good," she managed.

Snape watched with open amusement as she pulled on her protective apron, gloves, and glasses. Rigel couldn't begrudge him his humor at her expense, not when the warm glow of anticipation was climbing its way out from the deepest corners of her heart. She took up the brewer's position beside the workstation and gave the Potions Master her undivided attention.

"How do we begin?"

"There are differing philosophies when it comes to freebrewing," he told her. "The discipline is by its very nature non-standard. Some begin with a known recipe and attempt to alter it." He paused, as though gauging her reaction to the idea. Rigel pursed her lips. That didn't sound like true freebrewing. Snape's mouth curled into the semblance of a smile and approval slipped into his voice. "It is my opinion that such an approach only limits the imagination and stifles the entire process. It may be safer, but reward is always proportional to risk."

Rigel quite agreed. She didn't want to incrementally alter existing recipes until she reached an arbitrary threshold of different-enough. The point of freebrewing was to create something entirely new. "How did you learn?" she asked.

"Trial and error," Snape said. He grimaced in remembrance. "It was a frustrating and dangerous path—one I would not lead another down." Rigel frowned. The more she gleaned about his apprenticeship with Master Liu, the more she thought that not all brilliance lent itself to instruction. She was exceedingly fortunate that Professor Snape had both knowledge and the patience to impart it. Her Head of House gestured to the ingredients before her. "Instead, I have devised an introduction to this art that is both open-ended enough to foster free-thinking and limited enough to focus your efforts. What do most of these ingredients have in common?"

Rigel surveyed the counter slowly. Whether powdered, dried, or fresh, there were very few ingredients she couldn't recognize on sight. "All of them have effects on the mind," she said after a moment.

Snape inclined his head sharply. "You must come to freebrewing without a preconceived idea of how your potion will be constructed. Equally true, you must never put things into the cauldron without a purpose. The key, then, is to begin with a strict idea of what you want the potion to accomplish, and work backwards to the how."

She nodded slowly. It made a kind of sense, but she suspected she'd understand what he meant better when she actually did it.

"For now, I will set you goals and provide a semi-limited array of ingredients you may use," Snape said. He folded his arms across his chest and fixed her with a challenging look. "Your first potion must lessen a person's grief without also suppressing positive emotions."

Rigel's head tilted to one side as she thought. Interesting. Not just a blanket emotional suppressant, then. She waited to see if he would give her any other instructions, but her professor merely stared at her expectantly. With a slow grin, she snapped her magical awareness about her like a permeable shield and reached for the oils. Her hand hesitated for a moment over peppermint, but with a shake of her head she took the lavender oil instead and coated the cauldron.

As she set the fire to a mild temperature, Rigel ran through the various subtasks inherent in Snape's challenge. The brain was a complex series of balances, and she thanked her Healing training for giving her the vocabulary to express what she wanted to accomplish at the most basic level. More than anything, bad feelings flourished in the absence of good feelings. Foremost, then, she needed ingredients to increase norepinephrine for positive drive, serotonin for happiness, and dopamine for pleasure. Then something to cloud the sharp memories.

When the bottom oil was warm, she filled the cauldron halfway with plain water and turned up the heat until it simmered. Moving back to the counter, Rigel collected the petals and stigmas of a Crocus sativus plant first. The longer they steeped, the stronger the antidepressant effect would be. Next came root of Curcuma, sliced thin into rounds so unsettlingly orange she thought it must have been grown in a magical greenhouse. Chia seeds, ginseng, and powdered cocoa followed. She tipped a vial of raw honey into the pot and watched as it grew thin and dispersed as Rigel coaxed the fire higher.

Her sensitivity whispered along the edges of her concentration as she stirred clockwise, not counting so much as watching, waiting. Rigel resisted the urge to consciously imbue, reminding herself that as long as she was projecting her magical awareness, she probably didn't need to. She eyed the St. John's Wort, but in the end thought better of it; the powerful antidepressant was also unpredictably reactive. Without knowing exactly what it would do to the serotonin levels, it wasn't worth the risk. When the powder of the cocoa had completely dissolved, she removed the stirring rod and reached for two shining strands of hair. The first was Veela, and the second from the tail of a unicorn. She twisted the two hairs together and wound them around the stirring utensil before submersing it in the hot liquid. Rigel held it there, watching silver bleed slowly into the mixture, and when she felt the magic stop seeping into the potion, she removed the hairs, now blanched, and set them aside.

After a scoop of crushed Fae fruit to dull recollections, she sealed the bulk of the mixture with a layer of sunflower oil and sprinkled a handful of dried pixie wings across the top. Rigel thought the oil might allow the calmative magic of the pixie to seep into the potion without risking a reaction with the fairy fruit.

She was wrong. Her potion tried to explode—tried, because, just as the reaction began, Rigel flooded the cauldron with magic. The reaction froze before it could go any further, stalling into a kind of half-putrefied state, and Rigel thanked Snape's stubborn insistence on her perfecting her magical awareness that she got to keep her eyebrows.

Rigel let out a slow breath and stepped back from the cauldron with a sigh. She glanced over at her professor and surprised a look of utter astonishment on his normally impassive face. "What is it?" she asked, a frown sliding onto her face. "Was I supposed to wait for it to explode?"

He shook his head slowly and pulled a vial of thick, black sludge from his belt. She recognized the inertifying mixture as he poured it over her ruined cauldron and grimaced in rueful realization that he'd never expected her to create a viable potion on the first try. "Well done," Snape said, fixing her with a stare that was once again unfathomable. "Now, tell me what you did wrong."

"The sunflower oil wasn't strong enough to keep the fairy and pixie magic from reacting negatively," Rigel said at once. After a moment's thought, she added, "Maybe an entire layer of honey would have served better."

The Potions Master made a noise of agreement. "Why did you add the pixie wings at all? The potion as it stood prior to the addition of sunflower oil would in all likelihood have at least approached the goal."

Rigel shrugged. "I wanted something that would suppress the amygdala. That's where anger and fear reside, and I think those can be a part of grief, too."

"Interesting hypothesis," Snape said. "You'll write half a roll on that theory for next week." She nodded, and tested the heat of the cauldron with her hand beside it. Deeming it safe to touch, she carried it to the sink.

"That was fun," she said, looking over her shoulder. Rigel had expected freebrewing to be exhilarating, and perhaps intellectually satisfying, but she hadn't anticipated the sheer, untainted pleasure that came with creating something completely from scratch, with no recipe or rules to tell her what she should or shouldn't do within the cauldron. "Is it always fun?"

"When it isn't terrifying," Snape said drolly.

She laughed. It was impossible to imagine the serious professor being afraid of anything, so she supposed he only meant to tease her about the near-disaster that was her first attempt at the art. Never mind failure, she thought. She would try again. Now that she knew what it felt like, bringing a brew to life with nothing but the impulses of her own mind, Rigel didn't know how she could go back to relying solely on recipes. It would be like asking a bird to walk, after it had already learned to fly.

Well, she thought wryly, not fly, exactly. Glide, maybe.

Rigel helped her professor consolidate the ingredients into crates to take back over to lab one, and she thought nothing could ruin her good mood. Then Snape said, "Has Lord Riddle discussed his intention to prepare you for the third task himself?"

She growled audibly before she could stop herself. "I've no intention of humoring his attempts at mentorship. In case he doesn't get the picture, tell him kindly that I have a mentor—one who didn't shove his magic under my skin like some kind of human mosquito."

Snape winced minutely, perhaps in response to her analogy, but more probably at the reminder of what Riddle had done to her with the help of his own machinations the year before. "Have you…made progress in isolating the injection?"

Rigel scowled at him from under her lashes, not sure how much she really ought to tell him. He was as beholden to Riddle as ever, after all. "I've been looking into it. Given enough time, I think I can separate it from my own magic, but I still don't know what it was intended to do. Do you know?" she added, daring him with her level gaze to lie to her.

His expression was grave. "I have only suspicions. Lord Riddle never forgot that day you eavesdropped on our conversation in the Malfoy gardens. He does not have the subtlety required of the mental arts to recognize mental shields at a distance, as I do. It is my suspicion, therefore, that at least part of his intention was to mark you in a way that only he would recognize."

"It's not supposed to work like that," she said, frowning. "I've been reading about ritual transfer of magic, and the party who relinquishes a piece of his magic always loses touch with it as a consequence."

"There was no ritual that day," he reminded her. "No runes, no sacrifice. When you imbue magic into a potion, do you lose the ability to sense it?"

Her eyes widened. "No," she whispered. Then she shook her head. "But I can only sense the resonance when he touches me."

"It isn't your magic," Snape said. "What you perceive may not be a reflection of its limitations."

Her hands shook on a container of saffron and she stilled them with a desperate will. It was a terrifying thought, that she'd been wrong about how the magic he'd mixed with hers might be utilized. A fool she was to think Riddle would forget that her lack of aura allowed her to successfully eavesdrop on his private conversations more than once. She'd been so sure that he couldn't possibly track her with the bit of his magic swimming in her veins…but maybe it was all just wishful thinking.

Her Head of House caught her eye and said, with the air of someone stating the obvious, "If you refrain from attempting to hide from his immediate perception, it may not cause you additional difficulties."

It probably seemed simple to him. Snape had no idea as to her real concern. She'd thought avoiding any physical contact with Riddle would be tricky. This was much worse. How was she ever to be Harry Potter again, if Riddle could identify her as Rigel Black just by being in the same room? How was Archie to ever pretend to be Rigel in his presence? They couldn't until Riddle's magic was isolated and purged. A nuance in Snape's phrasing caught up to her and she looked sharply at his carefully blank expression. "What do you mean 'may not'? You think there is something else it could do?"

"If I am not wildly mistaken, Lord Riddle's primary motive in offering his tutelage in the first place was to convince you to use your magic in ways he deems beneficial," Snape said. His voice was so even as to be almost inflectionless, but she caught the hint of disapproval in the way he said 'tutelage.' He didn't think much of Riddle's teaching abilities either, then.

Rigel nodded easily. It had been obvious that Riddle wanted her to make the most of her powerful magic. "He wanted me to stop suppressing it."

"And he got what he wanted," Snape reminded her.

"That was due to circumstances beyond anyone's control," Rigel said quickly.

"Don't underestimate his hand in seemingly unrelated events." Snape looked down at her with a frown. "Did your magic not become more aggressive, harder to suppress, and more prone to defying your express will in the immediate aftermath of Lord Riddle's visitation?" Rigel blanched at the implication. Could that really have been his aim? To force her to deal with her magic by making it even more unruly than it had been? She began to shake her head slowly, wanting to deny Riddle any hand in what had occurred in the forbidden forest the previous spring. At her pained disbelief, her Head of House made an impatient noise. "Think, boy. The most obvious piece of evidence is one simple fact: Lord Riddle wanted you to confront your magic, and you did."

A dark scowl crept over her face. "Sure I did. Only after it killed Pettigrew, though." A hollow laugh escaped her. "If Riddle did have a hand in it, I guess the joke's on him."

Snape's hand came down on her shoulder and she snapped her eyes up to meet his storm-filled gaze. "You said the Dominion Jewel killed Pettigrew."

Rigel dropped her gaze first. "Both are true. The Jewel mummified him, but I suspect my magic was well on its way to crushing him by the time that happened." The words came out utterly detached, and all she felt was a distant resignation, a pity for circumstances that were no longer hers to alter.

Her Head of House growled. "Even if that's true, your magic was beyond your control at that moment."

"Maybe it was, or maybe it was acting on some subconscious desire I was afraid to acknowledge." She swallowed the bile that tried to rise at that admission. Steeling her stomach, she went on. "Even if I try to lay that at Riddle's feet—even if I believe his magic inflamed the wild, indominatable aspects of my magic to the extent that it acted more aggressively than it otherwise would have—that still leaves me with a handful of Riddle's magic and no idea what to do with it." She shuddered. "I hate that there's a piece of him in me. It makes my skin crawl."

"I understand," Snape said slowly. "However, I do not believe that some miniscule amount of him could make you any more or less than you already were. Any claim you perceive his magic has placed on you is symbolic. He cannot own you unless you let him."

Rigel's smile was brittle. "He owns me this year." She looked up at her professor with a determined expression. "It'll be worth it, though, if it crushes his awful legislation. If I win, things will be better for non-purebloods in Britain." She had to believe that.

Rigel found fire in her heart as she prepared to face the final preliminary task. Dueling was an arena she felt fairly comfortable in, but she knew that very sense of security might be her downfall.

Too many people knew Harry Potter's style of dueling. Even without Remus attending the third task, the chance that those who knew her in the alleys might catch the mirrored dissemination of the event was high. Rigel could not use any of Harry's tricks to succeed in the upcoming duels. Her only recourse was to prioritize speed above finesse, and hope to outclass her opponents in sheer efficiency alone.

The Room of Requirement obliged her needs, providing half a dozen panes of spell-reflecting glass that would throw anything she cast at them back in her face. Rigel trained with all of them, sometimes concentrating a flurry of spells on a single, shimmering pane, other times changing her target between every spell to test her footwork.

There were limits to the training. She could only practice countering spells she herself knew how to cast, so it would do nothing for the sort of tailored defense Dawlish was attempting to drill into their heads. Still, it was better than casting at a dummy that couldn't hit back.

By her third such session in the Come and Go Room, Rigel had ceased attempting to block any of the spells she cast. Instead, she moved the reflecting glass closer and closer, forcing her mind and muscles to react faster in order to avoid getting hit. There was something also dance-like about the exercise, and as her mind became clearer and her body lunged and twisted with increasing fluidity, she thought she finally understood what Remus had been trying to push her instincts toward all this time.

Such was the trance-like state her exercise inspired, Rigel didn't hear the door to the Room opening behind her. She didn't notice the footsteps that approached the circle of mirrors in which she spun, and she didn't realize she was no longer alone until Draco's voice called out, "What on earth are you doing, Rigel?"

She whirled to face him, and the spell she'd already cast sucker-punched her in the shoulder. Rigel hissed at the sharp Stinging Hex and rubbed her hand over the flesh with a huff of annoyance. "Draco," she said after the pain faded. "What are you doing here?"

"There's DA today," he said, stepping between a gap in the suspended panes of glass and examining them curiously. "I came early to set up. Do these reflect anything you shoot at them?"

"As long as it isn't more powerful than the magic that went into creating them," Rigel said absently. She felt an incomprehensible desire to wipe the sweat from her neck and brush back her hair, but she ignored it. The last thing she would ever do was primp for Draco Malfoy. A part of her wanted to collect her bag and just leave the room, but she was braver than that.

Draco turned away from the glass and silence stretched between them. Rigel didn't know what to say, and her friend's expression seemed suspended in some sort of cross between reluctance and regret. When she couldn't stand it anymore, she said, "This is ridiculous."

At the very same moment, Draco blurted, "I didn't mean to."

She stared at him. Blinked. Finally cleared her throat and asked, "Didn't mean to what?" She was pretty sure he had meant to kiss her. Unless someone had Imperiused him. That would be a pretty pathetic use for an Unforgivable Curse, though.

Draco blew out a frustrated breath. "I didn't mean to make it weird between us. This is why I never… before."

Her eyebrows rose against her will. He made it seem as though it hadn't been a spur-of-the-moment impulse. "Has this been malingering?" she asked, almost afraid to know the answer.

He laughed, a short, hoarse sound that cut off as abruptly as it had begun. "It's not an illness," he said, shaking his head. "Rigel, I've been interested for a while, all right? That night…I'd been thinking about you all day, since you reacted so strongly to my teasing." She winced, having already guessed that something about her embarrassment had triggered some underlying curiosity on his part. Draco wasn't finished yet, though, "I was half asleep, and getting all this feedback from my empathy, and I let myself get carried away. I'm sorry, okay? I wish I hadn't done it, with how it's changed everything."

Rigel sighed. Draco was dramatic, but she couldn't deny that things had changed, somehow. The kiss was like a wrong number in an Alchemical equation. A small mistake that had cascading effects. His expression beseeched her for forgiveness, and Rigel couldn't refuse her friend such a small thing. "I'm not upset, you know. I don't like you taking my emotions for permission, but I understand how you might feel…misled by your ability. That said, do you understand why I don't think this will work despite any feelings that may or may not exist? My life is complicated enough. Time is something I don't have to devote to a relationship. And there are other things," she added before he could speak. "You know about my…illness. Even if I returned your feelings, we would—could never progress beyond what it was that night."

Draco's face clouded. "I don't need—"

"Don't be an idiot," she said gently. At his scowl, she reached out to take his hand and pressed it between her own. "I know it's hard to redirect emotions when they've already gained momentum. I'm asking you to, though. For both our sakes, Draco." She took a deep breath and smiled wryly at him, even though it felt like a she'd swallowed a jar of snakes. "We would never work together. My goals preclude it. Really, though, that's a good thing. You're going to end up with someone a lot less crazy than me. Someone communicative and honest. Someone whose priority is you, Draco."

Her friend was visibly pained, but he swallowed the hurt and lifted his chin with a staidness that would probably do his father proud, had the man been present to see it. "You are crazy," he said bluntly. "And incredibly uncommunicative, most days. I don't pretend to understand all of your priorities, Rigel. Here's what I do know, though: I've never met anyone with your intelligence, courage, patience, or tenacity. If you think you don't shine brighter than everything and everyone around you, then you don't see yourself clearly at all. After knowing you, everyone else seems smaller, with petty problems and bland personalities." Rigel opened her mouth to protest, but Draco held up his free hand. "I'm not trying to argue with you. I can feel your determination from here, and I know better than to try to change your mind when it's made up. I just want you to understand why it might take me a little while to do what you want." He slipped his other hand from her grasp and shook his head ruefully. "No matter what you say, I don't think there's anyone in the world like you."

Rigel blinked the moisture back from her eyes and whispered, mouth twisting, "I promise you wouldn't want to fall in love with someone like me."

He grimaced, but didn't contradict her. "Are we still friends, then? I've missed you, lately."

She summoned a small smile. "I'll be your friend as long as I can, Dray. Even that much you might regret in the end. Just don't ask me for more. This time, I really mean no."

Draco peered at her, a frown tugging at his brow. "Why do you feel so foreboding? Don't scowl at me," he added, "You know it's a strain to turn off if you aren't Occluding."

Rigel rolled her eyes, but silently admitted that he was right. If she really didn't want him to read her emotions, she had the ability to prevent it. "It's nothing," she said after a moment, smoothing her feelings away to a place he couldn't see them. "Just an ominous feeling I have sometimes."

Perhaps he would have pressed her, if Pansy hadn't walked in at that moment. As it was, they exchanged bracing smiles and left the circle of mirrors to greet her. As her friends discussed the plan for that evening's DA meeting, Rigel thought at least some of the awkwardness between them had dissolved. Her heart felt lighter, and where there had been a ball of guilt and confusion in her gut there was now only a vague sense of soreness, like an infected boil that had finally been drained.

That feeling, too, would fade, she thought, and soon it would be as though nothing had ever come between them. Whatever the poets said of the power of romantic affection, true friendship was something far beyond it.

Thursday Rigel skipped lunch in favor of going to the library. She'd finally cracked open the Auror's Handbook that Dawlish had given her and found a long list of recommended spells, many of which she hadn't heard of. At the end of the section on spell choice was a footnote recommending Deter, Delay, Deny: Nonlethal Spells for Every Enemy, by Armando Dippet, and Rigel was curious to see whether Hogwarts stocked the book.

She found several copies in the Defense section, none of which looked terribly well-worn. She supposed when it was shelved next to Most Riveting Revenge Spells and 1000 Hexes and Jinxes, most people overlooked the more pacifist option. Rigel smiled as she tucked one of the copies under her arm, however. The less destructive magic she knew, the better, at least until the Vow no longer held her wand to the fire. She had no illusions about how the next task would be framed. There would be no third option this time, no wooly interpretation of winning that might give her leeway under the Vow. She could only win a duel or lose it, and losing would not be an option.

On her way to Madam Pince's desk, she spotted Hermione's exuberant hair peeking over a table full of books. Rigel changed direction and peered curiously over the tall stacks. The girl was hunched over a scrap of paper and appeared to be doing furious long-hand calculations, muttering under her breath as number after number appeared in the wake of her quill.

"What kind of arithmancy is that?" she asked, wincing as Hermione, startled by the unexpected question, slashed ink across her paper. "Sorry."

Hermione blew out a breath and scattered sand over the streak of ink quickly. "Hi, Rigel. That's all right. I'm just double-checking my calculations at this point. It's not Arithmancy; it's about the Fade."

Rigel raised her eyebrows. "You have enough data to begin drawing conclusions?" She'd tried to convince as many of her schoolmates as she could to speak to Hermione, but she hadn't honestly held out much hope that they would.

The brown-eyed girl nodded, gesturing for Rigel to sit beside her. Hermione pulled a sheet of paper from between two books in the stack before her and said, "This is everything totaled. I interviewed fifty-two students and cross-checked everything they said against at least one other person to verify they'd remembered correctly."

"Fifty-two?" Rigel was stunned. She hadn't known there were even fifty-two students in the whole school whose families had been affected by the Fade.

Hermione smiled, and there was a hardness to it. "I realized quickly that people who'd directly witnessed the Fade weren't keen to speak about it. Your friend Selwyn did answer my letter, as did your father. Miss Bulstrode approached me on her own, and Mr. MacMillan, but everyone else I asked directly declined to talk about it. So I started asking students who didn't have anyone in their immediate family succumb to the illness. I suppose one thing in favor of the rampant bigotry in this society is that every pureblood knows a great many of the others."

Rigel whistled. "So you asked people whether they knew of any families who had been affected, and if so to what extent. That's brilliant." Even about a topic as sensitive as the Fade, people rarely minded talking about other people's problems. It troubled her that she hadn't known Millicent's family lost a child to the Fade, but she supposed it wouldn't have come up in any casual conversation.

"The Weasleys gave me the idea," Hermione admitted. "They freely listed everyone they knew about, so that I'd know who to approach, and that made me realize that in a society this insular, everyone would know of someone, most often more than one. By having everyone list all the cases they'd heard about, and only using those confirmed by at least one other in my data, I've done a rudimentary statistical analysis of the phenomenon." She ran her finger down each column on the sheet of parchment. "No one reported any cases of the disease in a child who had at least one muggle or muggleborn parent. Seventy percent of reported cases are from pureblood couples whose families have married only other purebloods for four generations or more. Of the remaining thirty percent, about half were cases where one of the parents' family had only been 'pure' for three or fewer generations, and the other half were couples in which one of the parents was a halfblood. In both of the later cases, the other parent always came from a family with four or more generations of pureblood breeding."

She looked expectantly at Rigel, whose eyes were very wide. She swallowed, then said carefully, "You appear to have narrowed it down to a single constant. In every reported case, at least one parent came from a family that was four-or-more generations pure."

"That's what the numbers say," Hermione confirmed. "I've been combing the most recent Book of Gold, and I've come up with a list of every family in Great Britain whose pedigree meets that criterion." She reached into her bag and pulled out a roll of parchment. "This is all of them. Every family with a high risk of contracting the Fade."

"How high is the risk?" Rigel asked, almost afraid to look at the list. She was certain she'd see the names of most, if not all, of her housemates on it.

"That's where the numbers get tricky," Hermione admitted. "The number of first-borns to succumb to the disease is very small. In those instances, both of the parents in question came from an extremely long line of purebloods. For the vast majority of cases, it strikes the second child born to the same parents. In instances where the couple separated or the second born was the result of an affair, cases of the Fade were much less likely, particularly if the child was born of a different witch."

"That supports the theory that the mother's magic may have more to do with the Fade than the father's," Rigel said.

Hermione glared at her. "What theory is that?"

"Until now, I thought it was something wizards said to make themselves feel better. Like how they used to think the female determined the sex of the child, too." Rigel shrugged apologetically. "The first instinct is always to blame the woman."

Hermione huffed in amused agreement. "This time, they may have a point. It also gets more complicated if a couple continues to attempt to birth more children. There are a few cases, such as your father and uncle, where a couple had one healthy child, several Fade-stricken children or miscarriages, and then another healthy child. Lord Black indicated he suspected his mother of performing some sort of black ritual to ensure his younger brother's survival. There's no way to verify that, of course." She tapped her quill on the table restlessly.

"And it would have to be a very black ritual for other families to not even consider it as an alternative to losing a child," Rigel pointed out. "Perhaps it was something known only to my grandmother. I'll look through the Black Family library over the winter break."

There was a brief, but acute look of envy on Hermione's face at the mention of a family library. It passed after a moment, but Rigel wondered if Hermione ever wished she'd been born into an old magic family, if only for the sort of knowledge it afforded one. "I'll be doing a little more research of my own over the break, as well," Hermione said. "Healer Hurst has promised to let me look through the clinic's records and add the data to my study."

"The Lower Alley citizens don't keep long records of their families the way people here do," Rigel cautioned her.

Hermione nodded. "Still, more data doesn't hurt. Especially more information on the exact medical progression of the disease. All this information helps us understand where the Fade is likely to present, but it doesn't get us closer to curing it."

"Doesn't it?" Rigel blinked. "It seems to me that the Weasleys are the wisest of us all. If every family on this list made a concentrated effort to marry a muggleborn or halfblood this generation, the disease would be effectively eradicated for at least another four generations."

"I don't know if I'd go so far as to conclude that," Hermione said carefully. "Weren't you the one who said that most purebloods would only accept a cure that didn't force them to compromise their beliefs?"

Rigel grimaced, but had to admit she was right. "It's just maddening to know that, with a simple choice, no more children would have to die."

"It seems simple to us because it doesn't violate any beliefs we hold dear," Hermione said. "There are some muggles who have a religious objection to vaccines, for instance." At Rigel's frown, she explained. "Vaccines are a way of immunizing people against diseases before they catch them. Some are created with animal cells or even human cells, and there are groups of people who object to having them administered. It presents a social health risk, and it's always a tragedy when a child falls ill or dies from a preventable disease, but when someone believes something so strongly, almost nothing can change their mind." Hermione's eyes were alight, and in that moment she looked like a crusader of old, only her cross was something like the individual freedoms of all.

"So if we can't convince them to change their ways, the only thing to do is to cure it," Rigel concluded. She smiled ruefully. "No big deal, then."

Hermione laughed. She opened her mouth to say something, but they were interrupted by a gruff voice from behind them.

"Hermy-oin."

It was Krum, looming over them with an uncharacteristically uncertain expression on his face. He nodded briefly to Rigel, but his attention was drawn back to Hermione inexorably, and Rigel recognized the look in his eye with a jolt of surprise.

"Hello, Victor," Hermione said, her hands fluttering nervously before she clamped them firmly together before her stomach. "How are you today?"

"Very vell," the older boy said softly. "I vanted to ask you a quvestion."

"Oh, all right. I'm good at questions." Hermione laughed a bit awkwardly, reached up to tuck an errant curl behind her ear, then seemed to remember her plan to keep her hands still and returned it to her lap abruptly. Her face reddened. "Go ahead."

"Is there someone who vill be escorting you to the Yule Ball?" The Quidditch player's dark eyes were fixed on Hermione's face with cautious hope.

Hermione coughed, as though the air in her lungs had decided to choke her of a sudden. "Ah, no. Not yet. I—" her eyes darted toward Rigel, an expression of both panic and guilt in her eyes. "—no."

Krum glanced suspiciously at Rigel, who blinked at him blankly before realizing he expected her to challenge him for Hermione's hand. She grimaced and turned pointedly away to stare unseeing at a nearby bookshelf. Once she had, she heard Krum said, "Then vill you do me the honor, Herminon?"

Hermione's voice was somewhat unsteady as she said, "It would be my pleasure. Thank you very much for asking, Victor."

From the corner of her eye, Rigel saw Krum bow gallantly over one of Hermione's hands before smiling widely. "The pleasure vill be mine." He left the library, and Rigel turned back to Hermione with a feeling of cold foreboding in her stomach. How was she going to explain this to Archie?

As she watched Hermione's expressed descend from embarrassed, disbelieving pleasure to utter misery, thoughts of Archie receded and all Rigel could think of was how to stop the girl in front of her from dissolving into tears.

"What's wrong, Hermione? Don't you like Krum?" she asked carefully.

Hermione's breath hitched and her lower lip trembled. Rather than cry, the girl closed her eyes tight and counted to three under her breath. When she opened them again, her gaze was wretched, but clear. "I don't know. He's very…well. There's something alluring there. It's what I always thought I would feel, when…" She shook her head and gripped her hair, her shoulders slumping in despair. "I want to, you know. I want to want Harry."

Rigel froze, utterly sure that she had no more idea how to navigate this particular conversation than she had the last time. Hermione didn't appear to need her input, however, as she continued.

"Harry was my first friend. S—he understands me better than anyone. Harry is so much more than I ever thought one person could be. More outgoing, more earnest, fun, kind, protective, smart!" Hermione let out a watery laugh. "God, but Harry is so smart. Perfect. Almost. But without physical attraction, it's just friendship, isn't it? Not romance?"

After a moment Rigel realized she was expected to respond. She shrugged helplessly. "I don't know anything about romance. Really, I'm the worst person to ask." Hermione's heartbreakingly torn expression ate away at her reluctance to get involved, and she added, "If you really want my opinion, I think…be with who makes you happy. Whoever makes you feel whole. And maybe you don't know who that is yet. And that's okay, too." Rigel thought no one should have to decide about forever when they were fifteen.

Hermione considered her words with a solemn expression. "I do like Victor. Maybe it's just hormones, but I won't know unless I try, will I?" Something firmed in her eyes and she nodded slowly to herself. "It'll be an experiment, then. If I can puzzle through how I feel with different people, then maybe I'll figure out what it is I really need. Thanks, Rigel." She began to pack up her notes, and Rigel realized the lunch period was probably almost over. Rigel picked up her book, and was about to leave when Hermione added, "Who will you take to the ball, then?"

Rigel frowned. "What ball?"

Hermione stared at her. "The one Victor just asked me to. The Yule Ball."

"I assumed that was…some kind of Durmstrang thing?" The statement came out as a question as Hermione's expression turned exasperated. "I'm starting to feel as though there's a mailing list I've been left off of."

"The Yule Ball is scheduled the night after the third task," Hermione told her. "It's to celebrate the three blood champions and the halfway point for the tournament. Do you really not know about it? McGonagall told me weeks ago."

She groaned. "Snape probably cares less than I do. Is it mandatory?"

Hermione laughed. "The champions are to open the dancing, so I would say so." Rigel scowled in displeasure, but the scowl fell into a blank expression as Hermione added, "Will…Harry come?"

Rigel had the sudden realization that rampaging hippogriffs wouldn't be able to keep her cousin away. All she said was, "We are engaged, so it would be proper. Did Harry tell you about that?"

Hermione made a noise of affirmation. "Harry said it was arranged but not serious."

"That's right," Rigel confirmed quickly. "There's never been that sort of attachment between us. Harry's more like my sibling than anything. The engagement was drawn up as soon as we found out about the S.O.W.'s marriage law, just in case."

"For protection," Hermione said, eyes wide. "I see. That's quite a sacrifice for you, isn't it?"

"No more than it is for Harry." Rigel shrugged. "Anyway, it's not forever. Only until we're seventeen, as long as the legislation is killed once and for all before then."

"Do you think it will be?" Hermione asked, eyes penetrating.

"I aim to see it so."

Between freebrewing with Snape, training her reflexes in the Room of Requirement, and wrapping up a number of other projects in preparation for the end of term, the remaining week before the third task passed all too quickly.

Before she felt fully resigned to it, Rigel found herself walking down to the pitch through the early morning fog, frost crunching beneath her trusty boots. In addition to her Hogwarts jersey and loose breeches, she wore an underlayer of warm silk that she hoped would prevent her muscles seizing in the freezing air.

A part of her wished she was back in the alleys, that this was just another day spent in the courtyard of the Dancing Phoenix with her friends, but she willed those thoughts away firmly. She had to distance herself from that person. Harry-the-alley-free-dueler couldn't be anywhere near the tournament stage that day.

Draco and Pansy walked on either side of her, silently supportive, and in the distance, she could see the stands already filling up with spectators. "Are your parents coming to watch today?" she asked them, more for something to break the tense atmosphere than anything.

"Of course!" Draco looked offended that she would even ask. "They wouldn't miss it. Or did you forget again that you're family?"

Rigel smiled, but said, "I asked my family not to come to this one, actually. It's too much pressure with them watching."

Draco frowned. "Since when does pressure get to you?" After a moment's shrewd contemplation, he said, "You just don't like people fussing over you. Well, I'll tell Mother and Father not to overwhelm you, but what else can you expect when you risk your life and limb in front of all and sundry?"

"It wasn't Rigel's choice, exactly," Pansy said, defensive on her behalf.

"I don't mind your parents' version of fussing," Rigel said, a small laugh escaping her. "Sirius would wrap me in a bubble charm if he could."

"Rigel!"

They all three turned to see Zhou hurrying down from the castle behind them. Draco made an annoyed noise under his breath, but didn't stop Rigel from waiting for the girl to catch up to them.

"Hi, Zhou," she said.

"Hi." The girl panted a bit, but caught her breath enough to say, "I just wanted to wish you luck today. Ravenclaw is supporting you, no matter what happens."

"Thank you," Rigel said, genuinely touched. Never had she imagined the school could rally around her like it had. She'd expected so much more resentment for being chosen over older, better-liked students like Cedric Diggory. "I'll do my best to represent Hogwarts proudly."

"I'm sure you will." Zhou's voice was still a little breathless, and her eyes darted between Rigel, Draco, and Pansy nervously before she blurted, "Do you have a date to the ball?" Rigel's lips parted, but nothing came out for a long moment. Zhou turned red, disappointment creeping into her eyes. "I mean, you probably do. I just thought I'd…ask. In case you didn't."

Rigel summoned a smile despite the awkwardness she felt internally. Zhou was only trying to be nice, after all. If she hadn't had anyone to go with, she'd have been grateful to accept the girl's offer. "It's very kind of you to think of me," she said warmly. "Since I'm engaged to Heiress Potter, though, I'll be escorting her." She'd already discussed it with Archie, and he was prepared to play 'Harry' for the evening. Rigel thought some crazy part of her cousin was actually looking forward to it, from the mischievous gleam that had entered his eyes as they discussed the possibility. It worried her a little, but in light of the portion of Riddle's magic that Dom had yet to filter from her core, they had no other choice.

Zhou murmured something understanding and fled quickly toward the Quidditch pitch. Rigel peered after her with a somewhat puzzled expression and heard Draco snort from beside her. She slid a glance toward him. "What?"

"You really are the worst," he muttered. There was more amusement in his voice than censure, though.

"What's that supposed to mean?" she asked, unsure what she was supposed to be apologizing for.

"Ignore him, Rye," Pansy said, looping her arm through Rigel's. "Focus on the task."

Rigel didn't miss the look Pansy shot Draco behind her back, but she didn't know what to make of it, so she did as her friend suggested and bent her attention to the upcoming ordeal.

They'd all been officially informed of the nature of the third task three days before. Rigel wasn't sure what advantage Riddle thought an extra week and a half to prepare was supposed to have bought her, but she suspected he merely wanted her to feel beholden to him. That was his game, after all. Make people trust him by bestowing small favors on them, then take advantage of the impulse toward reciprocity. Rigel refused to be fooled. She also refused to feel guilty about any supposed advantage his words tried to bestow on her.

Draco was muttering last-minute strategy in her ear, and she humored him by listening, but she knew general strategy would be secondary to direct observation. The first match she would be going in blind, but every subsequent match she would have some notion of her opponent's style, simply by watching the others fight.

She left Draco and Pansy at the stairs to the stands and made her way to the center of the pitch alone. A large, perfectly circular platform had been raised there, not as high as the obstacle course had been, but elevated enough to give a better view to the spectators above them. The other champions waited in a loose circle in the shadow of the stage, and when Rigel joined them, Crouch cleared his throat.

"Now that we are all present, the task will proceed as follows: Granger and Sousa will duel first, followed by Krum and Zahi, Delacour and Antiope, and finally Shang and Black." Crouch raised his voice to cut across the murmurs. "Owens, being in the lead currently, will get a by the first round. The tournament is elimination style until the final round, so second round matches will be directly determined by the results of round one."

Bagman cut in with a broad smile. "That is to say, the winner of the first match will face the winner of the second match, and so on. Someone else will get a by in the second round, of course, but that will be determined at random."

Sure it would, Rigel thought cynically. She didn't miss the fact that both muggleborns who hadn't been given a by in the first round were on the same side of the bracket. At best, it meant only one of them would make it to the final round.

Hermione's face was set with determination, but Rigel wondered how much time the girl had really been devoting to preparing for the tournament on top of her investigation into the Fade. She couldn't fault the girl's priorities, but she worried for her safety. The Triwizard Tournament was, she thought, not a place for good people.

Hermione and Matheus climbed the steps up to the platform as the crowd began to thunderously communicate its approval. Crouch and Bagman directed the rest of them toward the edge of the pitch, where a staircase led them to their own private box from which they could view the duels.

After just a few short minutes, Bagman's amplified voice counted down the moments to the beginning of the duel. Hermione's stance was almost textbook, but she leaned slightly away from her opponent rather than toward him. Lack of aggression, Rigel thought. While initiative wasn't everything in a duel, it was harder to control the pace when you began on the defensive.

"—TWO, ONE, BEGIN!"

Hermione had a shield up before the echo of Bagman's voice had faded from the stadium, but Matheus merely stared at her, not moving, from across the ring. He spun his wand in idly, and faint laughter came down from the stands. The AIM girl scowled, clearly torn between keeping her shield up just in case and dropping it so that the magic didn't drain her unnecessarily. It was smart of Matheus to use her indecision against her. As long as she kept the shield up, she'd wear away at her own endurance.

Finally, with an impatient flick, Hermione dropped the shield and sent a wordless disarming spell at Matheus. The Brazilian boy was all the way on the other side of the ring, and had plenty of time to dodge the spell. She sent another, then two more in quick succession, but Matheus side-stepped them all without bothering to shield.

"Get closer," Rigel muttered. Hermione was only going to wear herself out at that distance.

The girl seemed to realize Matheus could dodge faster than she could cast, for she broke off the point-spell offense and instead lifted her hands into the air dramatically. A dozen small boulders materialized in the space above her head, and a sharp jap with her wand sent them hailing down toward Matheus. The spectators cheered at seeing such an advanced conjuration, and Rigel clapped along with them. It was smart; using an attack that covered such a wide area precluded physical avoidance.

The dark-haired boy finally lifted his wand and it bobbed in the air like a conductor's baton for a moment before a shimmering barrier of a type Rigel had never seen before appeared between him and the falling rocks. It didn't shield him so much as it spun the incoming projectiles off course and deflected them away. It was as though he'd created a localized twister out of the air before him.

A few of the rocks shot sideways and came to rest at the edge of the wards surrounding the stage. The rest fell somewhere between the two duelists. Hermione set about transfiguring the rock closest to her, and Rigel's eyebrows rose. To transfigure something you'd already conjured was a very advanced application of magic. A cloud of smoke momentarily obscured the girl, and when it cleared, they could see the rock had burst into a dozen shards. Hermione banished them with an audible cry. They rocketed toward Matheus, and for a moment it seemed the fast-moving pieces would cut through the wind barrier. At the last moment, they were turned aside.

Hermione stood at the ready position, but didn't cast another spell. A moment later, Matheus flinched violently and his barrier dissolved as he ducked his head and waved his arms wildly against something Rigel couldn't see. Hermione had a spell off the moment the boy dropped his barrier in distraction, and abruptly, it was over. Matheus caught the disarming spell in the back and crumpled.

"I'M NOT SURE WHAT WE JUST SAW, BUT HERMIONE GRANGER HAS WON THE FIRST DUEL!"

The stadium erupted, and Rigel breathed a sigh of relief that Hermione had made it through the first round unscathed.

"What waz zat?" Fleur demanded, glaring down at the pitch as though the duel had personally offended her. "I could not zee what happened."

Tahiil laughed. "It was clever! Did you see the smoke when Hermione transfigured that rock? It was a screen. I felt two spells, not one. The invisible thing that attacked Matheus must have come from that moment."

"She surprised him ven he let his guard down," Krum said. There was a pleased note in his voice.

Antiope scoffed. "It was still a boring duel. I hope you two provide us some more entertainment," she added, giving Krum and Tahiil a mocking look.

Tahiil was utterly unfazed. "We will certainly do our best, Antiope. Will you cheer for me?"

The redhead sneered at him. "Not a chance. I want to face Krum in the finals."

Fleur tossed her hair with a huff. "Getting ahead of yourzelf, are you not?"

Antiope's only response was a confident smirk. "This task was made for me. You're all using just your wands, but I petitioned the judges to be allowed use of my sword." Several of the others protested, but Antiope only laughed. "It's only right that I be able to show my skills to their best advantage. If any of you had trained with a weapon, you could have used it just the same."

"Freedueling iz dizgraceful," Fleur said. The fierce disgust in her voice didn't wholly disguise the trepidation in her eyes, though.

"It is the noblest of all arts," Antiope spat. "Only countries who have forgotten how to do it think it's beneath them. Luckily, this is an international tournament, so your close-minded rules don't apply. I'll prove to everyone watching today that steel is vital to true combat."

The appearance of Hermione at the top of the stairs forestalled the argument. Rigel went over to congratulate her, with Krum right on her heels. Hermione gave them a weak smile. "It wasn't great," she murmured. "I didn't realize what it would be like, dueling for real."

"You ver vonderful," Krum rumbled. "Very advanced magic."

"Matheus wasn't even trying," Hemione said with a sigh. "Thanks, though. Good luck in your match, Victor."

He took her hand and kissed it despite the sweat and dirt. "If you are vatching, I vill vin."

The frustration melted from the girl's face and she nodded. "I'll cheer you on."

Krum and Tahiil left the box, and Hermione's face hardened again. "Be honest, Rigel. How did I do?"

"You were a little timid," Rigel said kindly. "You hung back on your side of the ring without moving closer. If you'd been casting from halfway across, for instance, he wouldn't have had time to dodge your spells." Hermione winced, but nodded. Rigel went on. "Your quick-thinking was impressive, though. That sort of creativity can't be taught. I'm sure the judges were impressed with your conjuring and transfiguration. Can I ask what spell you got Matheus with in the end?"

"Avis," she said, smiling sheepishly. "I just conjured them invisibly and sent them around the barrier to dive at him from behind."

"Brilliant," Rigel said, smiling back. "Not many people can alter a spell before casting it. Harry would be so impressed."

Hermione flushed. "I'll wait to feel pleased with myself until we see how the next round goes."

"Just don't be afraid to move around, really use the whole platform," Rigel said. "The barriers won't let you fall off the edge."

Hermione nodded. "The next duel is starting," she said, and they both moved to the edge of the box with the other champions to watch.

Tahiil still had his irrepressible smile on his face, while Krum, whose dueling stance was slightly lower than Rigel would have expected for a boy with his height, was the picture of solemn concentration. At Bagman's word, the two boys sprang into action. Krum darted forward, aiming two spells in swift succession to either side of Tahiil. Trying to pin him in place, Rigel guessed. Tahiil batted at the air with one of his hands, however, and the spell that would have impacted to his left met an invisible force and reflected. As Tahiil moved left, Krum was forced to roll under his own spell. By the time he stood, Tahiil was behind him.

Krum cast a shield at his back without looking, and as Tahiil's first spell fizzled harmlessly against it he spun, catching the dark-skinned boy with a Flipendo that hurled Tahiil into the air and deposited him clear across the stage.

Tahiil held up a hand toward his opponent as he climbed slowly to his feet, and every spell Krum shot at him rebounded from the invisible defense. With his free hand, Tahiil began casting. It was eerie to watch spells appear from the end of a person's fingertips, Rigel noted. Stranger still to watch the boy cast wandlessly over and over again, a feat that would exhaust most wand users she knew before long. Tahiil was still smiling, though his eyes held a wary respect for Krum that had been absent before.

Krum grew tired of avoiding both his own spells and Tahiil's. The broad-shouldered Bulgarian stopped casting point spells and instead aimed his wand at the stage. A torrent of water burst from his wand like a flood, catching Tahiil up to the knees and forcing him to stop casting and brace against the hard current to avoid being swept off his feet. Krum was all the time chanting something, and beginning from his side of the platform the water, trapped by the wards at the edge of the stage, began to freeze.

Tahiil clambered onto one of Hermione's boulders to keep from getting stuck in the ice. By the time he'd reached the higher ground, Krum had conjured skates on the bottom of his boots and was gliding across the arena as though he'd been born doing it. He closed the distance between them in moments, and none of Tahiil's spells could hit him and he pivoted and slid back and forth on the frozen platform.

"He changed the terrain to suit him," Hermione said wonderingly.

Rigel agreed. "He's too fast on those skates for Tahiil to hit him now."

The Somali boy seemed to have realized the same thing. He lowered his hands, seemed to shudder violently for an instant, and then he was folding in on himself, transforming, Rigel realized. Her mouth fell open without her consent as Tahiil, now a spotted hyena, leapt from the rock and knocked Krum from his feet. The crowd went mad, shock and awe giving way to wild excitement as it became clear just what Tahiil was truly capable of.

Both boy and hyena rolled across the ice, and the hyena was the first to rise. The animagus gave a "woo-op" call and used its clawed feet to restlessly pace the ice until Krum, one hand gingerly poking the back of his skull, regained his feet. Krum eyed the animal warily, slowly circling on his skates. He cast a stunner at the hyena, but the large canine nimbly avoided it, something like a laugh escaping the powerful jaws.

Tahiil made a small bound toward Krum, then away again, feinting left, then right as Krum tried to decide which way to go. More laughing followed, and Rigel could see Krum's frustration even from her vantage point. The Bulgarian's wand flurried into motion and a thick net sprung out toward the animagus. Tahiil came back on his hind legs and batted it out of the air, coming down on top of the net and using the extra purchase on the ice to leap forward. Krum conjured a physical shield, but the force of the hyena's weight bore him backwards onto the ice anyway. As his head hit the ice a second time, the shield failed and Tahiil's jaw clamped around Krum's wand arm. He twitched his head the barest amount, and Krum's wand fell from limp fingers, spinning across the ice.

Rigel thought Krum would surrender. Tahiil must have expected it, too, as the animagus released Krum's arm and "woo-op"-ed loudly into the sky. As the hyena's head came back down, Krum punched him in the snout. A sickening yelp rang out and Tahiil scrambled back, but Krum found the strength to follow him. The Bulgarian tackled the hyena, wrapped thick arms around Tahiil's neck, and summoned his wand. When the tip of his wand pressed into the animagus' fur, Tahiil froze, then slowly shifted back to human form.

Krum didn't let up. He gripped Tahiil by the jaw and exposed his throat for all to see the wand-point digging into the vulnerable skin there. Stunned applause filled the pitch as Bagman said, "THERE YOU HAVE IT! VICTOR KRUM CLAIMS THE SECOND MATCH!"

The boys separated at once, Krum going so far as to help Tahiil to his feet on the slippery ice. Impossibly, the slighter boy still had a grin on his face. Healers took charge of both of them as they left the wards, and a small break was called as tournament organizers were sent to clean up the stage for the next match.

Rigel exchanged a look with Hermione. "Krum did well," she said.

"He never gave up," Hermione agreed, respect in her eyes. "Tahiil, though…do you think he went easy on Victor?"

Rigel's eyebrows rose. "He used his animagus form. I don't think he was holding back."

Hermione seemed unconvinced. "I read somewhere that hyenas have stronger jaws than a bear. If Tahiil wanted to, he could have ripped Victor's arm clean off."

"He wouldn't do that, though," Rigel said reassuringly. "These are exhibition matches, Hermione, not fights to the death. No one should be aiming to maim or kill. Tahiil did his best within reasonable limits. That's all any of us should do."

She didn't know if she was trying to convince Hermione or herself of that.

By the time the third match was ready to start, Krum had been released from the healers' care and rejoined them in the champions' box. Hermione congratulated him for his win, but Krum did not seem wholly satisfied with it. "I am not sure he vanted to vin," the older boy muttered when pressed.

Rigel couldn't speak to Tahiil's motivations, but she didn't think lack of heart would be an issue in the next match. Fleur and Antiope stared each other down like mortal enemies, for all that they'd only known one another a couple of months. Antiope did indeed have her sword, an impressively sturdy weapon that she hefted one-handed in her left hand, her wand clutched tightly in her right. Fleur appeared undaunted, though Rigel suspected that was mostly out of pride. The girl's distain for weaponed combat indicated she had no familiarity with it, and Rigel knew from personal experience what a jarring difference it could make in a duel.

"Who do you think will win?" Hermione asked from beside her.

Rigel felt bad saying it, but there was no point in dishonesty. "Antiope. If she's half as good with that sword as she thinks she is, it'll mess up everything Fleur's been trained to."

"Why is freedueling banned in Britain, anyway?" Hermione asked curiously. She lowered her voice and added, "I've heard Healer Hurst mention it once or twice—a lot of the injuries we see at the clinic are from such illicit duels."

Rigel nodded. "Part of it is because it causes so many injures. The added element of complexity that comes when you introduce weapons, potions, and other forms of magic into a duel can exponentially increase the probability of lethal harm, even when both participants know what they're doing."

"And the other part?" Hermione asked shrewdly.

"Old fashioned prejudice," Rigel said with a faint smile. "Wizards like to think they're too good to use anything 'muggle' in their traditions. Relying on something other than one's own magic is, for some, the sign of a weak wizard. Magic is Might, and all that."

Hermione groaned. "That phrase alone makes me want to take up a sword myself."

"Maybe Antiope will teach you," Rigel said with amusement.

"Maybe I'll get the king to teach me," Hermione said, laughing quietly.

Rigel froze, then immediately tried to disguise her alarm with a casual tone. "King?"

Hermione shot her a guilty glance. "Never mind. I think…maybe it's something I'm not supposed to mention." She sighed. "I don't understand everything about the lower alleys yet."

"Have you asked Harry?" she asked.

Whatever Hermione might have said, it was lost in the roar of the stands as the third match began.

Antiope charged. Fleur began casting, probably as fast as she could, but Antiope darted around every spell without ceasing her relentless advance. The fact that she wasn't blocking the spells outright with her sword made Rigel think it probably wasn't imbued with the same ability to absorb magic that Goldflame's had been. By the time Fleur realized Antiope wasn't going to be stopped, the redhead was upon her. She slashed viciously through the air and the beautiful blonde girl barely managed to leap out of the way in time.

Fleur retreated, shielding against the next several attacks as she steadily backed her way to one end of the platform. With a scowl of frustration, Fleur conjured a thick, earthen wall between her and her opponent. Antiope made to go around it, but Fleur cast a Bombarda at her own transfiguration and it exploded outward, burying Antiope in dirt.

As the redhead struggled out of the debris, Fleur took the time to conjure a shield of pure magic and affix it to her left arm. By the time Antiope had regained her feet, Fleur was ready. She met Antiope's next strike with her shield, but Rigel could see the way the impact reverberated through the part-Veela's slim frame. Antiope rained blows down on the girl again and again, and Rigel had to wonder if the freckled warrior was just toying with the Frenchwoman. Antiope hadn't cast a single spell yet, using only her sword to batter at Fleur's defenses over and over. She certainly was out to prove something.

The physical blows visibly tired Fleur, who had taken to hiding behind the shield as often as she attempted to cast. Antiope had uncanny reflexes, and a way of sliding out of the way of spells even when they were fired almost point-blank. The Beauxbatons champion couldn't get space to breathe, let along come up with a viable strategy in the face of Antiope's relentless pursuit.

Really, it wasn't too surprising when Antiope gripped her sword in both hands and finally brought it down with enough force to break through the conjured shield and bite into Fleur's biceps. The silvery-blonde girl fell to her knees, cradling her bleeding arm, and Antiope moved her sword to the place above Fleur's heart. The French girl glared up at Antiope from her defeated position, but Antiope merely shook her head, waiting until Bagman had officially declared her the victor before lowering her weapon.

"She didn't cast a single spell," Hermione said, clearly marveled.

"Her style gave her an overwhelming advantage against a dueler like Fleur," Rigel said ruefully.

"It seems as though her advantage would be the same against any of us." Hermione appeared troubled. "I hope I don't face her in the second round."

Rigel hummed, but didn't say anything. She sort of hoped Hermione didn't face her, too, but she didn't want to undermine the girl's confidence. She glanced across the box at Feiyan, who gave her a small smile.

"Now is our turn," the Asian girl said. She was dressed warmly, in a long tunic and thick leggings, and her long, black hair had been pulled back from her face in a bun.

Rigel nodded. "Shall we?" She followed the slightly shorter girl down the spiral stairs and onto the grassy pitch. The stage loomed large and intimidating ahead of them, but Rigel felt more anticipation than fear as she climbed the stairs to the top. Dark forests and obstacle courses were not really her forte. This, though? The look of determination in her opponent's eyes, the feel of her wand gripped securely in her fist, the sturdy, even platform beneath her feet—this she knew.

Feiyan's stance was wide, almost dramatically so. Rigel favored a loser, partial-crouch that kept her centered without sacrificing maneuverability. When Bagman called for them to start, it was a long moment before either girl actually moved. Rigel darted right, and watched as Feiyan matched her with sweeping footwork that explained her wide stance. A tripping jinx bloomed effortlessly from her wand and she carefully watched as Feiyan turned around it. There was something lovely about the economy of movement the dark-haired girl displayed, as though she were merely following a pattern long committed to memory.

Rigel wanted to know what that pattern was. She teased Feiyan's defenses, casting first to the girl's left, then to her right, then high and low, sizing up the nature of her response to each spell. Most of the time, Feiyan opted to dance around it rather than block it. Rigel moved closer, her spells coming faster, and Feiyan's footwork sped up in response. The girl was well-trained.

When Feiyan's first spell came, it was not one Rigel had ever heard before. A cloud formed between them and ice particles that had seemingly condensed within it shot out at Rigel. She summoned magic to heat the air around her, and when the attack finally reached her it was but the sting of fast raindrops. She sent an Incarcerous toward Feiyan, but the girl turned away from the spell even as she cast another, unrecognizable spell toward Rigel's feet.

The solid platform beneath her turned to mud, and Rigel promptly sank three inches. She conjured a Fortis shield to protect her as she pulled her boots free with a squelch and froze the mud directly below her feet with a spell from her free hand. Feiyan shot several fireballs her direction, but the Fortis repelled them easily. When Rigel dropped the shield to prepare her next spell, the Chinese girl turned to the air once more, calling up a torrent of rain over Rigel's head with a swirl of her wand. Rigel's clothes were instantly soaked through, and she realized the other girl was playing the long game. In the frigid December temperature, the rain clung to Rigel's bones and forced her to consciously ignore the impulse to shiver and slow. The rain also made the mud on her half of the platform much more slippery.

The rain didn't stop her from sending two Relashios in quick succession, however. Feiyan's footwork saved her from both spells, but Rigel had the time she needed to leap over the remaining mud and shorten the distance between them. She pressed forward with spell after spell, forcing Feiyan onto the defensive while she closed the gap. When she was close enough to see the consternation in Feiyan's eyes, Rigel tried a trip jinx again. The other girl did stumble, but not before hissing, "Feng!" at her with a sharp jab of her wand. A gust of wind lifted Rigel off her feet and knocked the breath from her lungs as it deposited her back the short distance she'd just gained.

So 'Feng' means Ventus, she noted sourly as she rolled with the fall through the waiting mud and came up on the defensive. Feiyan had already cast her next attack—fire again, this time a litany of small, burning hail that forced Rigel to call up another shield. With her free hand, Rigel reached beneath her to etch a basic state-change rune into the muck. The water evaporated from it instantly, leaving a layer of dry dirt behind instead.

Rigel gripped a handful of the dirt and, when the fireballs had stopped, dropped her shield. She flung the dust into the air, banishing it in a rocketing cloud toward Feiyan with careful control. It caught her in the face, and the girl spluttered and coughed, eventually choking out the wind spell again to disperse it. By the time the cloud was gone, Rigel was halfway across the platform again, an Impedimenta on the tip of her wand.

Feiyan swirled around the spell with one of her curious, sweeping half-turns, and Rigel heard her say, "Feng!"

She was ready this time. Rigel flung a Ventus with as much force as she could muster in the space of a second. It met Feiyan's wind spell head on and overpowered it, knocking the pale girl off her feet with an audible "Oooff." Feiyan was so close to the edge of the platform, Rigel's spell slammed her into the wards and she slumped to the floor with a groan.

Rigel summoned the girl's wand, and found herself almost disappointed with how quickly the match had gone. Then she shook her head at her own foolishness. She should be grateful to not have tired herself out in the first match. Cheers rained down on her from the stands, and Rigel summoned a smile as she helped Feiyan to her feet and handed her back the wand she'd taken.

"You all right?" she asked.

Feiyan nodded, shooting Rigel a rueful look. "I am well. Only shamed."

"It was a good match," Rigel said.

The girl shook her head, but did not seem overly disappointed. "After task number two, there was small chance I advance. Now, at least, I can go home."

Rigel made a noncommittal noise and they exited the platform as Bagman announced a short break while the second-round matches were decided. She was shivering with the drenching she'd had, but otherwise uninjured, so the healers let her go back up to the champions' box after a very thorough drying spell, a heated blanket wrapped around her shoulders.

"ROUND TWO WILL BEGIN WITH OWENS VERSUS GRANGER!" Bagman informed them all. "BLACK AND ANTIOPE WILL DUEL SECOND, AND KRUM RECEIVES A BY!"

Rigel wondered whether that decision was based on Krum having incurred the most severe injuries during the first round. She supposed it wouldn't be the worst way to decide, though it didn't escape her that the muggleborn candidates were exclusively matched against one another.

Hermione seemed, if anything, more nervous in the face of her second match than she had been before the first. Rigel thought the girl hadn't known quite what to expect the first time. She wished the AIM girl luck, but Hermione only grimaced at her before descending the stairs once more.

It was clear from the start that Owens had a great deal of training. The American boy took the initiative at once, with a handful of not-particularly-dangerous spells that nevertheless came one after the other fast enough to keep Hermione on the defensive. The girl was being herded slowly toward the end of the platform, and Rigel doubted she even realized how many steps back she'd taken until her back came up against the wards.

Hermione took a Tarantallegra without shielding in favor of getting time to cast a spell of her own. The ground beneath Owens' feet heaved, throwing the boy off his feet. Hermione cast a quick Finite on her jerking legs and dove around the boy's next spell, which boiled through the air where she'd just been. When Owens regained his feet, Hermione had switched their places and clearly hoped to box him against the wards instead. Owens blocked each one of her spells with split-second shields that he called up and released in the space between instants.

Rigel had never seen someone shield so fast before. The flickering technique probably saved him a lot of magic in the long run, she thought, but it had to take exemplary concentration and reflexes to get the shield up just in time to meet each of the spells Hermione hurled at him. Certainly, the strategy was having an impact on the girl's morale. Rigel hoped she found a way around Owens' defenses before frustration drove her to something desperate.

Finally, Hermione cast a spell that Owens couldn't shield against: conjuration, again, this time two small dogs that raced toward her opponent with lolling tongues. They closed on Owens from two different directions, but the boy swept his wand out with a vicious slash and something like a slicing charm swept out around him in a horizontal arc. It cut right through the conjured animals, severing their bloodless heads, and Hermione froze in momentary shock before stumbling backwards to avoid the tail end of the cutting spell as it dissipated.

Owens didn't give her a chance to regain her equilibrium. He began to cast again, almost lazily at first, and then faster and faster, battering Hermione's shield such that she couldn't risk dropping it to retaliate. His spells were not so innocuous any longer; Reductos and Bombardas replaced jinxes meant to slow or impede. Hermione lost ground, and, eventually, her shield slipped.

She jumped backwards as it failed, but couldn't escape the full range of a Confringo that exploded at her feet. Hermione was propelled across the platform, and the limp way she rolled to a stop told Rigel the girl was no longer in full control of her faculties. There was a sickening silence as Owens walked closer to where Hermione lay, gasping weakly. The girl attempted to raise her wand, but it shook in her fingers. The American boy paused, and Rigel thought he would disarm her.

He didn't. The spell that came out of his wand was Flipendo, and it impacted Hermione's chest point-blank with a sickening crunch. Rigel let out an involuntary sound as Hermione's body was flung backwards so hard she hit the wards with a second crunch and crumpled unmoving to the stone stage. The stadium erupted at the sudden violence, and Bagman hastily declared, "THE MATCH IS OVER! OWENS ADVANCES!"

Owens left the platform without looking back. Healers descended on Hermione's supine form, and Rigel waited in the grip of fear for her to move. Please, Merlin, let her move. A hand on Rigel's shoulder jerked her back from where she'd leaned dangerously over the railing and she inhaled sharply.

It was Krum's hand. She didn't know when he'd been released from the medical tent, but when she glanced back, she saw that his face expressed exactly the murderous anger Rigel felt flailing helplessly inside her. Muted clapping drew her eyes back to the stage, where Hermione was sitting up. A healer held a wand to her chest, and the girl was visibly struggling to breathe, but she was alive. Rigel slowly unclenched her hands from their death-grip on wood between her and the pitch, and by the time Jacob Owens had climbed the stairs to the champion's box, Rigel was pretty sure she didn't want to maim him. Much.

She wasn't above giving him her best glare as he casually said, "It's your turn next, isn't it?"

Rigel tucked the anger away, knowing it would not help her in the fight against Antiope. There was no smothering it entirely, however, and it simmered in the back of her mind, ready in case she needed it later.

She felt almost naked stepping up to the platform without a knife in her left hand. Antiope's sword was, if possible, even more intimidating when the redhead brandished it toward her across the stage. Rigel took a moment before Bagman began his countdown to tighten the long gauntlet on her left hand, grateful that the top plate extended nearly halfway up her forearm. There was no doubt this match would test its workmanship even further than her encounter with the werewolf had.

"—ONE! BEGIN!"

Antiope sprinted straight at her. Rigel had been charged by bigger people than her before, and stood her ground. Having seen the redhead dance nimbly around Fleur's spells, Rigel went for a broader approach. She conjured a net of fine steel links and banished at Antiope in the next breath. The girl sliced through it without stopping, proving beyond a doubt just how wickedly sharp that sword was. Rigel realized with sudden surprise that the girl had checked her strength when she struck Fleur. Otherwise, the sword would have bitten clean through her chest.

When Antiope was almost on top of her, Rigel called up a swirling cloud of black smoke. Snape had taught her the spell, and the only downside was that without her enchanted glasses, Rigel couldn't see through it either. It did stop her opponent's charge, as even Antiope was not reckless enough to run where she couldn't see. As Rigel was about to take the opportunity to put space between them again, a spell she recognized boiled at her through the black cloud. She ducked beneath it and dove forward to escape the resultant explosion. Her roll took her through the opaque cloud and into Antiope's booted feet. The girl gave a grunt of surprise and swung at Rigel in wild reflex, but she was ready with a shield that flung the girl back, sword and all, as it bloomed from her wand right into Antiope's personal space.

Rigel released the shield before it had even fully formed, choosing to press her advantage as Antiope quick-stepped backwards to regain her balance. She cast three stunners with barely a pause, aiming each one in a slightly different place so that the girl could not avoid all three with one move. Antiope's footwork could have made even Draco blush with envy, though, as she lunged and twisted around the oncoming spells. Her last spell went over Antiope's head as the stocky girl ducked under it and swung her sword up to try and get under Rigel's guard.

Rather than shield again, Rigel slammed her left hand down and to the side, meeting the blade with her gauntlet and redirecting Antiope's sword with sheer force. It was more surprise than anything that let her succeed, she thought, as Antiope's sword bounced off and away. Rigel didn't waste the second of shock that widened her opponent's eyes. She shot a stunner point-blank at the girl's chest and watched, unwillingly impressed, as Antiope's reflexes took over and the girl fell backwards in a truly beautiful backbend. The girl's left foot came up with a sweep as she did, and Rigel jumped back a step to avoid a boot to the face.

Rigel could do little more than gape as Antiope reversed her momentum on her right foot alone, her left leg arching forward to force her upright again before joining its pair on the ground in what was, she realized with a disbelieving smile, a perfect dueling stance.

"Incredible," Rigel breathed.

"Shut up." Antiope cast a Bombarda and Rigel called up a reflecting shield to send it straight back at her. The girl stepped back and to the side to let it sail over her shoulder and impact with a boom against the wards some twenty feet behind her.

There was a brief pause as both girls stared one another down. Rigel wasn't sure what tactic to use with someone as skilled as Antiope. There would be no getting around her footwork, and she seemed to seamlessly transition between sword and wand when necessary. Rigel would have to surprise her, she thought.

Antiope was clearly resizing Rigel as well. The girl brought her hands together and gripped her sword between both of them, her wand trapped parallel to the sword's hilt beneath her right palm. With a battle cry, the girl charged again, her chin-length hair flying wildly behind her. If Rigel thought Antiope wouldn't be able to cast with her wand pinned to the sword pommel, she was mistaken. Before she could consider how to defend against the sword, a stunning spell came jetting toward her along the trajectory of its point.

Rigel hastily got a shield up to intercept the spell. It held easily, but a moment later the sword came whooshing down. Rigel braced herself against the reverberations of such a strong blow impacting the Fortis, but Antiope's sword barely slowed when it touched the edge of the shimmering shield. Rigel yelped and twisted to the side with enough desperate force to strain several abdominal muscles simultaneously. The sword missed her neck, though, continuing down with enough force to clang against the stone floor as Rigel dragged herself sideways.

She sprinted away from the girl and her shield-eating sword, her heart thumping in her chest at the inexplicably close call. What in Merlin's name had happened? Rigel had seen Fleur's shield hold up against Antiope's sword several times. For that matter, Rigel's own shield had deflected Antiope's sword just minutes earlier. What had changed?

Rigel eyed the redhead across the healthy distance she'd put between them, and her gaze was drawn to the two-handed grip Antiope had on her sword. That's it, she thought. She'd switched to a two-handed grip when she broke through Fleur's shield, too. Something about it gave her sword that extra ability. Rigel had never heard of anything that could just slice through protective magic like that, but then, she was well aware that the world was full of more things than she'd personally catalogued in her short life.

Armed with renewed caution, Rigel cast several Impedimentas in quick succession, hoping that if she could slow the girl down, even for a short period of time, she might gain the upper-hand. Antiope ducked and dipped around each of them without trying. Perfect footwork, she reminded herself. Ranged attacks gave her too much time to dodge, and close-in combat gave her the advantage. Really, Rigel thought, this task had been made for a witch like Antiope.

Well, Rigel was not afraid of close-dueling either. She cast a few moderate dueling spells, but ultimately allowed Antiope to eliminate the space between them. She met the girl's next strike with the back of her gauntlet, using her right hand to brace her left and her slight height advantage to bear down on the girl until she disengaged. Antiope audibly growled as she came back for a second strike, this time toward Rigel's right side. She spun into the attack, dropping her wand from her right hand to her left and using the momentum from her pivot to counter the force of the redhead's blow, this time with her right gauntlet. She was casting a disarming charm with her left hand before Antiope's sword had even finished connecting, forcing the girl to let go of the pommel with her wand hand in order to simultaneously attack and shield.

As soon as Antiope switched to a one-handed grip on the sword, Rigel summoned her own shield and slammed it against Antiope's with as much force as she could summon. The redhead, not anticipating the physical assault, cried out as her unanchored shield was slapped backwards into her face. The unmistakable crunch of a broken nose made Rigel wince, but Antiope's sword descended like an avenging angel, precluding any true remorse.

Rigel spun away from the weapon and took a couple quick steps back to catch her breath. Antiope had blood dripping down her chin, but one wouldn't know it from the utterly focused look in her eyes. She spat a glob of red spit onto the platform, and Rigel couldn't help but think that no one should be so careless with their own blood.

Antiope advanced with a vengeance, resuming her two-handed grip and casting with a speed that Rigel spent every ounce of focus keeping up with. Eventually, the girl was close enough to begin slashing at Rigel again, and without the option of a shield, Rigel met every blow with one or both of her gauntlets. Her arms began to shake with the sheer amount of force raining down on them, but she was maneuvering Antiope around the platform all the while. Finally, Rigel reached the position she needed; she flung a Ventus so powerful she could perceive the net change in her core, and it flung Antiope back and down, pressing her into the ground until it dissipated.

With her opponent temporarily occupied, Rigel dropped into a crouch and dragged her fingers through the congealing wad of red spit that Antiope had abandoned. As she drew an abbreviated rune with the fresh blood on her fingers, she said, "Rigescunt indutae."

Antiope, who had scarcely regained her feet, literally froze. The blood in her veins seized just long enough for Rigel to lunge forward, wrap her gauntleted hand around the sword, and wrest the blade from Antiope's fingers. The effect of the single-rune magic only lasted a brief moment, not nearly long enough to do the girl any real harm, but it was long enough for Rigel to drop the sword to the ground and cast a sticking charm with a truly vindictive sense of satisfaction.

The first thing Antiope did was try to wandlessly summon the sword. It remained fixed to the stone, and the redhead girl shouted her fury to the sky. She charged, but Rigel thought the girl looked a lot less frightening with only a wand to brandish before her.

Antiope's entire style depended on her weapon. Without it, her defense had glaring holes, and Rigel took advantage of each and every one. She kept the duel close, so that Antiope had neither time nor space to dodge. Antiope tried several debilitating spells, but without the sword to swing in their wake, Rigel was free to shield or dodge as she preferred; the redhead was good, but Rigel was faster. She whipped spell after spell into Antiope's defense, and after the sixth over-powered stunner, Antiope's magic faltered. Rigel saw the shield flicker, and when it failed, she had an Incarcerous waiting. Antiope fell, bound and shortly thereafter disarmed, to the stone.

Rigel stared at her opponent's wand, resting innocently in the palm on her free hand, and it took her a moment to realize it was over. Then she realized no one was cheering.

"WELL THERE YOU HAVE IT." Even Bagman seemed vaguely stunned. "BLACK ADVANCES TO THE FINAL ROUND!"

The applause started slowly, and faded quickly. Rigel was amazed that she still had it in her to care, but something about the lackluster response to her victory set off warning bells in her brain. As the adrenaline receded and full reason returned, Rigel wondered belatedly if blood magic hadn't been the best way to endear the public to her cause.

It's not as though it was a blood curse or anything permanent, she reasoned. The rune was one she'd found in Dumbledore's book, Arrays for the Harried, and she didn't believe the Headmaster would give her anything dangerous.

She released Antiope and returned her wand, all the while trying not to quail under the fiery fury in the shorter redhead's glare. "What kind of dirty trick was that, Black?"

Rigel did not pretend to misunderstand her. "I drew a rune in your blood," she said, indicating the smudge on the platform that remained. "It wasn't shed willingly, but that doesn't mean it holds no power."

Antiope scowled and pointed her wand at the smudge. "Scourgify." Her expression was still furious, but there was a grudging understanding in her eyes, too, when she looked back at Rigel. "They don't teach us runes at Chalcioecus. Aside from the trick, you fought well. This wasn't your first time facing a weaponed duelist."

Rigel smiled, but didn't respond to the implied question. The two of them made their way toward the stairs, but Bagman's voice forestalled their descent.

"THE THREE REMAINING CHAMPIONS WILL EACH DUEL ONE ANOTHER FOR THE FINAL ROUND. THE MATCHES WILL BE: BLACK AND KRUM, KRUM AND OWENS, THEN OWENS AND BLACK." Rigel suppressed a groan as she realized she'd be dueling again immediately. Antiope gave her a smirk as she continued down the stairs. "THE HIGHEST SCORE WILL BE GIVEN TO EITHER THE COMPETITOR WHO WINS BOTH HIS MATCHES OR THE ONE THE JUDGES DEEM TO HAVE FOUGHT MOST IMPRESSIVELY OVERALL."

It didn't escape Rigel's notice that she was the only champion who would have to duel four times instead of three. Why couldn't they give her a by this round and let her duel the winner between Krum and Owens? Riddle really was a sadist, she decided as she turned around and moved back to the center of one side of the platform. She tightened the laces on her boots, gave her muscles a quick stretch, and waited for Krum to take the stage as well.

Krum regarded her warily as he took up a ready stance on the opposite side of the stage. Rigel dipped into a slight crouch and bent her mind to the upcoming duel. She'd seen from his match with Tahiil that Krum was a careful, strategic duelist. He was also well-rested from his break, while her muscles ached from the battering of Antiope's sword. If she wanted a shot at outlasting him, Rigel would have to keep him at a distance and wear him down with magic.

Grimly, she brandished her wand and waited for Bagman to count them in.

Three. Two. One.

The scene playing out on the platform below could not have gone better if he'd choreographed it himself. He supposed, in a way, he had, but Rigel Black had once again surpassed his every expectation. The boy was a diamond under pressure; each match he performed better, even as his competitors grew wan and worn.

Originally, he'd not expected the Slytherin to actually win the third task. The boy need only advance to the final round, and his existing point lead would ensure that he was crowned the pureblood champion. The two girls he was matched against should not have posed a major challenge—at least, not if the judges had followed his advice against allowing Antiope a weapon. The promise of a more exciting spectacle had been too tempting for the Department of Magical Games and Sports to ignore, however, and he was forced to grit his teeth as Black dueled an opponent he was in no way qualified to face.

Again, however, the boy had surprised him. Rather than fumble before the added challenge, as Delacour had, Rigel became more efficient. More creative. Pain seemed not to slow him and nothing—neither the cheers nor jeers of the crowd above him—could break his concentration. Few wizards had any real experience with dueling these days, much less the skill to handle both wand and weapon simultaneously. It was why he'd expected the boy to leap at the chance for real training in the art. When Rigel rejected his offer in amused pride, he'd thought him wholly foolish.

Now, he wasn't so sure. The boy looked utterly at his leisure, neither overly tense nor particularly nervous as he led the Durmstrang boy around the stage in a subtle dance. Krum thought he was setting the pace, carefully probing his opponent's defenses with an unpredictable combination of grey magic that mixed dangerous spells with relatively innocuous ones. It was clear to him, however, that Rigel was only obliging the pace to recover energy after his last duel. Eventually, the boy would strike back. Rigel Black was more ruthless than he admitted, whether he realized it or not.

He took a moment to observe those around him in the judge's box. Most of the occupants were utterly enthralled in the duel, impressed, as well they should be, in the level of talent the young wizards were displaying. There was one rather predictable exception. Albus Dumbledore's eyes were, as ever, leveled at Tom.

He wondered whether the old Headmaster suspected his final aim in all this. Probably he did—it mattered not. For once, Dumbledore was only tangentially related to his primary target. A dismayed gasp from Marchbanks brought his head back around sharply. Rigel had taken the edge of a slicing spell to the arm. The boy didn't slow, and Riddle's eyes narrowed thoughtfully. After several more spells were exchanged, Rigel failed to fully shield against a buffeting charm, and was knocked back several feet. Krum began to cast in earnest, no doubt sensing victory on the horizon. Rigel took several other spells in some peripheral way or another, and then Riddle realized his game. The boy never flinched or even betrayed surprise when one of Krum's spells caught him. Telling, too, was that none of the seriously damaging spells came anywhere close to him.

He's letting them hit. Lulling Krum into a false sense of security. Riddle had to smirk in heady approval. The boy was allowing Krum to come to the conclusion that he was tired, slowing down and getting sloppy. It was gloriously satisfying to watch the Durmstrang champion advance, like a particularly bold lamb to the slaughter.

His sharp peripheral vision surprised a troubled frown on Dumbledore's face. Tom slowly turned to acknowledge the ancient wizard, unable to hide his amusement at Dumbledore's distress. So he was worried for his precious student, was he? Rigel Black would not be the first soul Dumbledore failed to save, nor would he be the last.

Another sharp sound from Marchbanks, whose objectivity was but a fragile screen when it came to the young Slytherin dueling below, brought his attention back to the entertainment. Krum had attempted to press his advantage. He was nearing the center of the platform, risking the added vulnerability of the position under the assumption that Rigel was losing steam.

Rigel allowed himself to be thrown backwards and rolled, seeming to miss the next two spells almost by sheer luck alone. Krum darted forward, but by the time the fourth spell left his wand Rigel was on his feet again, sprinting toward the surprised Bulgarian boy with no sign of the fatigue he'd been feigning just moments before. Krum was thrown on the defensive as his opponent closed the gap between them, forced to hold a shield against the barrage of spells the slighter boy threw his way, scrambling backwards all the while.

Faster and faster the boy cast, continuing to advance until there was nowhere left for Krum to retreat within the wards. The stadium around them was almost silent as Rigel threw magic across the stage as if it was effortless. It seemed impossible that the young wizard could produce magic any faster, and yet, within the space of one breath to the next, he did. The entire platform was lit with the ferocity of the boy's casting, each spell taking off on wings of light before the one before it had been dispersed. He doubted any shield, no matter how expertly cast, could hold against it for long. Krum was utterly overwhelmed.

It was gratifying to see the boy perform so well, even as his talent made attempting to mentor him…inconvenient. The more Rigel Black succeeded, the harder he would be to control. And yet, his very plans depended on the boy rising higher than he ever dreamed. If only the child would not resist his destiny.

He could feel nothing but pure pleasure watching Rigel force his opponent to submit. Cunning. Patient. Ruthless. Was the boy not a perfect conduit for his knowledge and influence? Even his stubbornness would be an asset, when turned in the proper direction. As Bagman proclaimed Rigel's victory, he listened to the crowd's uneasy rumblings. As the boy lifted his head uncertainly to the sky, he saw the trepidation in his eyes.

He smiled slowly. This, he could work with. Often he bestowed on his followers validation where otherwise in their lives it was absent. Rigel Black would be set apart after this demonstration. Envied. Feared. Suspected of anything the shallow minds of the masses could conceive. The boy knew it, by the uneasy way he ducked his head and allowed the medics on standby to escort him to the healing tent.

Tom caught Dumbledore's eyes as he made his way from the box. The icy gaze levied a heavy judgement, but he was no longer a child. He had no interest in the following match, and took his time descending the many steps to the ground level. By the time he stepped into the healing tent, Rigel's wounds, minor as they were, had all been treated. The healers left the tent quietly as he entered, and he turned his attention to his quarry. The boy sat on a cot with his head down, a cup clutched between his hands. The water in the cup trembled, and when he spoke, it sloshed over the edge.

"Congratulations, Rigel."

The boy lifted his head with a gasp that was only audible to his superb hearing. "Riddle." His voice was flat, but resigned rather than combative.

"What a spectacular set of duels you've had," he went on. "It's easy to see that you're the most impressive competitor on that stage."

Sure enough, the boy's eyes flickered up toward the roaring crowd and back down unconsciously. Rigel grimaced. "I'm winning, at least," he said, shrugging uncomfortably.

He shook his head slowly. "And yet you sound guilty for doing so." Rigel scowled, but before an argument could surface, he'd pressed on. "Their applause means nothing, you know." The boy gaped at him in surprise. He smiled down at him ruefully. "There will always be those who are envious of true ability and trepidatious of its implications." He carefully did not mention the word 'power.' The boy had responded poorly to it in the past. "Of course they try to make less of you. They would rather see you as other than as something they could all aspire to if they ever bothered to truly apply themselves."

Rigel's eyes were wide, and he stared at Tom as though he'd never seen him before. He took a small step closer and lowered his chin slightly, just enough to convey a sense of empathetic rapport. "They don't see the hours of training, the late nights spent in fervent study, or the early mornings of disciplined practice. They don't see weekends and holidays sacrificed to self-betterment, but I see those things. I see your ambition, your perseverance, and your drive. You are extraordinary, and you shall not apologize for it in my presence." He lowered his voice, softening it deftly. "Anyone who doesn't realize that is in the wrong. Well done today. You've shown the world what you're truly capable of."

Rigel looked more lost than accepting of the words, but that was all right for now. He turned to go, and thought the boy didn't mean his muttered, "That's what I'm afraid of" to be heard by him. He did not acknowledge it, except in his head.

One day, Rigel Black, you will not be afraid of anything. When you stand at my side, fear will be but a memory of a time before uncompromising greatness was fully embraced.

As Riddle walked out of the tent, Rigel had to admit that, if she hadn't been a halfblood pretending to be a pureblood, and if she hadn't known he was full of shite, she might actually find him convincing. There were times, she conceded, when the man was incredibly persuasive. She could hardly blame people for being swayed by him. Somehow, in some sick twist of the fabric of time and space, Riddle had known exactly what she longed to hear in that moment, when doubt and unease churned their way to dread in her stomach. It was precisely that which made her distrust the man, though.

Friends did not come to you when you were at your most vulnerable and attempt to sway you. If the man had known the first thing about true friendship or even mentorship, he would know better than to try to use her weakness to leverage her viewpoint toward his own.

She sighed. Riddle's little pep talk aside, she still had one last duel before the day was done. The look in Krum's eyes as she'd pinned him in place and ripped away the last of his defenses was something she'd never forget. The Bulgarian had looked at her as though she'd peeled off her own face before his eyes. Shock, disbelief, fear, and panic all shot across the staid boy's face in the instant he realized how badly he'd underestimated her. Now they would all know that beneath Rigel's calm, collected demeanor there was something undeniably aggressive. Something merciless.

Knowing that staying in the tent wouldn't help her analyze Owens for her upcoming match, Rigel levered herself up from the cot and left the healing tent behind to seek out the stairs up to the champions' box. She was the only one left, so she let her shoulders slump and leaned heavily on the railing, taking in the match below with tired eyes.

It was clear almost immediately that Krum had exhausted himself in his match against her. He spent more time dodging than casting, and when he did cast the spells flew sluggishly. The boy's magical core was just about tapped from all the powerful spells he'd thrown her way. Owens was fairing much better, likely because this was only his second duel, not his third, and he conserved a lot of energy with his shield flickering technique.

Owens' footwork was fluid, and he seemed to slide effortlessly out of the way of Krum's ranged attacks. Whenever the Bulgarian attempted to close the distance between them, Owens switched his spells to area-effect charms and transfigurations to keep him back. It was clever, Rigel admitted, watching Krum once again fall back before a barrage of sharp stones banished his way. Krum's already weakened magic would be even more ineffectual at a distance: easy to dodge and somewhat attenuated by the long way the spells had to travel.

The match didn't last much longer. Without the strength to conjure any of his own area-effect spells, Krum was at an unrecoverable disadvantage. When Owen's caught the boy in a petrification charm at last, Rigel made her way down from the box with a thoughtful frown. Getting through Owens' defense was going to be a challenge.

She passed an exhausted, bruised, and scowling Krum on the way up to the platform. "You fought well," she offered.

He paused to let her by, shaking his head. "I lost the pureblood spot ven you beat me," he said. "I just vanted to pay that boy back for vat he did to Hermy-one." Krum leveled an imploring look at her. "Thrash him, Black."

Rigel pressed her lips together but nodded slowly. She didn't like the dark desire for vengeance that thrummed in her blood, but she also couldn't forget the sound of Hermione's ribs cracking beneath an entirely unnecessary Flipendo.

Owens was waiting patiently for her as she ascended the final steps. He smiled, and there was an unruffled quality to the tall boy that didn't sit right with her. Rigel wondered why she hadn't paid closer attention to the boy during the first two tasks. With so many competitors on the field, many of them boasting unique and exotic abilities, it was too easy to overlook the blond American. She should have listened to Pansy and Millicent; she couldn't for the life of her remember anything specific about his background. It should have been a red flag that the innocuous looking boy across from her was leading the scoreboard. Before, Rigel had been too focused on her own concerns to really see this boy, but she was looking at him now.

The boy bowed with a mocking grin as Bagman counted down to the last match. Rigel solemnly returned the bow—if he was going to invoke the courtesies, then she wouldn't be the one to disgrace them. As the final word rang out, Rigel's wand arched into motion. Two stunners and a disarming spell cast so fast there was scarcely space between them were enough to wipe the smile off the Ilvermorny boy's face, but his micro-shield flickered up to intercept each attack.

She had to admit his timing was impeccable. Not many could judge the speed of a spell's approach accurately enough to confidently raise and lower a shield at precisely the right moment. It meant he never spent much time passive, easily moving between defense and offense with seamless speed.

Every time Rigel tried to close the distance between them, Owens repeated his strategy for keeping Krum at arm's length: area-effect spells nasty enough to deter most people from bearing the brunt of them. She allowed him to force her retreat with wind charms, fire spells, and blasting curses. Just as she could see him begin to relax into the rhythm, she charged.

Startled, Owens conjured a barrage of icy shards and banished them toward her in a razor-sharp rain. Rigel shielded without stopping and didn't let up her sprint. Owen's jerked his wand down and the ice instead began to solidify beneath her feet. Rigel leapt forward over the ice and tucked into a ball, maintaining her shield tightly around her and letting it roll her forward in a dizzying tumble. The roll carried her forward so fast, even Owens couldn't get another spell up before she was in his guard.

Rigel's left hand clamped down on his wand arm, jerking the weapon away from her with brute force. Owen's let out a grunt of surprise but reacted quickly; his free hand grabbed wildly at her head, gripping a fist full of hair and yanking it down harshly. Rather than let him leverage his strength to pull her off him, Rigel inverted her wand and severed the hair with a wordless charm. Owens' wide eyes were riveted on her wand, waiting for it to turn around and curse him, but he was looking in the wrong direction entirely.

Her left hand hadn't been idle. The runeless fire array she'd imprinted in pure magic on his sleeve ignited, and the taller boy let out a strangled howl of pain. Rigel had let go of his arm before the array activated, and the boy was free to drop to the platform and roll in an instinctive attempt to put the fire out. Maybe she could have disarmed him right then in his distraction, but she didn't. Later, she could tell herself that she'd been playing it safe, hesitating to avoid overextending herself, but in that moment, she simply wasn't done with Jacob Owens.

As he rolled, she crouched to the stone and drew a ground shaking array with her wand. It ripped up the stage in a circle around her, bucking Owens' rolling form with the force of the magic she'd shoved into it. He hit his head on the stone but managed to raise a shield as he rolled to a stop—not one of his flickeringly short varieties, but a real shield, carefully layered and intended to last. No doubt he would try to hold it until he could regain his feet.

Rigel cast a Lightning Jaw at the shield almost idly, and the magic collapsed in on itself with a shudder. Owens cursed, only half-risen, and stumbled backwards away from the blasting curse that followed. As she pursued the boy around the platform, Rigel reflected that it was for the best that theirs was the last match. The stage wouldn't be in much condition for anyone after she was through with it.

The next several minutes were an exercise in sheer stamina for Rigel, and a prolonged, desperate escape attempt for Owens. The more disheveled the boy became, the more satisfied Rigel felt. By the time the boy found himself leaning, panting and sweating, against the wards, the stage was a lunarscape of potholes and crevices, interspersed with the occasional scorch mark. Rigel was beginning to tire too, however, and knew that only an end to the match would bring her real peace.

She tossed a couple of standard disarming spell at him and let Owens shield as usual, his signature defense flickering up and away again with the same precision it had at the beginning of the duel. Then, Rigel cast a stunning spell with her wand and followed it immediately with a wandless Banishing Charm, cast from her left hand without moving it from her side. The second, nearly invisible spell caught up to the first about two-thirds of the way across the space between her and Owens. The boy, clearly familiar with the speed at which a standard stunner moved, defended automatically. This time, however, his timing was just the tiniest bit off.

Rigel's accelerated spell reached him before his shield was fully formed, and he collapsed like a puppet with its strings cut. It was a long moment before Rigel lowered her wand and let out her breath in a slow whoosh. Her ears were ringing with the noise in the stadium, but for the life of her she couldn't tell whether it was approval or not. She supposed it didn't matter. She'd won.

The energy which had sustained her for most of the day began to drain out of her like the air coming out of a balloon when the hand holding it closed had let go at last. She considered reviving Owens, but there were already healers coming onto the stage to do just that. Instead, Rigel tucked her wand away and began her final descent from the dueling platform. A healer approached her as she crossed the lawn, but she waved the wizard off. There was nothing wrong with her that he could fix.

Bagman was shouting something to the crowd, but she wasn't listening. All her energy was bent toward putting one foot in front of the other. Pansy and Draco, somehow, got to her before she reached the exit. They must have left their seats the moment Owens collapsed. She attempted a smile for them, but it withered on the vine. She felt like a rag that had been wrung out and left to hang limply on a line. Already, she regretted losing her temper with Owens. Why had she let the stupid tournament get to her?

"Congratulations, Rigel," Draco said earnestly. "You did it. You're the pureblood champion."

The pureblood champion. She, Harriet Potter, was the pureblood champion. A hollow laugh escaped her, and she clamped her hand to her mouth to hold it in. Her shoulders shook with the effort. I'm the pureblood champion. Even her mental voice sounded hysterical. What a joke.

The laughter turned to hiccupping sobs, and Pansy gathered her close in a gentle embrace. "It's all right, Rigel. It's over, now. Let it out."

It wasn't over, though. At best, she was only halfway through the storm of madness. She turned her face into Pansy's shoulders and listened to the girl tut over her newly shorn hair. Somehow, the inane concern centered her, and she calmed as Pansy prattled on about the charms it would take to fix the uneven length.

"He looks dangerous," Draco argued. "We should shave it all instead."

Rigel choked out a laugh, imagining Archie's face if she told him he needed to go bald for the winter holidays. When she leaned back to send Draco a grateful smile, he smiled back bracingly.

"Seriously, you were great, Rye." He waggled a finger at her and added, "I think you've been holding back in Dueling Club."

The joke fell flat, and Rigel knew by the slightly awed look in his eyes that she'd really surprised him that day. Beneath his concern for her and his unquestioning support, Draco must be wondering how kind, studious Rigel Black could put someone on their back like that. She'd never gone so far in training.

She turned away from his conflicted gaze and took a deep breath. Forcing a nonchalant grin, she said, "I guess you never brought out my full potential. Maybe Pansy should take over the DA."

"But then it would be the PA," Draco complained. "The Pansy Association just sounds sad."

"How about the Perfect Army?" Pansy suggested lightly. She tucked her arm through Rigel's and began to tow her slowly toward the exit, studiously ignoring the churning crowd that stood between them and the castle doors.

"More like the Pathetic Army."

They bickered over the options all the way back to the Slytherin common room, and somehow the normalcy of their banter cut through the awe-struck faces and the whispers when no amount of stoic pride or quiet humility would have protected her.

By the time she reached her dorm, she had almost stilled the quivering anxiety in her chest. Whatever conclusions her friends may have drawn from her performance in the third task, they were sticking by her. It was that thought that Rigel clutched tightly to as she locked herself in the bathroom and turned the water as hot as it would go.

As the water washed away all evidence of the day, she told herself that Riddle was wrong. Power didn't count for everything, and not everyone who witnessed it would inevitably flinch away from it. It just confirmed her suspicion that the politician had no real friends. From that thought came another, far more disturbing. How different might the world be if he did?

Rigel woke the next morning with a vague idea of spending the day in her lab. She deserved some relaxation after the third task, she thought, and her walk to the Great Hall for breakfast was occupied imagining which potion she would brew first.

She veered toward the Slytherin table, but was waylaid as she passed the Gryffindors by a pair of highly complimentary redheads.

"Puppy! You were a right terrier yesterday!"

"Didn't stick around to let anyone congratulate you though," George added, shaking his head in mock disappointment. "Don't you know your adoring fans need face time to sustain their obsession?"

"More reason to remain scarce," Rigel said.

"No chance of that today," Fred said, chuckling.

She frowned, looking between the two sixth years suspiciously. "Why's that? I hope you haven't done anything extravagant."

The twins stared at her. George coughed and said, "It's, uh, the Yule Ball tonight, Rigel." His voice climbed higher as he added, "You do have a date, right?"

Rigel rolled her eyes on a groan. "I forgot about that."

"Forgot?" Fred laughed. "You're only the main even, Pup. Listen, if you need a date, I'm sure we can—"

"No need for that."

The three of them turned to see Matheus Sousa with a relaxed half-smile on his face. She searched his expression critically, but his eyes seemed clear for the moment. The Brazilian boy leaned down and said, voice light, "I will take you, if you like."

It took her an embarrassingly long moment to realize he was asking her to the Yule Ball. Her eyes widened and she shook her head apologetically. "That's very kind. I have a—well, my…fiancée is coming. But thank you. Sorry?"

Matheus tilted his head consideringly at her, but then he sighed dramatically. "I will never heal from this hurt. My life is now pale and black."

Rigel frowned. "It can't be both pale and black."

"Ouch, so harsh, Puppy." Fred snickered.

"Give the bloke a chance," George added, smirking down at her superiorly.

She glared up at them. "Why don't one of you give him a chance, then, if you feel so bad?" She turned to Matheus with a sweet smile. "Fred and George are excellent company. You should ask one of them."

The twins exchange an affronted look.

"One of us?"

"Impossible!"

"We're a set, Puppy."

She was certain they were joking, but Matheus smiled widely and spread his arms. "Will you two do me this honor, then?"

Fred and George had matching expressions of mischief.

"I'm imagining Mum's face," Fred admitted, grinning widely.

"And it's difficult to resist," George agreed, nodding in false solemnity. He eyed Matheus with sudden suspicion. "Say, we weren't your second choice, were we?"

Matheus widened his eyes with affected dismay. "Pray, do not imagine this. In truth, Rigel was but an excuse to talk to you."

"In that case, however could we refuse?" Fred wrapped his arms around George's neck and batted his eyes at Matheus playfully. "Be gentle with us."

Rigel looked between the twins and Matheus, confusion warring with horror as she imagined the three of them unleashed on the world. A thought struck her and she narrowed her eyes at the twins. "Don't drink anything he gives you," she said flatly. A moment later, she reconsidered and shot a worried look toward the Brazilian boy. "Don't drink anything they give you, actually."

All three of the boys laughed, and Rigel firmly told herself that it was not her fault if Hogwarts was a smoking ruin by the end of the night. She turned resolutely away, thinking that if the world was to end in a matter of hours, she at least wanted to eat breakfast first.

As she sat, Blaise said, "Bit early to be breaking hearts, isn't it, Rigel?"

She shot him a look that said she did not appreciate him using his enhanced hearing to eavesdrop. "The castle has gone mad," she muttered, spooning porridge into her bowl.

"One night of madness never hurt anyone," Pansy said, smiling slyly.

Rigel gave her an unimpressed look. "What hapless soul are you taking, then?" she asked.

Pansy sniffed, but there was something more nervous than haughty about it. "Draco is accompanying me, actually." Her eyes met Rigel's briefly before turning to study her orange juice with undue gravity. "As friends, of course."

"That's great," Rigel said at once.

There was an awkward pause before Pansy said, "Yes, well. Blaise is escorting Miss Abbot, of course. Theo has managed to catch Heir Smith's eye, and Millie is taking Mr. Zahi."

Millicent flushed, the color dramatic against her pale skin. "He's interesting."

Pansy nodded sagely. "He is, indeed. I think it's quite decorous of you to be such a faultless ambassador for Hogwarts, Millie. The visitors are in an awkward position, attempting to secure escorts in a foreign place."

"Not all of them did, though," Theo pointed out. "That Chinese girl brought a beau from home, I hear, and the American Rigel trashed in the finals did, too."

Rigel winced. It hadn't been that bad, had it?

"Delacour is going with Roger Davies, of all people," Draco put in. "Can you imagine that twit attempting a waltz?"

Rigel did a quick mental tally and said, "What about Antiope?" She was the only one, besides Krum and Hermione, they hadn't mentioned.

Pansy smiled slowly. "Miss Weasley asked her. I was there when it happened. She said that stunning redheads such as themselves could only logically deign to accompany one another, and Antiope agreed."

Rigel could easily imagine Ginny saying such a thing, and she had to smile in amusement. Picturing the two fiery, bold souls, she thought the combination would either be spectacular or disastrous.

"Weasley just wanted to be the only third year to attend the ball," Draco said cynically.

"Then she succeeded, and we can't fault her for that," Pansy said primly.

Rigel thought privately that people faulted others for succeeding all the time, but she didn't say so. She made it halfway through breakfast without thinking about anything other than how many cauldrons she could reasonably expect to brew simultaneously that morning. She was a little rusty at juggling multiple brews, but the challenge would be refreshing.

The mail brought ripples of surprised exclamations and murmured conversations. Rigel, despite her better judgement, turned her attention to the paper that Pansy was poring over with Millicent and said, "What is it, Pan?"

Her friend had a familiar, uneasy look on her face. "It's…the marriage law."

Her heart dropped. "It's passed already?"

Pansy shook her head quickly. "No, but…it passed committee last night."

Rigel was not at all familiar with legislative processes, but Millicent clarified at the frown on her face. "The bill was introduced for consideration and has passed the preliminary requirements for being voted on by the full Wizengamot at a future point."

"When will they vote on it?" she asked weakly.

"Not for a while," Millicent said, shrugging. "The Wizengamot is in recess through the holidays, and typically only sit about 60 days a year. With the number of propositions already on the docket for the spring session, I'd estimate it'll be at least after the spring break before it's considered."

She felt the ice in her veins thaw in slow relief. She still had time. To do what, she wasn't sure. All she knew was that there must be some way she could influence the outcome. If not, then all the time spent preparing for and stressing over the tournament would be an utter waste.

After a moment in which her blood pressure attempted to convince her to just pack up and move to Majorca, Rigel took a deep breath and turned back to her breakfast. There was no need to be macabre over breakfast. Rather, she should turn her mind to something more productive. How exactly Archie was going to get to Hogwarts, for instance.

Professor Snape had already made the arrangements, it turned out. Archie would be arriving in her Head of House's office by special international Floo access a short while before the ball was set to start, and Rigel had to wonder just how focused on the third task she'd been that she could hardly remember the conversation she'd had with Snape several days before outlining precisely that.

Pansy, bless her patient heart, had graciously found the time to select Rigel's dress robes amidst her own preparations, and so it was with tentative confidence in her attire that she arrived at Master Snape's office door. She pulled at the stiff collar awkwardly as she knocked. When the door opened, she was entirely surprised to find her professor also dressed in formal robes, his hair clubbed back neatly and his expression no less severe for the transformation.

It made obvious sense, she supposed. It was a formal event for all attending, not only the champions, and that included teachers, too. She stepped into the room to wait and tried not to scuff the shiny toes of her entirely unfunctional shoes as she walked. Archie was right on time, and both she and Snape moved out of the way as the temporarily connected fireplace lit up in a way that had nothing to do with the fire.

Her cousin spun out of the grate with a graceful stride, his delicate, sky-blue dress robes swirling around slender legs. There was an odd gait to his approach and Rigel realized with raised eyebrows that Archie was wearing improbably constructed heels of sparkling silver. Her eyes trailed up the form-fitting tailoring about his hips and waist, and she nearly choked when she noticed the cheerfully bouncing twin globes affixed to her cousin's chest, scarcely contained by the thin, draping material that gathered almost in afterthought around Archie's lithe neck.

What on Merlin's green earth…? Rigel did not return her cousin's stunning smile. Her face looked absurdly incongruous atop the menacingly curvaceous form she could only assume Archie had constructed solely on the basis of a Playwizard magazine.

"Cousin!" Archie wrapped graceful arms around her. "I've missed you so."

Rigel forced her arms to hug the alien being clinging to her, but dropped them immediately in distaste. Archie felt so wrong as a female. "Harry, so glad you could make it safely. Thanks for coming all this way."

Archie shrugged, patting his elaborate updo as he pulled back from their embrace. "Term is over anyway for us. Easier to Floo here and go home with you and Sirius tonight than to catch a flight from the States. Master Snape, you look fantastic," Archie added airily. "Thanks so much for setting up the international Floo tonight."

Snape's face was entirely blank as he said, "Perhaps you and your guest should make your way toward the Great Hall, Rigel."

She nodded, taking Archie by the wrist and saying, "Good idea, Professor. See you in a bit."

When they were safely in the corridor she whirled on Archie and demanded in a strident whisper, "What is wrong with you?"

Archie blinked at her in surprise. "What?"

She jabbed a finger in the general direction of Archie's metamorphized chest and hips. "That! Why didn't you stick to something more androgynous?"

"In this dress?" Archie looked down skeptically at the clinging fabric. "It would never have worked."

"Who told you to pick such a revealing dress?" she hissed. Could he honestly not see any problem with his appearance? "How am I supposed to look like that for the rest of the holidays after Sirius sees you tonight? Salazar, how am I supposed to replicate that for the rest of my life?"

A sheepish look dawned across her cousin's face. "Ah, I see. Well, the clothes you wear are usually so baggy. Who's to say what size rack you have? I bet Sirius will assumed he just never noticed. If he notices at all—I mean, he's your uncle. Ew."

"He'd have to be blind not to notice those. Trim them down. Now."

Archie pouted at her, the red lipstick on his mouth making the expression more dramatic. "Then it won't fit right."

"I'll shrink your dress a little," Rigel said through gritted teeth.

"Snape's already seen me."

"I swear on your life Professor Snape will. Not. Ask."

The boy in female flesh sighed, but obligingly went down a cup size. It was still overwhelmingly wrong in every way, but at least 'Harry' no longer looked like an underwear model.

When Archie's dress was appropriately adjusted to his satisfaction, they started toward the Great Hall again. He peeked over at her under dark mascara. "Are you still angry with me?"

Rigel sighed. "No. Sorry, Ar—Harry. I've been sort of stressed lately."

"I know." Archie smiled ruefully at her. "I heard you won the third task."

She immediately felt guilty for having forgotten to tell him so herself. "Yes. Sorry, cuz. I should have used the mirror to tell you. I just…"

"I get it, Rigel. Really. You've got a lot on your shoulders right now. I think you're doing great, though. Halfway through, right?"

She nodded wearily. "I can't wait to go home tonight. I need to get out of this mess for a bit."

"Just a few more hours," her cousin said, patting her on the back consolingly. His expression was poised and, if she admitted it, his version of her face was quite pretty all done up in makeup, glittering drops in his ears. It doesn't look like me, though, she thought uneasily. Then she shook her head and impatiently reminded herself that she didn't even know what she looked like anymore. What did it really matter what Archie did with her face? It wasn't as though she hadn't ever caused him difficulties wearing his face the last few years.

They reached the Entrance Hall and found the other champions waiting to the side of the Great Hall doors with their respective dates. Hermione waved shyly at them from her place next to Krum, but her welcoming expression faltered as she caught sight of Archie in full female getup.

"H—Hi Harry," she said. After a moment of awkward hesitancy, she stepped forward to embrace her friend warmly. "I've missed you," she added, her brown eyes searching Archie's. Whatever she found there, it softened her smile and relaxed the tenseness in her shoulders. "Letters just aren't the same, are they?"

Archie's eyes swept Hermione with bright appreciation. "Not at all the same. Look at you, 'Mione. You look like a fairytale come to life."

Hermione flushed and giggled embarrassedly. "I spent ages getting ready. I felt such a ninny in front of the mirror, but…well, it's not every day you get to attend a party like this."

Rigel realized that the Yule Ball, which had seemed like just another stiflingly elitist event to her, would be the first time Hermione had any real exposure to pureblood high society. She hoped the girl wasn't expecting a true fairytale—there were more thorns than roses to be found on a night like this, in her experience.

Then again, perhaps Rigel was just cynical. There was no reason Hermione couldn't have a wonderful time, dancing and drinking and reveling in the sparkling beauty around her without ever looking too closely at the sins it concealed.

Merlin, I sound like Rosier now. Rigel cast her eyes about for something else to focus on and found Krum hovering awkwardly where Hermione had left him. She smiled bracingly at him, knowing the Bulgarian boy had no idea what sort of undercurrents were being exchanged between his date and her friend from America. Taking pity on the situation, Rigel introduced Krum to Archie before Hermione had to present him as her date.

"Have you met Victor Krum, Harry? He's one of the other tournament champions," she said. "Krum, this is my cousin, Harriet Potter. Harry was nice enough to come all the way from America to be here tonight."

Archie's eyes left Hermione reluctantly and settled on the Bulgarian boy with careful blankness. "Nice to meet you. Shame you didn't make it to the finals."

Krum grimaced, but politely responded. "Your cousin vas the better vizard. I vish you luck in the next tasks, Black."

She thanked him, and it was a mercifully short wait that followed before McGonagall began to usher the champions into the hall. As Krum and Hermione pulled ahead of them, Rigel whispered, "Can you dance in those shoes?" to her unusually quiet cousin.

Startled from whatever internal reverie he'd been lost in, Archie blinked at her. "Dance?"

"Yes, dance. We have to dance now," she said.

"You hate to dance," he reminded her.

"I was not given the option of refusing," Rigel said, frowning. "So is that a yes or—"

"Mr. Black. Wait here until Mr. Krum and Miss Granger pass through the doors, then proceed." McGonagall barely glanced at them as she focused on the timing of their entrance. "When the first dance concludes, you'll be called to the small platform in the center to be officially announced as a finalist. Go now, Mr. Black."

They were the last through the doors, and she felt the air catch momentarily in her lungs at the sight of the Great Hall done up in all its festive splendor. She wondered whether the castle was always this beautiful during the holidays, but reasoned that whatever the usual standard was, an event such as the Yule Ball would no doubt have raised the bar higher.

The floating candles had been replaced with shining balls of soft light that danced to their own soundless tune above their heads. Great wreaths sat proudly in a river of thick garland, anointed by the same golden frost that coated the sills of every window. A dozen towering trees broke up the otherwise cavernous hall, each one decorated more spectacularly than the last, and in the center of them all was a large open space clearly intended for dancing. A full orchestra was stationed where the Head Table usually sat, and a long table of refreshments lined the left side of the hall.

The dance floor already held six couples and one triad, and as soon as Rigel and Archie took up their spot, the music began. She and Archie both stepped the same direction, then froze. Archie's eyes widened comically. "I don't know how to follow," he blurted.

Rigel felt a smile tug at her lips. "Neither do I."

They both laughed quietly, and Archie shrugged. "Let's just make it up."

They began again, Rigel moving so painfully slowly that Archie at least had a chance to mirror her steps before she stepped again. She tried to apply the correct pressure to his waist and hand, to cue him as to her intentions before each step, but Archie was comically incapable of processing her signals in time to meet her movements with his own. They fumbled about in a largely stationary circle, while other champions gracefully danced around them in their procession across the floor.

She met Archie's eyes again and couldn't stop the laugh that bubbled up from her stomach. "This is ridiculous," she said. Still, there was a large grin on her face. When was the last time she'd really smiled about anything? There was a lightness in her heart that hadn't been there for some time. She didn't even mind the pitying glances Delacour and Davies shot them as they twirled by.

The twins, who had formed a loose sort of triangle formation with Matheus, joined hands and lifted them over Rigel and Archie's heads in a bridge as they passed to either side. Archie pretended to cling to Rigel in swooning terror and she laughed again.

Finally, the music swam to a lingering halt and Rigel let go of her cousin to bow. Archie tried to bow too, forgetting that a dipping curtsey would make more sense in his robes, and they bumped heads. "You are the worst date ever," Archie said, rubbing his temple.

"Me?" Rigel snorted. "You're all over the place, Harry."

"But you love me that way, darling." Archie lifted his nose. "Shouldn't you be over there, anyway?"

Rigel looked to see Delacour and Owens both moving toward the very center of the dance floor, where a small platform was raised above the rest of the room. Riddle stood atop it in grand, silver-trimmed robes of evergreen. Rigel sighed, but comforted herself that after this, she would be free of champion duties for the whole winter break. She shot Archie a look before she left and said, "Don't wander off."

He gave a simpering finger-wave and smiled through closed lips. Praying he didn't cause any trouble without her there to stop him, Rigel moved to the raised platform and waited for the other two to ascend the short staircase first before she stepped up after them. From her vantage point, she had just enough height to see over the tops of every head in the Hall. Delacour moved sideways to give her room to stand, her short, moon-white dress glinting in the soft light, and a hush fell over the crowd.

"Welcome, ladies and gentlemen, to our little celebration," Riddle said. He did not seem to shout, but something amplified his voice clearly throughout the room in a way that was exponentially more pleasant than the usual Sonorous Charm. "As of yesterday, the New Triwizard Tournament is halfway concluded, and tonight we crown our Blood Representatives!"

Thunderous applause echoed up to the rafters, and Riddle paused a moment before beckoning Owens forward to the edge of the platform. "First, the Muggleborn Champion. Jacob Owens attained the highest overall score after the first two tasks, and in the duels he progressed further than any other muggleborn competitor. Congratulations, Mr. Owens. Is there anything you'd like to say?"

Owens had a broad smile on his face as he raised a hand in acknowledgement of the polite applause. "Thank you, Lord Riddle. All I can say is that I'm deeply honored to have made it this far, and I look forward to being able to test my mettle against serious competitors going forward."

Rigel's eyebrows came down in a frown at his words. What was that supposed to mean? That he didn't consider the other champions to be true competition?

Delacour was presented next as the Halfblood Champion, and Riddle explained that although she earned no points in the third round, her scores from the first two were high enough that Antiope, who had earned twenty points for winning her first match but subsequently lost the second, was unable to surpass her. The French girl smiled prettily at the assembly and gave a short speech expressing her renewed determination going forward and the glory and honor she wished to win for Beauxbatons.

Then Riddle turned to Rigel, a truly patronizing smile on his face. "Finally, our Pureblood Champion. Rigel Black. What can one say about this young man? Mr. Black demonstrated remarkable talent, rising to the top against incredible odds in the first two tasks and going on to defeat not two, nor even three, but four opponents in the final task. I think it's safe to say that he's the undisputed winner of the preliminary round!" Applause broke out all around them, and Rigel had to fight the urge to scowl at Riddle for singling her out of an already singular group. "Mr. Black, if you please."

Riddle's expectant expression told her it was not a request, and she stepped forward into the range of his amplification spell. She looked at all the upturned faces, wondering what she could say that would mean anything at all to them.

"Good evening. I'd like to first thank all the people who have supported me since this tournament began. I don't think I would be standing here without you." She gazed thoughtfully at the cheerful, entertained expressions below her. "It must seem very exciting, watching us all run and jump and bleed and fall, then get back up to do it all over again. I can't imagine what it's looked like, but I can tell you what it's felt like. These tasks are unlike anything the average person would face in a lifetime, much less just a few short months. I feel more as though I survived something than won anything. To the champions whose scores, determined by whatever arbitrary metric, didn't merit a place in the finals, I'd just like to say: congratulations. You survived it too, with grace and heart both, and I think that's all anyone could ask of us. Thank you."

She met Riddle's eyes with a defiant expression, but he didn't appear overly displeased at her subversive speech. Rather he bowed his head to her and said, "Thank you, Mr. Black, for reminding us all what an arduous journey it's been so far. Truly the young witch and wizards here before you have accomplished a Herculean task already. What awaits them in the new year…well, you'll just have to wait and see, won't you?"

Amused titters rippled through the hall, and like that, the solemn spell was broken, and any small amount of shame Rigel's words might have stirred settled back beneath the blanket of cheap delight.

"As a reminder, for making it to the finals each of our three Blood Representatives will receive an additional 1000 Galleons and a full scholarship to the secondary institute of their choice!" Rigel had actually forgotten about the prizes, and she wondered which secondary program Archie would want to go to. Riddle waited for the cheering to fade before continuing. "And of course, whoever is crowned Blood Champion will be going on an all-expense paid world tour next summer, in addition to becoming the new owner of this rare and powerful magical focus—the Rod of Zuriel!"

Riddle seemed to draw the silver staff out of the very air, and he held it high so that the light-catching red stone cradled on top could be seen by all. The splitting headache that attacked her had Rigel stiffening in pained surprise. Her ears roared and Dom's voice drifted through the white noise. Just a little closer…

Without realizing she was doing it, Rigel stepped forward. The pain receded and she cast out her magical awareness toward the staff, wondering what about it had got Dom so riled so quickly. It didn't feel powerful, exactly—there was no intense concentration of magic in the stone and it didn't seem to be exuding any sort of power into the air around it. There was something there, though, other than a pretty red stone. Something soft, dark, and slow-moving. She bent her focus toward the jewel with a frown, certain that there was more beneath the shadow-feeling at the surface.

She felt a creeping sensation in her mind, the likes of which she had not experienced since she was eleven. Rigel flinched backwards, breath stuck in her throat, and she rooted her feet in place while leaping inward to her mindscape. She'd only just manifested on the mountainside when she heard Dom yelling, "Get back, you fool! I can handle Zuriel's crawling mist!"

Rigel caught a glimpse of inky black fingers pressing through the storm at the edges of her mindscape, but a hand on her arm snapped her back to reality, where Delacour was tugging her surreptitiously toward the platform stairs. Riddle's eyes asked a question as she turned to descend, but Rigel ignored him. She was in the midst of a terrifying discovery and had no extraneous mental energy to spend.

Delacour hissed at her to hurry, but Rigel barely had the faculties to stumble down to the dance floor at her own pace. Her head was aching, her hands shaking, and she very much wanted to hurl at the idea of that stuff invading her head. Never again, she snarled in her mind, and only Dom's answering, I've got this, kept her from sitting down right there on the floor and sinking into a meditative state without care for where she was or how it would look.

She kept her Occlumency shields strong, aware of the parasite's tendency to jump into unguarded minds nearby, and pushed her way unseeing through the crowd. Rigel was vaguely aware of people calling out to congratulate her as she passed, but she didn't answer them. She made her way to a corner of the hall, skirting around one of the large trees to the backside of it, where she found a small space. The tree blocked the view of the rest of the hall.

With space to breathe, and think, Rigel turned her mind to the wonder, the horror, of the realization that the Rod of Zuriel was a great big ball of Sleeping Sickness. Had Riddle infected it? To what purpose? She replayed Dom's reaction in her mind and let go of the first suspicion. If Dom was familiar with what he called 'Zuriel's crawling mist' then it couldn't have been a recent change to the rod's nature.

What if the Rod of Zuriel was the original source of the Sleeping Sickness? She didn't know how long Riddle had been in possession of the staff, but there was a less than zero percent chance that he'd had it long enough to learn to weaponize its characteristics.

She could tell the exact moment when Dom succeeded in eradicating the black infestation from her mindscape. She felt instantly cleaner and more clear-headed. Rigel did her best to send feelings of gratitude toward the construct, knowing that if it weren't for him, she'd be collapsed in a heap on the floor. She got the echo of smugness in return, and the faint sound of his voice saying, Typical Zuriel.

That confirmed, Rigel was left to ask why Riddle would give the staff up now, and what he hoped to gain by awarding it to the tournament's winner. It could simply be that he had no more use for the tool, but she doubted it. At close range, its power was incredibly fast-acting and potent. It made her appreciate exactly how diluted a form of the sickness she'd dealt with in her first year. She wondered how susceptible she would be to its influence if she was in its presence for a prolonged period of time.

"Rigel, what are you doing?"

She whirled around to see Theo holding the hand of Zacharias Smith, clearly startled to find her in the place he'd intended to sneak away with his date to. "I just…needed a moment," she said. Summoning a smile, she smoothed her dress robes restlessly and calmly made her way back to the party proper.

It was only after she began to wander through the crush that she realized she had no idea where Archie had gone.

Rigel's cousin had changed. There was the obvious—made more so by her aggressively feminine attire—but something about the girl's very nature seemed to have altered since the last time Draco had seen her. Potter seemed to…bubble. She wandered the hall with a wide, cheerful smile on her face, greeting those who met her eyes good naturedly and without reservation.

He supposed with a critical frown that she may have simply gained some sort of social confidence with her…physical maturity. Certainly no one would mistake her for her cousin now. He personally hadn't found the halfblood lacking in confidence before, but what did he know about teenage girls? Pansy alone was enough mystery for one person to spend a lifetime unraveling.

The Potter Heiress paused in her journey across the hall as the Weasley-twin menaces called her name, and shortly the girl was engaged in animated conversation with the two of them plus a rather bemused looking Sousa. From his vantage point near the windows, he could see the girl's green eyes as she flicked them restlessly about the room. Eventually her gaze settled, and he followed its trajectory to the dance floor. She was watching the Bulgarian champion and his date, the Granger girl Rigel kept bringing to their table during meals.

No, he realized after a curious moment of analysis. She was only watching one of them. Potter's eyes followed Granger's smile with a wistful longing so heartbroken that it could only mean one thing. Potter wanted Granger. Draco was bewildered as the implications settled over him. Why hadn't the girl asked Granger to the ball herself, then? Had she not had the chance before Krum got there first?

Draco snorted. Perhaps the mudblood was smarter than he'd thought, if she'd chosen the pureblooded Bulgarian over a halfblooded bluestocking like Potter. The longer he watched her watch Granger, however, the more his emotions turned from amusement to irritation. Whatever her feelings, Potter had accompanied Rigel to the ball, not Granger. She ought to be at least attempting to pay attention to her date.

Where was Rigel, anyway? Draco craned his neck, aided by the extra height he'd gained since the beginning of the term, and eventually spotted Rigel near the refreshment table on the other side of the hall.

"Thirsty?" he asked Pansy.

His patient date slid him a sideways look that said he was not fooling anyone and said, "Yes, now that you mention it. Shall we move toward the punch?"

He took her arm with perfect gentility and led the delicate blonde confidently through the crush. A glance at her face revealed a very small smile of amusement, tucked into an otherwise blandly polite expression. Draco felt a pang as he admitted the lovely girl could have had her pick of suitors and had probably only accompanied him to save him the trouble of escorting someone he had no interest in giving his full attention. Pansy was too good for him, but then, that wasn't really news.

He didn't make further pretense of perusing the refreshments when they had crossed the hall; rather, he towed Pansy toward Rigel and caught their friend with a light hand on his arm. Rigel turned and eyed them both with a relieved smile. "How's it going? Have you seen Harry?"

"She's busy mooning after Granger," he said before he could check the words.

"Mm, not surprising," Rigel said distractedly. "Where, though?"

Draco made an impatient noise in his throat and said, struggling to keep his voice even, "Don't you even care? She wants someone else, Rigel."

"I know." Rigel looked over at him with eyebrows raised in surprise. "It's not a love match, remember?"

Draco didn't understand it. How could he value himself so lightly? Would he really rather be with someone who doesn't love him than entertain even the possibility of being with Draco? He tried to steel his mind against such thoughts. He was supposed to be moving past that, or at least trying to for Rigel's sake. It was hard to watch him act as though he didn't deserve anything more than his disinterested cousin, but Draco reminded himself that Rigel's priorities were not his own.

He guessed it was probably easier for Rigel to be in a relationship he didn't have to contribute to. Still, he thought Harriett Potter an unforgivable idiot who didn't deserve Rigel in the least.

"She was over by that tree with the silver birds on the branches," Pansy said softly.

"Thanks, Pan." Rigel shot them a parting smile and melted into the crowd again.

Draco forced himself to turn and begin ladling punch from a bowl rather than stare after his friend like some sort of lovelorn idiot. Pansy took the glass with a sympathetic smile and patted his arm gently.

"It's his life," she said. "We can't make him live it differently."

Draco looked at her, really looked, for the first time that night. He noticed the silver dusting of diamond powder in her hair, the painstakingly perfect curls that must have been created one at a time, and the slightly bored glaze to her soft blue eyes. "I've been a poor date," he said, apology in his tone.

She lifted a corner of her mouth. "I anticipated as much," she admitted. Then she added, "I considered a match with him too, you know." Draco's eyes widened in surprise, but Pansy only shrugged self-deprecatingly. "It was early on, before I realized the truth."

"What truth?"

"Rigel's already decided to live without love." Pansy's eyes were sad, but firm in their belief. "I don't know when he made that choice, but I suspect it was before he ever met us. It isn't personal, and it isn't something anyone can make him un-decide. Until he allows affection willingly into his life, it will always be something intrusive to him. Something troubling, rather than something wonderful."

Draco's mind fought against such a proclamation. "But he cares so deeply," he said, voice slightly hoarse.

"It isn't that he's incapable," Pansy agreed. "One day, Rigel may love someone quite fiercely. For now, however, he simply won't accept it from anyone."

Her words didn't make him feel better, exactly, but a pinch in his pride that he hadn't realized was there did ease just a bit. She's right, he realized with an internal groan, And I really am a willful fool. All the evidence had been before him, from Rigel's constant discomfort with attention and affection to his oblivious dismissal of those such as Zhou and Matheus. Even his lack of concern with his cousin's obvious desire for someone else was proof of Pansy's point.

Rigel neither sought love nor recognized it when it came for him. Perhaps it was best, then, that the dark-haired boy hadn't attempted to entertain Draco's suit out of some sense of kindness or duty of friendship. Perhaps, as Rigel had said, it would only have ended poorly.

By the time she got to the tree Pansy had indicated, it seemed Archie had moved on. She pressed herself up onto the toes of her too-shiny shoes and tried to see over the heads of those around her. Most of those present were adults, however, and she resigned herself to searching the sea of bodies one section at a time.

She saw her father standing at the Minister's shoulder and carefully avoided that circle. He didn't look pleased to be on guard duty again, but she supposed he couldn't ask Dawlish to do it as long as he was technically assigned to Hogwarts. Thankfully, Archie didn't seem to be anywhere near there. The last thing she needed was to see James publicly lose his mind over Archie's choice of attire.

"Archie!"

At the sound of her cousin's name, she whipped her head around to look for him, then realized that, obviously, it was meant for her. After a moment of confusion, she saw Sirius dart from behind two witches in voluptuous skirts and come to a panting stop before her. "There you are," he said brightly. "Mad crowd, eh?"

He scooped Rigel up into a hug fierce enough to take her breath away. "Congratulations, Arch. I'm glad you'll be coming home to us safe."

She hugged him back firmly. "I always will, Dad. And thanks, but I'm pretty sure the judging is rigged."

He barked out a laugh and drew back to look down at her. "I liked your speech. Thought Riddle was going to swallow his forked tongue."

She let out an undignified snort, picturing the statesman with said appendage flicking out from behind his teeth whenever he talked. "It was spur of the moment," she admitted. "I couldn't resist an opportunity to rain on Riddle's blood-fueled parade.

"Undermining from within, I get it," Sirius said, nodding slowly. He leaned closer and added, "Don't tell your aunt I said this, but… sometimes having a seat at the table is more productive than protesting the table's existence." His face screwed up as he attempted to caveat his metaphor. "That is not to say the table is the only outlet for expression. Just, you know, throwing away the opportunity to sit there won't help those who never get a chance to, right?"

She frowned. "Sure," she said, though she wasn't certain she knew what exactly he was trying to say.

Maybe he would have explained further, but Regulus Black swooped down on them in that moment, clearing his throat as he approached. She wondered whether he had embedded a tracking charm into Sirius's skin at some point; the man never had trouble finding his older brother, no matter how large the gathering.

"Sirius," he said, nodding with the barest suggestion of respect. "Nephew." His grey eyes on her were warm with approval. "Excellent showing in the third task. The might of the House of Black will be unquestioned for years to come."

She stared up at him in utter surprise. Regulus had never been so openly complimentary. "Thank you, Uncle," she said slowly. "I'm gratified you didn't find the display overly vulgar."

The slender man narrowed his eyes at her. "If the tournament were subject to the Common British Dueling Etiquette, you'd have been disqualified a number of times over. Then again, you'd never have faced an opponent with a blade in those circumstances, either. Anyone could forgive a certain amount of…indecorous creative action, as it were."

"Any Slytherin, you mean," Sirius said, rolling his eyes. "Just admit Archie was awesome, Reggie."

"Do not call me that," Regulus hissed. Watching his eyes flare over the childish nickname, Rigel tried to hide a smile. They never looked more like brothers than when they bickered. Regulus seemed to catch her amusement in any case, and he let the faintest of scowls cross his face. "Don't think you'll be excused for every lapse in tradition you displayed on that stage," he said sharply. "Wherever did you learn such swift application of runes? That's not in any compendium of standard dueling techniques that I've seen."

She smiled innocently at him. "It was more Alchemy, actually, than runes alone. Headmaster Dumbledore taught me."

"Dumbledore?" Regulus very nearly spluttered. "He takes less than a dozen students a decade. I'm to believe he's teaching you some sort of—of battle Alchemy?"

"He teaches me all sorts of things," she said, honesty making her words even sweeter. "His class is quite unstructured. Some days we just talk about whatever strikes our interest." Regulus went pale as his mind supplied a number of topics that the venerable Light wizard might broach. No doubt he thought the Headmaster was working to turn the Black Heir against Dark politics, at the least. She cheerfully twisted the knife a little deeper when she added soothingly, "I'm not surprised you haven't come across runeless arrays, though, seeing as Dumbledore writes all his own textbooks."

Sirius laughed lightly. "Of course he does. Half the time, I'm pretty certain he only humors the rest of us by pretending to be bound by magic's typical limits."

Rigel chuckled as well, much of her amusement derived from the apoplectic annoyance Regulus was trying and failing to suppress. "You're right, Dad. I've caught him using wildly different wand movements for the same Transfiguration. I think he's just having fun when he waves a wand. Great wizard, Dumbledore."

Regulus opened his mouth to say something, then snapped it shut and turned on his heel to leave their presence. Rigel and Sirius met one another's eyes and both burst into guffaws that had people around them turning to stare.

"That was priceless, Arch," Sirius said, wiping his eyes with one hand and clutching his stomach with the other.

"Uncle Regulus makes it so easy," she said with an amused sigh. "Do you think he's got the hint that I'm not worried about his approval yet?"

Sirius shook his head with a rueful smile. "Reg means well. He just cares a little too much about the Black Family legacy." His eyes took on a wistful gleam. "Cares for it more than he does for the individuals it consists of, anyway." He shrugged off the pensive expression a moment later and made a show of looking around. "Where's Harry, anyway? Don't tell me you lost your date already?"

Rigel grimaced. "I've been looking for her, but I'm afraid we got separated when I was called onto the platform."

She and her uncle spent a moment searching the Great Hall for a glimpse of Harry's sky-blue robes. Rigel saw Millie on the dance floor, wryly attempting to teach Tahiil an approximate quadrille. Blaise was locked with a blushing Abbott beneath a mistletoe-strewn branch, and Rigel turned away as the dark-skinned boy plucked a flower from the tree and tucked it into the girl's blonde hair.

When she finally spotted Archie, it was with an internal groan of despair. He was talking to Rosier. Why, in the name of Godric Gryffindor, was he talking to Rosier?

"Found her," she said in a clipped voice.

"Great," Sirius said, not seeming terribly concerned. His eyes had found Professor McGonagall, who was suspiciously casting revealing charms at the punch bowl, and he waggled his brows as pure mischief took flight in his eyes. "Think Minnie will agree to a dance?"

"If she does, Uncle James will kneel in awe at your feet," she said dryly.

Sirius puffed out his chest and said, "Challenge accepted. Hold my punch."

He thrust a glass of red liquid at her and Rigel sighed. Seeing nowhere to put the cup down, she tossed the rest of the drink down her throat and pocketed it. A moment later, the flavor caught up with her and she blanched. What on earth had Sirius been drinking? The sharp, biting taste was like no potion she recognized, so she could only assume he'd spiked it with a common spirit of some kind. Rigel shook her head against the unpleasant sensation and swallowed the nausea back. That would teach her to drink anything after her uncle.

Rigel set off toward where she'd seen Archie and Rosier near the orchestra, skirting the dance floor so she wouldn't collide with any of the dancers. She'd only made it halfway around when she was stopped by a frail hand on her elbow. Madam Marchbanks, dignified in a sober, high-collared robe of deep blue, had forestalled her.

"Mr. Black, there you are," the elderly witch said with a satisfied nod. "We wanted to congratulate you on your stunning performance in the tournament thus far."

She ducked her head with a murmured thanks, looking past the woman to where Mr. Ogden stood with a pair of unfamiliar, much younger men. Ogden smiled at her conspiratorially. "I suppose you haven't met the Lords Goldentower yet, have you? You can blame Raoul here for the points you lost in the second task."

The dark-eyed, curly-haired man he indicated gave an affronted look. "Unlike some of the judges," here he eyed Madam Marchbanks with a sharp glance, "I have been perfectly impartial." The man, who must have been the tallest and broadest person present apart from Hagrid, bowed with a chivalrous flourish. "Raoul Goldentower, at your service." he said. "This is my partner, Gareth Goldentower."

He indicated the paler, slightly less broad wizard with soft chestnut hair beside him. The second Lord Goldentower—and didn't that get confusing?—gave her a warm grin. "Nice to meet you, Mr. Black. Don't mind Raoul. His honor compels him to be harder on those he approves of."

Rigel smiled back, a little off-guard by the familiar way the man spoke to her. Something Pansy had said rose from the depths of her memory, and she tilted her head curiously at Gareth Goldentower. "Do you by chance run a correspondence school called Sphinx, sir?"

The wizard, who she judged to be about her father's age, raised his eyebrows in surprise. "Indeed, I do. Well, it's really Callaway who runs the program. I only finance the overhead."

"My cousin is one of your students," Rigel said. At Gareth's polite frown of confusion, she clarified. "Harriett Potter. She attends school in America, but is hoping to get around some of the restrictions on employing halfbloods in Britain by doubling up with your courses."

Lord Raoul Goldentower cut into the exchange, curiosity sharpening his sloe-dark eyes. "Smart girl. How does your cousin feel the curriculum compares?"

Rigel thought for a moment before saying, "She thinks Sphinx's Defense Against the Dark Forces material is more comprehensive than most programs' and that Household Charms should be taught in formal schools, too."

"But…?" Gareth pressed her with a cajoling grin. "Don't hold back."

"His ego can take it," Raoul added.

She smiled apologetically and said, "Harry says the Potions curriculum is fairly basic. She has pretty high standards for that subject, though. You should hear how she disparages her Potions Master at AIM."

Ogden made a noise of realization and said, "Miss Potter is the one who came up with the new imbuing technique Burke's nephew has been going on about."

Rigel nodded, but Marchbanks said sharply, "She also saved your life last Yule."

Ogden flushed. "I haven't forgotten." He turned to Rigel beseechingly. "I could never forget the debt I owe the two of you. If you or Heiress Potter ever find yourselves in need, I pray you come to me."

"Or me," Marchbanks put in staunchly.

Raoul groaned. "You can't be so openly partial, Griselda. Does the integrity of the tournament mean nothing to you?"

Marchbanks sniffed. "You know as well as I do that this entire affair has been bungled from the start. There are ways to test an adolescent's magical prowess without risking life and limb. We do it every year, after all."

"Somehow, I don't think the equivalent of a public O.W.L. test would garner the interest the Department of Magical Games and Sports is looking to cash in on, darling," Ogden said wryly.

"Crouch could certainly do a better job reining in that son of his," Raoul admitted. He gave Rigel an apologetic look. "The first task in particular was wildly inappropriate, and I hope you don't think we condone the danger you all were placed in."

Rigel looked between the adults in confusion. "I thought Riddle was designing the tasks," she said slowly.

Ogden shook his head dismissively. "A man of his position doesn't have time for such details. He's left the majority of the logistics to certain members of his party."

"Some of whom didn't do so well on their O.W.L.s," Marchbanks muttered.

Raoul and Ogden politely bit back smiles, but Gareth laughed outright. He caught Rigel's eye and winked. "I'm sure you have better things to do tonight than listen to a group of old-timers complain. Before you go, however, I wonder if we might ask a small favor."

Rigel blinked at him, but tentatively inclined her head. "I'm at your disposal."

The two Lords of Goldentower exchanged an embarrassed glance, and Gareth reached toward his robe pocket. Rigel fought against the instinct to stiffen, and felt foolish when the brown-haired man simply pulled out a piece of blank parchment and a quill and said, "Our heir, Gilmyn, is a fan of yours. He asked us to procure your autograph, if we got the chance."

Rigel stared at him, eyes wide. Then she let out a disbelieving laugh and said, "Really?"

Raoul met her eyes with long-suffering amusement. "His godmother, Buri, took him to see the second task in Diagon. The whelp hasn't shut up about you since."

"He thinks you're the greatest hero since Godric Gryffindor," Gareth added, a fond smile tugging at his generous mouth.

She took the parchment and quill with an expression of sheer incredulity. After a moment's debate, she simply wrote, To my first fan, Gilmyn Goldentower. I hope you grow into a hero more worthy of renown than I. Sincerely, Rigel Black.

It was only after she'd handed the parchment back with a nonplussed smile that she realized how natural it felt to sign Archie's name. Her smile grew stiff, but she held it as she turned to Marchbanks and said, "I should find my cousin before she thinks I've abandoned her for more beautiful company."

The older witch chortled dismissively, and Gareth shot her an appreciative grin. Rigel bowed and took her leave, determined to find Archie before she got sidetracked again.

It wasn't that she didn't trust her cousin, only that she would feel no surprise to find Hogwarts had been set aflame in his wake.

She searched the hall high and low for Archie, and as she neared the doors with increasing trepidation, she came across Ginny and Antiope sharing a sparkling glass of something pink near the entryway.

"Lost something, Rigel?" Ginny asked tauntingly. Her red-orange hair tumbled in gorgeous curls down her back, the sight a subtle contrast to Antiope's blunt, crimson locks. Both girls were stunningly beautiful in matching golden gowns, but Rigel was too on edge to appreciate Ginny's black humor just then.

"Hello, Ginny. Antiope. Where did Harry go?" She stared Ginny down with a no-nonsense expression, and after a moment the third-year caved.

"Your buxom fiancé left a few minutes ago," Ginny admitted. Her bright eyes flashed as she added, "Said she wanted to see a bit of Hogwarts while she had the chance."

Rigel groaned under her breath. Of course Archie would want to see the school while he could. Why didn't she think of that? He was supposed to have attended Hogwarts, after all. It only made sense to take advantage of the one night he could walk the halls to cement a few convincing details in his mind.

She muttered a hasty thanks and left the Yule Ball without a backwards glance, wishing she'd tucked the Marauder's Map into her dress robes that evening.

The Entrance Hall was deserted, the great doors leading out onto the lawn shut tight against the winter chill. She tried to imagine where she would go if she was Archie, and figured the dungeons probably wouldn't interest him. She headed up the stairs quickly, pausing at each landing to look down the main corridor, hoping Archie had the sense to not wander far from the central staircase. If he tried to take on the twisting side corridors or—Merlin forbid—the narrower, moving staircases in the upper levels, he could be lost for hours.

On the third-floor landing, she caught sight of light spilling out onto the flagstones from a doorway and made her way down the corridor to find the iron-gate door to the Trophy Room standing ajar. Rigel frowned and slowed her steps. Why would Archie be drawn to the Trophy Room of all places? He'd never been one for museums.

She peered into the cavernous room and startled backwards almost at once. It wasn't Archie; it was Riddle. The man was standing with his back to the door, staring with arms clasped behind his waist at a shining plaque. He hadn't seen her—she knew he hadn't—and yet his voice drifted out into the corridor. "Haven't you learned better than to listen at keyholes, Rigel?" Snape's theory was right, then, she thought with a sinking stomach: Riddle could identify her by proximity alone. When she hesitated, not really interested in having a one-on-one conversation with the man, he added, more quietly, "Shall I teach you that lesson again, then?"

With a brief grimace, she slowly stepped around the doorway and into the room proper. "Reminiscing doesn't seem your style," she commented.

He raised an eyebrow. "Do you imagine you know me so well?"

She glanced at the plaque he'd been staring at—his own, of course, and for 'Special Services to the School' no less. Knowing what he'd gotten the award for, she felt her mood sour further.

Riddle noticed, and he tutted chidingly. "What reason have the young to be so embittered? You should be downstairs, enjoying your youth with folly."

"I've seen where youth's folly can take one," she said sharply, still eyeing the brightly polished award. "Besides," she added, finally looking back at Riddle, whose face had gone carefully blank. "Thanks to you, I've more pressing concerns than my youth."

"I'm sure I don't know what you mean. You've won your spot in the final stage of the tournament. You have nothing to worry over until the new year." He put a hand to his breast and affected a hurt expression. "Why, I orchestrated this entire, frivolous event—or my people did, at any rate. You should be thanking me."

Thanking him? Surely, the man jested. Rigel stared at him with open incredulity. "I heard your prejudiced pet project passed committee," she said baldly. "How convenient for you, that it will probably be put to vote before the tournament ends."

Riddle smiled slyly. "My plans are proceeding apace, yes. Thank you for your concern."

"I'm concerned for the world, not for you," she said, disgust riding into her tone.

"I'm trying to save the world."

Rigel scoffed. "Yes, I know. 'Save Our World,' right?"

Riddle's eyes grew cold at her dismissive return. "No, Rigel. You don't know. Without this law, our world as you know it will fade to nothing within the next generation. You should be helping me, not undermining the tournament's messaging at every opportunity."

Rigel dearly wished to reject his words as so much political smoke. Something about the vehement cast to his sneer gave her pause, however. He truly believed what he was saying. She cautiously took his bait.

"How is your bigoted legislation going to make anything about the world better?" she challenged. "All it's going to do is consolidate power where it already exists and marginalize muggleborns further by denying them the opportunity to even marry into established wizarding families."

"The plight of the mudbloods can wait," Riddle snapped. "Ours cannot."

He looked as though he wanted to say more, but he didn't. That, combined with the word he'd used before—'generation,' he'd said, not 'century' or 'lifetime'—made Rigel stop and really think for a moment.

A horrible suspicion took root, and she immediately wished she had walked out the door when she had the chance. "No," she breathed, repulsion taking the sound from her denial. "Not even you could be so…" Rigel couldn't finish the sentence. Looking into Riddle's eyes, the truth slapped her in the face. It was utterly counterintuitive, but wouldn't that be just like him? He, who sickened the children of his own supporters in order to increase their political power. He, who found profound purpose in the repudiation of his own past. He, who tore to the fore the one student in all of Hogwarts who wanted most to slide into the shadows.

"I'm sure I don't know what you're mumbling about," Riddle said, turning his gaze away as though her suspicions were nothing worth considering. Riddle was a predator, though, and she'd never known him to look away from his prey. He was trying to dispel her confidence so she'd drop the subject. It was too late. In a moment of awful clarity, the whole of it had come to her awareness unbidden.

Still, she wished it wasn't true. "Tell me you aren't trying to preserve your twisted party ideals and stop the rate of population decline." She gazed at him in wide-eyed accusation. There was a sick feeling in her stomach and she could feel the sweat beading on the back on her neck.

His sharp eyes swung back around to meet her own, and lurking behind the warning there was a sort of mild surprise, as though he hadn't really expected her to figure it out.

"You are," she said dully. "Do your supporters even know?"

Riddle's face was blank as he retreated inward to calculate a response, no doubt attempting to come up with a way to spin her discovery. "In the long run, those in doubt will thank me. We've tried it their way for too long. Encouraged same sex relations, pushed witches to have children younger, longer—nothing works. The blood is now its own poison. We must take halfbloods into the fold."

"Not muggleborns, though," Rigel said sharply. "Why not? The data suggests that merging pureblood lines with the newest possible blood will result in the least likelihood of the Fade."

Riddle actually smirked at her. "Don't be ridiculous. Even I could not convince the old families to go that far."

"So you'll just leave muggleborns out of your new world order." She couldn't say she was surprised.

"Unless our society expands the genetic pool and procreates without the delay that forcing the traditionalists so far from their worldview would inevitably trigger…well, there won't be a Wizarding World for the mudbloods to stumble into one day, will there?" Riddle's tone was utterly condescending, as though she were being tiresome suggesting that something like equality or common decency should get in the way of his grand design.

Rigel dropped her gaze to the floor, disgust at his methods warring with the truths Hermione had recently confirmed. It was insidious, yet in retrospect so obvious an idea that she was stunned it hadn't been proposed sooner. The concept of imposing dictatorial limitations on who people could and couldn't marry was a hideous violation of free will, and of course it would end up consolidating pureblood power into the old families while at once strengthening the lines, if it worked, but…but.

Wizarding families are dying out. Magical children are falling victim to the Fade. What if he's right and wrong?

Shaken, she couldn't move when Riddle leaned closer to her and said softly, "I'm doing this to save us all, Rigel. Won't you help me?"

She didn't know what to think. She needed space to sort through everything, time to reevaluate what she wanted to do. Her instinct was to mistrust what Riddle was saying simply because it was Riddle. Just because an evil man said something, however, didn't make it untrue. If he said the sky was blue, she wouldn't call it orange just to spite him.

Still, she would be a fool to believe him outright, after all the careless manipulation she'd witnessed from his hand. Rigel stepped backwards, putting space between them, and said, "There has to be another way. Just because you haven't found it, doesn't mean it isn't there."

"Wishing such a path to exist won't make it so," Riddle reproved.

"Taking the path most convenient to you isn't any better," she said, lifting her head to allow him to see the stubborn set to her expression. "You do what you think is best, and I'll do the same. If the world is saved, great. If not, at least it won't be because nobody tried."

Riddle scowled down at her, clearly unamused with the turn the conversation had taken. "Rigel, don't be a fool—"

"Good evening, Mr. Riddle," she said firmly. Without waiting for him to respond, she left him there in the Trophy Room, amidst the reminders of a boyhood that, to her eyes, still lingered in the man in spite of his attempts to deny it.

She descended the stairs blindly, not truly paying any attention to where she was going, and her feet carried her past the Great Hall, where the party was evidently still in full swing. By the time she found herself in the dungeons, she realized she had no intention of going back up there, no matter how rude it was to abandon a gathering that was, in some ways, meant to celebrate her.

Rigel slowed her steps as the cool, dungeon air seeped into her bones. There was something calming about the still, somewhat damp atmosphere, and peaceful thoughts of the dungeons inevitably turned her mind to thoughts of potions.

With a jolt of surprise, she realized she'd completely forgotten to give Snape his Yule present. All thoughts of Riddle and the party receded to the back of her mind as it latched onto something she could do that very moment. Somehow, her intention to find the time for Snape's present had been lost in the maelstrom that was the third task and its aftermath.

With a smile of anticipation tugging at the corner of her mouth, she turned away from the main corridor and into the maze that made up the dungeons proper. He'll be so surprised, she thought with a small sense of satisfaction.

Severus paced the length of the Great Hall with a not-unanticipated sense of annoyed resignation fueling his steps. As expected, his colleagues were too busy socializing to pay any mind to exactly what their charges got up to. It fell to him to patrol the shadowy corners of the hall, all the while suspecting Hagrid of intentionally giving the hormone-laden beasts the perfect cover for mischief.

He rounded a garishly-strewn tree of gold and orange to find Nott plastered indecently against a Hufflepuff whose father assuredly did not know his son was stepping out with a Slytherin. Severus cleared his throat sharply and Nott, attuned to the noise after four years in his House, broke for air with a sharp gasp.

"Professor Snape! Uh, we were just—"

"Spare me the pathetic splutters of your false explanations, Mr. Nott," he hissed. "Unless you wish me to send happy solicitations to your parents, I will not catch either of you again this night."

Smith flushed a violent red and began to stammer a panicky plea that Nott cut off with a none-to-subtle stamp of his foot against the stockier boy's ankle.

"Yes, Professor Snape," Nott said firmly. "Won't happen again."

He jerked his chin toward the edge of the tree and the boys fled. He took a deep breath in a futile attempt to calm his irritation before following them back into the crowd. If he was being honest, and he always strove to be with himself, if no one else, Severus could admit a large portion of his annoyance had nothing to do with the rambunctious improprieties of his students.

He'd been…not looking forward to, precisely, but certainly amenable to the opportunity to speak with Potter about what progress she'd made toward the completion of her portable healing kit. Severus had a number of theories he needed to run by the young potioneer, only to find the chit had morphed into some nightmarish product of adolescent insecurity for the evening. If he was the chit's father, she'd not dare leave the house in that getup.

With a sneer, Severus shook his head sharply. No matter. He would speak to the girl when she was in a more academic frame of mind. He knew well the idiocy of youth.

As he veered for the next tree positioned too close to the edge of the hall, a frisson of discomfort along his spine alerted him that one of his wards had just been tripped. He froze, turning his mind to discovering which one, and identified it almost at once as the entry ward for his personal laboratory.

With a growl that sent nearby students scurrying away with apologies dripping from their lips, he rounded toward the exit. Severus might have known, with so many alumni on the grounds that evening, that the sanctity of his workspaces would be at risk. No doubt some former Gryffindor hoped to gain a small revenge for petty grievances past.

Guests and students alike slid out of his way automatically as they caught his eye, but it was still a frustratingly slow slog toward the Entrance Hall. Severus wanted to blast a path through, but knew that Albus would not appreciate his making a spectacle with so many eyes on Hogwarts that night.

By the time he'd escaped the sea of socialites, he estimated ten minutes had passed. He made a swift descent toward his lab, fury spurring his heartrate higher with every second that passed. Despite his hurry, his pace slowed to a creep as he approached the lab. The door was ajar, and the torchlight within told him the intruder hadn't yet escaped. He stalked closer on silent feet, wishing fervently for the perpetrator to give him an excuse to use lethal force. Albus could not be too angry, if it was in self-defense.

The door was open wide enough to slip in with the barest whisper of his robes against the stone, and he smirked when he saw the intruder crouched on the ground with their back to him. Amateur mistake, but then, the stature of his vandal told him it was likely a student taking advantage of the distraction upstairs. Severus raised his wand to the ready and said, in his most intimidating snarl, "Lost, aren't we? Did you really think—" The boy spun around on his heels, and the words died in his throat.

It was Rigel, kneeling on the stone in his dress robes and looking up at him with a sheepish smile. "Hello, sir. I suppose the wards gave me away, huh?" The boy looked wrinkled, but content.

"What are you doing?" he bit out after taking a moment to holster his wand. Rigel was holding a piece of chalk, and he'd scribbled several rows of runes across the floor of his lab.

Rigel looked back at his work, added a couple of lines to the last rune, then pocketed the chalk and drew his wand instead, saying, "Caelum gave me the idea."

Once his mind had reviewed the words and confirmed his hearing, he pointed out, "Caelum Lestrange hates you."

"Well, he told Harry and Harry told me," Rigel admitted. "They're sort of…friends?" The boy's nose scrunched and he shook his head. "No, that doesn't work. They have an understanding, I guess. Anyway, do you like it?" Severus raised his eyebrows, a pointedly blank look on his face, and Rigel flushed lightly. "Oh, right. Hold on, sir."

He turned back to the runes and began to cast slowly, a chant-like spell that caused the runes to glow white. The floor of his lab began to ripple, and he felt it buckle slightly beneath his feet. Severus locked his knees in place until the spell had finished and the runes dissolved. The floor did not reassert itself fully, however. With a frown, he tapped down on it with his foot and encountered a springy give that seemed to mold itself around his boot. He took several steps and his frown receded. It was…not uncomfortable.

At his silence, Rigel began to babble again, dusting off his hands carelessly. "I wanted to thank you for everything you've done for me this term. You tried really hard to prepare me for the tasks, and I didn't make it easy on you." Severus snorted. Rigel grimaced and said, "I was a brat, all right? And thank you for teaching me free brewing. I mean, I know this isn't close to equal value for your lessons, but…thanks. Happy Yule, sir."

Severus stared down at the child. Rigel looked back at him earnestly, chalk smudged across his cheek and nervous anticipation in his gaze. "Thank you," he said slowly. "This was very thoughtful." He did not, as a rule, accept gifts from students. Usually it was little more than a transparent attempt to bribe his favor. This, however…Rigel had taken time to adapt the idea, no doubt researched the necessary runes and spells, and attempted to surprise him with the gesture.

He was unavoidably moved and reminded why it was that, even when Rigel was being bullheaded and deliberately obtuse, he would bend over backwards to see him succeed. Rigel was, without question, deserving of everything he could give the boy and more.

The rest of the night was a blur. She remembered stopping by the Slytherin common room to collect Treeslider and her trunk before Snape escorted her back to the Great Hall, an oddly embarrassed expression on his face all the while. She remembered the relief at finally finding Archie talking cheerfully to Professor McGonagall about AIM's Transfiguration curriculum. After that it wasn't long before Sirius had found them both and asked if they were ready to go. Many of the guests had begun trickling out of the castle toward the Apparition point, and she was all too happy to join them.

It was late when they dropped Archie at Potter Place, and she hoped her cousin changed out of those robes and wiped off his makeup before James got off duty and confronted him about it. They would switch back tomorrow, and she was better at handling her father's ire than Archie was. If he went straight to bed, he could put off the lecture until the next day.

She dropped into Archie's bed as soon as she had deposited Treeslider with Sirius' other snakes for the night, not bothering to take off more than her shoes. The next morning, Harry was up with the sun. With a sleepy yawn, she mentally asked Dom to switch over to their pyramid mindscape. With the echo of his affirmation in her ears, she chose a pair of Archie's more comfortable jeans and a jumper to don before jogging downstairs. After leaving a note for Sirius saying Archie had gone to Potter Place, she snagged an apple off the counter and Flooed over.

Archie wasn't awake yet, but Addy was. The eighteen-month-old girl toddled her way across the kitchen under Lily's feet and squealed in delight when Harry ran into an invisible, waist-high barrier across the doorway and nearly fell on her face.

"Archie! You're up early," Lily said. She waved her wand and the barrier changed to a soft blue color so Harry could see to climb over it. "Sorry about the baby gate. She wanders into everything these days."

Harry shrugged, and hugged Lily quickly before answering Addy's insistently tugging fists. She swung the redhead up into her arms and bussed the cute kid on the forehead. "How's it going, munchkin?"

"Hawee!" Addy exclaimed, clapping her hands together seemingly just for the fun of it.

"No, darling, that's Archie. Ar-chie," Lily said, smiling apologetically at her.

Addy's cherub face scrunched unhappily. "A-choo," she kid gurgled, somewhat less confidently.

"Smart kid, Aunt Lily," Harry said wryly.

Lily smiled proudly. "Isn't she? The other day she recognized Sirius in his animagus form."

Harry waggled impressed brows at her little sister, and Addy giggled before squirming to be put down again. "I'm gonna go wake Harry," she told Lily.

"She's usually up by now," Lily said absently. "Maybe she's reading."

She nodded in agreement as she stepped over the baby barrier once more, but wasn't at all surprised to push open the door to her room and find Archie sprawled like a starfish, face down in her pillow. Harry shut the door quietly behind her and went to shake the boy awake.

Archie murmured a protest at the jostling and rolled over to swat at her arm. In his sleep, the boy had dropped his metamorphmagus ability and Harry stared for a moment at her cousin' true face. He'd grown so much in the last year. She shook his arm again, thinking it was a good thing she'd thought to come over so early. If James or Lily had come in to wake their daughter before she got there, they'd have had a lot of explaining to do. That is, if James let Archie explain anything before hexing the unknown boy in his daughter's bed.

"Archie," she hissed softly. "Come on, get up. You can go back to sleep at your own house."

"Wha—Harry?" Archie blinked open steely grey eyes and smiled sleepily. "Hi."

She rolled her eyes. "Hi. Tell me when your brain starts working again."

Harry got off the end of the bed and crossed to her chest of drawers to pick out her clothes for the day. She was going to get out of the house and take a break from everything, so she chose warm layers and dug her winter coat out of the closet. She shrugged off Archie's sweater so he could wear it back to his house and paused in slipping her own shirt on at the strangled sound from the bed. She cut her eyes over to Archie with an unimpressed look. "If you can handle altering my bust size to fit into an entirely inappropriate cocktail dress, then I think you can handle me in my undershirt, cuz."

Archie's ears were red and he coughed uncomfortably. "Yes, in retrospect my imitation was a bit off," he said, glancing embarrassedly at her androgynous torso and away again. "Still," he said, injecting a cheerful note in his voice, "I think you'll have a few new offers for your hand after last night."

"That's not a good thing," she told him, scowling as she shrugged first a long-sleeve shirt, then a warm jumper on over her tank top.

Archie shrugged and closed his eyes for a moment. His features rippled and slid into a perfect mirror of her own, and when he opened his eyes he abandoned her oversized pajama shirt and dragged the sweater she'd shucked over his own head. She'd changed into her own trousers while he morphed, and Archie slid his pale legs into the discarded jeans with an ungraceful hop that revealed how sleepy he still was.

Harry was lacing up her boots when Archie said, "Don't forget your contacts."

With a sigh of resignation, she fished a key out of her underwear drawer and opened the box on her bedside table. She only had a few sets left, but it would last her through winter break, at least. She'd order more in the spring.

She and Archie looked one another over once Harry had her eyes right. Archie had done a good job matching Harry's newly shorn hairstyle, and she allowed him to lengthen her hair with a quick charm so that it would at least approximate what he'd achieved with his updo the night before. With nods of mutual approval, they both made their way downstairs.

"When are we going to take the you-know-what?" Archie asked.

She grinned at him. "Whenever you like. Not today, though. I'm going into Diagon."

"Tomorrow night?" Archie suggested quietly. "That'll give us enough time to start pretending to be ill."

"Good call," she agreed. "After dinner, then."

She stopped by the kitchen to tell her mother she was headed to Diagon, and Lily bade them a fun time distractedly as she attempted to dissuade Addy from climbing the rubbish bin. Not correcting Lily's impression that Archie would be going with her, Harry led the way to the Floo. Archie gave her a tired grin and said, "Grimmauld Place."

She waited for the flames to die down before stepping in herself and Flooing to the Leaky Cauldron. Striding through the dim pub, she felt a strange buoyancy fill her chest, as though she'd shrugged off a heavy lifejacket and could swim freely for the first time in ages. By the time she melted into the bustling holiday crowd, Harry could feel a smile blooming across her face. A laugh bubbled up in her chest, but she held it in instead of letting it out. It made her chest tight but her head light.

She'd known as soon as she woke up that morning that she didn't want to spend the day at home. Her parents would want to catch up with her, would nag her to eat or play with her little sister, and for once she wanted an entire day to herself. Harry beelined for Tate's apothecary and greeted the cheery shop-keep warmly.

"What can I do for you today, Miss Potter?" He gestured toward a sign near the till and added, "Got a new model of portable fire charm on sale."

"I'll take two," she said brightly, collecting a basket with a practiced swing. "I also need a new standard size four pewter cauldron, a size two platinum cauldron, a starter kit of stirring rods and steel knives, two stands, three crates with glass vials, and a large ladle, if you don't mind."

Tate raised his eyebrows as he jotted the list down. "Stocking a new lab, are you?"

"Something like that," she said, smiling. As Tate fetched the equipment from the back, Harry began to peruse the isles of ingredients, loading her basket with all the basics and a few more specialized ingredients she used often.

By the time Tate had all her requested items lined up on the counter, she was finished. "Your usual account, Miss Potter?" Tate confirmed.

She nodded, and added, "Could you please shrink them for me?"

He obliged, and within twenty minutes of entering the apothecary, she walked out with the makings of a rudimentary lab in her pocket. With a satisfied bounce in her step, Harry slipped away from the crowds, into Knockturn Alley, and headed toward Kyprioth Court. She half-expected to run into Leo on her way to Dogwood Lane, but supposed the king must be busy with other matters. Just as well, since she really wasn't in the mood to chat. There was a restless energy in her veins that could only be cured with brewing.

Her flat was dusty, the corners smattered with cobwebs, so she took the time to cast each of the household cleaning charms she'd picked up from her correspondence course. When she no longer felt a sneeze lurking in the back of her nose, Harry pushed the furniture in the living room up against the walls to make space in the middle for her cauldrons. She tugged the musty quilt from the bed and spread it over the living room floor to protect it from small splashes, then set about unshrinking her purchases and arranging them to her liking.

After cracking the window to provide a bit of ventilation, she grinned in anticipation and started on her first potion. The size four cauldron would be used to make large batches of the potions she owed Krait, while the smaller, platinum cauldron was for her experimentation. Harry wasn't fool enough to freebrew in a lab with no protective wards, of course. While she thought she could probably contain any explosions if she was quick enough, it would be unwise to take the chance when she had neighbors living below her.

Still, that didn't mean she couldn't work on improving her latest series of shape-imbued healing potions. With the assumption that she could get a needle to administer potions to very specific areas of the body, Harry had gone ahead and made headway on potion versions of the spells to heal broken bones, torn muscles, and ligaments, as well as one to stymie internal bleeding.

Next, she wanted to develop a true emergency potion that would counter severe allergic reactions. There were a couple of spells that blocked histamine receptors in the body, and she wanted to try them both in a base with Bicorn milk as the signifying ingredient. Harry thought the protein-rich milk could, with the right emphasis, induce acute adrenaline production.

The faint sounds of passersby drifted in through the window, and Harry let the peaceful atmosphere lull her into complete relaxation as she worked. After months of stealing an hour or two at a time to brew, it was utter bliss to ignore the clock completely and let the world drift by without her.

She worked steadily from potion to potion, bottling, corking, and labeling before moving on to the next. The shadows walked across the room, but they meant nothing to her. When she ran out of bottles, she cleared away the dregs from her cauldrons with a quick spell, then set them in the sink to wash properly.

With the cauldrons resting upside-down to dry, Harry stretched her arms and back and peeked out of her front window with a contented smile. Looking out at the cloudy, mid-winter day, she felt more centered than she had in a long time.

Harry shut the window and separated her experimental brews from the bottles that would go to Krait. She hefted two full crates and carried them out to the stairwell, setting them down just long enough to lock up before continuing down to the street.

Across the way, the white-haired Mrs. Whitlock was leaning on her cane, watching the two Botting children kick a small Quaffle back and forth. Harry raised a hand in a friendly gesture, and Mrs. Whitlock waved her over.

"Good afternoon, Mrs. Whitlock," she said, setting the crates down for a moment to rest her hands. "How are you?"

"Just fine, Mr. Potter, thank you," the old woman said, squinting a smile her direction.

"Harry's not a mister," Jim Botting said smartly. He was about nine now, she thought, and last she knew not one of Leo's scamps. She wondered how he knew about her gender, but supposed the word must have slowly spread through the alleys after the freedueling tournament. Harry had to wonder how many people knew her last name now, as well. Mrs. Whitlock had known from the start, but she didn't think the older woman was the type to gossip. With luck, Leo's friend Harry would not be immediately connected with Harriett Potter.

Mrs. Whitlock wacked Jim with her cane lightly. "I'll address people as they're introduced to me, Jimmy." She turned back to Harry with a polite smile. "Haven't seen you in a good while. Away at school, I suppose."

Harry shrugged vaguely. "I'm sort of homeschooled, actually." At Mrs. Whitlock's somewhat disbelieving expression, she added, "I muffle the floors in the flat so I don't bother the downstairs neighbors. I suppose since I usually Floo everywhere, it must seem abandoned, huh?"

"Well, we never see any lights on anymore," Mrs. Whitlock said slowly.

"Unnecessary use of magic," Harry said with an easy smile. "I had a friend staying with me for a while, but since she moved out, I just go to bed when the sun goes down."

Mrs. Whitlock made a noise that was neither agreement nor reproof. "You've certainly been a very easy tenant. Everything working okay?"

"Just perfect," she said. Glancing at the crates, she added, "I'd best get these where they're going. It was lovely to see you again, Mrs. Whitlock. Jim, Clara, see you around."

"Bye Harry!" the two kids chorused.

She continued on to Krait's. The Serpent's Storeroom seemed to be doing good business when she walked in; Harry had never seen more than eight people in the shop at once, but Krait currently had over a dozen customers. She wove around them to the back room, where she deposited the crates out of the way. She was about to leave when Krait popped back into the storage room and shut the door behind him.

She raised her eyebrows, taking in the tall, blond man's serious expression. "What's wrong?" she asked.

He clenched his jaw before answering, and the scar along his neck jumped erratically. "There's been some trouble, kid. People are looking for you."

Harry frowned. "What kind of people? Why?"

"The bad kind," Krait said impatiently. "I've been threatened twice, once by mail and then last month some punk defaced my front window. Someone wants to know real bad which of my brewers can manage Potter's shaped imbuing method."

She sucked in a concerned breath. "Plenty of people in the alleys know I brew for you, and some of them know my last name."

"Exactly," Krait said. "It's only a matter of time before they ask the right person and put the pieces together. Watch yourself, kid. Leo can't be everywhere at once in these alleys."

"But why would they care who brews them when you sell the potions themselves in your shop?" she asked, bewildered. "If someone wanted one, they could just buy it."

Krait dropped his voice lower before saying, "There's recruiting happening down this way. Mostly cesspool scum, and for what, I don't know. Could be they're looking to round out their talents with a good brewer of their own."

"Recruiting for a play at the Kingship?" she guessed, disturbed. It had been over a year since a real challenge was made to Leo's position.

"No," Krait said slowly. "Something bigger. There's whispers…dangerous rhetoric, you know? Like the kind linked to these attacks what keep happening. Just take care, all right?"

"I promise to," she said quietly. "Thanks for the warning."

Krait straightened and rolled his neck in a too-casual gesture. "Can't go losing my best brewer when she's just started outclassing all the rest, can I? Get on home before it gets dark, then."

She smiled at his gruff dismissal and ducked out of the back room. When she stepped out into the late afternoon air, she spotted Leo lounging against the alley wall opposite the entrance, his posture so casual she knew he was trying hard to appear nonchalant. Merlin, but he was a welcome sight. There was something intrinsically comforting about Leo. It was in the familiar smile that hovered about his mouth and the unconsciously relaxed grace to his gait as he pushed off the wall and came up before her.

"Harry," he said, a fond crease around his eyes. "Right on time."

She raised an eyebrow while smiling up at him. "I didn't know you were the keeper of my schedule."

"Just a keen observer," Leo said with a laugh. He held up a hand and began to tick fingers off jokingly. "Let's see: first day of winter break, a restless Harry who suddenly has too much free time, and late enough in the afternoon to allow the completion of a handful of potions. Yep, that adds up to you being at the Serpent's Storeroom at this exact moment in time."

She shoved him for his presumption, but couldn't deny that he was exactly right. "So I'm predictable," she said, lifting her chin haughtily. "Maybe you should find a less boring friend."

"Boring, no," Leo said as they set off walking toward Diagon. "How was your first term?"

She shrugged. "Busy. A bit stressful. I just have too many projects going at once, I think."

Leo shot her a knowing look. "And how many of the projects did you bring home with you?"

Harry ducked her head in acknowledgment. "One or two…or a few." He laughed at her, but it wasn't censorious. Leo never was. "How've things been here?" she asked, Krait's warnings fresh in her ears.

"Pretty good," he said cheerfully. "The tournament up at Hogwarts has been great for business. They put one of the observation mirrors here for the second and third tasks, and my pickpockets made out like princes. Of course, it was lucrative for the shops and stalls in the main alley as well. Tithes are going to be good this year."

Harry kept her voice light as she asked, "Did you get a chance to watch the third task?"

Leo hummed. "I bit. I notice you taught your cousin a few things—he was wicked fast."

Harry grinned. "I tried, at least, when he came back from the Americas this past summer. He didn't take to the knife, though."

"A shame," Leo said, chuckling. "That would have been a thing to see: a nobleman wielding a knife like a common tramp on a worldwide stage. I almost wish he had."

"You're not angry at me for passing on your teachings?" she said, just to make sure.

Leo shook his head. "It's your skill now to do what you want with. I can't exactly patent hard work, can I? Anyway, I'm glad the boy's doing well, for your sake. I know it would kill you to see him hurt."

"Thanks," she said, her mood dipping a little. "I'll be glad when the final task is over."

"Might get to see that one in person," Leo said. "I gather it's to be a grand sort of spectacle, and one of our troupes got the contract with the Ministry in exchange for the damage that occurred during the World Cup."

"That's great," she forced herself to say, even while thinking it was anything but. "Won't it be dangerous for you to go, though? The Aurors might be looking for the elusive King of Thieves, and it'll be suspicious if my dad, who knows you as the son of the Aldermaster, notices the strange deference your people show you."

Leo waved an unconcerned hand. "You may not know it, but I'm a fair hand at disguise. My people know better than to identify me so publicly, too. It'll take more than the Ministry's usual security precautions to catch me."

His grin was infectious, and she found herself smiling back. It was so easy with Leo. Why couldn't it be like that with Draco? By all rights, it should be similarly awkward between her and the tan boy walking beside her. It wasn't, though.

Maybe it was the distance, she thought. Space and time could bring equilibrium to anything. Whatever the reason, she was grateful. She didn't know what she'd do without Leo. He was a fixture in her life, a strangely solid constant in a mercurial world that was otherwise defined by temporary truths in a perpetual state of change.

The following evening found Archie and Harry competing for the best-sickness acting award. Both were well-practiced in deception by now, and it was with some amusement that they attempted to one-up one another over dinner.

Archie was pale, and a sheen of sweat beaded on his brow. He picked at his food and every so often grimaced and averted his eyes, as though the very sight of the green bean casserole was making him nauseated.

In retaliation, Harry was somewhat flushed, her fringe sticking to her forehead damply and her eyes deliberately unfocused as she stared dully ahead with seemingly no care for her empty plate at all.

With a worried look between the two of them, Lily set down her fork and said, "Archie, Harry, are you all right? You both look ready to collapse."

Harry turned her head slowly toward her mother, blinking lethargically. "What, Mum?"

Lily put out a hand to feel Harry's forehead and tsked under her breath. "You're burning up, dear. Do you feel sick?"

She nodded pitifully.

Sirius, who was next to Archie, felt his own son's head with a frown. "This one doesn't have much of a fever, but he's clammy as anything."

"I was clammy earlier," Harry said, keeping her throat constricted so her voice came out rough. "Do you feel kind of achy, Arch?"

Archie groaned. "Very. Don't tell me it gets worse. What did you give me? Some American virus?"

Harry gave a weak glare, as though she hadn't the energy to be truly annoyed. "There was a bug going around school a couple of weeks ago." She looked apologetically around the table. "I hope I didn't give it to everyone."

"That's rather fast-acting," Remus commented with a frown.

James was already leaning away from her sharply. "I can't afford to get sick right before the holidays. Sorry, kids, but you both need to go to bed right now. Lily will bring you some soup later."

Lily raised an eyebrow at James and huffed. "I will, will I? What if I get sick and pass it to Addy, then?"

"I'll bring the broth," Sirius volunteered quickly.

"Maybe Harry should stay with me, then," Archie said slowly. "I've already got it, so we can quarantine ourselves from Addy."

Lily looked grateful at such thoughtfulness, but hesitated. "Will you be able to look after them both, Sirius?"

"Just leave it to me," Sirius said, tapping his fork against the table to emphasize his words. "I'll have them hearty and hale in no time."

Archie smiled at his father, then swayed in his seat suddenly. Sirius reached out a hand to steady him and said, "Let's get you home, sport."

"No soup tonight, Dad," Archie moaned as he took his feet slowly. "I don't think I can stomach anything."

"Drink lots of water, though," Lily said. "And take a Fever-reducer before you fall asleep."

Harry nodded, then winced and clutched her head as though the act had pained her. "I have some in my kit," she said. She pushed back from the table and made her way gingerly toward the stairs. When she was out of sight, she picked up the pace and rummaged in her potions kit quickly to find the bottles of Animagus Revelation along with two vials of spit-soaked Mandrake leaves. She pocketed all four and grabbed a couple of Fever-reducers to carry in her hands.

When she reached the Floo, Sirius was waiting for her. "Archie's already gone through," he said, sympathy in his eyes. "Go carefully, now."

She held the bottles in her hands tight against her sides, keeping the ones in her pockets from moving too much as she Flooed. Archie was waiting for her on the other side. He shot her a mischievous grin that quickly morphed into a pained grimace as Sirius followed Harry through the grate.

"Harry, you still have spare pajamas here, right?" Sirius asked. He shooed the two of them up the stairs like a fretting nursemaid.

She nodded and smiled weakly. "Always. Thanks for letting me stay, Sirius."

"Of course, of course," Sirius said. They reached the landing for Archie's room and Sirius said, "You two get comfortable and I'll get you some water."

He left them to change quickly into their pajamas. Harry fetched the sleeping bag she used when sleeping over at Archie's and laid it out on the ground with one of Archie's extra pillows. When Sirius came back with the water, they were both tucked up to their chins and the lights were out.

Sirius set a large glass of ice water beside each of them and brushed Harry's sweaty hair back from her face before saying, "Did you take the potions?"

Harry gestured to the empty bottles she'd dumped out in the sink just moments before.

Her uncle smiled and crept toward the door, closing it softly after a murmured, "Sleep well."

Harry and Archie were silent as they counted the seconds it would take Sirius to get downstairs and Floo back to Potter Place to finish his dinner. After a few minutes, they both sat up and lit the torches again. Archie had a grin as wide as his face as Harry pulled the bottles and vials they needed out of her pockets.

She handed Archie the vial with his spit in it and one of the Animagus Revelation potions. He eyed it with mixed excitement and trepidation. "It's going to make us sick for a week afterwards, right?"

She nodded. The Animagus Revelation took quite a toll on the body; there was a reason people didn't drink it whenever they wanted to turn into an animal, after all. "It'll make our cover more believable when we're actually sick tomorrow," she said.

"How do you know it won't cancel out the Modified Polyjuice when you take it?" Archie asked next.

Harry grimaced. "I don't. I made an extra batch just in case, though."

Archie nodded, his concerns evidently satisfied. He lifted the bottle of shimmering potion to the light. "I can't believe we're finally going to find out our forms," he said. "I hope it's something useful. Like a phoenix."

Harry rolled her eyes. "You read the book—you know it won't be a magical animal. There have been no recorded cases of that ever happening."

Her cousin shrugged, a smile tugging at his lips. "It was just an example. Useful comes in all kinds, I guess." A thought struck him and he blanched. "Harry, what if I'm a fish?"

She snorted. "There's nothing fish-like about you."

"I'm a water sign, Harry! I could die before we change back. Doesn't it take an hour to revert?" Archie gazed at her with wide, earnest eyes.

She sighed, but said, "I'll let you go first, then. If you're a fish, I'll put you in the bathroom sink." She was pretty sure neither of them would be a fish, whatever astrological indications to the contrary.

Her ludicrous reassurance seemed to calm Archie down, and he took a deep breath. "Okay. So I just add the leaf to the bottle and drink, right?"

"That's the gist of it," she said, nodding. She gestured to the mirror next to Archie's closet. "Try to note as many details as you can when you transform, so you can recall them later. Remember: after we take this potion, we still have to learn how to do the actual self-transfiguration. This is just to identify our forms."

Archie nodded. "Yeah, I get it. Ready?" He unstoppered the vial of spit and dipped a finger into it with a grimace. With the wet leaf clinging to his skin, he transferred it to the bottle of Animagus Revelation and swirled it gently.

"Wait until it turns silver," she said. It only took a moment before the potion looked like liquified unicorn horn. With a ready grin, Archie tipped it back and gulped the whole thing down at once.

He grimaced, opened his mouth to say something—no doubt a comment on the taste, but froze comically. He shuddered, his muscles twitching briefly, and then the bottle fell from his limp fingers and his body twisted around and into itself in the blink of an eye. Under Harry's watchful gaze, Archie shrank, his clothes folding into some dimension that only Transfiguration Masters had mapped, and in just a few short seconds her cousin was gone. In his place was a tawny fox about two feet in length, complete with narrow snout, pointed ears, and fluffy tail.

The fox rolled across the floor and back to its feet with a shake. He took a couple of steps forwards, fell, then took a couple more back. Archie seemed to notice his own tail out of the corner of his eye, because he spun quickly on the spot before tripping over his own feet and flopping clumsily to the floor.

Harry had to laugh. She'd worried it might be difficult to identify their exact animal types, but Archie was the most obvious red fox she'd ever seen. He was significantly larger than other species of fox, and his white underbelly ran all the way up under his chin to curl around the sides of his mouth. In a way, it made sense, she mused. Foxes were playful and adventurous, with very strong family ties. On top of that, they were a species of canine. When Sirius found out, he was going to be pleased as anything.

As Archie struggled to coordinate his newfound limbs, Harry turned to her own bottle. She added the leaf and swirled it expertly. Before taking it, she hesitated, Archie's worry echoing in her ears. With a soundless grumble, she headed into his bathroom, filled his sink with water, and sat herself on the counter next to it before drinking the potion. If she was a fish, at least she'd be able to flop her gills into the water before she suffocated.

The sensation was utterly dizzying, and Rigel had to close her eyes against the vertigo as an experience not unlike Polyjuice Potion wracked her body. Her stomach heaved against the feeling, but in the next moment a hook like a portkey in the vicinity of her navel overtook her awareness and she collapsed in on herself.

She could feel her body shifting, she noticed with a small sense of wonder. Harry felt every bone and muscle and organ as they shrank, shifted, and twisted into something new. When all the movement stopped, she held herself very still. Nothing hurt and she was still conscious of the fact that she was Harry Potter, human girl under the effects of an animagus potion. She could also breathe without effort, which told her without a doubt that she was not a fish.

When she opened her eyes, the first thing that struck her was the wide field of vision now afforded to her. She didn't have to move her head at all, yet she could see almost the entirety of Archie's bathroom. Including his mirror. Surprise took her as she caught sight of her new form, and her neck muscles twitched almost involuntarily. Her vision swam oddly as her head moved, but by keeping it still she could process what she was seeing.

Harry was a bird. A black one, at least a foot and a half long, with glossy feathers and a deep black beak to match. The only spots of color were her eyes, which gleamed like emeralds in her small skull. A startled noise escaped her, emerging as a sort of croak. Curious, she made the noise again, this time on purpose. A deep throated, "Pruuk, pruuk," rang through the bathroom clearly.

She lifted a foot, just to see if she could, then lifted the other one next. It wasn't easy to balance the clawed appendages against the smooth counter, and her arms went out automatically to stabilize her—wings, rather. The iridescent plumage was like slick oil, and she admired it for a moment. The wedge-like shape of her tail caught her interest, next, and Harry mentally classified herself as a raven, subspecies of the common crow.

Snape would be so disappointed if he knew, she thought with amusement. A raven instead of a snake. Better than a lion, she supposed, ruffling and smoothing her feathers reflexively. Ravens were exceedingly common. She could blend in just about anywhere, which was more than could be said about her father's stag animagus form.

A noise from Archie's room brought her attention away from her own reflection, and Harry waddled to the edge of the sink before pausing. The most obvious thing to do would be to fly down to the floor. She had no idea how to go about such a trick, however. Harry tried to lift her wings, and after a confusing moment realized the muscles to do so were located in her chest, not the wings themselves. With a few minutes of experimentation, she was able to isolate the muscles and draw her wings out to their full breadth. She had maybe four feet total wingspan, but the wings themselves were so light she didn't feel unbalanced at all.

She tried flapping her wings up and down quickly, but it only took her a couple inches off the ground before she landed awkwardly on clawed feet again. Harry peeked over the edge of the sink and wondered if she ought to jump or not. How did birds do it? She crouched down, pretty sure she'd seen birds do so before taking off. With a powerful beat of her wings, she tipped forward off the edge of the sink—and fell, plummeting to the ground as the air streamed between her feathers.

Harry rolled to her feet with an irritated twitch of her head. So much for animal instincts. She toddled toward the door, awkwardly holding her wings out as she wasn't sure how to tuck them back into place properly.

Archie was preening in front of his closet mirror, picking up his paws one at a time and every so often emitting a high-pitched yip that was almost a bark. Harry croaked to get his attention and the fox spun around instantly, a growl on his lips. Archie tucked his sharp teeth away a moment later, as his human mind caught up with him, but it didn't stop Harry from letting out a caw of alarm.

The stared at one another. It occurred to Harry that foxes sometimes ate birds, but after a moment Archie's tongue lolled out and he rolled on his back with a very foxy-like grin, showing his white underbelly. Harry relaxed, her feathers soothed back into place, and she cocked her head at the fox in inquisition.

Archie took to his feet again in answer and proceeded to prance about the room on all fours. Her cousin had gained an admirable amount of control over his limbs in such a short amount of time. Harry watching him with amusement before attempting to flap herself into the air once more. She rose a couple of inches, then landed again. Archie released a series of yips she was pretty sure counted as a laugh, and she clicked her beak at him in retaliation.

They didn't have forever in their current shapes, so she and Archie both set about learning as much about the feel of their animagus forms as possible. Harry desperately wanted to figure out how to fly, but the exact mechanics of it weren't intuitive at all. Eventually, she realized she needed to keep her feathers close together to prevent the air from simply escaping between them. Somehow, she still wasn't getting enough force to take her into the air, however. Focused only on her new shape, Harry didn't realize how much time had passed until Archie barked agitatedly to get her attention and pointed his muzzle at the clock on the wall.

It had been an hour and a half. Harry felt her heart sink as she realized they had far exceeded the advertised amount of time the Animagus Revelation should have afforded them.

She tried to remember what it felt like to be human. The awareness of her true form was just out of reach, and with a trickle of fear she realized for the first time that she couldn't feel Dom in this form at all. It was as though a large part of her human consciousness was locked away for the moment. She had no access to her magic, wandless or otherwise, and no matter how her mind raced she couldn't think of any way out of the raven's body.

Archie whined in the back of his throat and sank to the floor to rest his head on his front paws, ears drooping. Harry tilted her head to focus one of her eyes on him better and realized his fur was slowly changing color. It looked more rust now than tawny, and she wondered whether some of his natural metamorphmagus ability had bled over into his animagus form.

Harry waddled toward her worried cousin and tucked her beak up against his neck fur gently. Somehow, they would get out of this. The potion couldn't have gone that wrong, seeing as it had changed them perfectly into animals while allowing them to retain their human thoughts. It just appeared to be a bit…over…powered. Harry croaked in annoyance. Of course. She'd over-brewed it. Hadn't she replaced all her ingredients after Snape told her about the issue? Everything in her kit was new, except, of course, what had already been put into the Animagus Revelation potions before she'd been made aware of the problem. That, and the vials of spit, she thought in grim understanding.

It wouldn't last forever, then. Just…significantly longer than expected. Hopefully, it would wear off before either of them got too hungry. Harry didn't know exactly what ravens ate, but she suspected it included bugs.

Archie's ears twitched and he turned his head toward the door just moments before Harry heard the sound of footsteps coming down the hall. They both scrambled for cover, but neither was coordinated enough to move quickly. Archie dove into Harry's sleeping bag while Harry attempted to flap her way back toward the bathroom. She almost made it.

Sirius opened the door carefully at first, no doubt expecting to find two teenagers sleeping off acute illness, but when he spotted their empty covers, he flung it open wide and stepped into the room with alarm on his face.

"Archie? Harry?" He scanned the room and noticed Harry at once, conspicuous as she was in the bathroom doorway. With a frown, he drew his wand in an instant and leveled it at her warily. "What the devil—?"

Before he could decide to cast at her, Archie sprang from his hiding place and skidded toward Sirius's feet with a barking battle-yip, baring sharp teeth in her defense. Sirius leapt backwards with a cry and he tried to stun the fox, but Archie rolled out of the way and whined loudly, tongue lolling out at the wizard as he placed himself between Harry and Sirius' wand.

Sirius blinked, lowered his wand slightly, and said, "…kids?" Archie yipped happily and Harry let out a single croak of agreement. Sirius's eyes, already wide, blinked hard. "You…you managed the transformation already?" A smile grew across his face until he was grinning proudly. "Well done! Look at you! I mean—it's only been a few months. Now who is who?" He looked between the two of them eagerly. "Wait, I know! Archie, you're the fox, right?"

Archie bounced on his feet and plodded forward to nudge up against his dad's legs. Sirius sank to his knees and Archie happily jumped into his lap. The wizard laughed and ran his hands gently over the fox's sunset-colored fur. "Do you know what this means? We can go running together, Arch. Wait until James finds out—and Harry! I might have guessed you'd be a bird; always one to observe from afar before that endless curiosity drew you in. I suppose you're some sort of magpie or jay, eh? It's only just that the next generation of Marauders would embody the trickiest of nature's creatures."

After another minute of looking over their animal forms and making various exclamations, Sirius said, "Well, turn back then, and tell me how you managed it so quickly."

Archie began to whine again, his ears pulling back, and Harry ducked her beak into her wing embarrassedly. Sirius narrowed his eyes, looking back and forth between them. "Don't tell me you haven't learned to turn back yet."

Archie jumped out of his lap and over to where his empty potions bottle lay on its side. He nudged it with his nose and yipped.

Sirius let out a sudden laugh, throwing his head back in merciless delight. "Oh, I see! You haven't learned it at all yet—you've only taken the Revelation potion." He shook his head at their downtrodden postures and laughed again. "Serves you right, not waiting like I told you to. I suppose you're stuck for now? You know, a crueler man than me would leave you to sit it out."

Harry tried to make a noise of supplication, but the "pruuk" just sounded agitated. She flapped her wings restlessly and rose half a foot before dropping back to the ground.

Sirius snorted. "You might want to read up on bird mechanics, Harry. You look like a duckling with two broken wings."

She ruffled her feathers in annoyance, but had to concede that she would be doing just that, if she ever regained her human shape. Sirius raised his wand again with a sigh and said, "I suppose I can't torture you too long, seeing as I did promise Lily to look after you."

The Animagus Reversal Spell lit the room with a blue light, and with a lurch that felt a bit as though she was an accordion that someone had pulled sharply apart, Harry found herself standing on her own limbs again. She lunged forward to hug Sirius, nearly tripping as her usual muscle control reasserted itself. "Thank you," she said into his shirt. "I over brewed the potion and thought we were going to be stuck all night." Surreptitiously, she put a hand up to feel the shape of her face, double-checking that the Animagus Revelation potion hadn't interfered with her Modified Polyjuice at all. They'd been incredibly lucky, it seemed.

Sirius hugged her back before letting go to study her carefully. "You appear to be in one piece, at least. I wish you hadn't gone behind my back like this, though. It's dangerous to try and do this on your own. What would you have done if Archie got hungry and lost himself to his animal instincts?"

"The thought occurred to me rather late," she admitted, eyeing Archie's now-russet form with the respect paid by prey to a predator.

A second spell reverted Archie to his own, albeit metamorphed, form, and he whooped with delight before joining in on the group hug. "I wouldn't have eaten Harry," he murmured, sounding mildly offended. "She didn't smell like food."

Harry drew back with a skeptical expression. "What did I smell like then?"

"Not-food," he said at once. "Can't explain it better than that."

"You may have recognized her as pack on some level," Sirius said, sounding excited. Then he seemed to recall he was supposed to be scolding them. "Promise you won't do something unsupervised like that again. Why didn't you just wait for me to teach you?" he added, something like hurt in his eyes. "I told you I'd help."

Archie and Harry exchanged a guilty look. "We sort of wanted to prove we could do it," Archie admitted slowly. "Like you did, when you and Uncle James were young. Also, we thought since we don't have much time over the holidays, our lessons would go faster if we already knew our forms. Now we don't have to spend valuable learning time with you meditating or trying to cast a patronus."

"We wanted to surprise you, too," Harry said ruefully.

Sirius gave them fond looks of exasperation. "Come on, you two: you should know you don't have to try to look cool in front of me after all these years." They both poked him in the ribs as he laughed.

"But seriously, are you going to tell the other adults?" Harry asked. She had a feeling Remus hadn't changed his mind since the last time they'd brought it up to him, and Lily would almost certainly be furious that they'd taken such an unnecessary risk, on top of lying about being sick in order to do it.

"Would that be a very Sirius thing to do?" her uncle asked, waggling his eyebrows. He considered them for a long moment, then smirked. "Besides, now that I'm in on the secret it's much more fun. I can't wait to see the look on their faces when you really achieve it, but until then…well, it might be better to present the facts as fait accompli."

"Ask forgiveness, not permission," Archie agreed, grinning in relief.

Sirius pulled them into a hug again. "Aww, how can I be mad when you turned out exactly how I always wanted?"

Harry and Archie both had to smile at that. It was quintessentially Sirius to be more proud of the mischief behind an act than upset by the trouble it caused. They were lucky to be raised by a man so understanding and supportive, who encouraged their flight even as he guarded against their fall.

Once she and Archie recovered from the truly miserable sickness the aftermath of the Animagus Revelation potion inflicted on them, the holidays passed quicker than she wished. Days danced off the calendar in dizzying pirouettes of potions, animagus study, and time with her family. With Lily now working independently from home, she saw a lot more of her mother on those days when she didn't venture into the alleys. Lily also used her home lab more frequently, which meant Harry stuck to the makeshift lab in number eight, Dogwood Lane when she wanted a prolonged period of uninterrupted brewing.

Her experiments with Bicorn milk were only partially successful. The reaction was exactly what she needed it to be, but it wasn't enough of what she needed, unfortunately. A few short days before she was to return to Hogwarts found her tapping her fingers against the windowsill in her small kitchen, wondering if there was a way to tweak the base such that the Bicorn milk featured more strongly in relation to the neutral ingredients.

She supposed there wouldn't be any point to having a constant base for the process of shaped imbuing if she went and tweaked it whenever she wanted to achieve a different result. Maybe she could try imbuing the Bicorn milk before adding it into the potion? She didn't want to just increase the volume of milk; she was fairly certain the high fat content was already distracting the amplifying magic from the true signifying ingredient, which should be the proteins in the milk.

She had to remove the fat from the milk somehow. Harry sighed in annoyance. She knew only the bare bones of distillation theory. Mostly, she was good at adding things together, not separating them into their constituent parts.

There was someone she knew that might be able to help, though. She checked the position of the sun and wondered whether he'd be awake so early in the afternoon. Harry could wait until nightfall, but Krait's warning had made her more conscientious about her safety, and she didn't want to wander the alleys after dark if she didn't have to.

Thinking it couldn't hurt to try, she locked up the flat and made her way back toward Knockturn Alley. The Lamia Lodge hadn't changed at all, except that a significant amount of paint had abandoned the grey door since that summer. Eyeing the newer scratches distrustfully, she pushed the door inward with a wince for her poor ears.

Eyes narrowed in annoyance, Harry rummaged in her potions kit and produced a small vial of sunflower oil. A few drops on each of the hinges and the door swung shut near-silently. Feeling vaguely vindicated, she tucked the oil away and made her way down the dim corridor. Gavril was halfway across the lobby when she emerged from the entryway, no doubt having heard her entrance and prepared to investigate the delay. He stopped so fast at the sight of her his lank hair swung forward to drape around his shoulders.

"Good afternoon, Mr. Gavril," she said with a pleasant nod.

From his looming height, Gavril stared down at her consideringly. His waxen features creased in a slow smile. "The Rogue's little messenger bird. Come with more bad news?"

"Not at all. I was wondering if Mr. Kasten was awake yet. I wanted to ask him about a potions problem."

Gavril made a noise of impatience that was the scrape of metal on stone. "Always with the honorifics. We are not 'misters' here. The Newborn is below, as always."

He glanced toward the staircase that led down to the lower levels and turned to make his way back toward the desk, which she noticed had acquired a new leg since the last time she'd seen it.

She took a couple of steps toward the stairs, then remembered the way Leo had been careful not to use his wand in coven territory unless given explicit permission. "Could I take a light down with me?"

From the desk Gavril produced a taper that was as long and slim as he was, and as she approached he set a single match beside it with a smile that flashed his fangs. "How is the Rogue these days?"

"Fine, I'm sure," she said. "How's Irina?"

At mention of his mate, Gavril's smile softened just a little. "Still beautiful." As she headed toward the dark staircase he added playfully, "Watch your step."

She took what she thought was the correct passage at the bottom of the stairs, and before long came to a door that read 'Distillery' in faint letters. She knocked, and there was a long pause before the door swung slowly open.

The short-haired, yellow-eyed vampire blinked down at her over her small candle. His head tilted and he sniffed delicately. "You were here before," he said, his voice a strange combination of rustling leaves and trickling water.

"Harry," she reminded him. "I'm sorry to bother you while you're working—"

"I'm always working," Kasten said.

Harry smiled. She knew that feeling. "I just wanted to ask whether you had time to teach me a little about essences. It doesn't have to be right now," she assured him.

Kasten left the doorway and retreated back to his workstation. She hesitated, unsure whether he was dismissing her, but then he said, "Come inside."

The workroom was as she remembered it. Counters ran at waist height all along the walls, and the little light her candle gave off illuminated shelves upon shelves of purified ingredients reaching all the way to the ceiling.

"What do you want to know?" he asked, not looking at her as he put what appeared to be a thermometer into the cauldron that was simmering over a blue flame.

"I'd like to learn how to distill Bicorn milk into its constituent parts," she said. "I'm working on a potion that needs a more concentrated form of the milk. Could I turn the raw ingredient into an essence?"

"Perhaps," Kasten said vaguely. "It depends on what you want it to be. Milk is simple to separate, but the quiddity of the substance you're searching for will determine what kind of a separation is required."

Harry was quite sure she had no idea what he was talking about. "Quiddity?" she repeated, hoping her confused tone would encourage a more elaborate explanation.

Kasten's voice was impatient as he said, "Quiddity, yes. That which a thing is in itself, which is to say, that which, without it, it would not be."

"Okay," she said, only slightly more enlightened. "Well, I basically want the proteins from the Bicorn milk, but not the fat."

The vampire hummed in understanding. "You want the dry matter. Removing the fat will be easy. Once it is gone, heat and salt will decouple the water from the proteins you need. With some encouragement, you'll have an essence in no time."

Harry was heartened to hear that, though some of what he said was over her head. "Can you teach me how?"

His yellow eyes caught the light of the candle as he glanced over at her. "Yes."

She smiled. "Thank you. I can pay for your time, of course."

"Money is meaningless," he said, uninterested.

"Oh. Well, what would be not-meaningless, then?" she asked.

Kasten seemed to think it over while slowly stirring the cauldron before him. Finally, he said, "There is a shop in Diagon. It is only open while the sun is up."

She waited for him to continue, but he fell silent. Patiently, she said, "I could go there before it closes. Do you need something they sell?"

"I need a snake," he said.

"A snake." Of course he did. "I can get you a snake. Which one?"

"I also need a kneazle."

Harry blinked. "Okay. Is it a…pet shop?"

"Yes. The snake must be an elapid." Kasten hesitated before adding, "That's a family of snakes."

She nodded. "Tropical and subtropical, right?" Elapids included cobras and kraits, and as far as she knew all of them were venomous. "Are you still working mainly with toxins?"

Kasten shook his head, paused, then nodded instead. "Partly. I am interested in antisera at present."

"Like antivenins?" Harry guessed.

"Antivenins, antitoxins, and more," Kasten agreed. His voice began to pick up speed as he explained. "Sometimes the essence of one thing is an antiserum to another. Quite fascinating, isn't it? Practically speaking it is, of course, the opposite of essence creating, as usually a serum requires re-diluting to some extent before it is useful. The two fields are related, however. Antisera are an extension of my experimentation with inactive essences."

It did sound fascinating, and Harry said so.

Kasten seemed pleased, if his elaboration was any indication. "Essences are rarely understood. It isn't a simple function of opacity, as some assume. At times it is as simple as removing the non-essential, however, I find that an essence is also sometimes an amalgamation of separate, mutually dependent parts."

She didn't pretend to fully understand him, but she smiled in thanks for the explanation. "One elapid and one kneazle, then. Anything else?"

The young vampire shook his head slowly. "You'll go now?"

"Of course." She left him in his lab and made her way carefully back toward the staircase. When she rejoined Gavril in the lobby she said, "I'll be back."

Gavril didn't lift his head from its resting place on the desk, opting to flick unconcerned fingers at her instead. She set the candle down beside his lax arm and left the vampire hotel.

The sun was still strong in the sky as she strode into the Magical Menagerie. She told the young man behind the counter what she needed and he scratched his chin lazily.

"Got a green mamba," he said. "Bit dangerous, though."

She shrugged. "I'll take it. And the kneazle?"

"We've got black, grey, and orange," he told her.

"Any is fine." In truth she felt a bit awkward choosing the unlucky kneazle, as the odds of its being exsanguinated once it produced the antibodies Kasten wanted were relatively high. At least, that's what she assumed he was doing with the animals. She didn't know enough about his work to say for certain.

In the end, she left with the green mamba and a black kneazle in separate carrying cases. Harry wove her way back to Knockturn Alley and reached the Lamia Lodge well before sundown.

Gavril eyed her interestedly on her way back through the lobby. "Is that a courtship gift?"

Harry stopped walking to stare at him. Was it a what?

"Because you really should have sought permission from Count Aurel first," he drawled, disapproval lacing his rasping voice.

Harry spluttered. "Why would—? No. It's—he just needs these for his experiments." She didn't know where Gavril would get the idea she wanted to court the Count's grandson, much less why two random animals would be considered an appropriate offering to a vampire in such a situation. Gavril gave her a skeptical expression, as though she might be lying about why she was toting a snake and a kneazle through his lobby.

Her cheeks flaring, she transferred both carriers to one hand and swiped the still-burning candle with the other. Deciding to ignore Gavril's insane question, she descended the stairs again and fairly ran the distance to Kasten's workspace.

He bade her set the carriers on an empty counter and motioned her over to where he now had a second cauldron set up next to the first.

"You have raw Bicorn milk?" he asked. She produced a small bottle from her kit after a moment of searching. He took the bottle from her and examined it before nodding. "This will do."

He moved over to the counter on the right side of the workroom and Harry followed him with her candle. The counter held a strange-looking device. It was shaped like a wheel lying on its side, and in each spoke was an angled slot about the size of a small bottle. Kasten slid her bottle of Bicorn milk into one of the slots and put his hand on the edge of the wheel. With a sharp motion, his arm flew sideways, flicking the wheel into motion.

Round and round it spun, at a speed she could scarcely comprehend. Kasten used his incredible strength casually, pushing the wheel twice more to keep it moving at the rate he wanted.

When it stopped, he quickly removed the vial and held it up for her to see. The once-homogenous milk was now separated into distinct sections. "The heavier components will be pressed to the outside," he said. Uncorking the vial, he skimmed the top layer off of the milk with a spoon and said, "Fat is light. Now it is gone."

Harry was stunned that it could be so simple. She didn't know where Kasten had obtained such a spinning device, but she supposed she could find a spell to do the same basic function for her.

Kasten wasn't finished yet, however. He poured the remaining milk into the cauldron and took a pinch of something from a pouch at his waist, tossing it into the small cauldron as well and adjusting the portable fire charm to his satisfaction.

"Salt?" she guessed.

He nodded. "The proteins are not truly dissolved in the water, only bonded to it. The salt will disrupt those bonds. The heat will encourage them to abandon the bonds altogether, and the water will eventually evaporate. What is left it the essence you need."

Harry smiled, knowing she could recreate Kasten's methods herself with a bit of practice. If the concentrated Bicorn protein worked, that would be one more potion for her portable healing kit.

While they waited for the water to evaporate, Harry said curiously, "If you don't mind me asking, how long have you been doing this?"

Kasten's yellow eyes seemed to flicker in the candlelight. "I have been studying essences for sixty years, fifty of which I have spent as a member of the undead."

Seeing as he didn't look much older than twenty, she supposed he'd become interested in the subject as a teenager. "Are you really Count Aurel's grandson?" she asked. She had heard the count was hundreds of years old. It didn't seem possible.

Her fellow potioneer rolled his shoulders uncomfortably. "The Count is a distant ancestor of mine. It is easier to call him 'grandfather' than to count how many 'greats' our true relation reflects. He does not make a practice of turning all of his descendants," he added before she could ask. "Why he chose me, when I had several older siblings more conventionally talented and sociable, I've never been able to discern."

She wondered whether it had happened suddenly, or with his permission. Kasten didn't seem fully at ease with the subject, though, so she let her questions fade into the back of her mind. "Sometimes it does little good to ask why things happen. Better to focus on what to do once they have," she suggested quietly.

Kasten hummed his agreement. "I've found my purpose. I don't want for more in this life."

Harry was hit with an acute, irrational bolt of envy. What she wouldn't give to be left to brew whatever she wanted, whenever she wanted. Could there be a more perfect existence? In the wake of that longing came the bitter-sweet knowledge that such a life was beyond her, for the time being. Someday…but then, it didn't do to dwell on someday and ignore the now, did it?

Soon there was nothing left in the cauldron but a kind of damp paste. Kasten scraped it into a vial for her and said, "Any more and it might burn. Will this suffice?"

She grinned. "We'll find out when I try it in the potion tomorrow. Thank you, Kasten."

The vampire rolled a shoulder in a motion that she was coming to associate with some slight embarrassment. "Come back if you find another essence you need."

"I will," she promised, more than pleased with the day's work.

Harry took her newly acquired essence and left the lab. She was drifting somewhat absent-mindedly up the stairs when she heard a voice that made her pause and listen. It wasn't that she recognized the voice—in fact, she doubted she'd ever heard it before—rather that the tone of it was so out of place in the Lamia Lodge as to be remarkable in itself.

"—demand to see the Count this time," the man was saying fiercely.

It was Irina who answered. "The Count only entertains humans when he's hungry. Are you volunteering?"

An outraged huff preceded the man warning, "My master will hear of this insolence. When the time comes for the oppressed peoples of the world to take their rightful place, you'll be out in the cold."

Gavril let out an amused chuckle. "Mortals fear the cold, not we."

"And if you stay a while, I don't think you'll find us oppressed at all," Irina added, dark promise thrumming through her words. "In fact, we can be quite unrestrained when the mood takes us."

The man hissed something too low for Harry to hear, and footsteps told her he was leaving. Quick as a cat, she crept up a few more stairs until she could see the wizard. She caught his profile from the side and immediately recognized him from the World Cup. It was Crouch's son, disheveled haircut and strange lip-tic intact. When she heard the front door slam behind him, Harry slowly climbed the last few steps and gained Gavril and Irina's full attention.

"Eavesdropping is plebian," Irina told her.

Knowing full well that vampires could and did listen to almost anything that happened in their vicinity, Harry ignored the reprimand to ask, "What was he doing here?"

"Same as those who've come before," Gavril said, shrugging unconcernedly. "Trying to convince our coven to join in his glorious revolution."

"As if we'd ever participate in something the Carpathians deemed a worthy cause," his redheaded mate said with a curl of her upper lip.

"What revolution?" she asked, eyes tight with concern. Was this the same recruiting Krait had spoken of? "Did he say who he represents?" She didn't know much about Crouch jr., but Mr. Ogden had said he was one of the party members Riddle entrusted to help formulate the tournament tasks. If he was there representing the politician, recruiting from the alleys for some kind of coup d'état, then Riddle had played them all.

Gavril scoffed. "His mysterious backer does not give a name. Calls himself the flight of death. Baroque, no?"

The flight of death. Her French training translated the phrase automatically and Harry felt her stomach clench in unchecked dread. Voldemort. It had been a year and a half since she heard that name, but the memories came without calling, a rush of pain, anger, and fear.

"You can't trust Voldemort," she said sharply. "Whatever you do, don't listen to a word he says. And be careful; he doesn't like to take no for an answer."

Gavril exchanged a lightning-fast glance with Irina and said, "We've no interest in listening to a wizard who sends such rude messengers. If the conflict grows too irksome, we may simply relocate."

Harry accepted that with a small amount of relief. If Voldemort was truly still alive, and actively recruiting to boot, then the fewer who joined him the better. "Have you told Leo?"

"The Rogue has not asked."

Right. She would warn him, then. Come to that, she should warn others, too. Her father, to start. She had no proof that Crouch jr. had broken any laws, but surely she could think of something to tell James that communicated the seriousness of the potential threat Voldemort represented.

The only one who might truly understand, she realized with a sick sense of irony, was Riddle himself. Harry's mind raced in circles as she left the Lamia Lodge, and finally settled on a memory of Pettigrew, of all people, fiercely justifying his coming to Hogwarts with a simple truth. Those in Riddle's party were always more afraid of him than they were of anything else. If the DMLE couldn't get to Crouch jr., Riddle certainly could.